<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25999-LFW-LH-RW9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3355 IS: National Strategy for Combating Scams Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3355</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a national strategy for combating scams, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Strategy for Combating Scams Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc89101f422ef4ad4ac4c5844a69d2085"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id6640681a371445468fb2874ba2289beb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>More than 4 in 10 individuals in the United States, an estimated 141,500,000 adults, say they have lost money to scams or had sensitive information obtained and used fraudulently.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id527c412c489c447c985e2fd60c3cc971"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Consumers reported losing more than $12,000,000,000 to fraud in 2024, a 25 percent increase over the prior year, with imposter scams being the most commonly reported scam category.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9de517bce99147f9b2ee16922974e25a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Criminals are increasingly using Generative Artificial Intelligence to conduct scams, including hyper-realistic voice deepfakes to manipulate victims.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2e629056b4614b7dbf8203dfff6eb1c7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Scams harm all people of the United States, but can particularly affect older adults by harming their mental health and by forcing them to live with fewer resources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd3f6a41d96344fe9f10ff9d5ad71100"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Government Accountability Office found that there are at least 13 agencies engaged in a range of activities relating to countering scams, all of which have their own mandate and authorities and are largely carrying out their activities independently.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc2aad3ea9f44de2aa6103eee41c447f"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To improve the ability of Federal agencies to coordinate and target efforts to counter scams, the Government Accountability Office has recommended that the Federal Bureau of Investigations lead an effort to develop a National Strategy for Combating Scams.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id3d1143ea9ced4e5fa658a46d3531e41d"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Strategy for Combating Scams</header><subsection id="id8f2df6425e214486a961f224c9bd748e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of working group</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall assemble a working group to develop a National Strategy for Combating Scams, in coordination with the heads of each of the following:</text><paragraph id="id7a3ccf07684346169e0828a52154b243"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id107fdd08ced14c01b977d30a747e12d7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c98a55bcb3244edb5bd8540b8c64cfd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00933de894fb4dd9ab86318b878b6f19"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d28ccac385643f98a0e79c6058bddae"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id269c88e435f64ccda158ba9314b46f64"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Federal Reserve Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idae7a4672c8c043af95aec064efff9956"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Financial Crimes Enforcement Network.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7113a0dee20745f89800a7a353ce3805"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbaf8bced0fb74e7a901abdf9676cc45d"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The National Credit Union Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1afdb7659b004f719fd834754252fd03"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Office of the Comptroller of Currency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5ee9104b2214b4788934446b63d791e"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Office of the United States Attorney.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab7ed5e7f97645c595fc412411d59fc9"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The United States Secret Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida35bdd7111d64530afd5fffd147b47f3"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd63518c1048340ddbca648f99b957e05"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a11fd4583e343f8b25d47ba29f0ada7"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40833bcd7f97476987054a3571929d9c"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The Commodities Futures Trading Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ee20bc74c784f899a1118851ca81774"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Social Security Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5ed8a84b06941f38db6240e03e2de7f"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Any other Federal Department or agency, as determined appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idff20138cfd5c43078aacdfae9d1e0ea6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of National Strategy for Combating Scams</header><text>The working group established pursuant to subsection (a) shall develop a National Strategy for Combating Scams that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id965afce056054461acfad3d350b5ff8e"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporates feedback from community stakeholders, including—</text><subparagraph id="idb4cde06f9d8f4ee691547bf3bfa7c775"><enum>(A)</enum><text>survivors of scams, and groups that represent survivors of scams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id406233f1a6a74235ac1d24f512fd23da"><enum>(B)</enum><text>older adults and groups that represent older adults;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e1dfc0fd0f546c09d2fa846fb416ca7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities and groups that represent individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde68476de3de48e98097f057a7a4b39f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Federal, State, and local prosecutors and law enforcement officials with expertise in scams, and groups that represent such prosecutors and law enforcement officials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideeb54d977c044a548f7e7fb52af82208"><enum>(E)</enum><text>business and non-profit organizations that play a role in preventing and addressing scams, including telecommunications, financial, social media, retail, and technology companies, and groups that represent such businesses and non-profit organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddff221eb12de46b193caa77ebcba5256"><enum>(F)</enum><text>experts on human behavior and scam prevention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc70fdc8dac794de38282ba4c217aad50"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Adult Protective Services agencies, and groups that represent them;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61d4535bb6754ba4a2b9f9cc4fe8b17e"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Area Agencies on Aging, and groups that represent them;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idddc46926b8d0480b84d758b34c9c6f64"><enum>(I)</enum><text>State, local, and Tribal government officials, and groups that represent State and local government officials; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc228affd5387467a8b2dfbc468e8e1df"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any other community stakeholders, as determined appropriate by the working group;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id06f515abbfbc4ee6b12802d4269c0a15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishes a definition of <quote>scam</quote>, for use in the National Strategy and by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Federal Trade Commission, and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, the establishment of which includes—</text><subparagraph id="idc9f0f9d102d6430c894414067533d500"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis explaining the reasons the working group selected the definition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id34d2c8283b5b4e1890bea7195338de77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of whether agencies other than the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Federal Trade Commission, and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau FBI should adopt the definition, including an analysis of the barriers or unintended consequences of doing so;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6cc5b67afd5a4c8f87908037ce5037d4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evaluates the risks from scams, including an analysis of threats and vulnerabilities, health and financial risks to scam survivors, risks to national and economic security, and the proper Federal response to scams;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd5ecb6788bf44eaab12567e69e2f8c51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>evaluates methods for preventing scams, including evidence-based best practices that can be implemented and measured by the Federal Government, State, local, and Tribal governments, businesses, non-profit organizations, community members, and family members of those at risk of being scammed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id75efb18b8c3949dca4186ad7188e2dbb"><enum>(5)</enum><text>defines agency roles, responsibilities, and authorities for preventing and combating scams;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id074955b142a14fc1a0964f4ca9fe4167"><enum>(6)</enum><text>analyzes maintaining a single, government-wide estimate of scams perpetrated and the dollar losses associated with them, including incidents not reported, including either—</text><subparagraph id="id7e75ca72344143858dde36590e0fca18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a plan for developing and maintaining such an estimate; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31773e0e030e4a65ac503bf582ff40a9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of the barriers preventing the development of such an estimate and the legislative, regulatory, or administrative changes that could eliminate those barriers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8cbea3e8e0d24601930505130fcb6819"><enum>(7)</enum><text>formulates a plan to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63d6d297c8524a71a898934148acadf5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure coordinated, consistent, and accessible consumer complaint reporting for scams across Federal agencies, including complaint reporting that is accessible for individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf0ee6c3262be48b2b41e1696e669d2df"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify duplication in tasks and responsibilities between agencies and establish deconfliction procedures for overlapping jurisdictional authorities to improve coordination and collaboration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida37ad832491447038be1398886fdb06e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure harmonized, adequate, timely, and accurate data collection and data aggregation on scams across Federal agencies, including ways to—</text><clause id="idfe2d9750b1b3497993508a487a56da70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>better collect data and encourage reporting on scams;</text></clause><clause id="id28c98473dd3d4238ae668bea2c78ac0c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>better identify scams;</text></clause><clause id="idf266c8c586614860b11ee4f00a70ceb1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>consistently collect data on the types of scams, dollar losses from scams, payment methods used for scams, and other data, as appropriate;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdd6407666814e5786346e2fd6c41eb2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>promote Federal law enforcement data interoperability and intelligence gathering across data collection platforms; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d6dbf3d630845f5be9282bd3cefed2d"><enum>(v)</enum><text>modernize law enforcement data and reporting, including through the use of artificial intelligence and other innovative technology to enhance data synthesis;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida556c934360944f6907e9fd20d6b7635"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increase coordination between Federal and private sector efforts, including efforts by businesses and non-profits, to prevent scams by—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida7c792a1802145dea66e8448210181ec"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitating and coordinating the rapid sharing of data by private sector businesses (including technology companies, banks, and telecommunication companies) necessary to the investigation of scams by law enforcement officials;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4df9981eb7ce4adfa9910df60e119440"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>authenticating legitimate and blocking scam-related transactions and communications; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd27afd269dbe41e88425e4447da1eed6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coordinating preemptive enforcement and takedown actions;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3c785920f624639b8c757033cb22eb2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>establish coordinated rapid response protocols that provide individuals with timely, accurate warnings and prevention guidance through trusted channels, ensuring that scam threats are identified quickly and communicated effectively to the public;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8682be63df2d48bda9e42f2807b41be4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>increase coordination between Federal, State, local, and Tribal government efforts to prevent and combat scams, including analyzing the feasibility of the creation of elder justice task forces within local governments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec0ee2b668e74f54b18191fbb6aa6015" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(G)</enum><text>coordinate efforts to address complex and multifaceted scams that cross jurisdictional boundaries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8c97d37919d42ec8fa8be8a482c13a9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>monitor and evaluate the effectiveness of the implementation of strategies recommended in the National Strategy for Combating Scams;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide003ebf1c75a41a9b35d9f5562efaff0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>evaluate ways for the Federal Government to partner with State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies, financial institutions, telecom carriers, technology companies, and other entities determined appropriate to support victim recovery, including providing clear accessible resources for assistance and redress;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id923baf638a15409ab401375d255d19d6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>enhance coordination with foreign countries to combat large-scale scams originating abroad that target persons in the United States to improve cross-border enforcement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1adfdf165feb463fbc654fd4cf4d8464"><enum>(10)</enum><text>analyzes the legislative, regulatory, or administrative changes needed to carry out the National Strategy for Combating Scams and enable a comprehensive and coordinated Federal response to scams;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b6ef37f989c446a9fd2cda05e6d8be6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(11)</enum><text>identifies the resources needed to prevent and combat scams and implement the National Strategy for Combating Scams; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd649a326df334268878ba2813da2f971" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(12)</enum><text>addresses any other topic relating to the promotion of a coordinated national response to scams, as determined appropriate by the working group.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id181747fd6e154d7f8bae49da2076e117"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission and publication</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the establishment of the working group under subsection (a), the working group shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2bf5bec2cb654656a214cbccb6afc3ad"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit the National Strategy for Combating Scams developed under subsection (b) to the <committee-name committee-id="SPAG00">Special Committee on Aging of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34ccb1e33dad4ca0bf1c5e31f6d8b3b2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the National Strategy for Combating Scams publicly available, including on a publicly accessible website.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida882352098f64e3a84115d02bf353db4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Updates</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida445c617b36246b494d7b78b3fbad370"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the publication of the National Strategy for Combating Scams under paragraph (c), not less frequently than once every 5 years, the working group established pursuant to subsection (a) shall update such publication, including by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3c1fdbf084d420db9547e2246604764"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collecting and incorporating new feedback from community stakeholders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22e318ac03f449d5bf7a604ae5391b82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>updating the definition of <quote>scam</quote>, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8e6925285e242ba9e7de63247a93306"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission and publication</header><text>Not later than 30 days after each update under paragraph (1), the working group established pursuant to subsection (a)shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55e23e42ee9040f08d7e27826557690a"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit the updated National Strategy for Combating Scams to the <committee-name committee-id="SPAG00">Special Committee on Aging of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9bbc8f8ec3b3443d8a7ab7c6c8ece0fa" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the updated National Strategy for Combating Scams publicly available, including on a publicly accessible website.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1236c86cded8461baebcb62603d3f59a"><enum>4.</enum><header>Adoption of common definition of <quote>scam</quote></header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f361942bb5649fa8b38dd067b1c485f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the publication of the National Strategy for Combating Scams under section 3(c), the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Federal Trade Commission, and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau shall adopt the common definition of <quote>scam</quote> recommended in the National Strategy for Combating Scams.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1f1214d6a91b483aaa2b74a95dec986b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates to definition</header><text>If, pursuant to section 3(d), the working group updates the definition of <quote>scam</quote> in an updated National Strategy for Combating Scams, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Federal Trade Commission, and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau shall adopt the updated common definition of <quote>scam</quote> not later than 1 year after such update.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

