<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9147368C144E44C19A9442D2C6044B1D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7468 IH: First-Time Home Buyer Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7468</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260210">February 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow certain distributions from long-term qualified tuition programs for first home purchases, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H556C142C3951442AACAD771CFBA890EE" style="OLC"><section id="H3C7B0FB86C164B519E387444294B359E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First-Time Home Buyer Empowerment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H32408ABB72C849ECB1A4671ADB63364B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special rule for certain distributions from long-term qualified tuition programs for first home purchases</header><subsection id="HDADFC95FD57245B2BB3EB36ED22A3A67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">Section 529(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H46F7073679EB4163955DABF55A7FB4BC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H245942D9F5724503988110A93981E3CD"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Special rule for certain distributions from long-term qualified tuition programs for first home purchases</header><clause id="H37D49282E42F4EEFB48EC6A6FBC1D4B1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a distribution from a qualified tuition program of a designated beneficiary which has been maintained for the 15-year period ending on the date of such distribution, subparagraph (A) shall not apply to so much of the portion of such distribution which—</text><subclause id="H4E9344EB8D1C42CFBA286D1F649DDE06"><enum>(I)</enum><text>does not exceed the aggregate amount contributed to the program (and earnings attributable thereto) before the 5-year period ending on the date of the distribution, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6EDDC912449541D89E23252B93FCDE42" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is used, within 60 days of such distribution, for the purchase of a principal residence of a first-time homebuyer who is such designated beneficiary.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE81219A024D94EADA2FFF59D9E4B43EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Aggregate limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subparagraph shall not apply to any distribution described in clause (i) to the extent that the aggregate amount of such distributions with respect to the designated beneficiary for the taxable year and all prior taxable years exceeds an amount equal to $35,000, reduced by the aggregate amount of distributions to which subparagraph (E) applies with respect to such designated beneficiary for such taxable year and all prior taxable years.</text></clause><clause id="HCE606281C5704884808F2D59886AE49B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Special rule where delay in acquisition</header><text>If any distribution from a qualified tuition program of a designated beneficiary fails to meet the requirements of subparagraph (A) solely be reason of a delay or cancellation of the purchase or construction of the residence, the amount of the distribution may be contributed to a qualified tuition program or ABLE account of such beneficiary, as provided in subclauses (I) and (III), respectively, of subparagraph (C)(i), determined by substituting <quote>120 days</quote> for <quote>60 days</quote> in such subparagraph, except that—</text><subclause id="HFD6B418753DC41DCB635A4CF81143ACA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>subparagraph (C)(iii) shall not be applied to such contribution, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H296D66D165A54F49A412AEFB1FF730C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such amount shall not be taken into account in determining whether subparagraph (C)(iii) applies to any other amount.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA7AE718590494A6AAEF212B1937FC99F" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Recapture of tax benefit</header><subclause id="H73C88E539F8D4C58A04F4906CF93BC65" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If subparagraph (A) does not apply to a distribution by reason of this subparagraph and a qualifying event occurs before the close of the 5-year period beginning on the date of the purchase of the principal residence with respect to which such distribution was used, the designated beneficiary’s tax for the taxable year in which such qualifying event occurs shall be increased by an amount, determined under regulations, equal to the tax which (but for this subparagraph) would have been imposed, plus interest for the deferral period. The amount of any increase determined under the preceding sentence shall be reduced (but not below zero) by 20 percent for each full year occurring during the period beginning on the date of such purchase and ending on the date of such qualifying event.</text></subclause><subclause id="H2AB9CCBF461E4AEFBB73E5E8FEBB9F4A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Qualifying event</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this clause, the term <term>qualifying event</term> means, with respect to a distribution to which subparagraph (A) does not apply by reason of this subparagraph, the disposition of the principal residence which the designated beneficiary purchased using such distribution, or the cessation of such residence as the principal residence of the designated beneficiary (and, if married, such designated beneficiary’s spouse).</text></subclause><subclause id="HF5902ABC3230444582747A8527A0D8EF" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Deferral period</header><text>For purposes of this clause, the term <term>deferral period</term> means, with respect to a distribution to which subparagraph (A) does not apply by reason of this subparagraph, the period beginning with the taxable year in which (without regard to this subparagraph) the distribution would have been includible in gross income and ending with the taxable year in which the qualifying event described in subclause (I) occurs.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC8E57DBD123F4E8089FE2809D445194C" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (E) of section 36(f)(4) shall apply for purposes of this subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2ED883FDB6824F0594C164729D4C0F66"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the terms <term>purchase</term>, <term>principal residence</term>, and <term>first-time homebuyer</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 36(c).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6A106402A61447C8B851F2438B36FE32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with aggregate limitation on special rollovers to Roth IRAs</header><text>Section 529(c)(3)(E)(ii)(II) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HABD7F97D8ECF49FC9689702CD93F9193" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="HC02137798FD24D9FB0E4482219BF47D9"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Aggregate limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subparagraph shall not apply to any distribution described in clause (i) to the extent that the aggregate amount of such distributions with respect to the designated beneficiary for the taxable year and all prior taxable years exceeds an amount equal to $35,000, reduced by the aggregate amount of distributions to which subparagraph (F) applies with respect to such designated beneficiary for such taxable year and all prior taxable years.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0312785947D94D24B69F327BE533ADA9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to distributions made in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

