<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDB38C276252341F0AC4DDBD62E033DE9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9604 IH: Less Bureaucracy, Better Tribal Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9604</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260709">July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure the Department of Interior will manage all Tribal education and job training, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2BF78C08DCDA4BCDB4E61C0FB29D5A43" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H86549E57154448F48B9E76615A89DD45" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Less Bureaucracy, Better Tribal Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3138DC7B2BCA42DB9D4F8C15E6ACC115"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transfer and repeal of Department of Education functions relating to Tribal education and job training</header> <subsection id="H0EE52D61CD85487995260CFA85A43BC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are transferred to the Secretary of Interior all the functions which the Secretary of Education exercised before the effective date of this Act (including all related functions of any officer or employee of the Department of Education) with respect to each of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8A527BB8E18A4478BFC5303B9A6AE0D8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Demonstration grants program for American Indian children and youth authorized under section 6121 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7441">20 U.S.C. 7441</external-xref>).</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1767F88EE004FA4BA9EC0141332F07E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Indian Education Professional Development Grant program authorized under section 6122 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7442">20 U.S.C. 7442</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DC60A08FB2C47C3BED4D87BBD92C8A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Alaska Native Education program authorized under part C of title VI of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7541">20 U.S.C. 7541 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H030E70958DF749D59FC01CA21742C279"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Native Hawaiian Education program authorized under part B of title VI of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7511">20 U.S.C. 7511 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41E1628302794BDBBD8FA5FB40742923"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The American Indian Education National Activities authorized under subpart 3 of part A of title VI of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7451">20 U.S.C. 7451 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF393DB07C2F4EA28C4D194FF594EE7F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The State-Tribal Education Partnership program authorized under section 6132 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7452">20 U.S.C. 7452</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H218FB552434A4BC3AE07F9D07868CB39"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Native American and Alaska Native Language Program authorized under section 6133 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7453">20 U.S.C. 7453</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC448A255AE194CA2B5FCFA8EB16FE2C2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Native American Language Resource Center programs authorized under section 6131 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7451">20 U.S.C. 7451</external-xref>), section 2 of the Native American Language Resource Center Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7457">20 U.S.C. 7457</external-xref>), and the Native American Languages Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2901">25 U.S.C. 2901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5837281F6087455893753883B6D24638"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Native American Career and Technical Education Program authorized under section 116 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2326">20 U.S.C. 2326</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F8D5CDF91444B15AF82BD1D70082BD2"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Native Hawaiian Career and Technical Education Program authorized under section 116 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2326">20 U.S.C. 2326</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC24556B6DB44330B10A33A3844054E7" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Tribally Controlled Postsecondary Career and Technical Institutions Program authorized under section 117 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2327">20 U.S.C. 2327</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C46AB6874394F2CBDCB0E426487F50C"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Native American and Alaska Native Children in School (NAM) program authorized under section 3112 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6822">20 U.S.C. 6822</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38497FB23FDB48E98FE3FA60921C2EE6"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Grants to Alaska Native-serving and Native Hawaiian-serving institutions—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H51A9647054174D5980381CEE8191DAC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>authorized under section 317 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F13C21B56CD4ED1A90161A291D1D6E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which funds are made available under section 371 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43F9304EA3FD4EBEB9A01F020F5CFB74" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants to American Indian Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF4304A901454DEF901516EDE57F204F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>authorized under section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC622664DDAE145EB8B41A270C91ED5DE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which funds are made available under section 371 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H212E79A270454758AA8833A91600BD87" commented="no"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants to Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9E5CFA2E85CA4B85BE56D211548FE343"><enum>(A)</enum><text>authorized under section 320 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059g">20 U.S.C. 1059g</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60E01B54C56F4556BFBA024573A80A92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which funds are made available under section 371 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1083A76EC1924299BA440695FDB711CB" commented="no"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants to Native American-serving, non-Tribal institutions—</text> <subparagraph id="H62A76F3E9777449B9825BF043224688D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>authorized under section 319 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059f">20 U.S.C. 1059f</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB9024ED0C6D441BA8D7F34FDB05CF710" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which funds are made available under section 371 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9065B7B5B957418EA194AC4B3EA07FA8"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Indian Vocational Rehabilitation Services program authorized under section 121 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/741">29 U.S.C. 741</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5420ADE7CCC41E5B58284182B36FFF3"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Indian Education Formula Grants authorized under subpart 1 of part A of title VI of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7421">20 U.S.C. 7421 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F44BD5E69BB4A2F901F3DE092E8D83A" commented="no"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Indian education-related Research and Development Infrastructure Grant program authorized under part B of title VII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1138">20 U.S.C. 1138 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33897D4AED624B87AE0767A1F7EFF8BE"><enum>(20)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Indian education-related Special Education Grants to States program authorized under sections 611 and 619 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1411">20 U.S.C. 1411</external-xref>; 1419).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AABF8DC06244FF2A20F1E562758A0B9"><enum>(21)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Indian education-related Special Education Grants for Infants and Families program authorized under part C of title VI of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1431">20 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H557437CB497046F4BBAD8F052C9AA6CD" commented="no"><enum>(22)</enum><text>American Indian Resilience in Education program authorized under section 11006(1) of the American Rescue Plan of 2021.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H86E5A99FB5FE47ECBA15E326BEC8D046"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>The following provisions of law are repealed:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9C60D034779E4CC6BDE860E6E0B79938"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Part J of title VIII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1161j">20 U.S.C. 1161j</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE2BF88B7B8D44D2D8424A95DE3B14B18"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part Z of title VIII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1161z">20 U.S.C. 1161z</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H461D664E987B4B4EBF348BD86587FE99"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exercise of authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by law, the Secretary of the Interior may, for purposes of performing a function transferred under this Act, exercise all authorities under any other provision of law that were available with respect to the performance of that function to the Secretary of Education immediately before the effective date of the transfer of the function under this Act.</text></section> <section id="H798500551CE541428DB84803DFD3642D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transfer and allocations of appropriations and personnel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the personnel employed in connection with, and the assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, used, held, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with the functions transferred under this Act, subject to section 1531 of title 31, United States Code, shall be transferred to the Secretary of the Interior. Unexpended funds transferred pursuant to this section shall be used only for the purposes for which the funds were originally authorized and appropriated.</text></section> 
<section id="HE7A79CFA0B9544FEB99B23A1A6D9AAC1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority of Director of the Office of Management and Budget with respect to functions transferred</header> 
<subsection id="H38E8F44CA08D43E2ABE82CD8839CB3B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Personnel determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall ensure that this Act does not result in a net increase in full-time equivalent employees at the Federal agencies impacted by this Act, based on the number of such employees at such agencies on the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H38447C6BFD474D22B52C317EDE54794C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Function determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If necessary, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall make any determination of the functions that are transferred under this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E050C336C2B4DCFBDF939132BE961C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Incidental transfers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, at such time or times as the Director shall provide, may make such determinations as may be necessary with regard to the functions transferred by this Act, and to make such additional incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, liabilities, grants, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds held, used, arising from, available to, or to be made available in connection with such functions, as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act. The Director shall provide for the termination of the affairs of all entities terminated by this Act and for such further measures and dispositions as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC6B579A2022F41789BEAB80E8DDA54DA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certification of compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the effective date of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall certify compliance with this Act, including the requirement under subsection (a), to the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD69B0F30CD4A4371BB9219FEE413801E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Delegation and assignment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly prohibited by law or otherwise provided in this Act, the Secretary of the Interior may delegate any of the functions so transferred to such officers and employees of the Department of the Interior as the Secretary may designate, and may authorize successive redelegations of such functions as may be necessary or appropriate. No delegation of functions under this section or under any other provision of this Act shall relieve the Secretary of the Interior of responsibility for the administration of the function.</text></section> <section id="HBB497AA625064FB58999256A38688BEE" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With regard to functions transferred under section 2, a reference in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or relating to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H34BF99A81E6B4674BA473DBEA6F8AFB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education shall be deemed to refer to the Secretary of the Interior; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H953A0C5B309146E0B8EB7D4462396D66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of Education shall be deemed to refer to the Department of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7EDDB37D23354F9EAFBD200E55F5C3BD"><enum>8.</enum><header>Savings provisions</header> 
<subsection id="HAF99A050AC6C43F79E505F41136B8EE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Legal documents</header><text>All orders, determinations, rules, regulations, permits, grants, loans, contracts, agreements, certificates, licenses, and privileges—</text> <paragraph id="H0ABE6FD8536D4DA69ED2659BE260683C"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>that have been issued, made, granted, or allowed to become effective by the President, any Federal agency or official thereof, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, in the performance of any function that is transferred by this Act; and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD49A5042F57409AA76772FB45B0DD6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that are in effect on the effective date of such transfer (or become effective after such date pursuant to their terms as in effect on such effective date),</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated, superseded, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by the President, the Secretary of the Interior, any other authorized official, a court of competent jurisdiction, or operation of law.</continuation-text></subsection> <subsection id="H292CDD4BC0414535B3845E98AA6BE8A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceedings</header><text>This Act shall not affect any proceedings or any application for any benefits, service, license, permit, certificate, or financial assistance pending on the date of the enactment of this Act before the Department of Education (with respect to functions transferred by this Act). Such proceedings and applications shall continue, orders shall be issued in such proceedings, appeals shall be taken therefrom, and payments shall be made pursuant to such orders, as if this Act had not been enacted, and orders issued in any such proceeding shall continue in effect until modified, terminated, superseded, or revoked by a duly authorized official, by a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law. Nothing in this subsection shall be considered to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such proceeding could have been discontinued or modified if this Act had not been enacted.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7B75B00292A44DA59073743BCEE6EEBF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Suits</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (e)—</text> <paragraph id="HB805A753F1AC492493C46B01FD198FFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act shall not affect suits commenced before the effective date of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A69F3D83A9F438D8C29C658ECAE9086"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in all such suits, proceeding shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same manner and with the same effect as if this Act had not been enacted.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAC1D8F835E61411A92BA58119A84CD66"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nonabatement of actions</header><text>No suit, action, or other proceeding commenced by or against the Department of Education (with respect to the functions transferred by this Act), or by or against any individual in the official capacity of such individual as an officer or employee of the Department of Education (with regard to functions transferred by this Act), shall abate by reason of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H62B3E28D6E8147D3A2013B426BDAFC8C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Continuance of suits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, before the date on which a transfer of a function under this Act takes effect, the Secretary of Education or any officer or employee of the Department of Education in the official capacity as such an officer or employee is party to a suit relating to the function, then such suit shall be continued and the Secretary of the Interior, or other appropriate official of the Department of the Interior, shall be substituted or added as a party.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA5445AB922E54429AE7091F1241A804B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative procedure and judicial review</header><text>Except as otherwise provided by this Act, any statutory requirements relating to notice, hearings, action upon the record, or administrative or judicial review that apply to any function transferred by this Act shall apply to the exercise of such function by the Secretary of the Interior, and other officers of the Department of the Interior, to which such function is transferred by this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1E7F5E3B908942808A4B191F1253C3DA" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no"><enum>9.</enum><header>Transition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to use, for such period of time as may reasonably be needed to facilitate the orderly implementation of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H818170C17DE1490888DD1B857DAF89A9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the services of officers, employees, and other personnel of the Department of Education with regard to functions transferred under this Act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H913E09217B7547DBA62DFC91D4EC1C3B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assets of the Department of Education with regard to such functions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC720C6D15E0452A870E5D23D5552FB6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>funds appropriated to such functions.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H0E8263AA800148DCB742043EA22D8A30"><enum>10.</enum><header>Consultation</header> 
<subsection id="H1FC75956540C4671B0865824970E0550"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall consult and coordinate with Indian Tribes on the provisions of this Act in accordance with the policy of the Department of Education relating to Consultation and Coordination with American Indian and Alaska Native Tribal Governments developed pursuant to—</text> <paragraph id="H6878BEFB64C2445297661C086451FF23" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13175 (65 Fed. Reg. 67249; relating to Consultation and Coordination With Indian Tribal Governments); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38A7A6313B724AF9A164EEF814872118"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13592 (76 Fed. Reg. 76603; relating to Improving American Indian and Alaska Native Educational Opportunities and Strengthening Tribal Colleges and Universities).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD6D5E89B6B0E45F1B8983624307819D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Response</header> <paragraph id="H82BFB0B9303E47AA9D42BA888AA2A417"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall provide to Indian Tribes a written response to correspondence received from Indian Tribes pursuant to subsection (a) in accordance with the policy described in such subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54B66D277DD5482C894C1639AC0498C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The written response described in paragraph (1) shall be published on public website of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="HB53A679BE7654722BC9B4F1C7AC5E3EB"><enum>11.</enum><header>Definition of function</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <term>function</term> includes any duty, obligation, power, authority, responsibility, right, privilege, activity, or program.</text></section> 
<section id="H49B90F18DF2A4694BA66677D4B99C73F" commented="no"><enum>12.</enum><header>Effective date</header> 
<subsection id="H0CDCB28A0E4B4BD1A47079DE2D83F972" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in sections 9 and 10, this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 1 year after the date on which the Secretary of Education publishes the written response described in subsection (b) of section 10.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA22AF5E0AAB54A08B882D1CB5D63CB76" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Early implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a), transfers of functions under section 2 or any other provision of this Act (other than sections 9 and 10) may be carried out during the period—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB8380E76E89B44B0BDC3F126084AA508" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Education publishes the written response described in subsection (b) of section 10; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73AD072123844F3DB309D6EE747284B5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ending on the effective date of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

