<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA6E304A9CBA44DAA90F38FB2DC145972" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6557 IH: The Center for Strategic Deterrence and Weapons of Mass Destruction Studies Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6557</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to establish the Center for Strategic Deterrence and Weapons of Mass Destruction Studies in the Institute for National Strategic Studies of National Defense University.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C0170974F514F4FABB1E2767A16CE7C" style="OLC">
<section id="HA2279CEA6B1A4738A1FEC3FF697A6190" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>The Center for Strategic Deterrence and Weapons of Mass Destruction Studies Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEB9C500BFBA74089BD170A513886D07C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Center for Strategic Deterrence and Weapons of Mass Destruction Studies</header> <subsection id="H22FFD402043F42B6927F4E8397F3EBE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2165(b) of title 10, United States Code, is amended, in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>(including a Center for Strategic Deterrence and Weapons of Mass Destruction Studies)</quote> after <quote>The Institute for National Strategic Studies</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H878E7B8230FE47109B323FC8A65EF34F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mission of the Center for Strategic Deterrence and Weapons of Mass Destruction Studies established under such paragraph shall be to—</text> <paragraph id="HEC680E7C0CC3490BAC3BCB84BF5D198E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare national security leaders to address the challenges of strategic deterrence and weapons of mass destruction through education, research, and outreach activities throughout the Federal Government;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE31C3966202443858AD2A2A6B80C3224"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop leaders with an understanding of strategic deterrence and the implications of weapons of mass destruction;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAD18AF070D24492804D48B8BECE8B4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in accordance with guidance provided by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, develop and provide appropriate curricula, learning outcomes, and educational tools relating to strategic deterrence and weapons of mass destruction for use at institutions that provide joint professional military education;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE22959A80D534281997C2D4349D2BCFD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>serve as the primary institution within the Department of Defense for the study of strategic deterrence and weapons of mass destruction education in joint professional military education;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA642204865D42B29D36FC482F1C4869"><enum>(5)</enum><text>design, develop, and implement studies and analyses to enhance understanding of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4762AB1FC62A4B55A7D4C636639761C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strategic deterrence;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F877FD2A2484D48894F718DB14C5B91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the threat of weapons of mass destruction to the security of the United States and globally; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4258E210E1C446689BFB1497A2B2BCC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>responses to prevent, mitigate, or eliminate the threat in accordance with Department and national security policies and strategies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B0E435D8BBA49B6B32AAB30E80F53C3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><text> provide expert support on strategic deterrence and weapons of mass destruction issues to the Secretary of Defense and other Federal Government leaders.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>


