<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC71F553308BC41018A246BE5796EEE6F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7182 IH: Voter Outreach for Transparent Elections Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7182</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to establish minimum notification requirements for voters affected by polling place changes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H484816033A5D41538CF3536F8CA830B3" style="OLC"><section id="HEDDA399B4BD64200896383EFA5E664C8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Voter Outreach for Transparent Elections Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VOTE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3716DFC8302B47DD9DEAFAFD6CF6486F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Minimum notification requirements for voters affected by polling place changes</header><subsection id="HFE77A89FA40442D9BC054AC615A8D2C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 302 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21082">52 U.S.C. 21082</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9EBE2404DDE24BAFA911A9DC5C4436C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AE70E8CCF01417AA00511C63D370CEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6DB24A6D77B4E8CAB8C2ED99ECF2BD1" style="OLC"><subsection id="H79598346C91142859E1A33645735863A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Minimum notification requirements for voters affected by polling place changes</header><paragraph id="H1C4CB7BDCC0442B3B2DE77E047065E71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State assigns an individual who is a registered voter in a State to a polling place with respect to an election for Federal office which is not the same polling place to which the individual was previously assigned with respect to the most recent election for Federal office in the State in which the individual was eligible to vote—</text><subparagraph id="HCEE2C0F98A0F400B94A22D6AF6DF61A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State shall notify the individual of the location of the polling place not later than 7 days before the date of the election;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B86CD803E0346B5B123E7A328717AE6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appropriate election official of the State shall post a general notice on the website of the State or jurisdiction, on social media platforms (if available), and on signs at the prior polling place; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H420223EF298F4498A7C722FDD7ECD154"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the State makes such an assignment fewer than 7 days before the date of the election and the individual appears on the date of the election at the polling place to which the individual was previously assigned, the State shall make every reasonable effort to enable the individual to vote on the date of the election.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81FA8F4D5EF04B69BF2124BC0ECDEFB1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Methods of notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate election official shall notify an individual under paragraph (1)(A) by mail, telephone, and (if available) text message and electronic mail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H564B4DA4754A4F96AAAD16B918AA5EC5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements for vote centers</header><text>In the case of a jurisdiction in which individuals are not assigned to specific polling places, not later than 2 days before the beginning of an early voting period, the appropriate election official shall notify each individual eligible to vote in such jurisdiction of the location of all polling places at which the individual may vote.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6920E1E4CCB0412DB47A7CBD7418B492" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice with respect to closed polling places</header><subparagraph id="H12A7711CABF1435D89B8500BFC02C839" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a location which served as a polling place for an election for Federal office in a State does not serve as a polling place in the next election for Federal office held in the State, the State shall ensure that signs are posted at such location on the date of the election and during any early voting period for the election containing the following information:</text><clause id="H01E6B10DBEF34D6A8190D00004F7372B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A statement that the location is not serving as a polling place in the election.</text></clause><clause id="H99DAC544F85B42539E22F9C2189C7585" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The locations serving as polling places in the election in the jurisdiction involved.</text></clause><clause id="HC64B20BBD4064FF392768A0680452008" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The name and address of any substitute polling place serving the same precinct and directions from the former polling place to the new polling place.</text></clause><clause id="HCD89B2818F8341F4A3AAE68A1FA83579" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Contact information, including a telephone number and website, for the appropriate State or local election official through which an individual may find the polling place to which the individual is assigned for the election.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H274E4B631A634CECAE30DA0738424FE5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Internet posting</header><text>Each State which is required to post signs under subparagraph (A) shall also provide such information through a website and through social media (if available).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19568C14F636427DAB433FB2B94178E4" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Linguistic preference</header><text>The notices required under this subsection shall comply with the requirements of section 203 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10503">52 U.S.C. 10503</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H329AAF60126F4FC281046C5708E664DF" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall apply with respect to elections held on or after January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62CEA5AF019F4C05940A28590EF6F358"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 302(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21082">52 U.S.C. 21082(f)</external-xref>), as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended by striking <quote>Each State</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (d)(5), each State</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

