<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7FB7EBE2110C4B65A04651BF6460ACA8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9388 IH: One-Stop Pilot Program Extension Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9388</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize an extension of a program to permit screened passengers and their property arriving on direct flights or flight segments originating at certain foreign last point of departure airports to continue on additional flights or flight segments originating in the United States without additional screening, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H95651636AEA143959258041D69936B24" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H35583374DFE940FC92DF36CADA874AE2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>One-Stop Pilot Program Extension Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H91C53BB6B104424DB67AF211AD1C77C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>One-stop program</header> 
<subsection id="HFDF0E14B811040C999734B11B2F5B749">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Checked baggage re-Screening</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 7132 of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44901">49 U.S.C. 44901</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H87E9AE700B6E414A9B926D9342013246"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <subsection id="H3BFCF5DD51804D64A5D4C2AA8C65D714" commented="no">
            <enum>(d)</enum>
            <header>Re-Screening of checked baggage</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (f), the Administrator, in coordination with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP), may permit checked baggage arriving on direct flights or flight segments arriving from participating foreign last point of departure airports referred to in subsection (b) to continue on additional flights or flight segments originating in the United States without additional TSA security re-screening if the following requirements are satisfied:</text>
            <paragraph id="H2A4AEE1069B54818868F0CC87F0010D8" commented="no">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The initial checked baggage screening at such an airport was conducted using an explosives detection system in accordance with an aviation security screening agreement described in subsection (e).</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H40AAC18E114F4817B482112E337B81F0" commented="no">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Passengers arriving from such airports are unable to access their checked baggage until arrival at their final destination.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HDE46EDACA5D94FE1AFFD1C66F81CEE54" commented="no">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>CBP has received timely images of such baggage prior to the arrival in the United States of such passengers and baggage that satisfy CBP requirements from such an airport corresponding to the checked baggage of such passengers to ensure appropriate border security enforcement can be completed in an efficient manner.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HE52FD56AF5F94D44B02B9FF5FDA4F094" commented="no">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>CBP has not identified any such passenger or baggage for further inspection.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H098DEE64DB0D4030897BF027AE5A5576"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (k) of section 7132 of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 is amended by striking <quote>six</quote> and inserting <quote>ten</quote>.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

