<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6F30E87B95B749DD9AF2C46D1A1E0237" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8373 IH: Improving Access to Financial Coaching Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8373</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Treasury, acting through the Director of the Office of Consumer Policy, to establish a program to award grants to eligible entities to provide financial coaching services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE736FC6BA32041418921714940493410" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBB8C84E1DCBE4EBEAA21697442B11275" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Access to Financial Coaching Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H750845E6B53046B3BB9F00903AE87B98"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="HF626A1ADE3CB4E228BEBB722C4F94455"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF0F7C282C95543DFBE4CE7AB680572A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>many consumers, particularly low- and moderate-income households, face significant challenges in managing personal finances, reducing debt, building savings, and accessing responsible credit;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H900E8C32AC514E26B6FC7A0E789593D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>financial coaching services have been shown to improve financial stability, increase long-term financial capability, improve credit scores, and reduce vulnerability to economic shocks;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DE017DD562E4D42BEDECB8CF8653FD5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nonprofit and community-based organizations play a critical role in training and deploying financial coaches to deliver culturally competent, accessible, and individualized financial coaching services to consumers in need;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40905E99228444ED9DC108A308BA6A43"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury, through its Office of Consumer Policy, is well-positioned to administer a national program supporting financial coaching initiatives that promote household financial resilience and economic mobility; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD98A15839114265A7058FE75EF490DC">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>the absence of uniform certification standards for financial coaches results in inconsistent service quality and restricts the professional development of practitioners, underscoring the need for Federal support to inform a standardization of credentialing for financial coaches and agencies that provide these services.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8817D34F8B2640C388798E25E0FE50E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="HA2471A9A199B4B338E23C0AF22B97E58"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>to establish a Federal program to provide grants to eligible organizations offering financial coaching services to consumers;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H106C4073C69B46B5AA363F31E720662C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to strengthen the capacity of community-based providers to deliver effective, evidence-based financial coaching;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8FA5546629C74893906865B5FAE084C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to enhance consumer financial well-being by increasing access to trusted, high-quality financial guidance; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08B8298DD5654EBBBF3F5A8464F43B97"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to authorize the Office of Consumer Policy within the Department of the Treasury to administer, oversee, and evaluate the program; and to research and develop standardized practices for certifying financial coaches and the agencies that employ them.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H4DFA22F7F24C4895AD1DDAE165508A3E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Financial coaching services grant</header> <subsection id="H90503B40494440AF9A439291766B199B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury, acting through the Director of the Office of Consumer Policy (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>), shall establish a program to award grants to eligible entities to provide financial coaching services.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5749C41030E24257B53D0F5F8903AC51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC7A211474BA94704ABD56D21B5593808"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC670CC464C3B4239BC256469F8C2DC6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a nonprofit, community-based organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B0B177B02CE407781E154C39006B269"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a community development financial institution (as defined in section 103 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4702">12 U.S.C. 4702</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3F019307B36242D196061420BC461DA3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a minority depository institution (as defined in section 308(b) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note)); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4AB1AD1EED85468EA845BFAA43DF11E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB32EAE2313D340E88A9CD5960FA55711"><enum>(A)</enum><text>been in operation for not less than 1 year;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H867293ACDC024001B952B9A83D0470A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if serving a clientele or service area with a high rate of non-English proficiency speakers, established relationships with private, public, or nonprofit community-based entities that provide non-English language services and can provide referrals for financial coaching services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H37C277053FA342079C8D02242D253911"><enum>(C)</enum><text>established, or plans to establish, a financial coaching program as described subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14D02F4A18C54DD0836202A58BDD0CFB" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such program—</text> 
<clause id="H5900F03236EA4B27AE8C2DA38561030A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>located in, or predominantly serving—</text> <subclause id="H27CACB0325F9405CABF8FF1990602F0E" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 or more census tracts where—</text> 
<item id="HC2E4890A9F944559BC4A095F1E120E82" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>with respect to a census tract located in a metropolitan area, the median family income is at or below 120 percent of the metropolitan median family income; or</text></item> <item id="H9AF3436B5CE946B9B854B110AF33A4F0" commented="no"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text>with respect to a census tract located outside a metropolitan area, the median family income is at or below 120 percent of the statewide median family income;</text>
                </item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1DDECAB1B5644E2D8708EF223B7B98AE" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a census tract where not less than 50 percent of the population self-identifies as a racial or ethnic minority; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H91DF6127200049ECAE2AA43008E378CF" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 or more census tracts in a rural area (as the term is defined by the Director of the Bureau of the Census); or</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H2EE0F825431F412F8468CE6202374D1D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>predominantly serving individuals making at or below 120 percent of the Area Median Income.</text></clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDBAF5B81624141038B900CE17CDD2E30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity that seeks a grant under this section shall submit to the Director an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director requires, including a description of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9A77083639BA4130B2DC70E42C923E68"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">organizational information and financial coaching services of such entity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44C53BF458F3456DAF15AA1564CA4799"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">staff qualification and experience, including a detailed description of any certification, credentialing or continuing education required of its financial coaches;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74269D124CC24B87AF04AF2E2099F3E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a work plan that outlines activities, target audiences, goals, and anticipated results;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C91F1C84E584073994B08ADE9477138"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the financial stability of such entity, including financial statements and a proposed budget for the financial coaching program of such entity; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2895DF95EF448E78E4936C7A0598F57"><enum>(5)</enum><text>languages served by such entity.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0E519C282A124955A47A2E96715F3ACE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible uses</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities under this section to be used—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC1F597A724134C12819E78BFDFE01DC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by the eligible entity for general purposes of such entity; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF69E53A9A69D432D8EA4802E9E337037"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the eligible entity for the purpose of awarding subgrants and technical assistance to other eligible entities that provide financial coaching.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBB7438F46DFD4889A7CAB98D2049EC65"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Financial coaching best practices</header><text>The Director shall carry out such activities as necessary to help elevate best practices in the financial coaching industry, and to facilitate the development of standardized protocols for credentialing financial coaches and agencies that provide these services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5342702F8C14463B875F91BB65A5B529"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <paragraph id="H8793F34337F44BF9B58E88C19F4F4B87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Director $100,000,000 for fiscal years 2026 through 2028, of which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H62AB75E5C3594F5EB063E8C84FCD7C6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>55 percent of such appropriated sum be used for the purposes described in subsection (d)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34A49C8E19C74C4FA17B27EB91DF2CB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>45 percent of such appropriated sum be used for the purpose described in subsection (d)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66B5A716E041416F9095B02477E6A13A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proportions</header><text>The Director may update the proportions of funds described in paragraph (1) if the Director determines that there are insufficient amounts to carry out either purposes described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

