<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H25C5FD4AF69F47A682CA4866CA1FAF81" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1364 IH: Commemorating 10 years since the Pulse nightclub shooting in Orlando, Florida, on June 12, 2016.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1364</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating 10 years since the Pulse nightclub shooting in Orlando, Florida, on June 12, 2016.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas June 12, 2026, marks 10 years since the Pulse nightclub massacre in Orlando, Florida;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this massacre took place at Pulse nightclub, a safe space for the Orlando community, especially members of the lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, questioning, Black, and Latino communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Orlando and Orange County law enforcement, the Florida Department of Law Enforcement, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, and other emergency and health care professionals responded to the act of domestic terrorism bravely, admirably, and in a coordinated manner, saving many lives;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, following the massacre, the city of Orlando, the State of Florida, and the United States came together and expressed overwhelming support for the victims and their families regardless of race, ethnicity, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or political affiliation; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in his first term, President Biden signed over 25 executive actions in an effort to reduce gun violence nationwide, and Congress passed the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/159">Public Law 117–159</external-xref>) on June 24, 2022, which President Biden signed on June 25, 2022: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HA6DD590E99DD431686314BDA35569477"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC50FFAFF51F740C7AE93740D310E062F"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H34242CEF18404566AB4C54A89DDB6F93">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes, remembers, and honors the memory of the victims killed in the Pulse nightclub massacre in Orlando, Florida, including Stanley Almodovar III, Amanda L. Alvear, Oscar A. Aracena Montero, Rodolfo Ayala Ayala, Antonio Davon Brown, Darryl Roman Burt II, Angel Candelario-Padro, Juan Chavez Martinez, Luis Daniel Conde, Cory James Connell, Tevin Eugene Crosby, Deonka Deidra Drayton, Simón Adrian Carrillo Fernández, Leroy Valentin Fernandez, Mercedez Marisol Flores, Peter Ommy Gonzalez Cruz, Juan Ramon Guerrero, Paul Terrell Henry, Frank Hernandez, Miguel Angel Honorato, Javier Jorge Reyes, Jason Benjamin Josaphat, Eddie Jamoldroy Justice, Anthony Luis Laureano Disla, Christopher Andrew Leinonen, Alejandro Barrios Martinez, Brenda Marquez McCool, Gilberto R. Silva Menendez, Kimberly Jean Morris, Akyra Monet Murray, Luis Omar Ocasio Capo, Geraldo A. Ortiz Jimenez, Eric Ivan Ortiz-Rivera, Joel Rayon Paniagua, Jean Carlos Mendez Perez, Enrique L. Rios, Jr., Jean Carlos Nieves Rodríguez, Xavier Emmanuel Serrano-Rosado, Christopher Joseph Sanfeliz, Yilmary Rodríguez Solivan, Edward Sotomayor, Jr., Shane Evan Tomlinson, Martin Benitez Torres, Jonathan A. Camuy Vega, Juan Pablo Rivera Velázquez, Luis Sergio Vielma, Franky Jimmy DeJesus Velázquez, Luis Daniel Wilson-Leon, and Jerald Arthur Wright;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2C6A3AB33DE4B309812DE89DC534119"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offers heartfelt condolences and deepest sympathies for the families, loved ones, and friends of such victims on their day of remembrance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D6EEDAB6DAE4C0FB80127E323F056F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expresses the continual support to those affected and marked by this act of domestic terrorism many years later;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3220C1870A274E8284902AD80D94E49D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>applauds the bravery and dedication exhibited by the hundreds of local, State, and Federal law enforcement officials, emergency medical responders, and others in the city of Orlando, Florida, who offered support and assistance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB463245CE85446194A4EBAD27BD0453"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stands together with all people of the United States, regardless of race, ethnicity, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or political affiliation, in the face of terror and hate; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H73FC690DD4E2496B89AF02FF59A097DF"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">must continue to work toward gun safety and mental health legislation.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

