<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0AD22B7499A44E63B89C98F6FF6A0ECB" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 853 IH: Recognizing the 95th anniversary of the Detroit-Windsor Tunnel and its enduring significance to international trade, economic development, and cross-border relations between the United States and Canada.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 853</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 95th anniversary of the Detroit-Windsor Tunnel and its enduring significance to international trade, economic development, and cross-border relations between the United States and Canada.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on November 3, 1930, the Detroit-Windsor Tunnel officially opened to the public, becoming the second-busiest crossing between the United States and Canada and the first vehicular underwater international tunnel in the world;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the tunnel has served as a vital transportation and trade artery for nearly a century, connecting Detroit, Michigan, and Windsor, Ontario, and supporting millions of commercial and passenger vehicles each year;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Detroit-Windsor Tunnel has strengthened cultural ties and economic integration between the United States and Canada, facilitating binational cooperation, tourism, and commerce;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the tunnel has played a critical role in ensuring the flow of essential goods and frontline workers, especially during the COVID–19 pandemic, when reliable cross-border access was paramount;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the city of Detroit and American Roads, the private operator of the tunnel, have maintained and modernized this critical piece of infrastructure, ensuring it remains safe, accessible, and secure for future generations; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the 95th anniversary of the tunnel offers an opportunity to reflect on the legacy of cross-border partnership and to reaffirm the commitment of the United States to infrastructure investments that strengthen regional and international connectivity: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H66D414B9BF054B6E8BBDEB8277A9CBF0"> 
<section id="H6A3E1F6FC88848E8A7FA204DFD8B501B" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H1578929FB6C84CBA8ABF5D86B4FFF6F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the 95th anniversary of the Detroit-Windsor Tunnel;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4AF42D55DABB40CE9BBD20B0E9B08D6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the city of Detroit and American Roads for their stewardship of this critical international crossing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H024085F101F14453B47BBCE02636D211"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the importance of modern, resilient infrastructure to support trade, economic development, and regional mobility; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB9D7C6D8E3D43C29E5097DB873A433D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>celebrates the continued friendship and economic partnership between the United States and Canada.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

