<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25C24-2J0-W5-SV4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3351 IS: Developing and Empowering our Aspiring Leaders Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3351</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to revise the definition of a qualifying investment, for purposes of the exemption from registration for venture capital fund advisers under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940, to include an equity security issued by a qualifying portfolio company and to include an investment in another venture capital fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H0337A126AAC24D8699B919A95E591D12"><section section-type="section-one" id="H003B89B140FD49FD814B9A3FBE751CC3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Developing and Empowering our Aspiring Leaders Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCCB42ADB099D4B9E8B447E698271D881"><enum>2.</enum><header>Revisions of regulatory definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall—</text><paragraph id="H6FB7B26481704C71B05951D2C699C5A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revise the definition of a qualifying investment under section 275.203(l)–1(c) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation—</text><subparagraph id="HECCB67D1C627432F9DAC7027B7DC4590"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to include an equity security issued by a qualifying portfolio company, whether acquired directly from the company or in a secondary acquisition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDD2FADB58BC4709ADEDD1ECC9F88C80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to specify that an investment in another venture capital fund (as defined in section 275.203(l)–1(a) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation) is a qualifying investment under that definition; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H72D4702A72884F399288D6AA330E3D00"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revise section 275.203(l)–1(a) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, to require, as a condition of a private fund qualifying as a venture capital fund under that provision, that, immediately after the acquisition of any asset, the fund holds not more than 49 percent of the amount of the aggregate capital contributions and uncalled committed capital (excluding short-term holdings) of the fund in—</text><subparagraph id="HD3EB759B7334465884860E1E381D3260"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 or more venture capital funds; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37E380B2E7DA4E2882CB34BF29E197C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>qualifying investments acquired in a secondary acquisition, valued at cost or fair value, consistently applied by the fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

