<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF73F5C4DA10A4B2BBD043700859F4C6D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1037 IH: Expressing support for the designation of February 4, 2026, as “National Cancer Prevention Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1037</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000307">Mr. James</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of February 4, 2026, as <quote>National Cancer Prevention Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas National Cancer Prevention Day is a day to remind us that, when looking at cancer, we need to look at prevention and reducing risks for human health and the environment;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, when we work to prevent cancer risks, it impacts human health, the environment, and the economy;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas cancer is one of the leading causes of death around the world and has touched the lives of nearly everyone, either directly or indirectly;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2026, there will be an estimated 2,114,850 new cancer cases diagnosed and 626,140 cancer deaths in the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2026, an estimated 9,680 children ages 0 to 14 will be diagnosed with cancer, and 1,090 will die from it;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Cancer Moonshot has been reignited to encourage all Americans, companies, institutions, and organizations to work together to cut the death rate from cancer by 50 percent over the next 25 years; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas February 4, 2026, would be an appropriate date to designate as <quote>National Cancer Prevention Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFADF3853B6944E7D9DADC61F2575932D"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H538544C3F1D6412ABF02A2CD7D6500B1"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H38A790993E044A89A9F46E9ED8590ED1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Cancer Prevention Day</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC56034CAA2743F59625B759F02CED40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes all efforts to raise the awareness for the reduction of cancer risks; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FDD3DDF366C4BBA9C1412EB715E5AF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the devastating effect cancer has on families and wishes to expand knowledge, encourage early detection, and work with friends in the medical and scientific fields to put an end to this deadly disease.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

