<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC57C47FF1C9D46639C01B90E93DB7481" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1286 IH: Calling for a trade policy that supports workers, consumers, independent farmers, small businesses, and the environment.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1286</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Calling for a trade policy that supports workers, consumers, independent farmers, small businesses, and the environment.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, for decades, United States trade policy has put corporate interests first, benefiting wealthy individuals and large corporations at the expense of working families, communities, independent farmers, small businesses, the environment, and the national and economic security of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 1994, the United States has seen—</text><paragraph id="HB74143445DC948FA815F2BB7592FF1F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the closure of over 70,000 factories;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H863B3791DE404F4B96C031EB7C148252"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the loss of millions of manufacturing jobs, including millions of good, union jobs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C9DBBF2D6C34C9E839C54F4739922C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the decimation of more than 300,000 family farmers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D6064F5878B47A5BD2E713B3CA76958"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the hollowing out of communities across the Nation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DA590CA5E5F415BA6F0EADBFBE85AF7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>threats to collective safety created by United States reliance on farflung supply chains;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas corporate-centered trade policy has undeniably failed the American people, and under trade agreements like the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement, layoffs, plant closures, and offshoring persist;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in response to the justified anger of so many Americans hurt by this bankrupt trade model, President Trump campaigned on a promise to leverage trade policy to reverse these failures; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, instead of keeping this promise, President Trump has used the erratic imposition and removal of tariffs to cut backroom deals to enrich his friends and family, not American workers, and eliminated billions of dollars of investments in domestic energy and manufacturing, as companies continue to close factories and lay off workers to pad profits by chasing low wages overseas: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H1894439A7C5F46F4BC964313A6AC2EA6"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HECECD15016DE4273BDC7D34E803D023D"><enum/><text>That—</text><paragraph id="HEEC913CD84C141D38C3C10B410BF428D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the House of Representatives rejects the choice between President Trump’s chaotic, corrupt, corporate-captured trade policies and a return to the devastating trade model of the past;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA314100831AB478AB715ED871ED883C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the House of Representatives supports a trade policy that unflaggingly centers workers, supports family farmers and consumers, promotes a healthy environment, and enhances national well-being, resilience, and security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H013C24F68D3148C9A98CB357176B862F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><subparagraph id="H7866755C5E9948ADB949D1938DA227D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to eliminate major incentives for companies to offshore jobs, any trade agreement must include strong, binding labor and environmental standards and rules of origin backed by swift and certain enforcement mechanisms;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H297DE4B536674ED89E7D6AE38D4B0737"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trade agreements must include effective tools for challenging violations, including at the facility level, and businesses and governments must be held accountable when they fail to uphold workers’ rights and environmental protections;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A391A902A714B5C8720D04944851FE4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>trade agreements must also include fair wage guarantees across manufacturing, food processing, call centers, back-office, and other tradeable sectors to disincentivize offshoring;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73A7D203CBC14FB78C46613494370194"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">robust development assistance funding, including the grant program administered by the Department of Labor’s International Labor Affairs Bureau, should ensure that strong labor provisions level the playing field by improving respect for workers’ rights;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D343B7665E04D5391298877A0D52B07"><enum>(E)</enum><text>corporations seeking preferential tariff treatment must be required to meet a wage floor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ACFF8B6CD0A4292934FA98848BF541F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>trade should raise wages and standards globally, not allow companies to seek out low-wage labor markets with weak workers’ rights and environmental protections, pitting workers against each other in a never-ending race to the bottom;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H899A8468B2664449A058EF781D3BB439"><enum>(4)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><subparagraph id="H70FC2F51D8F74435B669A0A287C7F36E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public procurement and infrastructure investment should support United States workers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD65C0890B9F54A56B3EB29EE7E5A920F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>trade agreements must in no way undermine governments’ ability to—</text><clause id="H2C065241EFA14E9B89532D6227F7CEF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>preference the purchase of domestic products at the Federal or State level; or</text></clause><clause id="H5372576CC6074E7481607F3F0B300BA5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include labor, environmental, and other standards in their purchasing preferences;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ACC869AC9B44AC38CAAD3845D6AE87A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>domestically, Buy America requirements must be strengthened to ensure goods are truly made in the United States, not minimally assembled or routed through loopholes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECFA77B0BCEA44AFA6300F64E43E00CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>rules must be strengthened to ensure that products, such as steel and aluminum, are melted, poured, smelted, cast, and fabricated domestically; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D2FEB816E4C41F68591EE64768AE6D5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>waivers to such requirements and rules should be limited, and domestic content standards should apply across infrastructure, energy, and defense spending;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB43D551693D84C65815B4C6225EA8A4B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><subparagraph id="H29684BC34C6B431188F9AAFCCC1965B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>United States trade and tax policy must stop incentivizing companies to move production overseas and, instead, should penalize them for doing so;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA826D6285EB5422DA95F171067B37853"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States trade agreements must include mechanisms for targeting individual cases of offshoring and should condition United States market access on the creation of good American jobs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA76FA127737444FA7DF671CC6B10833"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Federal contracts, tax incentives, and financing must prioritize companies that invest and produce in the United States, and should include clawbacks and other remedies against companies and their leaders that offshore jobs or supply chains;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H027C57022B1B4B9F891ED1859BE210D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>trade should rebuild domestic manufacturing capacity, not accelerate its decline, and must be complemented by robust industrial policies to support union jobs, with similar conditions and remedies to support workers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A49BE0191AD4EFAB339C2EF39E266E1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when trade policies fail to prevent offshoring, the United States must have an active, accessible, and fully funded Trade Adjustment Assistance Program to help workers get back on their feet;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A74DAF5D9C44CADAAF914D67BB51C9F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><subparagraph id="H16E3AA95CDB44B9EA149BC0538D013A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trade policy must not allow companies to undercut United States workers by exploiting weaker standards abroad;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE3586BEA09E42AB9E7F45E199303613"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States trade agreements must include robust environmental standards, including those to limit industrial point water, air, climate, and ground pollution, that are enforced with effective mechanisms to challenge violations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1ED91DE9D7AC4FB19BE99B7173C11E29"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">industrial espionage, forced technology transfer, and intellectual property theft conducted to create unfair advantages over United States producers must be treated as trade violations and met with strong enforcement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H787E4AD940C949DD8808011E0AC910A5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States trade and investment agreements must exclude the investor-state dispute settlement system that incentivizes offshoring and threatens environmental, labor, and other public policies by granting special rights to transnational corporations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE77EBE0BF074A7A95FBD45C8B509BB5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>trade should reward responsible production, not a race to the bottom;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H900EE31F103844598614052EAFDE7AF0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><subparagraph id="HF399B702AAA64B2BA00554B61453CD21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>trade agreements should prioritize access to affordable medicine at home and abroad;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB9452F847244D339355B1311DB34524"><enum>(B)</enum><text>trade policy must not constrain governments’ ability to adopt policies that enable the domestic production of medicine to address public health needs and to negotiate with companies for lower prescription drug prices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE836E89DB3FF446C998E1FA4C9D83E81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>United States trade agreements should not provide monopoly protections that enable pharmaceutical firms to raise drug prices;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HECBCB65AF9B74AC69D262A1F06B50EF4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><subparagraph id="H1CF61A77C6C3447A982C00CA2243AFAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>trade must prioritize benefits for independent and family farmers and rural communities, including through—</text><clause id="H4411F7D5C0A84AA7807761BDE2F006A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>mandatory country-of-origin labeling rules to ensure market transparency;</text></clause><clause id="H11E35BF3495548A4B9989E3BF2CA5D73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disciplines on subsidies that exclude large producers and processors but permit targeted support for small-, mid-, and family-scale farmers; and</text></clause><clause id="HAA3A70212A7943D3975E8EAB29B4C9AA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>antimonopoly disciplines to promote fair input prices and farm gate prices; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF87A4819A7A14E68874518324385396F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>trade agreements must also recognize countries’ sovereignty to set their own food safety standards and related inspection standards;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C7436ED04A44019A9C7E21A2F99EC82"><enum>(9)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><subparagraph id="HD9C871C44AFD49A18A52CE03107A0AD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>much of the digital economy, including the training of <quote>artificial intelligence</quote>, is being built on the backs of exploited workers overseas and without regard to its multiple impacts here at home;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C06F19E5DB446D0A32FA44ACB75ACA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trade agreements not only need robust worker’s rights protections for the digital economy, but must in no way constrain countries’ ability to set and enforce policy with respect to—</text><clause id="H7294AE754344417DA83267E64FD77D70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>data privacy, security, and storage;</text></clause><clause id="HE5BDB91DF80E44D39498916DD979CF62"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>right-to-repair policies;</text></clause><clause id="H116F0B2F877144E983B6BBE8601B7A3B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>regulation of artificial intelligence;</text></clause><clause id="H911ACD0014BD4A5B8E801F5A8C0ADE15"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>protection against online discrimination and other civil rights violations;</text></clause><clause id="HEADB0223A54F446FAF3AC8A8598FE1B3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>competition in the marketplace; and</text></clause><clause id="H858FA3FB49E24293B15B32C2A46EBB1B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>related issues; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5688B32485145C786BB7C90DE38A887"><enum>(C)</enum><text>trade policy must also provide protections for the copyrighted work of the more than 5,000,000 people who work in the motion picture, television, and music industries;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB213B3E1C17C481EBA2337A82F3EFAF3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><subparagraph id="HFB7E8FF44DEA4F16BE0C68BA1314762D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>trade policies should not privilege corporations, whether through provisions included in trade agreements, special access to policymakers, or privileged positions in tariff and waiver discussions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9DF14F3EE95456FA1F5CF334228161C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the priorities of working families should be front and center in transparent negotiations, including when decisions are being made about food safety, environmental, health, privacy, labor, worker safety, and other standards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB72BD00355004082AE825609177763B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Congress must vote to approve any new or renegotiated trade or investment agreement that includes binding terms that change any existing or constrain any future United States policies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2CAE644F276403C8F2E6DEE8E1898A9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><subparagraph id="H238BDD9876BB4535968000FC16E6FEF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tariffs are a critical tool to counter unfair trade and corporate greed and to strengthen strategic sectors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70C4F990A6564A73BB7BFCC5D4912576"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States must maintain and strengthen tariffs under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1862">19 U.S.C. 1862</external-xref>) and section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411</external-xref>) where they support domestic production and good-paying jobs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H800FF0327187429B8CA4C722DD563DA6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when an Administration fails to maintain and strengthen such tariffs to support American industry and workers, Congress will exercise its constitutional trade authority to address specific abuses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F38CF06E0374C07A8A9571D1803977C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such tariffs should not be weakened or removed if doing so exposes workers to import surges or trade cheating; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6B3B77AA90D4331ADD2B54F2CBFEC04"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Congress opposes giving corporations and bad actors overseas a free pass; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HACDC43F83AB04508BAF3B5D2AE7CBD19"><enum>(12)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text><subparagraph id="H9C36E730963D4C229367DB3A81F5462B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States must fully enforce its trade laws to stop other unfair practices, such as dumping and government-subsidized products on the United States market, to undercut United States producers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67139FB4FDF54558992F6CF07C546F14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>antidumping and countervailing duty laws must be applied robustly and without delay; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D3812D10BA2408EA0EDAB6D310CBE24"><enum>(C)</enum><text>existing trade preference programs must be updated to close loopholes that allow companies to evade duties; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD15A6D03E8B64196BFCA3862349449D9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enforcement agencies must be fully funded so they can act quickly and effectively to catch and prevent abuses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

