<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MAZ25708-RNV-K7-VGM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3317 IS: Water Resources Technical Assistance Review Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3317</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Comptroller General of the United States to review all clean water-related technical assistance authorities of the Environmental Protection Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H164B9095E62E466D956EB14AC338EBC8"><section section-type="section-one" id="H79E7DC4B8CA44988AEF0FC3966D0D5EB"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Resources Technical Assistance Review Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H3404B87AC19545A887B507DA3E9A3512"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO report on clean water technical assistance</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc8de89b8b9546fd85a83abe9461b8a8"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d2495510e454d06b975b86fcf5c7f03"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44c6a9752e79419e8d5b4b52cb55ac1d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comptroller General</header><text>The term <term>Comptroller General</term> means the Comptroller General of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6178c91752349d09fda524c75968b53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered technical assistance</header><text>The term <term>covered technical assistance</term> means a technical assistance authority, initiative, or program of the Administrator that is related to clean water infrastructure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD22BA7162955490587DC7245CE7A0F68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comprehensive review required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall initiate a comprehensive review of all covered technical assistance.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8B7E5D60F85B4EB3AD0DAE7123A93907"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Comptroller General shall include in the review required under subsection (b) the following:</text><paragraph id="HA2AEBA10616B43B3BEC1D4E8A175FED0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of all covered technical assistance available to States, Indian Tribes, local governments, and nongovernmental organizations, including—</text><subparagraph id="H94C8CB6731B9414B9ADB4FA6AFC8755E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the regions and populations that are served through the provision of covered technical assistance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86B9005D2742429387035821668AEB0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary of the activities and actions carried out through covered technical assistance during the 5-year period ending on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5710B99A17064A23AC46A16397A2A77D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comprehensive review of how the Administrator, through the Water Technical Assistance initiative (commonly known as the <quote>WaterTA initiative</quote> and referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>initiative</quote>), identifies, selects, and partners with technical assistance providers to support communities, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2D150BAD70CC40D58B213758AD284AF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the criteria, evaluation process, and contracting mechanisms used for selecting those providers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41F1DC3A69BC4DFFB1D42C9F5C5821B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the extent of coordination with State, Tribal, and regional partners in the selection and deployment of those providers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B20A444311F422AB49E640026744566"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how those providers are matched to meet the needs of local communities, including any pre-engagement scoping activities or community consultations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H947E1FBF907D46FBB467961C013D3437"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how those providers identify communities in need of technical assistance, including economically distressed communities, and conduct outreach to those communities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB14CDA080FDB4A1797CA12FF84488AB3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the scope and types of assistance delivered through the initiative; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8E3FC807092458090A4A2E0D8A749CB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a list of communities that received technical assistance support through the initiative, including the type and cost of assistance received by each such community and a summary of the outcomes associated with the provision of the technical assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24B80EC1D04E401DA9975E5CF9320F7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of any duplication of covered technical assistance available through multiple programs of the Administrator.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5919F894F80048A98149915FEF5B045B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of how the provision of covered technical assistance builds capacity in communities to access other water infrastructure programs carried out by the Administrator.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H32AB21AB62BC4CBD8E45FBCBC3DA4D84"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of the needs of economically distressed communities eligible to receive assistance under a clean water infrastructure program carried out by the Administrator that is not addressed through covered technical assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6C1F2EE09F74BE3819CCAFF0665740D"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of how the Administrator carries out covered technical assistance in coordination with the heads of other Federal agencies that provide technical assistance related to water infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0950F323E5BB4361971DA5162A06EBD0"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of how covered technical assistance supports communities in understanding, identifying, and implementing alternative and cost-effective technologies and features of treatment works that achieve long-term savings and improved outcomes in addressing water quality challenges.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1CAEC83792D45318D513EB0FF8CFFEC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>On the completion of the review required under subsection (b), the Comptroller General shall submit to the Administrator, the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report containing—</text><paragraph id="H10E3CEA18EEE4DF994D39E3059DFE968"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the review; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35DB7FE9F3C24CC9B16526B6613D6169"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendations to improve covered technical assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85C643B6CD9A4ECAA9B0C3DDE3E7CD27"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Plan for compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Comptroller General submits the report required under subsection (d), and annually thereafter for each of the following 5 years, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a plan describing any actions the Administrator has taken to comply with the recommendations contained in the report.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

