<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26279-S86-N2-PFJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3855 IS: United States-Israel Framework for Upgraded Technologies, Unified Research, and Enhanced Security (FUTURES) Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3855</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To enhance bilateral defense cooperation between the United States and Israel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H62DB24278E00405D80A28F3868EF39D2"><section section-type="section-one" id="H1E38F3727FCE445F96FD5BC56B5B0A41"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States-Israel Framework for Upgraded Technologies, Unified Research, and Enhanced Security (FUTURES) Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H023982A3259E49E0811EE5DCADCDDE51"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HFDC9A15DB4BF4948B03B0FCD33174E35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States and Israel—</text><subparagraph id="H90A52184010A426FAA1E0204A48FA854"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are bound by shared democratic values, strategic interests, and deep cultural and technological ties; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83EF1B623EE74A8CBA47BAA0B1E59D96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>can benefit from further joint innovation and rapid technology deployment in facing common and evolving security challenges;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H700FDBADA4434E038B8F34F3AFFD3E06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Israel is a strategic and capable ally of the United States that advances United States strategic interests, strengthens United States military capabilities, and bolsters the United States economy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H766F6FA5627A49D7AE47ABA2C5B6C8E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as a global leader and innovator in the development of defense technology, Israel is a close foreign defense partner of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C34404CCFDA43468DE6DF3764D7C1B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on September 14, 2016, the United States and Israel signed a 10-year memorandum of understanding reaffirming the importance of continuing annual United States military assistance to Israel and cooperative missile defense programs in a way that enhances the security and bilateral relationship between the two countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA1E39527E844559EDD5000BBAAFD20"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States-Israel defense partnership, through sustained joint research and development, has yielded critical advances in both countries’ national security capabilities in areas such as missile defense, directed energy, counter drone, anti-tunneling, counterterrorism, and emerging technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17622540E95B4128BCE47801333B6690"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to maintain Israel’s qualitative military edge while deterring adversaries and ensuring mutual security, the United States and Israel must expand cooperation in emerging domains; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD630C0B9CD0D4883ABD949AB1224F760"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to grow American technological supremacy, the United States must leverage the unique capabilities offered by each country and more rapidly integrate jointly developed and Israeli-origin defense technologies into United States military systems, programs of record, and the defense industrial base.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HDA0FDD1E979744EAB58AE7C7E16E29BE"> <enum>3.</enum> <header>Establishment of the United States–Israel Defense Technology Cooperation Initiative</header> <subsection id="HB6F13424EB11426AA1BE9594C8AC4198"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Establishment</header> <text>The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Minister of Defense of Israel, shall establish a cooperative initiative, to be known as the <quote>United States-Israel Defense Technology Cooperation Initiative</quote>, to expand and accelerate bilateral defense technology research, development, testing, evaluation, integration, and industrial cooperation by—</text>
        <paragraph id="H86A6747A638741D2BDD739902CE87DDB">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>identifying jointly developed or Israeli-origin technologies with operational utility for integration into United States systems and programs of record;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H177AB821D27A4BBC98FCF9ADB583FEB6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>conducting collaborative research initiatives involving government, private sector, and academic institutions in the United States and Israel, in a manner that protects sensitive technology and information and the national security interests of the United States and Israel;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA77EA260C0FF4C0298ECAE42A1571249">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>facilitating the transition of technologies from research and development into procurement and acquisition pathways;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H908D22004387460EAA287EBAE003BC45">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>establishing frameworks for joint ventures, licensing agreements, and United States-based co-production or manufacturing partnerships with Israeli industry;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB343B9316ADD45F884A84BDBD0B18247">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating with relevant Department of Defense components, including the Irregular Warfare Technical Support Directorate, capability development and innovation divisions, the Defense Innovation Unit, the United States-Israel Operations Technology Working Group, the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, the Missile Defense Agency and United States Space Command, and the military services, to align efforts and avoid duplication; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H843E507076B84E63A63D80C83A5A1D63">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>promoting joint training exercises and information-sharing mechanisms to enhance operational readiness to deploy jointly developed technologies.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H267A7F3FDDB94BE3B71519BDAA0BF4D8">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Initiative domains</header>
 <text>The Initiative shall be carried out through cooperative efforts in domains such as the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="H43E43075DD6F427CA8584DC9C4CBAEE5">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Counter-Unmanned Systems including aerial, maritime, and ground platforms.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF651F28A0CFF41E9BC3CB6DDFA45A44A"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>Anti-tunneling and subterranean threats.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFA3BD0055D9E4028A4B2320E4C0A8B61">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Missile and air defense technologies, including Golden Dome for America.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE46E9A8CD34E4821AF986F4F47C78042">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Artificial intelligence, quantum, machine learning, and autonomous systems.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H6711ED984628471181FA15E5C15C2B68"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>Directed energy and advanced sensing.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H02071776B00D40EEA242DCE905577772">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Cyber defense, electronic warfare, and digital resilience.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD758A46866C549D7BF2CEA2A9E6CFEB4"> <enum>(7)</enum> <text>Biotechnology, biomanufacturing, and medical defense.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB39693AEC9E64FD2A127CC5A9AEFC919">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>Network integration, data fusion, and contested logistics.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H156B9CABCA584019949E29E802D3D5E2"> <enum>(9)</enum> <text>Defense industrial base cooperation, manufacturing, and co-production.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE0E3682A97854858B20D9A2D4B22F44E">
          <enum>(10)</enum>
 <text>Other emerging technologies as jointly agreed by the United States and Israel.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HACAF01170BA749EDA97AA608B5F7A7E4">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Activities in coordination with other Federal departments and agencies</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall coordinate activities under the Initiative with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, to ensure consistency with existing laws and regulations.</text>
      </subsection>
 </section><section id="HB4F278778F45411DAB8FD2C126988027"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reporting</header><subsection id="H25C67D15C5114164931571E2967F50AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interim progress update</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the congressional defense committees an interim briefing or written update describing—</text><paragraph id="H8F935DC35C004D028430E17C3CAE2485"><enum>(1)</enum><text>steps taken to stand up the initiative;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H495807F2CC004AF3B24F4DF241A4C952"><enum>(2)</enum><text>early coordination with Israeli counterparts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B9582B21FA44F7BAE40504DA576F10"><enum>(3)</enum><text>initial technology areas identified for accelerated cooperation and technologies with operational utility for integration into United States systems and programs of record;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA995B7025C4A648F84D3B66C0CB35D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Department of Defense components designated to lead implementation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D34E501F982433BAB72FD8D1F07F347"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any early transition, prototyping, or integration activities initiated during the period covered by the update.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9E41C2F1BD34DCA930B2A9853FDBE0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on implementation of the program established under this section. Each such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="H0B4777D7020342548F8C571EC9452225"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of activities conducted under the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H719059E2488C4C7EA1F3C59907F8A046"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of progress made in advancing shared national security interests;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BBFDFC63ADD4899886FBFF29817ED71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the program’s collaboration with other relevant Federal programs, including the United States-Israel operations-technology working group and United States-Israel cooperative programs run by the capability development and innovation division and the irregular warfare technical support directorate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEDA3CD47B1D4AF084B486FDC9BB2E4B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of technologies transitioned into United States acquisition programs or fielded systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA6308C04FCF4F38A41489D708F6F511"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of partnerships established with United States and Israeli industry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82D3C8A6F93B47AC873B97D8BAA993B0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recommendations for future priorities and assessment of resource needs, including further authorities necessary to promote the long-term integration of joint capabilities between the United States and Israel.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC77E7FE5331A436398294CB9B42ACC35"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report required under subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="H786D45F56CC24D01A47105AAE9CA081A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public transparency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall make available on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Defense periodic, unclassified updates, to the maximum extent practicable, on activities conducted under the Initiative, including a description of how these activities contribute to American technological and military supremacy. Such updates shall be made in a manner that ensures that classified information or other information that would compromise operational security, export controls, or sensitive technology are not released.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB0E3B495E3594A95BC17D044F8F1BEE2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees defined</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>congressional defense committees</term> means the Committees on Appropriations and Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</text></subsection></section><section id="HEC81A3B3A0E8485AACC21BF035063492"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $150,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2029 to carry out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

