<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDCAD6A800F5B49F19D37685725B44333" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7595 IH: Superfund Area Facts and Exposure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7595</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260217">February 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study that identifies how many residential dwelling units, and how many dwelling units in public housing, are located within 1 mile of a superfund site.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H39FD634352AE4BBEA2CE04AD12FD28EE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2CA3F2F9158440239F3280A10672D543" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Superfund Area Facts and Exposure Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3F47DDFE779A46F0B2F59BF29156F373"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study to determine proximity of housing to Superfund sites</header> <subsection id="HA46A15ADE7514F4BADC71EC6EDF95710"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall carry out a study to identify how many residential dwelling units, and how many dwelling units in public housing (as such term is defined in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (42 U.S.C. 1437a(B))), are located within one mile of a site that is included on the National Priorities List pursuant to section 105 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9605">42 U.S.C. 9605</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H95A807A9FA2548EB913DDF2604314C12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the expiration of the 6-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a report to the Congress identifying, for each site referred to in subsection (a), how many residential dwelling units, and how many dwelling units in public housing, are located within one mile of such site.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

