<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE7C940D516AB4EB8B22573DF696038C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8060 IH: Elder Justice Reauthorization and Modernization Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8060</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260324">March 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reauthorize funding for programs to prevent, investigate, and prosecute elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBDF8A96827BE4E3CBEE185A11F10BCC2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7DF5FD5F5E254559A31F8AD3A3A0B682" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Elder Justice Reauthorization and Modernization Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC4C98A2030764C21A9CDAD7E4250AE4D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reauthorization of funding for programs to prevent and investigate elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation</header> <subsection id="H5E4171831E86400DAB094DB3D274EEEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nursing home worker training grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2041 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397m">42 U.S.C. 1397m</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10E72FE6FA264FA69EF6C3D3599E2A5D"> 
<section id="H9D13068A0BE848FA9D598CBEEDB5B7B4"><enum>2041.</enum><header>Nursing home worker training grants</header> 
<subsection id="H36AA3AB2FD824D4A9BCE151BBD8E6B25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph id="H67062D6F4687462F9F5042B7F60F2F98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State entitlement</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9968A06C661C4BB8BA6EE9D96BBAF60D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State shall be entitled to receive from the Secretary for each fiscal year specified in subsection (e)(1) a grant in an amount equal to the amount allotted to the State under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA780DC1ED09E4DD3B989F694424088DC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State allotments</header> <clause id="H95E880E9044C44B8AA60177403896208"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), the amount allotted to a State under this subparagraph for a fiscal year shall be—</text>
                                        <subclause id="H7716F485252744538F3FD29BA446B5C1">
                                            <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>the number of State residents who have attained 65 years of age or have a disability (as defined in section 216(i)(1)), as determined by the Secretary using the most recent version of the American Community Survey published by the Bureau of the Census or a successor data set; divided by</text>
                                        </subclause> 
<subclause id="H898101DEC59346F19428E0A203152229"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total number of such residents of all States.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H03A4B1F22ACD475C861652E6CF30059D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount allotted to a State under this subparagraph for a fiscal year shall be not less than 0.25 percent of the available amount for the fiscal year.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H748FE46A4B1D4075B4B8E884A15FA9E0"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Adjustment of State allotments</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), the Secretary shall proportionately increase or decrease the amounts allotted under this subparagraph for a fiscal year as necessary to ensure that the available amount for the fiscal year is allotted among the States.</text></clause> <clause id="H88255E82D0D447A387BCA17F3DA4A944"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Redeterminations</header> <subclause id="H9A98D51D75F04EE2B902E27D17E7A97A"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Secretary shall make the determination referred to in clause (i)(I) every 5 years.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA3A3AFE5EEB649B690A2B4DF63271C45"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), the amount allotted to a State under this subparagraph, on the basis of such a determination, for a fiscal year after fiscal year 2031 shall be—</text> <item id="HBEEC640132A34E45A78D2B8F0C8F427D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>not less than 90 percent of the amount of the grant made to the State under this subparagraph for the then preceding fiscal year; and</text></item> 
<item id="H98AB447BCC6A48EBAFB656F2B5C4BAA3"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not more than 110 percent of the amount referred to in item (aa).</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74A40B11E52F4341B6D707C47A8FDC06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants to Indian tribes and tribal organizations</header> <subparagraph id="HCAF4CFB4CB784998A8E527821C986DF3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall make grants in accordance with this section to Indian tribes and tribal organizations who operate at least 1 eligible setting.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A7C2A981E354022A09E52EBA5A14279"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Grant formula</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall devise a formula for distributing among Indian tribes and tribal organizations the amount required to be reserved by subsection (e)(1) for each fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCB87B15B0784A5794CC86221C98CBC5"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Sub-grants</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State, Indian tribe, or tribal organization to which an amount is paid under this section may use the amount to make sub-grants to local organizations, including community organizations, local nonprofits, elder rights and justice groups, labor organizations, joint labor-management organizations, and workforce development boards for any purpose described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b).</text>
                            </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3EEADB40DA3D4C90A087EDEC38A6DACE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="HF987C8F948654503B218784475101540"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State to which an amount is paid under this section shall use the amount to—</text> <subparagraph id="H1629DF326C2A465CB02DF0776C3290DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide wage subsidies to eligible individuals;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7992103AE0AD4A7F820451E868E016F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide tuition assistance to, and directly pay the cost of applicable licensing exam fees for, eligible individuals for a degree or certification in a field relevant to their position referred to in subsection (f)(1)(A);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD4220900EFE40128C1F527A258F00DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide, subsidize, or facilitate access to child care for eligible individuals, including help with referrals, co-pays, or other direct assistance as needed; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23908C45BD634439869F58A92FD3B5B8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide assistance where necessary with obtaining appropriate transportation, including public transportation if available, or gas money or transit vouchers for ride share, taxis, and similar types of transportation if public transportation is unavailable or impractical based on work hours or location.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4E792C59FF64823853FA84FD8B2BB70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized uses</header><text>A State to which an amount is paid under this section may use the amount to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H248D4106AF624EC4A2B8FF2BA8DB56E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a reserve fund for financial assistance to eligible individuals in emergency situations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D3EB6A97EEF4CD0BCCA293618728374"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide in-kind resource donations, such as interview clothing and conference attendance fees;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H646266326F1B46CDA59FABBE16DF48F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide assistance with programs and activities, including legal assistance, deemed necessary to address arrest or conviction records that are an employment barrier;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40043F0E715A4FDD82493CF32267B4B9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support employers operating an eligible setting in the State in providing employees with not less than 2 weeks of paid leave per year; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD285548F18034B53A1D052879DF41DD9"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide other support services the Secretary deems necessary to allow for successful recruitment and retention of workers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07D22A4619DE48FFA696FB9105E4F030"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Provision of funds only for the benefit of eligible individuals in eligible settings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State to which an amount is paid under this section may provide the amount to only an eligible individual or a partner organization serving an eligible individual.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52E786E5CD2C47F1AE5C4ECC8F665919"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nonsupplantation</header><text>A State to which an amount is paid under this section shall not use the amount to supplant the expenditure of any State funds for recruiting, supporting, or retaining employees in an eligible setting.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF59AD5175B04AD1A20EE47CBA3EE05A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Obligation deadline</header><text>A State, Indian tribe, or tribal organization shall remit to the Secretary for reallotment under this section any amount paid under this section for a fiscal year that is not obligated within 2 years after the end of the fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3112EF7BBCD344D1B337925F0DC0D065"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State to which a grant is made under this section shall reserve not more than 10 percent of the grant to—</text> <paragraph id="HDBEBFE5B716640E1AAE30AA26EEF8787"><enum>(1)</enum><text>administer subgrants in accordance with this section;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E1300D21FA643EABE3E797D38F5A3B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide technical assistance and support for applying for and accessing such a subgrant opportunity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8CBF56C11284F4B8F33D0419063941C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>publicize the availability of the subgrants;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF6DC62523DF4B17A44BDE8E50005AE4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carry out activities to increase the supply of eligible individuals; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4F8252BBAA0463696DEBF62796BDCB5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to help subgrantees find and train individuals to provide the services for which they are contracted.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC7671B91C27842BC88C6D74360CDD844"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="HA452A5058DB84CD48291D17724E31663"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State reports</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, each State to which a grant has been made under this section shall transmit to the Secretary a written report describing the activities undertaken by the State pursuant to this section during the period covered by the report, which shall include a specification of—</text> <subparagraph id="HCD6C27DA5B4D42C59803B7033195FCA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total amount expended in the State for each type of use described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE8CC0D361A214C879BFBC66EC07D1746"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of non-State organizations in the State to which grant funds were provided, and the amount so provided to each such organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19121AE5222C49C980089C79E5CD84C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the change in the number of individuals working in each job category described in subsection (f)(1)(A) in an eligible setting in the State due to programs or services funded with grants under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04742CEAFB2542A4B3BEB9B24BA1B421"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average duration of employment for each such job category for individuals receiving, or who previously received, services or supports from a grant under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74855C95F68D42B89D1EE4CA4F8914D8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">wages of workers in each job category described in subsection (f)(1)(A) in an eligible setting in the State with support from grants under this section, as compared to all other workers in the same eligible setting in the State;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H863F3219F1394CDBBBA37D7CED2BE327"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average amount of paid time off to which a worker in each job category described in subsection (f)(1)(A) in an eligible setting in the State is entitled by their contract among workers with support from a grant under this section, as compared to all workers in eligible settings in the State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4D7EFA0DBA14C88B4A0B252B85F3EF3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>such other data elements as the Secretary deems relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAFA584E356024FB3B3D935F6D6AC4E1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to the Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this section, and every 4 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a written report outlining how the States have used the grants made under this section during the period covered by the report, which shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HD0330818B20D4788AEB312A8D2472E10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total amount expended in each State for each type of use described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H22472420AA904066B1202D20FFECA0DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of non-State organizations in each State to which grant funds were provided, and the amount so provided to each such organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59A87A2220C440F08CBA628F76F1CA6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an analysis of the data provided in the State reports; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H652E8275950D44FC93E8DE430F567B94"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other data elements as the Secretary deems relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H326E8519252140B0A2A8A672AE81EC63"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there is appropriated to the Secretary $410,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030 to carry out this section, of which—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDAC41397BD16469E94FDABD2A7880173"><enum>(1)</enum><text>2 percent for each fiscal year shall be reserved for grants to Indian tribes and tribal organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45D5D21156A74B4CBF0D830790185CDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>2 percent for each fiscal year shall be reserved for administrative costs associated with Federal staffing for grantmaking and independent evaluation activities under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC11A6326CB5342F6A6490F00D9F2D2BA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB41C9B0EC0A74BAA8B1A09697C80FF9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Available amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>available amount</term> means, with respect to a fiscal year, the amount specified in subsection (e) that remains after the reservation required by such subsection for the fiscal year, plus all amounts remitted to the Secretary under subsection (b)(5) that have not been reallotted under subsection (a)(1)(B)(iii).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75CB2BF018704D83A81F55D896B7D15B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="HE19C5BBA7BAF4E3F84E0E1707FF36D84"><enum>(A)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H85CDA546F3BF44D98139B85C4DF60A00"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a qualified home health aide, as defined in section 484.80(a) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2AA1A330692743B39957260B9B14C381" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a nurse aide approved by the State as meeting the requirements of sections 483.150 through 483.154 of such title, and is listed in good standing on the State nurse aide registry;</text></clause> <clause id="H7AD6F90ED9C744D0971CC92CC1F2B5F1" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is a personal care aide approved by the State, and furnishes personal care services, as defined in section 440.167 of such title;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H46363D37B0244815BF3D304221343387" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is a qualified hospice aide, as defined in section 418.76 of such title;</text></clause> <clause id="H9443ACAEA4134BC2B7104325EBE270AF" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is a licensed practical nurse or a licensed or certified social worker; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE57276C8159846E08AB2CA6357CC749C" indent="up1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>is receiving training to be certified or licensed as such an aide, nurse, or social worker; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H736C5E33499E4E5E94B2EFC9EDF640BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides (or, in the case of a trainee, intends to provide) services as such an aide, nurse, or social worker in an eligible setting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6ED4724950B48AE9002C6AAB68297FB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible setting</header><text>The term <term>eligible setting</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H668589DE713441938CABAFDCBBA8B6FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a skilled nursing facility, as defined in section 1819;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H727930011CD84D54A2A3F33A5215F8BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nursing facility, as defined in section 1919;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H94E9B5184625430BB6B1F593A5F5549A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a home health agency, as defined in section 1891;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0C134C11174447BBFBFD0FBD0F59CA7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a facility approved to deliver home or community-based services authorized under State options described in subsection (c) or (i) of section 1915 or, as relevant, demonstration projects authorized under section 1115;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB628B0EB9DD6420D93997D9B7952895B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a hospice, as defined in section 1814; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59D66BD40DD94416908960A595F99393"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a tribal assisted living facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H699D309E54574DE5B5CB69CBE9B0DAD7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>tribal organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H510A0FF393C540F68774348C195C0952"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adult protective services functions and grant programs</header> 
<paragraph id="H7C0420E83D924125BEA1CCB4F0906754"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Direct funding; State entitlement</header><text>Section 2042 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397m-1">42 U.S.C. 1397m–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H8DEB8ACBA38844618A84D127A52A74E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAED50DA8836641309AFDE106F6EF0C4A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H558AEAB5D9644445A888D08F2E19A029"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8CE193ABEC31453A80D1F1BF0E6DAE84" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<clause id="H4EABBAEBC314417B9DA8DFF33CEB4368"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>the availability of appropriations and</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCEB759E893384C9C91E230B9B30E6D4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9F67DB07F2C4981AAEE0AB290295CE3"> 
<paragraph id="H46DFFAEABF944D0DB773E6079C4E8511"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary $500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD985873E184542E29FBE832E7257B111" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking paragraph (6) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70F58F605D014453BC36FB1BB4AFE1CA"> 
<paragraph id="HB22A690ACD30481180FCD952AB151299"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary $80,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB512C00161494013AE18AB08553F132F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State entitlement; grants to Indian tribes and tribal organizations</header><text>Section 2042 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397m-1">42 U.S.C. 1397m–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H930279245B3146ED8BE84862F4F9984F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)(A), by striking <quote>State and local</quote> and inserting <quote>State, local, and tribal</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2FE54CCD3AD43D7ABF8B8AA0B8C92C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>the Secretary shall annually award grants to States in the amounts calculated under paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>each State shall be entitled to annually receive from the Secretary in the amounts calculated under paragraph (2), and the Secretary may annually award to each Indian tribe and tribal organization in accordance with paragraph (3), grants</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2EDAA0D1AAB14609BEA870268D3240B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)—</text> <clause id="H88E6CEE2EC76470F88AB1B1A56EA9044"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">for a State</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">payment</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD327D2914D4145AE90C6351A2E87B2C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>that remains after the reservation under paragraph (3)(B)</quote> before <quote>multiplied</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H172E4364EE4643E086E6D8B2FC59C2A8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i)—</text> 
<subclause id="HA67C00430693474A8A86EFDC5E79D806"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>that so remains</quote> after <quote>such year</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAE5E1B223BA2446190672479D17E4BD8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>amount so appropriated</quote> and inserting <quote>remaining amount</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9199C25B22FB4F71AF60155109EFDE50"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (5) as paragraphs (4) through (6), respectively, and inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5E3A4FEC5E124D9697BC4FE56D4D72E3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H74D7FC6D8FFA4587A1FB376104D7E621"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amount of payment to Indian tribe or tribal organization</header> <subparagraph id="HFB4C6C29EE734016A5DFDCF4DB3B330B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with Indian tribes and tribal organizations, shall determine the amount of any grant to be made to each Indian tribe and tribal organization from the amount reserved under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph. Paragraphs (4) and (5) shall apply to grantees under this paragraph in the same manner in which the paragraphs apply to States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H838C4C67616249AE8BD07361E556722D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reservation of funds</header><text>The Secretary shall reserve 2 percent of the amount made available by subsection (b)(6) for each fiscal year for grants under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD91C9BD918574CA4B3AD27083DB19E2E"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>in subsection (c)—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H8465BAFD0CB240DFB07C60310C69D467">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>to States</quote> and inserting <quote>to States, Indian tribes, and tribal organizations</quote>;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H642DE8F1531A47E8B54151F2F27332AA">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="H22D8CBB23CA54025BAE8462F5798497D"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>and Indian tribes and tribal organizations</quote> after <quote>government</quote>; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H3DA5C371A3484670B11404154E58DE82">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (D), by inserting <quote>or Indian tribe or tribal organization, as the case may be</quote> after <quote>government</quote>;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HF8BD37F137114A60AF81F9C3BD4076E8">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>or Indian tribe or tribal organization</quote> after <quote>a State</quote> the first place it appears; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HE31DC77817454ED687D12E6D0DE1CD25">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (5)—</text> <clause id="HA6D5C8B6D69C45C7B9D7911E36D2F6AC"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>by inserting <quote>or Indian tribe or tribal organization</quote> after <quote>Each State</quote>; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H11D42A9A89E74FE39233B20A8B250938">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>or Indian tribe or tribal organization, as the case may be</quote> after <quote>the State</quote>; and</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B2E07908C5E48B4BDD91A9E10534013">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD474E6185FF14EF18940FFF490992E9B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H16BABB007F8F4D91B6B963E025B4E726"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Definitions of Indian tribe and tribal organization</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms <term>Indian tribe</term> and <term>tribal organization</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 419.</text>
                        </subsection>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H932E72FDE6DF47F6B520437C9925EB1D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Long-Term care ombudsman program grants and training</header><text>Section 2043 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397m-2">42 U.S.C. 1397m–2</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB95E15C7826C403CA5C395B421005F07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H72A1087C8F244BD5A5662CCF525A3E62" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H05CE4CC1EB7D474ABD124B5F31D93C71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H42072A3BAF8149488B8A36B21BDEFDA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$23,000,000 for fiscal year 2027; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA256F410EF904AED8FD491CCAD4E9A8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2028 and 2029.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDCFE4CD1A8B498EBF20AAF6B17011E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1868C7A82FD947D8A19B084192101B77" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HBFD5DAA8248A42939121A6A46CEECD3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030 to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEE4432F33A5D4004935287D0EA62FACC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Incentives for developing and sustaining structural competency in providing health and human services</header> <paragraph id="HB234684725B1454897A7A49F369F6D6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part II of subtitle B of title XX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/397m-5">42 U.S.C. 397m–5</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4883EE5A28174B0ABA8236947019A8B9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H7CA8486587CF49FFBB2B23594A91563F"><enum>2047.</enum><header>Incentives for developing and sustaining structural competency in providing health and human services</header> 
<subsection id="HF3864D5491974A7AA0332DD211F486FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants to States To support linkages to legal services and medical-Legal partnerships</header> 
<paragraph id="H17D4E42FBC244D7898D3DF2B8252C1FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish and administer a program of grants to States to support the development or adoption of approaches to maintain or improve linkages between health services, human services, and legal services for older adults and adults with disabilities, including through the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H073D9FD62C9140D3AD43658D6013351F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Medical-legal partnerships</header><text>The establishment and support of medical-legal partnerships, the incorporation of the partnerships in the elder justice framework and health and human services safety net, and the implementation and operation of such a partnership by an eligible grantee—</text> 
<clause id="H8A489405AAA94E438FC46972312258D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at the option of a State, in conjunction with an area agency on aging;</text></clause> <clause id="HB95D05EDB2524DC3B28F45D115B949B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a solo provider practice in a health professional shortage area (as defined in section 332(a) of the Public Health Service Act), a medically underserved community (as defined in section 399V of such Act), or a rural area (as defined in section 330J of such Act);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFB2BAD82D434493F95E127F04B03053C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in a minority-serving institution of higher learning with health, law, and social services professional programs;</text></clause> <clause id="H6446C510367348A085DD23179388A8F3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a federally qualified health center, as described in section 330 of the Public Health Service Act, or look-alike, as described in section 1905(l)(2)(B) of this Act; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB5BD63346A1445BAB0F44825717B08D3"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in certain hospitals that are critical access hospitals, Medicare-dependent hospitals, sole community hospitals, rural emergency hospitals, or that serve a high proportion of Medicare or Medicaid patients.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD9A04EC2AD347AB8998364D018B0285"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Legal hotlines development or expansion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provision of incentives to develop, enhance, and integrate platforms, such as legal assistance hotlines, that help to facilitate the identification of older adults and adults with disabilities who could benefit from linkages to available legal services such as those described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H109025A631A240DA84D05D16441025CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State to which a grant is made under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary biannual reports on the activities carried out by the State pursuant to this subsection, which shall include assessments of the effectiveness of the activities with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="HFC171A1D5E7A4C90BBF652844D0FDBA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of unique individuals identified through the mechanism outlined in paragraph (1)(B) who are referred to services described in paragraph (1)(A), and the average time period associated with resolving issues;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H413DBB1A904645169C6A123B855A3996"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the success rate for referrals to community-based resources; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A6FDF48FF504F72901AD4307A6F9F8A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other factors determined relevant by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF75FE8B54F04DA997133BE0198726EC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to the Congress</header><text>Every 4 years, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a written report on the activities conducted under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E41CFA975054DCE9BA7B6A59A14AA51"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary $125,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030 to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38273E5AD3A84EDFB2EB354597E104EE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Support provided to area agencies on aging, State units on aging, eligible entities, or other community-based organizations pursuant to this subsection shall be used to supplement and not supplant any other Federal, State, or local funds expended to provide the same or comparable services described in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA02D5F16C03C47C4AA1446D598C53CF5"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Grants and training To support area agencies on aging or other community-Based organizations To address social isolation among older adults and adults with disabilities</header> <paragraph id="H9FF9A62A7EB343B9A1457473889241D3"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Grants</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make grants to eligible area agencies on aging or other community-based organizations for the purpose of—</text>
                                    <subparagraph id="HA70055258B104B2E8EC9817EBC123B02">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducting outreach to individuals at risk for, or already experiencing, social isolation or loneliness, through established screening tools or other methods identified by the Secretary;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H330FB9256ED34C1FA738249BDE002F9A">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing community-based interventions for the purposes of mitigating loneliness or social isolation (including independently evaluated evidence-based programs, developed with multi-stakeholder input for the purposes of promoting social connection, mitigating social isolation or loneliness, or preventing social isolation or loneliness) among at-risk individuals;</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H8E9DFF71784549D5B046179A10A4ED74">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>connecting at-risk individuals with community social and clinical supports; and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="HCBA62718A34B4DE7979F6B492A991043">
                                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluating the effect of programs developed and implemented under subparagraphs (B) and (C).</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="HCD7169D6EB9E48528B7765455FA4FE41">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Training</header>
                                    <subparagraph id="HDD5EB254410249D7BF57FC618D4DD839">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                                        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish programs to provide and improve training for area agencies on aging or community-based organizations with respect to addressing and preventing social isolation and loneliness among older adults and adults with disabilities.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H4EF2DDAD37ED449580B4CB002E7B9991">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                                        <header>Prioritization authority</header>
 <text>For purposes of connecting at-risk individuals with existing community social and clinical supports, the Secretary may, in carrying out subparagraph (A), prioritize models that incorporate training and service delivery in coordination with medical-legal partnerships.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="HEE67479501F4416E874E888E33627DCB">
                                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                                    <header>Evaluation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this section and every 3 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a written report which provides—</text>
                                    <subparagraph id="HA6575B7495DF4C8DB7C90484CF6F613F">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a discussion of the status of implementing the programs developed under this subsection; and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="HCF31416D2DB64637A6C1165A6B138B96">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>an update on the independent research and evaluation being conducted on the effects and outcomes of the programs.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="HF742C18A35514A6FA8B1915D10693364">
                                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                                    <header>Appropriation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary $63,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030 to carry out this subsection.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H9DCC25911CC24353A436AF6846B2315E">
                                    <enum>(5)</enum>
                                    <header>Coordination</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall coordinate with resource centers, grant programs, or other funding mechanisms established under section 411(a)(18) of the Older Americans Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3032">42 U.S.C. 3032(a)(18)</external-xref>), section 417(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3032F">42 U.S.C. 3032F(a)(1)</external-xref>), or other programs as determined by the Secretary.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6108B3A564F44B219B826711E049B7E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1F4460D9C38D4107A43C7F78C8C4CFF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Area agency on aging</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>area agency on aging</term> means an area agency on aging designated under section 305 of the Older Americans Act of 1965.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27570470FDC642BF92456CAE66A7CDA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Social isolation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>social isolation</term> means objectively being alone, or having few relationships or infrequent social contact.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC01555B17BFE450E88C6C85AF121B416"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Loneliness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>loneliness</term> means subjectively feeling alone, or the discrepancy between one’s desired level of social connection and one’s actual level of social connection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21F77BAA37AB44D39A77392491E9EDC0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Social connection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>social connection</term> means the variety of ways one can connect to others socially, through physical, behavioral, social-cognitive, and emotional channels.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EEC0642A0FC47B48E319826B4F8A158"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Community-based organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community-based organization</term> includes, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, a nonprofit community-based organization, a consortium of nonprofit community-based organizations, a national nonprofit organization acting as an intermediary for a community-based organization, or a community-based organization that has a fiscal sponsor that allows the organization to function as an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB965B824A0A48E081468AA4A2EAFE58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clarification that medical-legal partnerships are authorized adult protective services activities</header><text>Section 2011 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397j">42 U.S.C. 1397j</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H994731F209CB40468A465529269B153F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(D), by inserting <quote>, including through a medical-legal partnership</quote> before the period; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84A18E5A4112488B9E785969544EA4FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (16) through (22) as paragraphs (17) through (23), respectively, and inserting after paragraph (15) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9CA4A11B83A043FC812AD8CE9437F87A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H354454B2B6D840A9BFE9B9ACA7BF34F6"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Medical-legal partnership</header><text>The term <term>medical-legal partnership</term> means an arrangement in a health care or human services setting which integrates lawyers and social workers to address the needs of an individual patient related to social determinants of health, and to help clinicians, case managers, and social workers address structural problems at the root of many health inequities, including a multidisciplinary team integrated into such a setting to address the needs and establish and maintain structural competence within clinicians, case managers, and social workers to best address structural problems at the root of many health inequities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD0903080BDD44BA1B007C0284C9F9D98" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Section 2011(12)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397j">42 U.S.C. 1397j(12)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>450b</quote> and inserting <quote>5304</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H37AB81DD7851401D908C8A6E4BADADB6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Assessment reports</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HFCC2BD5DB85B429480AE58E94F9A2A63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit a report to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance and the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate on the programs, coordinating bodies, registries, and activities established or authorized under subtitle B of title XX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397l">42 U.S.C. 1397l et seq.</external-xref>) or section 6703(b) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (42 U.S.C. 1395i–3a(b)). Each such report shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE60749C720F14F8CB8ACF838F3141F0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an update on any ongoing independently conducted evaluations of the extent to which such programs, coordinating bodies, registries, and activities have improved access to, and the quality of, resources available to older adults, adults with disabilities, and their caregivers to ultimately prevent, detect, and treat abuse, neglect, and exploitation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF36B64150CE45C5A21ADD5F505643A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as appropriate, recommendations to Congress on funding levels and policy changes to help these programs, coordinating bodies, registries, and activities better prevent, detect, and treat abuse, neglect, and exploitation of older adults and adults with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC4DE0E1E98C4C3686F644A34D060217"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of the independence of federally funded research and evaluation</header><text>Section 2023 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397k-2">42 U.S.C. 1397k–2</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7D836BEEA49840FEB4AAAAE4218FAC90" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H395753000B27481694A61C0FBA903A64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Independence of federally funded research and evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall continue to maintain and support with adequate staffing and resources the Office of Performance and Evaluation at the Administration for Community Living, which shall conduct independent research and evaluation activities associated with the programs and policies provided for in this subtitle. The research and evaluation activities shall reflect the rigor, relevance and utility, independence and objectivity, transparency, and ethical principles specified in the evaluation policy established for the Department of Health and Human Services under section 313 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H438D35A0E4DA43C38FA788250F9C3F52" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

