<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26508-H7H-D4-SXR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3995 IS: Location Updates for Custody and Transparency Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3995</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement to timely update the Online Detainee Locator System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Location Updates for Custody and Transparency Enforcement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LOCATE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id789d9043a706475db3abdddc13974d8c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id3a51190518634e80ac3948694480d386"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Custody event</header><text>The term <term>custody event</term> means, with respect to an individual in immigration detention, any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id386dc5348763456d9bf741e67f3f1280"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Initial intake or placement into custody by U.S. Customs and Border Protection or U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb206dad25a654122872be840b2477fae"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Transfer from one detention facility to another detention facility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd991dc30afe84b128edeb28b0a138171"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Release from custody.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided5db6205e014fcaa00640add69a48d1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Removal from the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8239121e7f1b42b49aab9a13fefd2ccf"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Death.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0dc77eb64f143e99a39d8fe7cb5b900" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any other significant change in status that materially affects the individual’s location or custodial status.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ce6e41c93e141dd894ca0f7a6217b55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Online detainee locator system</header><text>The term <term>Online Detainee Locator System</term> means the online system maintained by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for the purposes of tracking detainees in its custody or the custody of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ida73b0a0b43f2442b934aa6ab19db37dc"><enum>3.</enum><header>Timely reporting of detainee custody events</header><subsection id="id5ef3368e310e4239aa20912e70b2404a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Timely updates</header><text>Not later than 6 hours after any custody event affecting an individual in the custody of U.S. Customs and Border Protection or not later than 12 hours after any custody event affecting an individual in the custody of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, the Online Detainee Locator System shall be updated to accurately reflect such individual’s current custodial status and location.</text></subsection><subsection id="id68a00fbe8bb5460e8a29e0533007be5d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers between CBP and ICE</header><text>If an individual who was initially taken into custody by U.S. Customs and Border Protection is subsequently transferred to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall provide all relevant biographical and custodial information relating to such individual to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement not later than 4 hours after such transfer to facilitate timely entry into the Online Detainee Locator System.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5eb68a7262ef4a57b5fc315ad128a21a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data accuracy</header><text>The Online Detainee Locator System shall include, for each detainee—</text><paragraph id="idc7504a1e30234f1882b3591d907e613f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the full name and date of birth of the detainee;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida889d1c488134fe5b6267d0e72145bc6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the current facility where the detainee is being held, including the address of such facility and the contact information for a knowledgeable official at such facility;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida15a837a4daf4a21984d80d6825bad49"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the date of initial apprehension and most recent transfer of such detainee, if applicable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91d0d069d66944d7a3b10e8a5a1e012a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any scheduled release, removal, or transfer date for such detainee, if known; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9a804f6b4ef4731a21cc24ce9a8a5ed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>information regarding the release, deportation, or death of such detainee, if applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id95dfc4d2d94f44b4bc4422ad07495eab"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to supersede or replace any requirement that U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement report in-custody deaths in accordance with section 3 of the Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13727a">42 U.S.C. 13727a</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="id7240e31138f74b2d92283a5d95319bb6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement and accountability</header><subsection id="idcb5ef9273a044124be41a02b0f79244a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inspector General audits</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc37bcefa2dd64f75b8c0b7eda94b6622"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct annual audits to evaluate the Department of Homeland Security's compliance with the requirements under section 3; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf5c3cd07c5a74781804628fe45741a38"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit annual reports to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that summarize the findings of such audits.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddf18af391137445e95b7fbbe3a57ab77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timely notification of family or representatives</header><text>Not later than 12 hours after a custody event involving a detainee, reasonable efforts shall be made to notify close family members or legal representatives of such detainee, if known, of such custody event.</text></subsection></section><section id="idc4e923bea04749c38533844d7196e1d0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

