<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD66FE111E093443B89411E661BC090A9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9569 IH: Making Condos Safer and Affordable Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9569</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Housing Act to authorize insurance of certain mortgages to finance repairs and improvements to condominium projects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H11C6B40F14E04270A577A5DC465BD0F1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5D42CCD7E67744DAA071EB59F007F481" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Making Condos Safer and Affordable Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9B873CF2FCF641AF988944342C3C0B9C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Insurance of mortgages for condominium associations to finance repair and replacement of common facilities of condominium projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 234 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715y">12 U.S.C. 1715y</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H990D551D61C9476EA5A6D80A0C08C515"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>and preserving</quote> after <quote>increasing</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E09F87FD4BB4025B5B5A54EDFEA475C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the first sentence of subsection (b), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, and except that the term <quote>mortgage</quote>, for the purposes of subsection (l), includes a loan financing the costs of a rehabilitation, alteration, repair, improvement, or replacement of any common system, infrastructure, facility, feature, portion, or area serving a condominium project and that is secured by future lien-based mandatory unit owner payments required pursuant to State statute, a recorded declaration of covenants, or lawful rule, by-law, or guideline adopted by the governing body of the condominium project, real property, or a combination thereof</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE9474B2892134AD8807262F89D786E2C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H67275BBC346341849F3DD8695F8C6F5C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HC245DAFBD1F44503AEC7488E3C419F4B"> <enum>(l)</enum> <header>Insurance of mortgages To finance repairs and replacements of common facilities</header> <paragraph id="HCFCD5F3743A0407292400CBBFE30948E"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to mortgages insured under the other provisions of this section, the Secretary may insure, in the discretion of the Secretary and under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, a mortgage—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H518FA73D8DE3411D8A8A7CC7F2806590">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>that finances, in the case of condominium projects, the costs of a rehabilitation, alteration, repair, improvement, or replacement of any common system, infrastructure, facility, feature, portion, or area serving the project; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H5096ED73B2934FA5BB7CD1392363369B">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under which the mortgagor is the governing body of the condominium project.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="HCCAD081D41C7480C99E776F518A4E801">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Loan limit</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for insurance under this subsection, a mortgage may not involve a principal obligation in an amount exceeding 90 percent of the cost of the proposed rehabilitation, alteration, repair, improvement, or replacement project.</text>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB6A1FE20FC7B4BEEA05A162B1AA802AA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by inserting <quote>or (l)</quote> after <quote>subsection (d)</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H5315BF708BCB4065B02020BB43B8FBD8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Insurance of mortgages for owners of condominium units to finance special assessments</header> <subsection id="H5FA3EAB0991C48848F37D7ACEC126C7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Section <enum-in-header>203(k)</enum-in-header> rehabilitation loans</header><text>Section 203(k) of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1709">12 U.S.C. 1709(k)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H4DA85690AAA84D4292CF9B2C42123172"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFC7DF194960C463AAC1AE56E588588F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
<clause id="H7AB4BEEED7AF4FFFB3BB48317C79779F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></clause> <clause id="H214B8D27C4FE450BA2BBFD5F9C8F2879"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end and inserting <quote>or</quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H760BE642ED534AA7AF5EE7B362683AA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H92C2BC4A4F644B36B02CBF4CB6EDC68F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HD72D6C3883CF435F9BA74FC32E4304F2" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a dwelling unit in a condominium and notwithstanding any other law, regulation, or guideline of the Secretary, including subpart C of part II of the FHA Single Family Policy Handbook 4000.1 of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the payment of a non-regular assessment charged by the governing body of the condominium project to the unit owner to cover costs of a future rehabilitation, alteration, repair, improvement, or replacement of any common system, infrastructure, facility, feature, portion, or area serving the project; and </text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H243FCAD3D885462AB7F6BEB61FBCC5CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>or the funding of reserves for future project-level improvements or repairs,</quote> after <quote>in connection with a structure,</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A9AAA0BBFC14BF0A5ADF32106492548"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3)(A)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H075ECE0CD9EB4EC3B046D8262970BEF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>the greater of (i)</quote> before <quote>the sum of the estimated cost of rehabilitation</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6DD3BE63825C4EE3B1048E3741ADB4AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, or (ii) the Secretary’s estimate of the value of the property after rehabilitation; except that in no case shall the principal obligation exceed 115 percent of the Secretary’s estimate of the value of the property after rehabilitation</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0E9FA6C5195C4C719340DA4161FE98CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) and (6) as paragraphs (6) and (7); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H394C24AB72BD4BE48C9DD30DA03DDE9F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1D1DB41E3E794439B83292EC3634BC8E" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<paragraph id="H8DB8AC7ACB2041568D753CC2CCE8C8CC" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall streamline regulations and guidelines applicable to verification of rehabilitation and repair plans, management of rehabilitation work, disbursement of loan proceeds, and certification of work completion for any rehabilitation loan insured under this subsection for purposes of payment of a non-regular assessment described in paragraph (2)(A)(iv) or payment of reserves for future project-level improvements or repairs described in paragraph (2)(B) to account for management of such rehabilitation work or reserves by the governing body of the condominium project.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H185095EDFD8D43899FC3DC1E3FEB21D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Title I property improvement loans</header><text>Section 2 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1703">12 U.S.C. 1703</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H5E85B5CC1353495880AB2316830F4D49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence of subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HA1A22208BA0449B2AF1C353240B02F46"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(iii)</quote> before <quote>financing the preservation of historic structures</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H12F0C63C4D954EA38554ABD00248503F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>; and for the purpose of (iv) financing, in the case of a dwelling unit in a condominium and notwithstanding any other law, regulation, or guideline of the Secretary, including subpart C of part II of the FHA Single Family Policy Handbook 4000.1 of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the payment of a non-regular assessment charged by the governing body of the condominium project to the unit owner to cover costs of a future rehabilitation, alteration, repair, improvement, or replacement of any common system, infrastructure, facility, feature, portion, or area serving the project</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9827F7F4E77C49E2A951547400646366"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H37DA081887864E4EB15BA721290F05E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i)—</text> <clause id="H0E349FF36BB34345AF96EBD01D16849D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$25,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$55,000</quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H67D05283AA364D4F9FA657A9C6E5D614"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>or a non-regular assessment charged by the governing body of the condominium project to the unit owner to cover costs of rehabilitation, alteration, repair, improvement, or replacement of any common system, infrastructure, facility, feature, portion, or area serving the project</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8480A544200B40E99277083DBBD09EBB"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>in the matter after and below subparagraph (G), by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Secretary shall, by regulation, annually increase the dollar amount limitations in subparagraphs (A)(i), (B), and (F) (as such limitations may have been previously adjusted under this sentence) in accordance with the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (CPI–U).</quote>.</text>
          </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

