<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAA536675822A46BC8EFD82D014A6F59D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7121 IH: Securing Federal Devices from Chinese Applications Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7121</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the download or use of a Chinese application on any Federal Government device.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6A4AFB4CE99449CBA184774CC3810C11" style="OLC"><section id="H8DA6F47519114A4A8F66D1AF3169C556" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Federal Devices from Chinese Applications Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB3C6BA9D0F484E27A426EEE9452DBDF8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Chinese applications prohibited on Federal Government devices</header><subsection id="HA19EA68BB5C846268FC51BDC1E55A451"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered application may not be downloaded or used on a Federal Government device, unless the head of an agency determines that such use is for ensuring appropriate and controlled access to fulfill a research or intelligence function required by law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H80396F0FCCE84DD682812275E8801DB0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Excepted use of covered applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the head of each agency shall issue guidance with respect to an exception made under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H1D67DFD64BD04F18B0C5ABA2EACDD129" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that ensures safeguards for cybersecurity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15345F088C2C4DC69836B969B9AF4C66" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that includes requirements for the development and documentation of risk mitigation actions for such exception.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H909A66A900DF45CF853DBC81D7A9D42E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered Application List</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and every 180 days thereafter, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of National Intelligence, shall issue guidance on how the list of covered applications will be created and periodically updated.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8FF8D3796D0543EE9CE25654D5627295" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadline for removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall ensure that a covered application is removed from a Federal device within 60 days after the date on which the application is identified as a covered application pursuant to subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB3DD40EAF12C42E3831D041FB345B880"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H17677AB76BB648B29E50D3BC15E93ADE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H94A1237DCBC543AE9CDD890F360BBB78" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any Executive department, military department, Government corporation, Government controlled corporation, or other establishment in the executive branch of the Federal Government (including the Executive Office of the President), or any independent regulatory agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B153C18E43D4A54A08FC13055CEE840" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include the governments of the District of Columbia and of the territories and possessions of the United States, and their various subdivisions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1482BF9157F24C589E7658D9F9F19B0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered application</header><text>The term <term>covered application</term> includes an application that is—</text><subparagraph id="H8D1FEAFAFEBC4114A12A34E246059394"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developed, owned, or controlled by—</text><clause id="H3E935D7BCA8A4A34811275F7B28B8D76"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an entity headquartered in the People’s Republic of China;</text></clause><clause id="H631CCCFD42C94FC792876439B8E95C99"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity in which the government of the People’s Republic of China, the Chinese Communist Party, or a person acting on their behalf, holds a controlling interest; or</text></clause><clause id="HC00A06EFD5874C47A9792F15ADCF4384"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a parent, subsidiary, or affiliate of such an entity; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53C780BAA11A4865B4A09A42D5267EAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determined by the Secretary of Defense to pose an undue risk to the national security of the United States due to ownership, control, or influence by the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H975C77428FAB4B9DA5630CD009FF5330" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cybersecurity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cybersecurity</term> means the prevention of damage to, unauthorized use of, exploitation of, and, if needed, the restoration of electronic information and communications systems, and the information the systems contain, in order to strengthen the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the systems.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

