<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26155-XPR-55-L2M"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3740 IS: Save the Kurds Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3740</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260129">January 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To impose sanctions and other measures with respect to the Government of Syria, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb04d4877b51442ca9d6d8ed5d9becbde"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Save the Kurds Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9c895e6b1eb4966a129b6a532006c9c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idcb6adc440a1d4954a3ef98b34be11867">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id03ef7cdb19e64363b46ff38a0de4c456">Sec. 3. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id6308f516465d43e7bdbef58c6b139899">TITLE I—Redesignation of Hay’at Tahrir al-Sham as a foreign terrorist organization</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id77f93b311eb84b2db301e64f721c5da5">Sec. 101. Redesignation of Hay’at Tahrir al-Sham as a foreign terrorist organization.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idce8f0869ea2c4c7d85c5368f5f70aab8">TITLE II—Congressional review of termination of state sponsor of terrorism designation of Syria</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6d89764d54b9463eab18f4f4e8c330d6">Sec. 201. Authority to terminate state sponsor of terrorism designation of Syria; congressional review.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idc27554e54f5245c1b54d728ea18f1668">TITLE III—Sanctions and other measures</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idcc8037444d9f4da6b2d4864e627fd344">Sec. 301. Imposition of sanctions with respect to certain persons affiliated with or supporting the Government of Syria.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida73a0f3f475b4ab9a6640fc9352e38c9">Sec. 302. Imposition of sanctions with respect to Syrian financial institutions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="iddd624b98d1d14472b8d371c18eb75d89">Sec. 303. Reimposition of sanctions under repealed Executive orders.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id3f0d42a348e64b3cad5a4d765927d12d">Sec. 304. Imposition of sanctions with respect to other entities owned or controlled by the Government of Syria.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id57d2e9117a9c40b6a2bf2c9760642f70">Sec. 305. Prohibition on transfers of funds involving Syria.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0df67414592348cb85fc3379d11822ff">Sec. 306. Prohibition on listing or trading of Syrian entities on United States securities exchanges.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6e0cba46cd0441cebf038d86327df8be">Sec. 307. Prohibition on investments by United States persons in Syria.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc58f3a23d7ec4adf94783cd67deb022c">Sec. 308. Imposition of sanctions on energy exports to Syria.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id668e06197d144a71a3e54f219dc5a8f6">Sec. 309. Prohibition on purchases of sovereign debt of Syria by United States persons.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idbc2985b2247a45f38751fc46371279ef">Sec. 310. Prohibition on provision of services to sanctioned financial institutions by international financial messaging systems.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="ide051860ecb9f4431988cc9d32bcdf630">TITLE IV—General provisions</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ided1eac4967e24891bf75a5581942c2c6">Sec. 401. Exceptions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide004c974796b4f22a4c09208939fcc47">Sec. 402. Implementation; penalties; regulatory authorities.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idfc4cab68ddaa447b8e95ca87ed01bad9">Sec. 403. Exception relating to importation of goods.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id9e51404ddb074eeab7841f6b98aff79a">Sec. 404. Suspension and reinstatement of provisions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id746cea7a1ef24ea98ec2d4625d0f3e0a">Sec. 405. Rule of construction.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id0f44fff6b730473fadbcd5a81e41b488">Sec. 406. Prohibition on construction of provisions of this Act as an authorization for use of military force.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id3d1d3a782a3847f5a33f5166bec49b2c">Sec. 407. Sunset.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="idcb6adc440a1d4954a3ef98b34be11867"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idebe6911a88d14dd0b1eb1834aab40fe7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admission; admitted; alien; etc</header><text>The terms <quote>admission</quote>, <quote>admitted</quote>, <quote>alien</quote>, and <quote>lawfully admitted for permanent residence</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1656fadb7504b90889ffc3fb6d7318a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9dd7cc27bd524320b017d954508cc2f9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6886524231ec47f3bc2ab4f05c9a3ca1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id54b2b1bcddaa417f807e9c1081943b07"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id251a2718fc6e43c79372722d5c4cb8ad"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5a99f7004d74efaa37c2ae1761a282a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State sponsor of terrorism</header><text>The term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism for purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="id99cba7f3447e40e7840ae0dc634cf0dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1754(c)(1)(A)(i) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae2b7b60425048d7bc1dd702308e0b7b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide58876d6aee54f87b2fb7ed7ff47ae90"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 40(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780(d)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id729dda2a8d564174b1027a0dff36f6b7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id43bc9b1f7012420cacb4b174bc4ad52e"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id980e7873785448dcba643de86687be00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5919a67bfb534aefb77a0a88a394763e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States (including any foreign branch of such an entity); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida89fd46412884d14a32a7aa1ba67d388"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id03ef7cdb19e64363b46ff38a0de4c456"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id666b645cd0c4404a8ca292e49c6294a5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Kurdish-led Syrian Democratic Forces made significant contributions to the elimination of the ISIS <quote>caliphate</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id44cbce0221a94496a030e341566744a5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Kurdish-led Syrian Democratic Forces, with assistance from the United States-led coalition, have detained thousands of ISIS fighters and their families, ensuring the safety of the United States and the region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e0c1eda66da4299aca46a3b800dd383"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Kurdish-led Syrian Democratic Forces continue to be a reliable and critical partner in preventing the resurgence of ISIS; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf81ba3b1cb244ec7a0c236906581b6c4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any behavior by the Government of Syria or regional actors that undermines the role of the Kurdish-led Syrian Democratic Forces in countering ISIS and protecting United States security interests is inconsistent with the national security objectives of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><title id="id6308f516465d43e7bdbef58c6b139899"><enum>I</enum><header>Redesignation of Hay’at Tahrir al-Sham as a foreign terrorist organization</header><section id="id77f93b311eb84b2db301e64f721c5da5"><enum>101.</enum><header>Redesignation of Hay’at Tahrir al-Sham as a foreign terrorist organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Upon the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall designate al-Nusrah Front, also known as Hay’at Tahrir al-Sham, as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></section></title><title id="idce8f0869ea2c4c7d85c5368f5f70aab8" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Congressional review of termination of state sponsor of terrorism designation of Syria</header><section id="id6d89764d54b9463eab18f4f4e8c330d6"><enum>201.</enum><header>Authority to terminate state sponsor of terrorism designation of Syria; congressional review</header><subsection id="id7c56f1e4400b4c2689ab72b93ce8304e"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Authority To terminate state sponsor of terrorism designation</header> <text>Subject to subsection (b), the President may terminate the designation of Syria as a state sponsor of terrorism if the President submits to Congress a report explaining why the termination is in the national security interests of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id7b3b4e8aa11e405cb9d3b8bf6a615da4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period for review by Congress</header><paragraph id="ide6022ae7628c45bea1b42680d4ec0f0a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the period of 90 calendar days beginning on the date on which the President submits a report under subsection (a) with respect to termination of the designation of Syria as a state sponsor of terrorism, the termination shall not take effect. If, after the end of that period, a joint resolution of disapproval with respect to the termination of the designation has not been enacted into law under subsection (c), the termination may take effect.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb32994850d27431097543778becb0a77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration by Congress</header><text>During the period described in paragraph (1), the appropriate congressional committees should, as appropriate, hold hearings and briefings and otherwise obtain information in order to fully review the report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01ebf687cd4547b8a4195c1382334539"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The period for congressional review under paragraph (1) of a report required to be submitted under subsection (a) shall be 120 calendar days if the report is submitted on or after July 10 and on or before September 7 in any calendar year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0dc5ba66763f4e8993c65eac364ccd11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header><paragraph id="idb216ebec906d4092aa14412457db8bcd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves of the termination, under section 201 of the <short-title>Save the Kurds Act</short-title>, of the designation of Syria as a state sponsor of terrorism, with respect to which the President submitted a report on ___.</quote>, with the blank space being filled with the appropriate date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id09f3d1612ff849d8b52fdf5abea7f2fb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text>During the period of 90 calendar days provided for under subsection (b)(1), including any additional period as applicable under the exception provided in subsection (b)(3), a joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced—</text><subparagraph id="id23599ce5d8ae420c8f722919df8ad692"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the House of Representatives, by the majority leader or the minority leader; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1932cfc5d74b4e258df7593e5ef5d0a5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the Senate, by the majority leader (or a designee of the majority leader) or the minority leader (or a designee of the minority leader).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id13c988d545724c9daffa7d7bd40e1393"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration in House of Representatives</header><subparagraph id="idf7e99eedddfa4c9597ad40970c87330a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>Any committee of the House of Representatives to which a joint resolution of disapproval is referred shall report it to the House of Representatives without amendment not later than 10 calendar days after the date of referral. If a committee fails to report the joint resolution within that period, the committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be referred to the appropriate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide2dd931254624a6eb0139b41e75481ee"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>After each committee authorized to consider a joint resolution of disapproval reports it to the House of Representatives or has been discharged from its consideration, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution of disapproval in the House of Representatives. All points of order against the motion are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa06fe9875e24eb2a52602147cec9cab"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The joint resolution of disapproval shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution of disapproval and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution of disapproval to its passage without intervening motion except 2 hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution of disapproval shall not be in order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c30c8dbda594540948ca90c61a07fa3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration in the Senate</header><subparagraph id="id0e385bb22787405d886a1d8ec26c65f5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the committee of the Senate to which a joint resolution of disapproval has been referred has not reported the joint resolution within 10 calendar days after the date of referral of the joint resolution, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbc24b2b218a348b9b61d15849d160167"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after the committee of the Senate to which a joint resolution of disapproval has been referred reports the joint resolution to the Senate or has been discharged from consideration of such a joint resolution to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) are waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. Approval by the Senate of a motion to proceed to a joint resolution of disapproval shall require the affirmative vote of three-fifths of Members of the Senate, duly chosen and sworn.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida6946c20dc22450c9ac40b77f28938dc"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>Consideration in the Senate of a joint resolution of disapproval and of all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith shall not exceed a total of 10 hours, which shall be divided equally between the majority and minority leaders or their designees. Any debatable motion or appeal is debatable for not to exceed 1 hour, to be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the motion or appeal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a0cfd5168db42e884e5674ef91698b5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No amendments or motions</header><text>An amendment to a joint resolution of disapproval, a motion to postpone, a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the joint resolution is not in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide7358d86ee644d418160681c0967bdc5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Vote on joint resolution</header><text>If the Senate has voted to proceed to a joint resolution of disapproval, the vote on approval of the joint resolution shall occur immediately following the conclusion of consideration of the joint resolution, and a single quorum call if requested. Approval by the Senate of a joint resolution of disapproval shall require the affirmative vote of three-fifths of Members of the Senate, duly chosen and sworn.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ea6f52b57344978bf3e010bf1c16490"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Consideration of veto messages</header><text>Consideration in the Senate of any veto message with respect to a joint resolution of disapproval, including all debatable motions and appeals in connection with the joint resolution, shall be limited to 10 hours, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idccd273710aa246c2aa477f82d2dc49e7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination with action by other House</header><subparagraph id="id0b03d8496a5b40febb7d8166f74f6d82"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Receipt of resolution from other House</header><text>If, before the passage by one House of a joint resolution of disapproval of that House, that House receives from the other House a joint resolution of disapproval, then the following procedures shall apply:</text><clause id="id291bd260d2364e0f92b0e69ea4523f7f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The joint resolution of the other House shall not be referred to a committee.</text></clause><clause id="id17b665d0af4040bab9ee7cca35550666"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>With respect to a joint resolution of the House receiving the resolution—</text><subclause id="id9bb994da55d4421f87738b1059374471"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the procedure in that House shall be the same as if no joint resolution had been received from the other House; but</text></subclause><subclause id="id481e311179a247bf9532015977ef92ad"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the vote on passage shall be on the joint resolution of the other House.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7cae9bbe2f5e47eb80efdb51af829b42"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of joint resolution of other House if no companion measure</header><text>If one House fails to introduce or consider a joint resolution of disapproval under this section, the joint resolution of the other House shall be entitled to expedited floor procedures under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideceee084576d43da8ce9094973d1b801"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of companion measures in Senate</header><text>If, following passage of a joint resolution of disapproval in the Senate, the Senate then receives a joint resolution of disapproval from the House of Representatives, the joint resolution from the House shall not be debatable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3919ae7bd69c4453b8231f92524f3667"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Rules of the House of Representatives and Senate</header> <text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text>
            <subparagraph id="id89cc9b8fbfa94042aa4604dfd3774837">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="ideb3beb6b0a854e3587a34cf37894e280">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text>
            </subparagraph>
 </paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="idc27554e54f5245c1b54d728ea18f1668" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Sanctions and other measures</header><section id="idcc8037444d9f4da6b2d4864e627fd344"><enum>301.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to certain persons affiliated with or supporting the Government of Syria</header><subsection id="id579234a48146496ba58382ff77110c94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose sanctions in subsection (c) with respect to the following:</text><paragraph id="idaf48bcd7c93d43a0b77b33a9fb2dd3b9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The following officials of the Government of Syria:</text><subparagraph id="idb5dfcc1c67774f96b147c65d503613e8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The President of Syria.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d29fbf117ac4425a9a42f950a420191"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Minister of Defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1046e20edc554fe1a8bb2bbf74337ead"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Minister of Economy and Industry.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide092485569fb49ff8edc1dbafc4a0ab7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Minister of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idabc34ca8cf8842168cba38905119a7a4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Minister of Administrative Development.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62acbd62579b4b63b9cf8ee31e060b62"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Minister of Communications and Information Technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id062b81c9626544b986ae6c97f54f3443"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Minister of Culture.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id111dd10062b64229b4b33ac8a8f90908"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Minister of Education.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a961447c9024770845d1cfda2f60f17"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Minister of Emergency and Disaster Management.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1f08d7342e64702b6e3fd638a8e0893"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The Minister of Energy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca0dcc3e23284505848054eacc882802"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The Minister of Finance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85e61be49f324225bf89af2f37c9603b"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The Minister of Foreign Affairs and Expatriates.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c7cc2e4df134c248d5a35aea3df92b6"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The Minister of Health.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76caa8de93534af4860eefa7abacaa38"><enum>(N)</enum><text>The Minister of Higher Education and Research.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41412880af50487bb4a59aae645252ee"><enum>(O)</enum><text>The Minister of Information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca9efb5b6f4d45adac9a686df37cb908"><enum>(P)</enum><text>The Minister of Interior.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca7127f76e1a4f0781894b2fba785994"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>The Minister of Justice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31b103f5c1ec452b9b4c48606ee74efa"><enum>(R)</enum><text>The Minister of Local Administration and Environment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id168161ab53874005b4a56f6c4578d5cd"><enum>(S)</enum><text>The Minister of Public Works and Housing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c51782954014ae4a943e2d51cc56ed6"><enum>(T)</enum><text>The Minister of Religious Endowments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26a1047f54674590bc9bd32256abc8be"><enum>(U)</enum><text>The Minister of Social Affairs and Labour.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80eba3e1d52a4c03bc355314c27c4594"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The Minister of Tourism.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb95138807744f9e8250d464af328ded"><enum>(W)</enum><text>The Minister of Transport.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3c1f366ecc7c4e708a3ee6c47bc7e8ec"><enum>(X)</enum><text>The Minister of Youth and Sports.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3585febe966146c78870c5b21cd815a9"><enum>(Y)</enum><text>The Chief of the General Staff of the Army and Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55f1aada17a14932bf6627c1afa220a0"><enum>(Z)</enum><text>The Governor the Central Bank of Syria.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a8f395fe20b4965a040022d65f2c93d"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>The Board of the Syrian Sovereign Fund.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide54fa728c29d4ffc8207f2dc87f54c46"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>The Director General of the Syrian Development Fund.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaed0fc36c83c49189d1a552cb8e43f65"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>The Director General of the Syrian Investment Authority.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8779aba09fd2461bb6d0cbbbc8137801"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>The Head of the Syrian Central Financial Control Body.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide2b8960b56b54777a91b8d5c223aeccf"><enum>(EE)</enum><text>The Head of the Syrian Petroleum Company.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14c422a039164b438af9ac4cfdf45593"><enum>(FF)</enum><text>The Head of the General Authority for Borders and Customs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76492d431e8041e88d69cf69b98439ef"><enum>(GG)</enum><text>Any other senior official of the Government of Syria, as determined by the President.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f3222e8762e496aa52a6ece051ee92a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any foreign person that is responsible for or complicit in, or has directly or indirectly engaged in, for or on behalf of, or for the benefit of, directly or indirectly, the Government of Syria—</text><subparagraph id="idb74c351b48084cf2806f55d55cbf005b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transnational crime, corruption, bribery, extortion, or money laundering;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9df143677ac045afa28af17da78fb1fd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assassination, murder, or other unlawful killing of, or infliction of other bodily harm or other crimes against humanity against, a United States person or a citizen or national of an ally or partner of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id760dc8d459d34b228ae292339f7ef5f4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>activities that undermine the peace, security, political stability, or territorial integrity of the United States or an ally or partner of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id570e6f7c97d84a888cb17c10e8afe055"><enum>(D)</enum><text>deceptive or structured transactions or dealings that circumvent the application of any sanctions imposed by the United States, including through the use of digital currencies or assets or the use of physical assets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4974a1d8da08438c8e05ca3e365029c9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any foreign person the President determines knowingly, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text><subparagraph id="id2a4c006ff01d4e57b657f099cc0a4c9b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides financial, material, or technological support to, or engages in a transaction with—</text><clause id="id9420a2ab1ddb4ec9bdde68adddf46208"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Government of Syria (including any entity owned or controlled by the Government of Syria) or a senior political figure of the Government of Syria;</text></clause><clause id="id2314128b509846ec9ca7c63de81934d5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Armed Forces of Syria or a foreign person that is a military contractor, mercenary, or a paramilitary force knowingly operating in a military capacity inside Syria, or any other armed entity or foreign person operating, for or on behalf of the Government of Syria; or</text></clause><clause id="id802d4a19bda448f1af26ea9cf53bbe0f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a foreign person subject to sanctions pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to Syria or any other provision of law that imposes sanctions with respect to Syria;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd3101bf066e94849b05ba3df978826e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sells or provides goods, services, technology, information, or other support that facilitates the maintenance or expansion of the Government of Syria’s domestic production of any energy product, including natural gas, petroleum, and petroleum products;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68fc97e3f4a5435b94c145590945d247"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sells or provides aircraft or spare aircraft parts that are used for military purposes in Syria for or on behalf of the Government of Syria to any foreign person operating in an area directly or indirectly controlled by the Government of Syria or foreign forces associated with the Government of Syria;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53255669dbbd4ea59c95bcea1c067444"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides goods or services associated with the operation of aircraft that are used for military purposes in Syria for or on behalf of the Government of Syria to any foreign person operating in an area described in subparagraph (C);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7d59eb39dda410b985ca0538f03a1b2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>directly or indirectly, provides construction or engineering services to the Government of Syria;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd388d2c38d7f42429a41ad5549d77895"><enum>(F)</enum><text>is involved in committing serious abuses of internationally recognized human rights against citizens of Syria, including forcible transfers, enforced disappearances, unjust detainment, forced deportation of children, or torture; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc56ed097294d4ed9876a9ab119ffa5ec"><enum>(G)</enum><text>is a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of, or principal shareholder with a controlling or majority interest in, an entity that is operating in the defense industrial base or energy or transportation sectors of the economy of Syria in support of the Armed Forces of Syria.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id409b781c14a648e78008bf370c4da7b9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that, in implementing this section, the President should consider financial support under subsection (a)(3)(A) to include the provision of loans, credits, or export credits.</text></subsection><subsection id="id37b7cdc986e142728a4a09d5560e0df1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><paragraph id="id6a6945e827d34409a7daac378bbf77a4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions to be imposed with respect to a foreign person described in subsection (a) are the following:</text><subparagraph id="id4ac729b984d840009afab65108b3c8f3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id157231becf2543dca112c029b80961c4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><clause id="id6c3798409a0a469d9cc90ea542917cb2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a) is—</text><subclause id="id32de66aee9b1498db8e47a0ab08d6092"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="id8d23a49601ac4a0898a2825cef9e5163"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id153237639fc14b42a0f9258452092da8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3920686b2e95461693d5d4e3ce044475"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subclause id="idc6a6bf13c06842778917cc78d35e3a89"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien described in subsection is subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></subclause><subclause id="idb0b7366235cb4e0db667f0bc4124746c"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under subclause (I) shall—</text><item id="id0508e9f4e05e4319ae043c8c7e1db99e"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></item><item id="id1d8d6fb3372042c982bb80d71b506d4c"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ida73a0f3f475b4ab9a6640fc9352e38c9"><enum>302.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to Syrian financial institutions</header><subsection id="id995a40d32341468b87d5a30ddfee385a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><paragraph id="idbba4533dbb904483a099774bd2c97944"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon the enactment of this Act, the President shall—</text><subparagraph id="id955b7a2e342f47a0808ae37dcea79432"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impose all of the sanctions described in subsection (d) with respect to—</text><clause id="idd838519fa5174721b9fb481a9c89010c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Central Bank of Syria;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3135ef2e077047a1838b38707e0a61db"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any financial institution organized under the laws of Syria and owned in whole or in part by the Government of Syria;</text></clause><clause id="idb296096b6a8d4f798b787fa2e8c70997"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any subsidiary of, or successor entity to, the Central Bank of Syria or any financial institution described in clause (ii); and</text></clause><clause id="idb83567d4b0a44ac09c959cb512932985"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>except as provided by subsection (c), any foreign financial institution that engages in transactions with the Central Bank of Syria or any financial institution described in clause (ii) or (iii); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id467efb1434f348749b1e28f311af2368"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impose the sanctions described in subsection (e) with respect to any leaders, officials, senior executive officers, or members of the board of directors of, or any principal shareholders with a controlling or majority interest in, the Central Bank of Syria or any financial institution described in clause (ii), (iii), or (iv).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id31e6dc7118ad48c8838df4f4b55eb46a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Not later than 210 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall—</text><subparagraph id="idecd6949b3eb04bcea56cbb22c25fdcbe"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review any persons that may be described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id783654f489ae4d77ba535739beb41ffe"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if sanctions have not been imposed under this subsection with respect to any person the President determines is described in paragraph (1), impose such sanctions with respect to that person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8533064f90b04eb4b03245ce1cea5bf2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on transactions by United States persons</header><text>Effective on the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall prohibit any United States person from engaging in any transaction with the Central Bank of Syria or any financial institution described in clause (ii), (iii), or (iv) of subsection (a)(1)(A).</text></subsection><subsection id="id16dbc9ca819245b9bb6c046883735d9c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception for certain financial institutions</header><text>The President is not required to impose sanctions under subsection (a)(1)(A) with respect to a foreign financial institution described in clause (iv) of that subsection if the Secretary of the Treasury determines that imposing such sanctions is not consistent with the economic or foreign policy interests of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="ideb79ad134eef41c6bda40e3f6514495e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sanctions applicable to financial institutions</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection to be imposed with respect to a financial institution described in subsection (a) are the following:</text><paragraph id="id85dc4cd105c54d4492324a77c799195e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the financial institution if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8606441aefd4816818d5e50336dec33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restrictions on correspondent and payable-through accounts</header><text>The President shall prohibit the opening, and prohibit or impose strict conditions on the maintaining, in the United States, of a correspondent account or payable-through account by the financial institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id998a6016d9d24338b1cac2d65ce9ab4a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sanctions applicable to individuals</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection to be imposed with respect to an individual described in subsection (a) are the following:</text><paragraph id="id7fa7fa2aa7704ea29236c2808b09716f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the individual if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c46d4ac7eef45ba8ba62585f8489739"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="id9518ee96297949bd8929ef1742e05648"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a) shall be—</text><clause id="ida01137d4d5254018afdf6e3ea5a803f9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="id5b7e7cb905a5405592703c5496689e7f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="id550f6bd19dfb482aa0b1a3407f511045"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id964b301f64cc45a59406fb89bd6eb0fb"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="id719f472319f6498b9788b173ba10ce1a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of an alien described in subsection (a) shall be revoked, regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></clause><clause id="id4ec8be23ce374edd84daec3a84bb2756"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="ide553f7c87b42499387af4e7f46e4e557"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ide3ff36e391f14727aca75d16e658c22a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the alien.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd624b98d1d14472b8d371c18eb75d89"><enum>303.</enum><header>Reimposition of sanctions under repealed Executive orders</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d6b1a965b364e3bb7077cb7616fba95"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>On and after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id597c9350ae5e4020a6d4d4e7b1d199d5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sanctions and other measures provided for under each Executive order specified in subsection (b) shall apply; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id806162d427dc4af4a96f29458c485001"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sanctions and other measures imposed with respect to a person under any such Executive order on June 30, 2025, shall be reinstated.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81b8c364e36d4b2cbfe8a766c317f092"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Executive orders specified</header><text>The Executive orders specified in this subsection are the following, as in effect on June 30, 2025:</text><paragraph id="id3ed2a7f80daf492084c0ce1df05a1f3c" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Executive Order 13338 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of certain persons and prohibiting the export of certain goods to Syria).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id204cadb93a4d4df19bfac92b3660cee0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Executive Order 13399 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of additional persons in connection with the national emergency with respect to Syria).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2b3b18f9ef64ba7bf600ef03d81ec0f" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Executive Order 13460 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of additional persons in connection with the national emergency with respect to Syria).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id18dd3601f16e4ef7baeabee0ed83eca1" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Executive Order 13582 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property of the Government of Syria and prohibiting certain transactions with respect to Syria).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3f0d42a348e64b3cad5a4d765927d12d"><enum>304.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to other entities owned or controlled by the Government of Syria</header><subsection id="id8fab98aad1824287ac4bfd888ded19cb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="iddc2cda55a2f844e5b68b039bfab12df5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review any entity—</text><subparagraph id="id81bdd76a31c5466e80d2152c4badc52a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which the Government of Syria may have a controlling or majority ownership interest; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd3b9350c64ec44e88ddf104f28f49cb7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that may otherwise be affiliated with the Government of Syria; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id773bcff8512a4afc93ef9224fd3cc618"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to an entity if the President determines that—</text><subparagraph id="id5245616789c24452827fe8c84d3abeda"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Government of Syria has a controlling or majority ownership interest in the entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e155533006e46d7b12214a51cb39e06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the entity is otherwise affiliated with the Government of Syria.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id21e2b95c4f3746ad84ed87a0ecf7cd5b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of an entity described in subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subsection></section><section id="id57d2e9117a9c40b6a2bf2c9760642f70"><enum>305.</enum><header>Prohibition on transfers of funds involving Syria</header><subsection id="id0cdd3a4d2fcc4180982878b6af327617"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by subsection (b), on and after the date of the enactment of this Act, a depository institution (as defined in section 19(b)(1)(A) of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/461">12 U.S.C. 461(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>)) or a broker or dealer in securities registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.</external-xref>) may not process transfers of funds—</text><paragraph id="idec8fbe08bc0940589fc47e97ab846f04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to or from the Government of Syria, including any entity owned by the Government of Syria; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idafb593d662d642a49726f98397d3b8eb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for the direct or indirect benefit of officials of the Government of Syria.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb45005e8f7f54c109c0f7eaf5c6ead98"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A depository institution, broker, or dealer described in subsection (a) may process a transfer described in that subsection if the transfer arises from, and is ordinarily incident and necessary to give effect to, an underlying transaction that is authorized by a specific or general license.</text></subsection></section><section id="id0df67414592348cb85fc3379d11822ff"><enum>306.</enum><header>Prohibition on listing or trading of Syrian entities on United States securities exchanges</header><subsection id="id8ad0748566be429a9b994cfa2c9131dd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall prohibit the securities of an issuer described in subsection (b) from being traded on a national securities exchange.</text></subsection><subsection id="id28ff81aedcf2439088838b522d41e221"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issuers</header><text>An issuer described in this subsection is an issuer that is—</text><paragraph id="idbe902e25c42f4e7b924d7941953db7c9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an official of or individual affiliated with the Government of Syria; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03e1db181ec5434193531da70f5a47aa"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an entity—</text><subparagraph id="id3c67f8864d444148aac43b9e8ad3bb61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which the Government of Syria has a controlling or majority ownership interest; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6199e39954764da5b71363a607b6116b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is otherwise affiliated with the Government of Syria.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id99c4307fc81644619126adc8ecf208ac"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id81c7d84f7f74435fac609485d329c4c3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Issuer; security</header><text>The terms <term>issuer</term> and <term>security</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8eeffc85ade34f38a81a37ef15359e06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National securities exchange</header><text>The term <term>national securities exchange</term> means an exchange registered as a national securities exchange in accordance with section 6 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78f">15 U.S.C. 78f</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6e0cba46cd0441cebf038d86327df8be"><enum>307.</enum><header>Prohibition on investments by United States persons in Syria</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On and after the date of the enactment of this Act, the following are prohibited:</text><paragraph id="idac1c0a8457934f7983cab7319fe9c911"><enum>(1)</enum><text>New investment in Syria by a United States person, wherever located.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfd401843e8d740c4ae7c8a887329c188"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The exportation, reexportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States, or by a United States person, wherever located, of any category of services identified by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, to any person located in Syria.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a939d0a02b142e881d870de4bd4e705"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any approval, financing, facilitation, or guarantee by a United States person, wherever located, of a transaction by a foreign person if the transaction by that foreign person would be prohibited by this section if performed by a United States person or within the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc58f3a23d7ec4adf94783cd67deb022c"><enum>308.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions on energy exports to Syria</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall impose the sanctions described in section 301(c) with respect to any foreign person that the President determines knowingly sells, supplies, transfers, markets, or otherwise provides goods, services, technology, or other support that facilitates the maintenance or expansion of the production of oil, natural gas, liquefied natural gas, petroleum, petroleum products, petrochemical products, coal, or coal products for use by any person subject to sanctions under section 301.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id668e06197d144a71a3e54f219dc5a8f6"><enum>309.</enum><header>Prohibition on purchases of sovereign debt of Syria by United States persons</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On and after the date of the enactment of this Act, the purchase of sovereign debt of the Government of Syria by any United States person (including a United States financial institution) is prohibited.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc2985b2247a45f38751fc46371279ef"><enum>310.</enum><header>Prohibition on provision of services to sanctioned financial institutions by international financial messaging systems</header><subsection id="id8687020bdf8d40b58a28c4a4e005cb20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="id4bda20db0a6b43c3baeea5e1426c2c3b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review any person that may be described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19ddb935a6af4c7090f5e4d47fdf45aa"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose sanctions pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to any person the President determines is described in that subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id08df2d151a6c45fe8056c36057313672"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>A person described in this subsection is—</text><paragraph id="id753cf138402c4f55a048155d769c7f54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any entity that—</text><subparagraph id="id2bbf03fd975f497ca2946a828c93f06d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operates with the intent to predominantly engage in the business of providing global financial messaging services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida20dc1aa581b4d50975d0d4bad3144b2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, as knowingly being used to circumvent any sanctions imposed under any provision of this Act; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9eaabf9d1cb049d7874725f997519164"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of, or principal shareholder with a controlling or majority interest in, any entity described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide22b8fca327e48d4baab4b71093c3d16"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The President may waive the imposition of sanctions under subsection (a) with respect to an entity predominantly engaged in the business of providing global financial messaging services for, directly providing such services to, or enabling or facilitating direct or indirect access to such services for, any financial institution subject to sanctions under any other provision of this Act if the entity—</text><paragraph id="idbb9a2fac2ab34f5ea38ff09af4ed4c7f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is subject to a sanctions regime under its governing foreign law that requires it to eliminate the knowing provision of such services to, and the knowing enabling and facilitation of direct or indirect access to such services for, foreign financial institutions identified under such governing foreign law for purposes of that sanctions regime if the President determines that the sanctions regime under governing foreign law is not inconsistent with the economic or foreign policy interests of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8566100a972340c7b93ac11e83ec6c05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has, pursuant to that sanctions regime, terminated the knowing provision of such services to, and the knowing enabling and facilitation of direct or indirect access to such services for, foreign financial institutions identified under such governing foreign law for purposes of that sanctions regime; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id792cf6f3ea01483090eda252d1516d78"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides significant financial messaging services to United States financial institutions, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id75fdfd2e2bd6455d978d88c52e2a5c54"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the President pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></title><title id="ide051860ecb9f4431988cc9d32bcdf630" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>General provisions</header><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided1eac4967e24891bf75a5581942c2c6"><enum>401.</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subsection id="id0d12e41d102d4e0587115bb0d58b5761"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Intelligence activities</header><text>This Act shall not apply with respect to any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) and any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc87d90086d4a4fb3a3c2d137844547f8" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Admission for international and law enforcement purposes</header><text>Sanctions under this Act shall not apply with respect to the admission or parole of an alien into the United States if admitting or paroling the alien is necessary—</text><paragraph id="ide39ce8e72a91435693dcb896ab7ac16d" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8f6d19729a445a986b320849747c38e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to carry out or assist law enforcement activity in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id14187784f6a84e4da16f9b96d1d4e5ce"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception for humanitarian assistance</header><paragraph id="id1ad08b25e2e44de38706b5b8bb564ba5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Sanctions and other measures under this Act shall not apply to—</text><subparagraph id="idea39bb68c5f94c75bb75c9df7f7d18fc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the conduct or facilitation of a transaction for the provision of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, medical devices, humanitarian assistance, or for humanitarian purposes; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72020a113fa3435085134d49ad8b22d5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transactions that are necessary for, or related to, the activities described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a292aac9e4f4f88b4951f1e7b4f48fd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id771f8352b1574b09a4375821e1be3dc9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Agricultural commodity</header><text>The term <term>agricultural commodity</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5602">7 U.S.C. 5602</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b9c73d234a245f1bf2c19964995e57d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Medical device</header><text>The term <term>medical device</term> has the meaning given the term <term>device</term> in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc90e99f293f34ba196d6585397c51a41"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Medicine</header><text>The term <term>medicine</term> has the meaning given the term <term>drug</term> in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida9b61a6e9da64022bdefdb60b9158233"><enum>(d)</enum><header>General licenses</header><paragraph id="id3b98af7f96fe4c318f92f9008efc3867"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This Act shall not apply with respect to a United States person that is operating under the terms of a general license issued by the Department of the Treasury before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id71c3f831e25f476b8f8cfd675b06ef7e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the terms of a general license described in paragraph (1), the authority of United States persons to continue to operate under such a license, or the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to extend or issue new general licenses.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide004c974796b4f22a4c09208939fcc47"><enum>402.</enum><header>Implementation; penalties; regulatory authorities</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf027a27f40246a5b4993233f0cba19b"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementation authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) for purposes of carrying out this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb9ad0d4e2c8b43b28dc58d3593125206" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this Act or regulations prescribed to carry out this Act to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc7238652f7c4bd798803c0bb9bb54b6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc4cab68ddaa447b8e95ca87ed01bad9"><enum>403.</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><subsection id="idaeb7e8d6dc86444bb0d4196dac15334e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions under this Act shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subsection><subsection id="id94e01a7ea4804f30a7c00413437d4f62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></subsection></section><section id="id9e51404ddb074eeab7841f6b98aff79a"><enum>404.</enum><header>Suspension and reinstatement of provisions</header><subsection id="id8587dfa68c494ada95d11d2324ec8b02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Suspension</header><text>The President may suspend, in whole or in part, any provision of this Act if the President certifies to Congress in writing that the Government of Syria has ceased all attacks on the Kurdish-led Syrian Democratic Forces and their partners.</text></subsection><subsection id="idabb9a1fd8c8646a6975d27a29f378e17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reimposition</header><text>If, after the suspension of any provision of this Act under subsection (a), the Government of Syria, or any other entity or foreign person acting on behalf of the Government of Syria, attacks the Kurdish-led Syrian Democratic Forces or their partners, the President shall immediately resume application of the provision and continue the application of any provision not so suspended.</text></subsection></section><section id="id746cea7a1ef24ea98ec2d4625d0f3e0a"><enum>405.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except for section 403 with respect to the importation of goods, nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the President pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other provision of law.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f44fff6b730473fadbcd5a81e41b488"><enum>406.</enum><header>Prohibition on construction of provisions of this Act as an authorization for use of military force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed as an authorization for use of military force.</text></section><section id="id3d1d3a782a3847f5a33f5166bec49b2c"><enum>407.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></title></legis-body></bill>

