<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFCCEA70695BC43948464BD2C36A12A79" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6852 IH: Advanced Wound Care and Regenerative Medicine Access and Reform Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6852</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to adjust payment for skin substitute products under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEBF8C405D77F46999638990BA122439E" style="OLC"><section id="HD05BED79083144E8BBD4131AC5A6AEF0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advanced Wound Care and Regenerative Medicine Access and Reform Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB134DABE0A6F4421AC58C9886372E77F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Payment reform for skin substitute products</header><subsection id="HEC081AC06C8947E5954BB8DD88A3125F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage of skin substitute products</header><text>Section 1861(s)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB18C7848144A4104BAFC1139150C0085"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (II), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB42B0C387A4A4C8382CADCB81B674CEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (JJ), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A73264291C341A0927FF955C5D0012B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (JJ) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="HCD7593F7F2AC4168BBCE077A329AFBA0" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H8A2559088E4C473A871AD5F1C203C3CD"><enum>(KK)</enum><text>skin substitute products (as defined in section 1847A(c)(6)(J)).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FA650E8F54940AD95AA02F63FBB5D2F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment</header><paragraph id="H7840F7101FB94456B4C71F5170D4EAC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment amount</header><text>Section 1847A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3a">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H4B7E571F992A4CC79569A09C2C7B4295"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><clause id="HFEA7B2B658AA4463868AFE1F0D34304A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HBEFF8BEE202E40AF8FB07A13E8C02DE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall apply to</quote> and inserting “shall apply—</text><quoted-block id="H1F390E3584CC4EF79E21DE097BB12011" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H255313B4DCD945C6ACA9D18209513D70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H7E59F7C9FAC248DB8B478FFB2F55F4E0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H4AE4393579614B888F8FD77E705041B4" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H56CA2155B07E4D5DB3E4BFC5F5BBCF88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to payment for skin substitute products (as defined in subsection (c)(6)(J)) that are furnished on or after January 1, 2026.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2DB382FC7CA45CF88FAA3A2F25D6A72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="H45F902CDE1B64707BC8057A4E8B93D02"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subclause id="HB9D7B409F9AC4FD89B92285C6BD3988F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the text preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or a skin substitute product</quote> after <quote>drug or biological</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="H21F92CFA42ED44EA8581EAA573E71CED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subclause><subclause id="H4405E0E6279F4AC8A2F3C417E4B29FAD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7CC4743576E347D7A7B95471EAFC21CB"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H409DD4B6FACD47B5AE8D0E0BCBDF121B" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H51508627C56E4300B418AF021F2933FD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of a skin substitute product (as defined in subsection (c)(6)(J)), the amount determined under paragraph (9).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="H2432475523614D31956F2839BFF444C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subclause id="HAAF306F32B0C45E380AC1CEA6570DB59"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or a skin substitute product</quote> after <quote>drug or biological</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H246078246A93475AA0366CA2737A4BED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>, and, with respect to a skin substitute product, a square centimeter</quote> after <quote>pertaining to liquids</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H142106242ED0461296626976D2BB1400"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HC270DA35240047EC934C0EAFC61A6896" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H03BD00FCF48D4466ACF7BF8153920F6F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Skin substitute products</header><subparagraph id="H34F4CB6063A044A8801A3822C84E5FC3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Payment amount</header><clause id="HED27519505194C968097A59FFA420DC8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial payment amount</header><text>For 2026, the amount determined under this paragraph for a skin substitute product is the volume-weighted average of the Medicare payment allowance limits for skin substitute products, as determined under subparagraph (B).</text></clause><clause id="HDDAE875C4B59480B8569A8098F66ABA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Annual update</header><text>For 2027 and each subsequent year, the amount determined under this paragraph for a skin substitute product for such year is equal to the amount determined under this paragraph for the previous year, adjusted by the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (United States city average) for the 12-month period ending with June of such previous year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H445F952799B8403FB4FA6D3FEBF98627"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Volume-weighted average payment limit</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the volume-weighted average of the Medicare payment allowance limits for skin substitute products is determined by—</text><clause id="H34AC553BBAB948E9A5CEE712AF60051B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>calculating, with respect to each billing and payment code listed in the April 2023 ASP Pricing File for each skin substitute product, an amount equal to the product of—</text><subclause id="H4C0E987AB95D4F08B5EF649D2C51E76E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the payment limit included in such file with respect to such code; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4559380d4394430c8d3f36ec7865afdd"><enum>(II)</enum><text> the number of units (as specified under paragraph (2))—</text><item id="HFEA69A4141CB4CA089ACC950C833CBD5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>billed with respect to such code for a date of service in 2023; and</text></item><item id="H9057538277F14A5596321161F09C47D5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>listed in the CMS Integrated Data Repository for Part B (Carrier &amp; DME) claims data;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H4C821D5B1FD048E19807342BD240A84A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>calculating the sum of all amounts determined under clause (i); and</text></clause><clause id="H96D3F4A3948948FC962725FC6FA58069"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>dividing the sum calculated under clause (ii) by the total number of units determined under clause (i)(II).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57621B10946C4E7FBE3205FBF13610C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 1833(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H3B005595830442E7BA28D31BAD8BA59C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (S)(i), by striking</text><quoted-block id="H562682497B3044E781816C1C487AFAA7" style="OLC"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">subject to subparagraph (EE)’’ and inserting ‘‘subject to subparagraphs (EE) and (II)’</text><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A25F0B299124D7BA8FD4BB90AD4A339"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (HH)</quote> and inserting <quote>(HH)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5BC7C9DF579477D94AF4EAFEEF49BC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and (II) with respect to skin substitute products under section 1861(s)(2)(KK), the amount paid shall be 80 percent of the lesser of the actual charge or the payment amount established under section 1847A(b)(9)</quote> before the semicolon at the end.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H770B7DE61FE14026B4B20E10B12D70C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Skin substitute product defined</header><text>Section 1847A(c)(6) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(c)(6)) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H3C2EFC33CB0E4768AAC31578A3437280" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HF5761C9C289F4D59998BAA5416E4EC7D"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Skin substitute products</header><text>The term <quote>skin substitute product</quote>—</text><clause id="H14E5814C38294830BDC0924D1E6E1487"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a cellular, tissue, biological or synthetic material that—</text><subclause id="HB89CD455492F4F0180CBE058813E72C6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is applied to a wound and intended to remain within the wound bed; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H973B97327C954E2E963906D6F22D338A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is marketed pursuant to section 510(k), 513(f)(2), or 515 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, or section 361 of the Public Health Service Act; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H78CCA4BD104C4D1880818EDDD7CCE9EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include a product that is intended to temporarily protect or cover the wound bed and be removed without resorption such as a dressing; and</text></clause><clause id="HE38758675E0748E4962C1DF1884070B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the term <quote>skin substitute product</quote> shall include any products reimbursed pursuant to skin substitutes codes by the Medicare program at any time prior to January 1, 2026.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDD7B6CAE492949DF924AD5553871DA96"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exclusion from reporting requirements</header><text>Section 1847A(f)(2)(A) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(f)(2)(A)) is amended by inserting <quote>(except that, beginning January 1, 2026, a drug or biological so described does not include a skin substitute product (as defined in subsection (c)(6)(J)))</quote> after <quote>products that are payable under this part as a drug or biological</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF09C668EEC3442489387F01D53BA6701"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consolidated billing and payment code</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2026, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a new billing and payment code for all skin substitute products (as defined in subparagraph (J) of section 1847A(c)(6) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(c)(6)), as added by subsection (b)).</text></subsection></section><section id="H82FAE57DD66049FB897FAF0E0A1BDED0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Equivalent reimbursement in outpatient sites of care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that reimbursement for skin substitutes products and outpatient applications of skin substitute products are equivalent to those payment amounts outlined in Section 1847A of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(b)(9)), regardless of the site of care in which the skin substitute product is applied.</text></section><section id="H273DE966AAC340D9B16D664D441A18AC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enhancing program integrity for skin substitute products</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H8C63BD7DBF9D469A9FF9A20623FC8363" style="OLC"><subsection id="H7C8E1A5F35BE4C55892358C470D5C50B"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Special payment rules for skin substitute products</header><paragraph id="H775A7A58D7294FC493D484904E3FC010"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification of outlier providers of skin substitute products</header><subparagraph id="HD5C88EA4F04F4932ADB411D725840217"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than March 1, 2026, and every 2 years thereafter through March 1, 2035, the Secretary shall determine the 3 percent of the total number of providers of skin substitute products that are outlier providers of skin substitute products.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE9D69A8724947DAB426433598BA173E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Outlier providers of skin substitute products</header><text>The determination of an outlier provider of skin substitute products under this paragraph shall be based upon the providers (as identified by national provider identification number) that received the greatest total payment under this title for skin substitute products furnished in the year preceding the year in which the determination under subparagraph (A) is made.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF47109BB16F64A07A920B8A963332297"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Referral to oig</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><clause id="HC9C266B1A46D446D8537BAABDDA65DB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>make publicly available the list of outlier providers of skin substitute products identified under each determination under subparagraph (A); and </text></clause><clause id="idc4b2e7a7f01348ddbabfaabd3bc3cf46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text> transmit such list to the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services for the assessment of potential fraud, waste, or abuse.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D8A69FF1B3740B8A03052E7B1AC0630"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial prepayment claim review for certain outlier
 providers</header><subparagraph id="H0154FEA272CE412BA9743026D1041B82"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning March 1, 2026, the Secretary shall conduct prepayment review of claims for skin substitute products submitted under this title by an outlier provider of skin substitute products unless 1 or more of the conditions described in subparagraph (B) is met with respect to such provider.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD29BE1AAF2140C3B8572B4416BD591E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the conditions described in this subparagraph are, with respect to an outlier provider of skin substitute products, the following:</text><clause id="H06F28DB687A44018BA8ACDA511420249"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Skin substitute products furnished by the provider are subject to prior authorization under paragraph (3).</text></clause><clause id="H9B0A4CE00D8A45E3884DFBA80AC30864"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The rate of approval for claims for skin substitute products furnished by such provider that are subject to prepayment review under this paragraph exceeds 90 percent (as determined over a period of time or number of claims specified by the Secretary).</text></clause><clause id="H3CD639FE4D3946FF98ACE1E3EE257272"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Secretary determines that the billing practices of the provider are consistent with the applicable coverage criteria and requirements under this title.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7D8CAF46DDD4F37824E7030BC0A86FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prior authorization for outlier providers of skin substitute
 products</header><subparagraph id="H0876C9FAB00A4B73ABB2EE6E0F4CCC49"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning not later than January 1, 2027, subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall, for a period determined appropriate by the Secretary, apply prior authorization for skin substitute products that are furnished by an outlier provider of skin substitute products identified under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9BFABA92D254961A36415164A63100B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal from prior authorization</header><text>In the event that the Secretary determines, with respect to an outlier provider of skin substitute products, that the rate of approval for requests for prior authorization under this paragraph for skin substitute products furnished by such provider exceeds 90 percent (as determined over a period of time or number of claims specified by the Secretary), the Secretary may cease to apply prior authorization under this paragraph for skin substitute products furnished by such provider.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FCC9F3A220A4E70B0F27D4AD7CBD45E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary shall provide for the transfer, from the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund under section 1841, to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Program Management Account, of $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030, to remain available until expended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB72FD96BE854964A0948DC8E001BE41"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enrollment revocation or exclusion of noncompliant outlier
 providers</header><subparagraph id="H4A43B09C6B8F4F05926A66A89CA9D25A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning January 1, 2028, if the rate of denial for requests for prior authorization under paragraph (3) for skin substitute products furnished by an outlier provider of skin substitute products exceeds 75 percent over a period of 6 or more consecutive months, the Secretary shall determine that an abuse of billing privileges exists with respect to such provider for purposes of section 424.535(a)(8)(ii) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77C06199CA9D442AA589D65B4205F6ED"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Referral for exclusion</header><text>If the Secretary determines under subparagraph (A) that an abuse of billing privileges exists with respect to an outlier provider of skin substitute products, the Secretary shall direct the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services to determine whether such provider should be excluded from participation in any Federal health care program under section 1128(b)(6).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H104C99F13C114680AFFB3897B1E69F1C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Skin substitute product wastage</header><subparagraph id="H4ADB7AE982E54F57A59ABB5061E28C47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>With respect to skin substitute products furnished for the treatment of chronic or acute wounds, payment shall be only made for the reasonable and necessary portion of the skin substitute product used in the treatment of the wound, excluding wastage.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H190146B1788847168AF6B59769ACF020"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For the purpose of subparagraph (A), the reasonable and necessary portion of the skin substitute product is defined as the greater of (i) 3 square centimeters, or (ii) 120 percent of the size of the treated wound.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H551A76B155B64BF7B3C56E0C94A63889"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Skin substitute product defined</header></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">In this subsection, the
                        term <quote>skin substitute product</quote> has the meaning given such term
 in section 1847A(c)(6)(J).</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H3607EE0C16AF4A94A0A009EE63B56FF1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Streamlining approval processes for human cells, tissues and cellular and tissue-based products</header><subsection id="H5AE1F7648DED4A1E8660CA152F4B5554"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall—</text><paragraph id="H61F3075F71AC4901B37898445A31F1F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a comprehensive review of the approval process applied to human cellular and tissue allografts and autografts that are not subject to regulation only under section 361 of the Public Health Service Act, including those processed into liquid, gel, or powder forms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6A56B42D7044217AD03732C520960C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify opportunities to streamline application requirements, review timelines, and evidentiary standards for such products while maintaining appropriate safety and efficacy oversight;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD81D160E044407198A17E35DACAE5D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider the development of a tiered review framework based on risk assessment factors including degree of manipulation, processing methods, mode or administration, and clinical safety profile;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2ECB0DD7E7DB49A6A650A2304594D8DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>evaluate the need for pre-market clinical evaluation and the appropriateness of leveraging existing clinical data, real-world evidence, and registry data to reduce duplicative clinical trial requirements where scientifically justified; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E7EE78CEBAA4F8AA3B2CE812AE01242"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assess mechanisms to harmonize requirements between products currently regulated only under section 361 of the Public Health Service Act that may transition to section 351 regulation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0b2b63d1cad540f3ae3ca4bf83d0e5fe"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Stakeholder consultation</header><text>In conducting the review under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="idce7ee75138b94998b89abb59a98eb9ff"><enum>(1)</enum><text>manufacturers of human tissue allografts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1da72e34fd454737990fc483306f18ea"><enum>(2)</enum><text>tissue banks and procurement organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4d29fe3ef61248f487e300cb84bb5690"><enum>(3)</enum><text>clinicians specializing in wound care, surgical reconstruction, and regenerative medicine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7cb2513baad4401eb2caaf7e04c2fcbb"><enum>(4)</enum><text>patient advocacy organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf25f4ba238eb4ff9aca58596e7dc98e2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>health insurance payors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9774c74fc8a04048bfaf2a3cf34b6c92"><enum>(6)</enum><text>relevant scientific and medical professional societies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5a3c6a22ac584e84863abc482995e3ad"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The review shall specifically consider—</text><paragraph id="id08c9ba9e5b2e45ffb3350e7fcccd4ed7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appropriate modifications to Chemistry, Manufacturing, and Controls (CMC) requirements reflecting the biological nature and donor-dependent variability of human tissue;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideae6b370996c403ead95b6f1254b11df"><enum>(2)</enum><text>potential use of expedited review pathways, including priority review designations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide52bd3c255e7430a804f3734a4075482"><enum>(3)</enum><text>opportunities for modular or staged application submissions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida40c3bcbc8ae4e74a761d0452f2a591a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>appropriate clinical endpoint criteria and study designs for different types of allografts and autografts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id32c4d4a4a21b4cf5b20a08a539d2589f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>post-market surveillance requirements as an alternative to pre-market evidence requirements; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideea86d467f1943e9bdf9fbafd3e5ea54"><enum>(6)</enum><text>international regulatory approaches to similar products.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C6CF57570684A78AA72097EFA2E1026"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue draft guidance implementing any streamlining measures identified under subsection (b), and shall finalize such guidance not later than 12 months after the close of the public comment period.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFAF17F95F3CE4FC5985F4A06F8AB8D66"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the review conducted under subsection (b), including—</text><paragraph id="H5097D9F564A84A6EB63AB1E0B914A4D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>findings and recommendations for regulatory streamlining;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H341C5BD91ADA41778299EB2432AA1DC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any administrative actions taken or proposed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A22B831FF2148D9A692FB48754E88B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for additional legislative action, if any; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF9C0037939B402988B27C63C4F55217"><enum>(4)</enum><text>estimated impacts on patient access and public health.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H126666364BDE4A17B6DFCCEF5383C532"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preservation of safety standards</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to reduce or eliminate safety or efficacy standards applicable to human tissue allografts or autografts subject to licensure under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

