<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDAD3AE00A54C4D63B77A116BB388D87D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9098 IH: Congressional Records Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9098</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000177">Mr. Onder</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect the separation of powers enshrined in the United States Constitution and end the weaponized surveillance of Members of Congress.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF60F867231244F0B88F4564BB9105422" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE03BB92240EB42F398B76DFBFD1EF45C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Records Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H94415D4628F14058AA6E8BEEFED2BD66"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on obtaining records for Members of Congress</header> 
<subsection id="HFB600E4F9DC34CD7A49B6C054FA34750"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DD24CF4F77D4A55B168AF8964816300"> <chapter id="H61BBD59DAA2D42119C26737E53735E79"> <enum>239</enum> <header>Congressional Records</header> <section id="HEF5A90A696834550A46A446CC83E2D7B"> <enum>3773.</enum> <header>Prohibition on obtaining records for Members of Congress or congressional employees</header> <subsection id="HA9392B6D12F149598BC230FBDB18E124"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Prohibition on obtaining records</header> <paragraph id="H15D6A5A8D5C24853A581B5A01BD53F65"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal or State law, a governmental entity may not—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="HB3730E04DBD24663AEF7175F6ABCC008">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>seek or obtain a search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory authorization, certification, or subpoena that could reasonably be expected to return any covered material; or</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H7230AB3F5B3C4AB8BB42311B76570179">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>issue an administrative order that could reasonably be expected to return any covered material.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H1DEA19D75DF24EF084E1BB108E7908FD">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Exception</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall not apply if the subject of the search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory authorization, certification, subpoena, or administrative order is—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="HF8C8CD7B5C1349E0BCDCD1B44FC355B7">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the target of a criminal investigation; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52232835D6284EAFA8EAC99090EFE480"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a third party and the search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory authorization, certification, subpoena, or administrative order demands records, information, or the content of communications pertaining to a Member of Congress or congressional employee who is the target of a criminal investigation.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="H16781C57DBE8451A821CC9908F0E2D40">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Notification requirement</header>
                <paragraph id="H0AA4AD1B8EEF49989C70D585371B54A6">
                  <enum>(1)</enum>
                  <header>Notice</header>
                  <subparagraph id="H371FBDF97CDB446E966A34F99722906A">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A governmental entity shall notify the Member of Congress or congressional employee—</text>
                    <clause id="H40424D1031E445B5828F6889198EC2E8">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>prior to or concurrently with the execution of a search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory authorization, certification, administrative order, or subpoena that could reasonably be expected to return any covered material; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="H8D79A66570964F7CBA11595EDDB2EFAB">
                      <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>as soon as practicable following the execution of a search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory authorization, certification, administrative order, or subpoena that unexpectedly returns covered material.</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HCFB24D5FD44B46709ED9A057060C29BE">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Exception</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a subject of the search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory authorization, certification, subpoena, or administrative order is the target of a criminal investigation or if the subject is a third party and the search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory authorization, certification, subpoena, or administrative order demands records, information, or the content of communications pertaining to a Member of Congress or congressional employee who is the target of a criminal investigation, a court may, upon application by the governmental entity, issue an order delaying the notice required under subparagraph (A)(i) with respect to an acquisition, subpoena, search, accessing, or disclosure that could reasonably be expected to return covered material in connection with such investigation for a period of not more than 10 days if the court determines that there is reason to believe that providing notice would—</text>
                    <clause id="HAD715B8DEE954874B9E7C0F48C4D3DD4">
                      <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>endanger the life or physical safety of any person;</text> </clause> <clause id="HE4CFDAEDF7154E44983F7FC499812F5D"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>result in flight from prosecution;</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="HE6AB75B0B29F45779C851ECEE9768F5D">
                      <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>result in destruction of or tampering with evidence;</text> </clause> <clause id="H4E1CBAD842A44D9FBE058AEAA2AB6EA7"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>result in intimidation of potential witnesses; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause id="HEC867A255F3649FF8F388C4FF05DB4BC">
                      <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>otherwise seriously jeopardize an investigation or unduly delay a trial.</text>
                    </clause>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HDB33142FA28544F69B1E7B7A881F42DD">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Delayed review</header>
                  <subparagraph id="H846558ACE76348C391440A63E74A7823">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>The governmental entity may not review materials that are reasonably expected to contain covered material until the date that is 30 days after the date notice is made pursuant to paragraph (1)(A)(i).</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H767798DD96FB48518739A47D84F2A41B">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                    <header>Unexpected Return of Covered Materials</header>
 <text>In instances where a search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory authorization, certification, administrative order, or subpoena unexpectedly returns covered material, the governmental entity shall halt review of the returned material upon the discovery of the covered material until the date that is 30 days after the date notice is made pursuant to paragraph (1)(A)(ii).</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H5AD818D4E90448F8985E29A75CF457EB">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                    <header>Exception</header>
 <text>Subparagraphs (b)(2)(A) and (b)(2)(B) shall not apply when a 30-day delay in reviewing materials could cause an imminent risk to life or serious bodily injury.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="HDD5DD9D007814A3DB5E1EF3310B74BF0">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Rule of construction</header>
 <text>This section may not be construed to limit the scope of any protection applicable under article I, section 6, clause 1 of the Constitution of the United States.</text>
              </subsection>
              <subsection id="HC134ABF740474EA6BAF86F42AE2CC9EE">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H951C1EFDE0AB43C3B8277764276A5F55"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Congressional employee</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>congressional employee</quote> has the meaning given that term in subparagraphs (1), (2), (3), and (5) of section 2107 of title 5 and includes current and former congressional employees.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBAF8AE0998704B5CB5C3130B7A3F6104">
                  <enum>(2)</enum>
                  <header>Covered material</header>
 <text>The term <quote>covered material</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C7D1B5DEF2C4F65B450B7139ACD7CC8"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>records, including all written materials, wire communications, and electronic communications, that were prepared by, shared with, or otherwise obtained by a Member of Congress or congressional employee in the course of their official duties, including electronic devices containing such records; and</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="HDBA083FBB6FC4153A9FF023F8D1693AB">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>records from an electronic or wire communication service related to any accounts of Members and from the time period of their service in Congress or official congressional accounts of congressional employees, or related to any communications between a Member of Congress or congressional employee and other Members of Congress, other congressional employees, or executive branch employees while at least one party to the communication was serving or working in Congress and another party to the communication was serving or working in Congress or the executive branch.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H230EC902C1AC49ADA35ACE08D515FE06">
                  <enum>(3)</enum>
                  <header>Wire communication; Electronic communication</header>
 <text>The terms <quote>wire communication,</quote> <quote>electronic communication,</quote> and <quote>electronic communication service</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 2510.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H40646BAF8C36438D86F95B0E5DB5C609">
                  <enum>(4)</enum>
                  <header>Governmental entity</header>
 <text>The term <quote>governmental entity</quote> means a department or agency of the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H97C23B50E4784386A2D20A5565D042C5">
                  <enum>(5)</enum>
                  <header>Member of Congress</header>
 <text>The term <quote>Member of Congress</quote> means a current or former Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the United States Congress.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD99B94D7C70D49E099372496E69EAC7E">
                  <enum>(6)</enum>
                  <header>Executive branch employee</header>
 <text>The term <quote>executive branch employee</quote> has the meaning given that term in subparagraph (2)(A) of section 78u1(h) of title 15 and includes current and former executive branch employees.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H282EC0657CDB43EFB3106B65142E9F25">
                  <enum>(7)</enum>
                  <header>Subject of the search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory
                    authorization, certification, subpoena, or administrative order</header>
 <text>The term <quote>subject of the search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory authorization, certification, subpoena, or administrative order</quote> means the person whose records are sought by the governmental entity, or, if records are sought from an electronic or wire communication service, the person to whom the sought records pertain.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H861CF076DF46473E994E6DC327F59738">
                  <enum>(8)</enum>
                  <header>Target of a criminal investigation</header>
 <text>The term <quote>target of a criminal investigation</quote> means a person whom a governmental entity has probable cause to believe has committed a crime. If the person is a Member of Congress or a congressional employee, then the governmental entity shall submit an application certifying to a magistrate judge with authority in the district—or if there is none reasonably available, a judge of a court of record in the district—that there is probable cause to believe the person has committed a crime. The judge must certify that the application establishes that probable cause exists prior to or concurrently with the governmental entity seeking, obtaining, or issuing a search warrant, grand jury subpoena, court order, statutory authorization, certification, subpoena, or administrative order for covered material.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H624A4DCA66994EE689D282AABFA54B6C">
                  <enum>(9)</enum>
                  <header>Third party</header>
 <text>The term <quote>third party</quote> means any person who is not a Member of Congress or congressional employee.</text>
                </paragraph>
              </subsection>
            </section>
          </chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9958A7C919F34B3EA98687A1022E1DAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters at the beginning of part I of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 238 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1D5BEC63E1784E37A9A679799AF57CAA"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">239. Congressional Records 3773</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

