<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25B40-WDF-1W-LP2"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 492 IS: Recognizing community care as an essential tool for meeting the health care needs of the veterans of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>III</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>S. RES. 492</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20251110">November 10, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Recognizing community care as an essential tool for meeting the health care needs of the veterans of the United States.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas, 10 years ago, the Department of Veterans Affairs (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>VA</quote>) experienced a nationwide crisis regarding the ability to provide access to care that highlighted the urgent need for timely, high-quality services for veterans;</text> </whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas Congress responded with the bipartisan passage of the VA MISSION Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/182">Public Law 115–182</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 1393), which expanded opportunities for veterans to receive care in their communities when the VA could not meet their needs;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas community care has since proven to be a vital complement to the VA health care system, offering veterans greater convenience, accessibility, and choice, particularly for those in rural areas, those facing transportation or mobility challenges, and those requiring specialized treatment;</text> </whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas VA data demonstrate that community care is cost-effective and also strengthens veteran trust in the VA as an institution;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas veterans, their families, and caregivers have consistently affirmed that community care provides life-saving access to oncology, mental health, emergency, pain management, and other essential services; and</text> </whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas Congress has consistently provided the VA with record levels of funding to support both direct care and community care, ensuring that resource constraints should never justify limiting veterans’ access to needed treatment: Now, therefore, be it</text> </whereas> </preamble> 
<resolution-body id="HDF9D5B9B72CD4D4A8964E8D2007953CB"> 
<section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"> <text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id2a473da0a5464fcdba3838165909a19f"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>recognizes community care as an essential tool for meeting the health care needs of the veterans of the United States;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id41aaaec59e994d7888aa54389b766fe5"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>affirms that community care complements, rather than threatens, the mission of the Department of Veterans Affairs (referred to in this resolution as the <term>VA</term>);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id86d626b64a8e4c94af4f8b91b0cd7157"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>urges the VA to implement the VA MISSION Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/182">Public Law 115–182</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 1393) in both letter and spirit, ensuring veterans have timely access to community providers when the VA cannot meet their needs; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="id057b82aae62441eba3cd61b54cc54b96"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>reaffirms the commitment of the Senate to ensuring that every veteran has timely access to high-quality, affordable, and veteran-centered care, whether provided in VA facilities or in the community.</text> </paragraph> </section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

