<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2CF253E0DF104D4388A8A95E3A218126" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6952 IH: January 6th Oral History Project Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6952</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260106">January 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the American Folklife Center at the Library of Congress to establish an oral history program to collect certain video and audio recordings of personal histories and testimonials and written materials with respect to individuals who were affected by the events at the United States Capitol on January 6, 2021, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7E1F4E91A0EB40D4859093A1AF7A378D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H928EAD7F220C4BE291BE98E3D6E115D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>January 6th Oral History Project Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H4BE0F30275674F41B7F65A658026EE67"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of program at American Folklife Center to collect video and audio recordings of histories of the insurrection attempt of January 6th 2021</header> 
<subsection id="HB4C02CF4AE594FD99F43C0D12CC51E3C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the American Folklife Center at the Library of Congress shall establish an oral history program to—</text> <paragraph id="H301EF0E892B3427A986A926517AB6A54"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collect video and audio recordings of personal histories and testimonials of individuals who were present at or affected by the events at the United States Capitol on January 6, 2021, including but not limited to Members of Congress, congressional staff, Capitol Police officers, other law enforcement personnel, journalists, and other witnesses;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H806F69D292834760992F7D5D52546DC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create a collection of the recordings obtained (including a catalog and index) which will be available for public use through the National Digital Library of the Library of Congress and such other methods as the Director considers appropriate to the extent feasible subject to available resources; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2745BACBD52F453DA916C993ED3B71F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit, reproduce, and collect written materials (such as contemporaneous notes, text messages, emails, social media posts, photographs, and other documentation) relevant to the personal histories of individuals who experienced or witnessed the events of January 6, 2021, and to catalog such materials in a manner the Director considers appropriate, consistent with and complementary to the efforts described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF4E8BFF350514611B95BCEF664E81C18"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of and consultation with other entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may carry out the activities described in paragraphs (1) and (3) of subsection (a) through agreements and partnerships entered into with other government and private entities, and may otherwise consult with interested persons (within the limits of available resources) and develop appropriate guidelines and arrangements for soliciting, acquiring, and making available recordings under the program under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7F8261AA8556468A8D581E3C2CDFD63B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall begin collecting video and audio recordings under subsection (a)(1) and shall prioritize the collection of testimonials from individuals whose accounts may be most at risk of being lost to time or whose perspectives are essential to understanding the full scope of the January 6, 2021, events.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB4AAD00CB8634133A9D4A4132B0DE919"><enum>3.</enum><header>Private support</header> 
<subsection id="H5BAC711B19DA44F896BEAE18DACB2188"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acceptance of donations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Librarian of Congress may solicit and accept donations of funds and in-kind contributions to carry out the January 6th oral history program under section 2.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H036CA5DAF1C746AB928338356857929D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of separate gift account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury (among the accounts of the Library of Congress) a gift account for the January 6th oral history program under section 2.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC807784315A4427B802A69DB3A2AD05E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dedication of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text> <paragraph id="HE750724F0F984BE494AF0090ACEE88B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any funds donated to the Librarian of Congress to carry out the January 6th oral history program under section 2 shall be deposited entirely into the gift account established under subsection (b);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCB88BAF2A78419F80928C6CE44E327A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the funds contained in such account shall be used solely to carry out the January 6th oral history program under section 2; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB351115029D44674BE92F4368B86AF66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Librarian of Congress may not deposit into such account any funds donated to the Librarian which are not donated for the exclusive purpose of carrying out the January 6th oral history program under section 2.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4134F1CE9F894009828CDC692D2B8CD4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H73B2449C158A43ACB95C1A710180B048"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$500,000 for fiscal year 2027; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B1C1F9997B947B3B1ABE00F188CD0A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such sums as may be necessary for each succeeding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

