<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H78ED1D8770AE4332A046BD5FE983E702" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7868 IH: Expanding Support for Living Donors Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7868</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260309">March 9, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to the Living Organ Donation Reimbursement Program.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HF96AB5C160CF4381B9B1D08EB31A725D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFB80159C1E8D4C1AB5BAF02BCAA76610" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Support for Living Donors Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H85E9E0E68231457B81775715295A0721"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expanding support for living donors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 377 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/274f">42 U.S.C. 274f</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H89113D4ECF6542C8AC32B4FF71FF32C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (f) through (h) as subsections (h) through (j), respectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB70974F48CFB4DFC85446BBD44E18B74"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (e) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5B4755E5FCB24C4CBB13E2E3DFB309D3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HEEACAB2E82D04C849C89BF5092782AEB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Eligibility of donating individuals based on household income</header> 
<paragraph id="H03DD08B27C164568A2FDF063CD0830FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In providing reimbursement to donating individuals using funds from grant awards under this section, the recipient of the grant award shall not limit the eligibility of a donating individual for such reimbursement based on the individual’s income if the individual’s household income is at or below 700 percent of the poverty line.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C8EB41E7AE4464D80974527799D5692"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>poverty line</term> means the applicable poverty line as set forth in the most recent poverty guidelines of the Department of Health and Human Services published under the authority of section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8CB71CDD93464A769FF4FD4ADB78A0B7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reimbursement amount</header> 
<paragraph id="H2D9755FDE6EB448A86C231C4C08AD183"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of reimbursement of qualifying expenses provided by a recipient of a grant award under this section to each such donating individual shall be the lesser of—</text> <subparagraph id="HFC0414310C134E6FAD5CBC17E61E4651"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total amount of the donating individual’s qualifying expenses; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD1B189BB93FF4669BF8F5D468F2E66B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the maximum permissible amount described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF268B7E8C014B7AAC10D6EFD21351B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum permissible amount</header> <subparagraph id="HCB8C1E2913E941B7A70F962B70FCD995"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Rule</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the maximum permissible amount described in this section is—</text> 
<clause id="H73AD4A3F56614F1287E7A9B77130D211"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2027, $10,000; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2D00083EF4144F66AF09D2B4F332572A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for subsequent fiscal years, the maximum permissible amount allowed under this subsection for the preceding fiscal year adjusted by the total percentage change (rounded to the nearest hundredth) that occurred in the Consumer Price Index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) for the preceding fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6356D07D5FC3486E8D4500F1FBD93DA0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for recipients based on insufficient funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, with respect to reimbursement provided by a recipient of a grant award under this section to donating individuals, lower the maximum permissible amount under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year if the Secretary—</text> <clause id="H62ABC5ED0EEF47EBA1BAA64FC99A1C41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determines that such recipient has insufficient funds to provide the full amount that would otherwise apply under paragraph (1) to all donating individuals; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9A475113A6B743EAB26B7C14F71F4465"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least 30 days before making such determination effective, provides to the Congress written notice of such determination, including a justification.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92F063F8611341219883548215CE60C6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary, with respect to reimbursement provided by a recipient of a grant award under this section to donating individuals, makes a determination under subparagraph (B) to lower the maximum permissible amount under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year—</text> 
<clause id="H413FA740D11E4F0F8117C8D81ED23EE3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such determination shall not affect the amount of reimbursement for any approved donating individual prior to the effective date of such determination; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1D392FE94F8B490F8C2E7E0FD5AF89EE" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the maximum permissible amount under subparagraph (A)(ii) for any subsequent year shall be calculated without regard to such lowered amount. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFC20BAF040845A6A57AF3ED0FF24411"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (i), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2005 through 2009</quote> and inserting <quote>are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2028 through 2037</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E3C176A79C84E6EB18A38E0CDFA3CEF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by amending subsection (j), as so redesignated, to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDDC3270621C0481A8886D819FE1D7C99" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HBFE54B7AFB8948E9B7EE12071E06D07A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31 of each year, beginning in fiscal year 2027, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3581A188008C4958810A778991572BE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare, submit to the Congress, and make public a report on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA06DEF531F9348899C9341AF2143D132"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether grants under this section provided adequate funding during the preceding fiscal year to reimburse all donating individuals participating in the grant program under this section for all qualifying expenses; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA3B78AFB02542189200A22E713F3674"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impacts, ongoing activities, challenges, and future needs of the program under this section; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A2FCB412F6A4F219A72E4F32E2F715C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include in each such report, for the fiscal year covered by the report—</text> <subparagraph id="HDFA7BB24CD9D435C84D6444DF3E2856B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimated number of all donating individuals participating in the grant program under this section who did not receive reimbursement for all qualifying expenses;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1311A6947F4469FA043BCE6051C8075"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total amount of funding that is estimated to be necessary to fully reimburse all donating individuals participating in the grant program under this section for all qualifying expenses;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5173FA935F8466E8DA07DEE50BB6216"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an overview of the program under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD80D76873B644C98DF6355FAC97711B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>current and trended historical information about the program under this section, including—</text> <clause id="H600945255C054275A37D5821359D1DB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total number of donating individuals applying for reimbursement;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5A3F8769048E48179EE00D83BB742585"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average and median reimbursement amount provided to donating individuals;</text></clause> <clause id="H4891710F3D084A01BC4FA7195186FB67"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>demographic information regarding—</text> 
<subclause id="H371E40611E284371A8E697B3DE958B98"><enum>(I)</enum><text>donating individuals applying for reimbursement; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H241081D88E3643C7B691FA0EFD8B3D5F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>donating individuals approved for reimbursement;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HAAFC7B65C5FE4EBCA617BD501DA97AD7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the types of expenses for which reimbursement was requested (including requests for reimbursement of non-qualifying expenses);</text></clause> <clause id="H69DD85BD85824D739DD036AE15072F6D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the amount of funding provided to donating individuals with respect to each such type of expenses;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H54B01F5B96CF49B695EA004E5CEFEF09"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the amount of funding provided to donating individuals with respect to each organ category; and</text></clause> <clause id="H13CF80EEE1384CC498467A01D6A3D5A2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the total amount expended to carry out this section, disaggregated by—</text> 
<subclause id="HDE84AC0E67D24FC3B59C565AE36F8433"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount expended by the Secretary and the recipients of grants under this section on administrative expenses; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9ABE39E47D3E42D8A95E5AC02047DC22"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the amount provided to donating individuals as reimbursement;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H469FE0181FB4429FB729C388F457D801"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the impacts of the program under this section, including—</text> <clause id="HDDC550C19AAA4D0CB4475FEDEECCB487"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of completed donations for which reimbursement was provided;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB52740915FE542CE87A67011252512A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the proportion of living donor transplants in the United States in which the donor received reimbursement through the program under this section; and</text></clause> <clause id="H58DBBC19DA864A08B01E0EA8FB2C9D4B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an estimate of the savings to the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act resulting from the program under this section, both—</text> 
<subclause id="HF6DD70AC07E3451BB6CF9296AF373576"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for the fiscal year covered by the report; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H21FC4E9CB1624CAFBC61F6ED80778AAE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>cumulatively since the program’s creation;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H506C866E7F1F4AC496166611E33AC049"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the types of donations made by donating individuals receiving reimbursement, disaggregated according to—</text> <clause id="H83B0D0AC603346B2BACE868AD4C34B44"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the type of organ donated; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC90C097CB55545FCA9F30BEDA220E270"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the donations were directed, non-directed, or a paired exchange;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0399F92B755340FA8CDE9EA342BB0241"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of any efforts to expand or improve the program under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF8162E2B8374588A55F68F1DA274B63"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a description of the efforts of the Secretary and recipients of grants under this section to increase awareness of the program under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE11A0CE1FEE34A55AFAE83A19498A519"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a description of challenges experienced by the program under this section, including—</text> 
<clause id="HB2464A93A348406B92458DC435FADF2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number and percentage of donating individuals applying for reimbursement whose qualifying expenses approached or exceeded the maximum amount allowed under subsection (g); and</text></clause> <clause id="H16031DAE2B3349C997D3E26127932939"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an estimate of the total funding needed to fully reimburse, without regard to the maximum amount allowed under subsection (g) or donor income eligibility caps, all donating individuals in the United States for all qualifying expenses;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB527827EAC48499A8FD788C57698EB61"><enum>(J)</enum><text>areas of concern regarding, and identified barriers to, the elimination of financial disincentives to living organ donation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1A7E9FF61144526ACC477C97057042E"><enum>(K)</enum><text>such other matters as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H0BE5753A2D8D41ED9B58F4090003A710"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6817C22D167D4D89BE478696E4C3F590"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study on how the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) could, under existing statutory authorities, pay costs that would otherwise be paid through the Living Organ Donation Reimbursement Program under section 377 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/274f">42 U.S.C. 274f</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC424169C720F42A6A161649E400A6563"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Congress a report on the results of such study, including recommendations for any changes needed to achieve such purpose.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

