<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL26353-XC6-ST-GLJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 670 IS: Supporting the goals and ideals of the 2026 Day of Silence in bringing attention to anti-LGBTQI+ bullying, harassment, discrimination, and other forms of victimization faced by individuals in schools, and calling on communities across the country to take action to demand equal educational opportunity, basic civil rights protections, and freedom from erasure for all students, particularly LGBTQI+ young people, in K–12 schools. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 670</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415" legis-day="20260414">April 15 (legislative day, April 14), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of the 2026 Day of Silence in bringing attention to anti-LGBTQI+ bullying, harassment, discrimination, and other forms of victimization faced by individuals in schools, and calling on communities across the country to take action to demand equal educational opportunity, basic civil rights protections, and freedom from erasure for all students, particularly LGBTQI+ young people, in K–12 schools. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, for every year since its initiation in 1996, LGBTQI+ students, teachers, and allies have recognized a National Day of Silence to bring attention to the silencing of LGBTQI+ students through harassment and bullying; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for more than 2 decades, Congress has supported a resolution for a National Day of Silence and a resolution for No Name-Calling Week, and most recently, Congress has supported a <quote>Rise Up Resolution</quote> to demand equal educational opportunities, basic civil rights protections, and freedom from erasure for all students;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas young people, teachers, school staff, families, and communities must be free from transphobia, homophobia, racism, sexism, and ableism in K–12 schools;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas K–12 schools must be safe and inclusive learning environments that include and affirm LGBTQI+ young people, especially those who are transgender, nonbinary, intersex, Black, Indigenous, people of color, and people with disabilities, and those who are from communities that experience marginalization;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQI+ young people frequently experience bias-based bullying and harassment, discrimination, and punitive discipline that increases the likelihood they will enter the school-to-prison pipeline;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Glisten’s 2025 National School Climate Survey showed that—</text><paragraph id="id0b89711a1f0d42468eef349344ab422c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>58 percent of LGBTQI+ students reported being verbally harassed by their peers at school because of their sexual orientation, and nearly 57 percent because of their gender identity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfee39f4a2e2747248d440b42d5ed66ea"><enum>(2)</enum><text>nearly 23 percent of LGBTQI+ students reported being physically harassed by their peers at school because of their sexual orientation, and 23 percent because of their gender identity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id704449d5047440808ff8cbc697111c0b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>8 percent of LGBTQI+ students reported being physically assaulted by their peers at school because of their sexual orientation, and over 9 percent because of their gender identity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide40cdcc100374c3fa9d558e42034471a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for Black, Indigenous, and students of color, these trends were exacerbated, with 75 percent of students reporting experiencing harassment or assault related to their sexual orientation or gender identity;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Glisten’s 2025 National School Climate Survey found that 67 percent of LGBTQI+ students reported that they felt unsafe in school because of their sexual orientation or gender identity in 2025, and nearly 30 percent reported missing at least 1 entire school day in the preceding month because of safety concerns;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 200 anti-LGBTQI+ education bills have been introduced each year in State legislatures across the United States, the majority of which specifically target transgender and nonbinary young people, including—</text><paragraph id="H81AF26F60E16419E974BE880A1CB9F5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the 27 States that have enacted policies between 2021 and 2025 that prohibit transgender students from playing alongside their peers on school sports teams; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D6E8AC00A6B4F04AACE27B230502D5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the 20 States that have enacted laws between 2021 and 2025 that prevent transgender students from using the school bathroom or locker room that corresponds with their gender identity;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas LGBTQI+ young people are more likely than their non-LGBTQI+ peers to experience mental health concerns, including stress, anxiety, and depression;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly half of LGBTQI+ young people seriously considered suicide in the last year, a trend that increases among Indigenous, Black, and multiracial LGBTQI+ young people;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Glisten’s 2025 National School Climate Survey found that 7 percent of LGBTQI+ youth surveyed had to change schools in the previous year because they felt uncomfortable and unsafe at school, and more than a quarter of LGBTQI+ students who did not see themselves graduating from high school said that anti-LGBTQ+ policies or practices at school were a contributing factor;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas States have passed or attempted to pass legislation that erases or censors LGBTQI+ individuals, history, and contributions from classroom literature and curricula, including the 14 States that enacted laws censoring instruction related to LGBTQI+ people; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these laws harm students and force families to consider leaving their homes, as demonstrated by Williams Institute reporting, which found that, in the year following the 2022 passage of the Parental Rights in Education Act by the Florida State legislature, 56 percent of LGBTQI+ parents of students in the State of Florida considered moving out of the State, and 16.5 percent have taken steps to move out of the State;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 90 percent of transgender and nonbinary young people say that recent debates prompted by State legislation restricting the rights of transgender individuals have negatively impacted their mental health;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas data provided by the Department of Justice shows that there were a reported 222 anti-LGBTQ hate crimes in schools in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every young person must have equal educational opportunity and freedom from the fear that their basic civil and educational rights will be taken away from them;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas young people who develop in positive school climates that are free from bullying, harassment, and discrimination report greater physical and psychological safety, greater mental well-being, and improved educational and life outcomes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas positive school transformation must recognize that safety is too low of a bar and that all communities deserve to be acknowledged and affirmed in schools;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas students, families, educators, and community members in every State and territory are advocating for safe and inclusive learning environments that affirm LGBTQI+ young people, particularly those who are transgender, nonbinary, intersex, Black, Indigenous, people of color, and people with disabilities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas affirming policies such as enumerated anti-bullying protections, gender neutral dress code guidelines, and inclusive learning practices are proven strategies to address hostile learning environments for all students; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas we must all demand the best possible future for all young people in schools, particularly those who identify as LGBTQI+, without exception: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H092EC924EDAF41AAA4410BEF6FE25C3B"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H50967BC0DB21472B941EA16A9D9D3209"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="H296090B328A6406894A7810FF98A67D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the goals and ideals of the <quote>National Day of Silence</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H268BA5E44AF1421CBC1452CB6003FA58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the contributions of students, families, educators, and community members who participate in the <quote>National Day of Silence</quote> to draw attention to the bullying, harassment, assault, and discrimination faced by LGBTQI+ students; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F4B736174C845F29CE3440CB8E16D87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages each State, city, and local educational agency to adopt laws and policies to prohibit bullying of and discrimination against students, teachers, and other school staff on the basis of their sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics (including intersex traits), so that the schools of the United States are institutions where all individuals are able to focus on learning.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

