<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26020-LN7-51-CD4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3595 IS: No War with Venezuela Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3595</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the use of funds for the deployment of United States military or intelligence personnel in Venezuela for certain purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No War with Venezuela Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5d773d09fde4ae3a6ceadb003aca115"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on deployment of United States military or intelligence personnel in Venezuela</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69055743165341cb89b1cd0fb0cfbb8d"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be used for the deployment of United States military or intelligence personnel in Venezuela for the following purposes without congressional authorization:</text><paragraph id="idac756ae3bbcb4499875efc2346ecaa7e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Conducting military operations against the regime or people of Venezuela.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d7e6a8a51094f2a8db6c46bd86d9216"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assisting United States law enforcement operations, including efforts to arrest individuals indicted by the United States Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9c027026a4f44809c16e632fcc99dd8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any military occupation of Venezuela, including activities that would be reasonably viewed as administering its governance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd683f136cad140d8a31133d463c54131"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing security or other services to private extractive industries, including oil companies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4d3b74356d84f0b81e88a62ee564078"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any other activities Congress has not explicitly authorized.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2fc22dc3e03849ddb87b93e54ddf34bb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (a) does not apply to the following activities:</text><paragraph id="id9e4f0744b8fc44fcb4de2bedd940b232"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Defense against an attack by Venezuela on the United States personnel or facilities located outside the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8cdadeecd9594d329bf4702fe44b870e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Activities solely for the purposes of collecting, analyzing, or sharing intelligence and counterintelligence information of interest to the United States Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97210f7a062a4393a94d67a2c877ec37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Activities solely for ensuring the security of any United States diplomatic presence in Venezuela.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a40caea60494868998a15afe6f70f8c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Collecting, analyzing, or sharing intelligence and counterintelligence information for the purposes of securing the safe return of United States nationals wrongfully detained in Venezuela.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idac273005d23448b9aca9de47761d2afa"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Collecting, analyzing, or sharing intelligence and counterintelligence information for the purposes of interdicting and disrupting the production and distribution of illicit narcotics that the United States intelligence community finds to be emanating from Venezuela.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5cfce4138724966aadbb4acb9fe142b"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Activities solely for the purposes of countering the activities of the Governments of the People's Republic of China, the Russian Federation, Iran, and the Democratic Republic of Korea in Venezuela and neighboring countries.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

