<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H485806D54D73403095C4079C50359700" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8135 IH: Cost-of-living Emergency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8135</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260327">March 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To declare an emergency regarding the cost of living in the United States and direct actions to be taken to address the cost-of-living emergency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1809617248C94AAF9946FDEA8F3FB2FE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9E14FD229F1E4D98A7151C55EAC67A95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cost-of-living Emergency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87D04086AD0348DCB6089D32B544BB31"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71B29ECB1EFD4B24BE7E01B52BE8E236">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Average U.S. household</header>
 <text>The term <term>average U.S. household</term> means a household in the United States earning less than the median household income for the prior year, as determined by the United States Census Bureau.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E5CEE6BC1AA4A65B88624DCA1183349"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basic household necessities</header><text>The term <term>basic household necessities</term> includes the following expenditures, as defined by the Bureau of Labor Statistics on January 1, 2026:</text> <subparagraph id="H9FCA2BCFAA2D4744A0A40BCC3BC6BAEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Food at home.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA1A27B18B2874A21B7DE85E3BD2C5568"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Owned dwellings.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF847C0F0A38948B6AACC74D71304DFA1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Rented dwellings.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F9F3708ED714755B5A6CF3105C9CC0C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Gasoline and other fuels.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1BEF413BB3C14CC18C88E7E43D301580"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Medical services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF434761BC0344D7AB2B4484065642869"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Utilities, fuels, and public services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2313E75C3D19480DB0025969F0F03C35"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Co-chair</header><text>The term <term>co-chair</term> means an individual appointed to serve as a co-chair of the Commission under section 8(a)(3)(B).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB618CB34E5FE4621A648E14BD798AB53"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Cost-of-Living Commission established under section 8(a)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69F1C4DDE6494F8681D129F2390CC6A3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Council</header><text>The term <term>Council</term> means the Council of Economic Advisers established under section 10 of the Employment Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1023">15 U.S.C. 1023</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7420BC9209134DC29473014A31AC264D" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Large corporation</header><text>The term <term>large corporation</term> means any business that is not a small business concern, as defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFE4542B53BE447CB4B9DDC86C07E7D8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Outside expert</header><text>The term <term>outside expert</term> means an individual who is not an elected official or an officer or employee of the Federal Government or of any State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EAEE567614D480EB4F8D7989E24F3B7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Special Advisor</header><text>The term <term>Special Advisor</term> means any individual appointed to the role of Special Advisor to the President under section 4(3)(A).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8406CD08AAE840E28C8FCFE8D18EDCB1"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H590238E887454B7EAC06901D580E2096"><enum>3.</enum><header>Declaration of emergency with respect to cost of living</header> 
<subsection id="H2E326915DAE74DC5B8435E7E8EB5653E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Declaration</header><text>There is hereby declared an emergency with respect to the high cost of living facing the people of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A2D466697A34B8B944681F04F05049B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5588B75BCFB4C66AF2C4596DF590C5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by paragraph (2), the emergency declared under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6CD5953A500443889B0FB3BD4CCA0B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The emergency declared under subsection (a) may continue after the date described in paragraph (1) if there is enacted into law a joint resolution extending the emergency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1AB5374499043E59DD896D1495F43CE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expedited procedures</header><text>A joint resolution described in paragraph (2) shall be considered in accordance with the procedures set forth in section 202(c) of the National Emergencies Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1622">50 U.S.C. 1622(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HCCE59334B8A54DBDA5E67109F5C07FC6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Actions to be taken by the Council of Economic Advisers during a cost-of-living emergency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">During the period that the emergency declared under section 3 is in effect, the President, acting through the Chair of the Council, shall undertake the following actions:</text> <paragraph id="HD1F7058956A64A339C2EEE3B495417A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Updated advisory mandate</header><text>In carrying out the duties described in section 10(c) of the Employment Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1023">15 U.S.C. 1023(c)</external-xref>), the Council shall prioritize economic analysis and advice addressing the following subjects:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE5852A3846294AC9A773F7E945B791C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The affordability of basic household necessities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0AAAE3EC2AD744ADB7989A16F77B0A26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The economic pressures impacting low- and middle-income families.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A6431DB79664D51945566A3B2A81F9D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The distributional consequences of Federal economic policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC200A105F42437A9E08847EB17C88C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of White House Cost Cutting Council</header><text>Not later than 7 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chair of the Council shall establish within the Council a White House Cost Cutting Council that shall be responsible for coordinating whole of Government efforts to reduce the costs of basic household necessities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0D6A5A325D04717B46D07762B13C8AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designation of personnel</header> 
<subparagraph id="H326ACE2107174A9085275A2A56BAA959"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Pursuant to the authority under section 10(b) of the Employment Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1023">15 U.S.C. 1023(b)</external-xref>), the Chair of the Council shall appoint personnel to serve in the following roles:</text> <clause id="H27CC09DA36C44213B39D97E208E42584"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Special Advisor to the President for Grocery Costs, who shall serve as the principal advisor to the President for all issues relating to the costs of food at home in the United States.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF0E7348E73CD426DA317215AD84EB17F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Special Advisor to the President for Housing Costs, who shall serve as the principal advisor to the President for all issues relating to the costs of owned or rented dwellings for individuals in the United States.</text></clause> <clause id="H0EBC511A8EEC46FCADF563E1AB43F85B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Special Advisor to the President for Utility Costs, who shall serve as the principal advisor to the President for all issues relating to the cost of utilities, fuels, and public services for individuals in the United States.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H75B0BAA219F44D108196A0CF3B2705A3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Special Advisor to the President for Health Care Costs, who shall serve as the principal advisor to the President for all issues relating to the cost of health insurance, health care services, and medications for individuals in the United States.</text></clause> <clause id="H6235A45C6D544B81A93A52C12F960637"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Special Advisor to the President for Transportation Costs, who shall serve as the principal advisor to the President for all issues relating to—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D06E209ADAA439FB5FCB947FE29E728"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of gasoline and other transportation fuels for individuals in the United States;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94E8DC5CCD0A4C1C9F2CAE8745177BD6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">costs associated with owning or leasing a personal vehicle for individuals in the United States; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87AE32BFAB824379B1324C20B1BAEBCD"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other costs relating to transportation to or from work, school, or other essential activities for individuals in the United States.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H3C5FEAAEC60447C5B512657E3A086F87"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Special Advisor to the President for Wages, who shall serve as the principal advisor to the President for all issues relating to wages of individuals in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20473BD4E4E848DE866D3EEBEF5ECC98"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Each Special Advisor appointed to a role under subparagraph (A) shall carry out the following duties:</text> <clause id="H21E7AE799B5744E38BAF3AC95645A908"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Assemble and lead a task force to be made up of members of the Cabinet (or the designees of such members), the heads of independent regulatory agencies, as defined in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code, and other senior executive branch officials who shall meet not less frequently than weekly to discuss actions that may be taken to reduce the costs of the goods and services and strengthen household wages within the purview of the Special Advisor.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFE8B35D2DC9947D7994CCC6B236DA62F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Prepare a weekly report to be distributed to the President, Vice President, the Chief of Staff to the President, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, each member of the Cabinet, and other senior employees serving in the Executive Office of the President that—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49794E889CDF4E41BC405445B10633B5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides details on the costs of goods and services within the purview of the Special Advisor; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D58F5192A4545A7A92CFABFEBDD56DE"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies actions that may be taken to lower those costs.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H2CEABF05E999474CA039C39681F7664E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Host regional listening sessions focused on the costs of the goods and services within the purview of the Special Advisor that—</text> 
<subclause id="HDB7F123EBB6A4154A633B50B9068E629"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are held in geographically diverse regions of the United States;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H16F698503F9341EB80E721BA604777D0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>allow members of the public to participate and share concerns related to the costs of goods and services within the purview of the Special Advisor; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2AE5DD9F45AE4A4C8C4B5BDE22BB3297"><enum>(III)</enum><text>occur not less frequently than 3 times per year.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5EC1167685A747CF8665BB0AA4498704"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Prepare a summary report of each regional listening session held under clause (iii) and share the report with the Council, the Joint Economic Committee, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the President of the Senate.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H147C8F6A877046D2AA34202C2B4FA59E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Provide testimony to the Joint Economic Committee not less frequently than once a year to identify actions that may be taken to reduce the costs of the goods and services within the purview of the Special Advisor.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H149B573286254A2BB12E033CC7048D78"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State of Household Budgets report</header><text>Every 3 months, the Council shall submit a State of Household Budgets report to the President, the Commission, and the Joint Economic Committee that includes information relating to the following metrics:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5F5BB9C2FB974889AE8DB6765509B7AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The median household purchasing power in the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99AF81CA1CF4443390E2E08C55BCE0D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The real wage growth net of housing and health costs in the United States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC4B30AB25A748769DDFB38258B7F4A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Household debt-to-income burdens in the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H24916EAC5B6A4E279136A8A8EA499D7F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Regional affordability indexes in the United States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC226DB0EF27E488DB8EEC652159C3597"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Basic household necessities inflation measures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HCFF62B45C429446EA7009F26143C86E4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Household budget impact statements</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EDA01646E2B486087CAF30A509FADC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period that the emergency declared under section 3 is in effect, the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget shall require each agency head to include a household budget impact statement in any major regulatory action submitted to the Administrator.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19B81DF50E5340728C23D1F64FD20C34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A household budget impact statement shall include—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7677A3F9E6B44335942608CB984FE411"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the estimated effects of the regulatory action for an average U.S. household;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94546368C8BC4BE2A51B147797D5BC20"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the regional variation in cost burdens on the average U.S. household;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE521E12382774B02A5C9DE2301D0BF96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the estimated benefits that a large corporation might see from the regulatory action; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C8665DAC9B043309145F632CAE8BD67"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an analysis determining whether the regulatory action would provide more benefits for the average U.S. household or large corporations.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H154113BC7EFB4EC988E5C88ABC7E3CAE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Each agency head shall make any household budget impact statement submitted under subsection (a) publicly available unless national security prohibits disclosure.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB08E97185BAB4B4090572AED7571EA59"><enum>6.</enum><header>Emergency enforcement of price gouging laws</header> 
<subsection id="H41AF5F2253E64B558B97EFC48CAA79D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>During the period that the emergency declared under section 3 is in effect, the Attorney General and the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission shall jointly establish a task force to be known as the <quote>Joint Task Force on Consumer Costs</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H30A57ECD7EC14F118F9CC296A2234C27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Task Force shall be composed of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H48DB2A4CCF624C418A87C6E9B24C2801"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Attorney General (or a designee), who shall serve as a Co-Chair;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9E47B136D4B4A29B222BB1647A02A59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission (or a designee), who shall serve as a Co-Chair; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C4683A05164491687083EF899517B5C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such other officers and employees of the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission as the Co-Chairs may jointly designate, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H3D894C7A0AA341F8A1F593C6D7B3B2CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>attorneys from the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEE7BA84B99014C02BD0EAB53EDF40DA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>attorneys from the Bureau of Competition and the Bureau of Consumer Protection of the Federal Trade Commission; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BAB84C710FD427890A70FE4B5477CF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>economists and investigators with expertise in supply chain dynamics and retail pricing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD76D22F9BDA747E18EB30F3B0BDC4182"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Task Force shall coordinate the efforts of the Federal Government to prevent and prosecute price gouging and other anticompetitive practices during the period that the emergency declared under section 3 is in effect, including by—</text> <paragraph id="H195194D5E2F44AEFB46531A4492F730E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>monitoring retail and wholesale price increases for essential goods and services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2C06BD1F4224F03BA3E7F7AE58014F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sharing information and evidence between the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission regarding potential violations of Federal law;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD679A72912C34392BB826CFF52FD7821"><enum>(3)</enum><text>investigating business and industry practices that inflate costs for households;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CA9CCB054384C86AB5DBC7763330C56"><enum>(4)</enum><text>initiating joint investigations into suspected anticompetitive practices, unfair or deceptive acts or practices, and unfair and illegal pricing practices such as price gouging, price-fixing, and price discrimination;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H913BF1F71379402B8E00143B477E1009"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing guidance to State attorneys general to ensure a coordinated national response to localized unfair and illegal pricing practices; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B8DE8D09446496B9488F7063858E5D8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establishing a centralized public portal for consumers and whistleblowers to report suspected anticompetitive, unfair or deceptive practices, and unfair and illegal pricing practices.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7C97759950454308B64598D23393EC76"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement powers</header><text>In carrying out its duties under subsection (c), the Task Force shall utilize all authorities available to the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission, including authorities under—</text> 
<paragraph id="H221BEB84B66648778CD41D4DDE33C5EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE46F141EFB674B4DBDF0A80E5D4E2A0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76460DBA18C44228BF13E26BC7D916F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D7274BB3CD34AC09B194AE3BB14E4CD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other Federal statute prohibiting fraud, hoarding, or the manipulation of prices in interstate commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H24D528B451174ED1B6B3E8F7F7FC90AD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Resource sharing</header><text>The Attorney General and the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission may—</text> <paragraph id="HEA990EA9ABB74236AE64343CBA21B45E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>detail personnel to the Task Force on a non-reimbursable basis; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F0B981E253B40BA97C335298B63D8A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notwithstanding any other provision of law, share investigative files, data, and technical resources if—</text> <subparagraph id="H5887B6304E4B455BB2863AA6AF71A46A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such sharing is necessary for the performance of the duties of the Task Force under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A4ACB9B9AF44A0894FA99A26049F39D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appropriate protections for confidential business information are maintained.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H49FE8D3C45EB4D6197B413D0DD5C79F7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the establishment of the Task Force, and every 90 days thereafter until the Task Force is terminated pursuant to subsection (g), the Co-Chairs shall submit a report on the activities of the Task Force, including the number of investigations opened and the status of enforcement actions, to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0939D5B1D3CF4B0085EC2687E63E207F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D5FF9CA138E4569BACB02024A25EE19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H335CDC75AB9945BD8F7D0C29D3C32633"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B237190D1C54BDABCFD7E12236CE5A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB94B9F49204945F68AF5BF2B2234F5B4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Task Force shall terminate on the date that is 30 days after the expiration or rescission of the emergency declared under section 3.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H977FCD8F0178426DA5A6B7335180F3B5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed as authorizing the Department of Justice or the Federal Trade Commission to suspend, terminate, or deprioritize any ongoing investigation, enforcement action, or litigation initiated by the Task Force that is ongoing at the time the Task Force terminates pursuant to subsection (g).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2D73FA85E5D742A4AC309CFB8F2297FD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Use of authorities under Defense Production Act of 1950</header> 
<subsection id="H0E891DB3930F419C8C0FF5EB61A40A79" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Covered agency head defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered agency head</term> means the head of an agency to whom the President delegated, under section 201(a) of Executive Order 13603 (77 Fed. Reg. 16651; relating to national defense resources preparedness), authorities under section 101 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4511">50 U.S.C. 4511</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73CFEEEBFB5248FDA28CF34CA4FA3C75"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mandatory utilization</header><text>During the period the emergency declared under section 3 is in effect, the President shall use the authorities provided under title III of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4531">50 U.S.C. 4531 et seq.</external-xref>) to expand productive capacity with respect to and supply of basic household necessities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB2B8FA74EFF7415F9E0E0D4C01D2B2AB" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with Council of Economic Advisers</header> 
<paragraph id="H5BF3895597844663ADBDE71BC8F6ACFD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President, acting through each covered agency head, shall develop a strategic plan for the expenditure of funds from the Defense Production Act Fund (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4534">50 U.S.C. 4534</external-xref>) to increase the domestic supply of basic household necessities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H340C94DBD7474E8EB1543AA73A0421BE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Economic impact analysis</header><text>Each covered agency head shall conduct a continuous assessment of the domestic industrial base within the purview of the covered agency head to identify supply chain bottlenecks that contribute to price volatility for basic household necessities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB749C937111E428EABF979BEEB406152" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Evidentiary requirement for project execution</header><text>The President may not execute a contract, loan, or purchase commitment under this section unless a relevant covered agency head submits a written certification to the President that the proposed activity supported by the contract, loan, or purchase commitment—</text> <subparagraph id="H1D79B882BD0C463BB1895F3F28C08BBA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is directly supported by empirical economic data; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF83F9C998CB545CA996339C250F0A31A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>can be reasonably proven to result in a reduction of the retail or wholesale cost of a specific basic household necessity within 180 days of the commencement of the activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5C53D183BCE453FA8931A234D3E79EB" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorized actions</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the President may carry out the following actions:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC40115F390ED4C088440C49EE5E5D3B7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Loan guarantees and loans</header><text>Issue guarantees and make loans under sections 301 and 302 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4531">50 U.S.C. 4531</external-xref>, 4532) to small- and medium-sized businesses to modernize facilities for the production of basic household necessities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5E04AA2C68540B1A3C8545D27116495" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purchase commitments</header><text>Execute purchase commitments under section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4533">50 U.S.C. 4533</external-xref>) to make available basic household necessities at a consistent price to individuals in the United States for the duration of the agreement.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD9876E415208413CA46C2CFC4D2982C0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Production cost offset</header><text>Provide for subsidy payments under section 303(c) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4533">50 U.S.C. 4533(c)</external-xref>) to offset the costs of domestically produced raw materials essential to the production of basic household necessities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H62E6603010AF43139291030B349AA29E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemption from national defense requirement</header><text>Under subsections (b) and (c), the President shall exercise the authorities provided under title III of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4531">50 U.S.C. 4531 et seq.</external-xref>) without regard to any requirement of that Act that the exercise of such authorities be for the national defense.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H936CF3AD74774389A644541C6C13EF6F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Congressional action on cost-of-living emergency</header> 
<subsection id="HC7DE91B7AB9E4A74AD550144F62C7F29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Cost-of-Living Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="HFF334DDF72914827A652EA6A4D2F7372"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is hereby established in Congress a Cost-of-Living Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F30D27364514DF9BE530B4CBC5F0BCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header> <subparagraph id="H5AE0114531C948D3858E6AA5DE491F9E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>General</header><text>The Commission shall identify policies to—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86CE272049644E1687A7922E6BCCBB3C">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meaningfully improve the cost-of-living situation for the average U.S. household in the short- and medium-term, including by reducing cost drivers for specified sectors; and</text>
                        </clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE4747CEA4A0476885A09F9D6DD4E037"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">achieve national economic growth that maintains a stable and sustainable cost-of-living over the long run.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9659EDFE260C48B2901E0D1F48E9552A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recommendations of committees</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, each committee of the Senate and the House of Representatives may transmit to the Commission any recommendations of the committee to further the legislative policies described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H157C24F9FA5A4D8D9CB316A8E6766D80"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text>The Commission may meet to consider, and vote on, an interim report on—</text> <clause id="H99A9DC74B54748F9927A8BE150C22236"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any findings, conclusions, or recommendations of the Commission relating to the policies identified under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H730F26217C494D12B02E7B4CB5D00DD3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as the Commission determines appropriate, any findings resulting from any hearing held or evidence received by the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2641B3EDB0D47928D0B3E8C6527673B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report, recommendations, and legislative language</header> <clause id="HB110D89930A349A38D36B47BB09393C0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Policy recommendations; permanent actions</header> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52BA9A84539C48918EBA691DA955155D"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Policy recommendations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall meet to consider and vote on—</text> 
<item id="HA09F198F4A4145BBA6E293C8D0E02FF1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a report that contains a detailed statement of the findings, conclusions, and recommendations of the Commission relating to the policies identified under subparagraph (A) and the estimate of the Congressional Budget Office required under paragraph (4)(D); and</text></item> <item id="H6A13AFC0BB6F47FE9EC1D8A3ED4C3E36"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>legislative language to carry out the recommendations of the Commission relating to the policies identified under subparagraph (A), which shall include a statement of the economic and budgetary effects of the recommendations.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1094C0D69214BDFBE40F7ECD47770BD"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Permanent actions</header><text>Not later than 30 days before the date on which the emergency declared under section 3 terminates, the Commission shall meet to consider and vote on—</text> <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A15ABA93E4C4C00BA7CB3873480E79D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report that contains a detailed statement of the actions that were taken in accordance with this Act and findings as to whether any of those actions should be made continued after the date on which the emergency declared under section 3 terminates; and</text></item> 
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5472F22F9B842A1BD74013994D0350D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>if the Commission finds that the actions taken in accordance with this Act should be continued after the date on which the emergency declared under section 3 terminates, legislative language to carry out the actions, which shall include a statement of the economic and budgetary effects of the actions.</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6748A5D236C9407A97A26A4162E03674"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <header>Approval of report and legislative language</header> <text>A report and legislative language of the Commission under subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i) shall require the approval of a majority of the members of the Commission, provided that such majority shall be required to include not fewer than 2 members of the Commission appointed by members of the Republican Party and not fewer than 2 members appointed by members of the Democratic Party.</text>
                        </clause> 
<clause id="HE90690A7C8A54C30BF2BE55078B3185D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Additional views</header><text>A member of the Commission who gives notice of an intention to file supplemental, minority, or additional views at the time of the final Commission vote on the approval of the report and legislative language of the Commission under subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i) shall be entitled to 3 days to file those views in writing with the staff director of the Commission, and such report shall be included in the report of the Commission published under clause (iv).</text></clause> <clause id="H29099A8D02DB48B4B58A5EF285964DE0"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Report and legislative language to be made public</header><text>Upon the approval or disapproval by the Commission of a report and legislative language under subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i), the Commission shall promptly, and not more than 24 hours after the approval or disapproval or, if timely notice is given under clause (iii), not more than 24 hours after additional views are filed under that clause, make the report, the legislative language, and a record of the vote on the report and legislative language available to the public.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF574B192984A4D0792A72BDFC513752B"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Submission of report and legislative language</header><text>If a report and legislative language are approved by the Commission under subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i), not later than 3 days after the date on which the report and legislative language are made available to the public under clause (iv), the Commission shall submit the report and legislative language to the President, the Vice President, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the majority and minority leaders of each House of Congress.</text></clause> <clause id="HAD340020B25E449BBDFDB1CE2B23DCC3"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Extension</header> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBD47CFDD8A7421FA2F20C7D00030B16"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may extend the deadline set forth in subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i), if the Commission determines that additional time is necessary to complete the duties of the Commission under this section.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H437CA61C495642B0A21A87AC65AF3006">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
                                <header>Approval</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An extension under subclause (I) shall require the approval of a majority of the members of the Commission, provided that such majority shall be required to include not fewer than 2 members of the Commission appointed by members of the Republican Party and not fewer than 2 members appointed by members of the Democratic Party.</text>
                            </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H677B17A0B467418EBAEFBF7082D08B5E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFBAA60DD08B846C388D7A8FBB30D307B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 14 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and with due consideration to the chairs and ranking members of the committees and subcommittees of Congress that maintain subject matter jurisdiction, as applicable, the Commission shall be composed of 12 members appointed as follows:</text> <clause id="H801B0782B84F4160B0426F063A6568F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>2 individuals from among the Members of the Senate, and 1 outside expert, appointed by the majority leader of the Senate.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H09CE0569E8714455B352D85EFAA425BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>2 individuals from among the Members of the Senate, and 1 outside expert, appointed by the minority leader of the Senate.</text></clause> <clause id="HE7B693FB4C6B4F4EACF19595999FA15D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>2 individuals from among the Members of the House of Representatives, and 1 outside expert, appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H33E92539610246B98E6046E87A9BC7B0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>2 individuals from among the Members of the House of Representatives, and 1 outside expert, appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB3043C9C11584E6C851B3F015E204E30"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Co-chairs</header><text>Not later than 14 days after the date of enactment of this Act, with respect to the Commission—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3201D295BEAC4AD8BC2B2BABA7280076"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the leadership of the Senate and House of Representatives of the same political party as the President shall appoint 1 individual among the members of the Commission who shall serve as a co-chair of the Commission; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10F75B5AE2FA4FE5A5B0ADA15EAF535E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the leadership of the Senate and House of Representatives of the opposite political party as the President shall appoint 1 individual among the members of the Commission who shall serve as a co-chair of the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03FBE63361264FEBB7A6BF9F949D003B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Staff director</header><text>With respect to the Commission, the co-chairs, acting jointly, shall hire the staff director of the Commission.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE5726325E6B48D59932F6CD4B44DC9D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Period of appointment</header><text>The members of the Commission shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59AFD0CC612A419496C6D436BF22F329"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>Any vacancy in the Commission shall not affect the powers of the Commission, but shall be filled not later than 14 days after the date on which the vacancy occurs, in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC15EE4F781A74E449A0C565C78D8FD2E"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Ineligible members</header><text>If a member of the Commission who was appointed as a Member of the Senate or the House Representatives ceases to be a Member of the Senate or the House of Representatives, as applicable—</text> 
<clause id="HCDDCC702966147FC9F282828913BD21F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the member shall no longer be a member of the Commission; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6E7282A4DB5C448F8463EBE0D4582C17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a vacancy in the Commission exists.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4B0EB61031A44C395F3A6B09BA1BCF4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administration</header> 
<subparagraph id="H925477764E3F45BA90D6748584772DB9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to the Commission, to exercise the powers, functions, and duties of the Commission, there are authorized to be disbursed by the Senate the actual and necessary expenses of the Commission approved by the co-chairs of the Commission, subject to the rules and regulations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B9D73D1037D4617A2875FA2E90EFCE8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expenses</header><text>With respect to the Commission, in carrying out the functions of the Commission, the Commission is authorized to incur expenses in the same manner and under the same conditions as the Joint Economic Committee is authorized under section 11(d) of the Employment Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1024">15 U.S.C. 1024(d)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03F86C7243684E7DA81427EB308B4EE4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Quorum</header> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A72384FF6C54CBB8198D0D4426C86AB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the Commission, 7 members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for purposes of voting, meeting, and holding hearings.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CE280731EC14174A21B32A9FBEE5F42"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Outside experts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Outside experts shall not count for purposes of determining whether there is a quorum under this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5DBE5B34D428466097820C8F20C50FE2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Congressional Budget Office estimates</header><text>The Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall, with respect to the legislative language proposed by the Commission under subclause (I)(bb) or (II)(bb) of paragraph (2)(D)(i), provide to the Commission—</text> <clause id="H61BA5CAD0E814F49AD9BFA667949610C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>estimates of the legislative language in accordance with sections 308(a) and 201(f) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/639">2 U.S.C. 639(a)</external-xref>, 601(f)); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H84A9B5FEB3FF4860BE79BB348E14D8C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information on the budgetary effects of the legislative language on the long-term fiscal outlook.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30618064C04648BDBC03C0D72A7194DA"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Hearings</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2BC95E1A05B45B19DF825488EF38C93"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this section, hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, require attendance of witnesses and production of books, papers, and documents, take such testimony, receive such evidence, and administer such oaths as the Commission considers advisable.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAAFCE0980E0042E38B5E82713CA5DF90"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Hearing procedures and responsibilities of co-chairs</header> 
<subclause id="HBFEECF710FDD400488BCCBDA5605B5DD"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Announcement</header><text>The co-chairs shall make a public announcement of the date, place, time, and subject matter of any hearing to be conducted under this subparagraph not later than 7 days before the date of the hearing, unless the co-chairs determine that there is good cause to begin such hearing on an earlier date.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H98CD04E937F4495E9E36F4E12F5A71BE"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Written statement</header><text>A witness appearing before the Commission shall file a written statement of the proposed testimony of the witness not later than 2 days before the date of the appearance of the witness, unless the co-chairs of the Commission determine that there is good cause for the witness to not file the written statement or waive the requirement.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1CE91A0E3A6F43499F5027E423F08112"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Hearing requirements</header><text>The Commission shall hold not less than 6 hearings under this subparagraph, which shall include—</text> <subclause id="HF7277119E3CC45928856334CB9F6AAA3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>field hearings throughout the United States;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H069608D1B1E94D539C0DDD7D5591D1B6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>hearings to solicit testimony from appropriate officials of the executive branch; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H655A629F5F554C6D9C3E824639D97004"><enum>(III)</enum><text>hearings to solicit testimony from Members of Congress (in this subclause defined as a member of the Senate or the House of Representatives, a Delegate to the House of Representatives, and the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8AD85459108E4276A9E357998F8DA03D"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Technical assistance and consultation</header><text>Upon written request of the co-chairs of the Commission, the head of a Federal agency (including a legislative branch agency) shall provide technical assistance to, and consult with, the Commission in order for the members Commission to carry out the duties of the Commission.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC6CB80993014AE0A031B41D0057E6A3"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Outside expert</header><text>Any outside expert appointed to the Commission—</text> 
<clause id="HA2FC4012A3334C1A8EF6F41F6F2A3739"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not be considered to be a Federal employee for any purpose by reason of service on the Commission; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1939B3DC40F946C9BAB1630CB74DF8A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the outside expert in the performance of services for the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B6574D49AFB4D5D922A123DFA07A2EB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Staff of Commission</header> 
<subparagraph id="H51B4A3F41F9F44DF87555BC70C5FD597"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The co-chairs of Commission may jointly appoint and fix the compensation of staff of the Commission as the co-chairs determine necessary, in accordance with the guidelines, rules, and requirements relating to employees of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32EBE95DDA7B419EA8CF0109D0A10A55"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ethical standards</header> <clause id="HFC3D73E7FD2345AEBC3A259A450CE91F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Senate</header><text>A member of the Commission appointed by a Member of the Senate and staff of the Commission shall adhere to the ethics rules of the Senate.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H71A48FFABF704D779C0D46CB3E559F82"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>House of Representatives</header><text>A member of the Commission appointed by a Member of the House of Representatives shall be governed by the ethics rules and requirements of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70F52267B2B84E38A4568A49FCD4CF49"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Commission shall terminate 30 days after the date the Commission submits the final report under paragraph (2)(D)(v).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCE3BDFA5320A46C4922C3417C5064943"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Funding for the Commission shall be derived in equal portions from—</text> <paragraph id="HA281C6C5E25C4AEC9670F14AEA71719E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the contingent fund of the Senate from the appropriations account <quote>Miscellaneous Items</quote>, subject to the rules and regulations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1590B0E37EEF4154A9056D35CD1986F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

