<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF04D8AC93FDB47E0AEE894D4FD5171AD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5856 IH: District of Columbia Government Title Equality Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5856</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251028">October 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to redesignate the Office of the Mayor of the District of Columbia as the Office of the Governor of the District of Columbia and to redesignate the Council of the District of Columbia as the Legislative Assembly of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFC57D4E5E97F426D8EBB39C1F3DC94C0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5E7B612FD6554D16A14CF7EA42F23EEA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Government Title Equality Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H30EE5CDF97D8480AA2E39FA96E2B10D7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Redesignation of Office of Mayor of District of Columbia as Office of Governor of District of Columbia</header> <subsection id="H1E263D1425E54A4E816E358A3468969B"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Redesignation</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 421(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (sec. 1–204.21(a), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7C57ADF21B8946AF934E4055440E928B"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <subsection id="H5A6870B044D041259A61726165051FC7">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Office of the Governor of the District of Columbia, and the Governor shall be elected by the registered qualified electors of the District.</text>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H55B9E6591CE8461986FA0FA43C857318"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of current Mayor</header><text>For purposes of section 421(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, as amended by subsection (a), the individual holding the Office of Mayor of the District of Columbia as of the date of the enactment of this Act shall be deemed to have been elected to the Office of Governor of the District of Columbia by the registered qualified electors of the District.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6AF2873FC14849EAAA91BCB1172BC28B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References in law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference to the Office of the Mayor of the District of Columbia in any law, rule, or regulation of the United States or the District of Columbia shall be deemed to refer to the Office of the Governor of the District of Columbia, and any reference to the Mayor of the District of Columbia in any law, rule, or regulation of the United States or the District of Columbia shall be deemed to refer to the Governor of the District of Columbia.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H7F55AB8CBAF747FF92F333E44CCF4D06"><enum>3.</enum><header>Redesignation of Council of District of Columbia as Legislative Assembly of District of Columbia</header>
<subsection id="HBDBF2D6616CB43EAA2612BB5D1CE85DB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Redesignation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (sec. 1–204.01(a), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <quoted-block style="traditional" id="H0A5175DDDAF942AEAA927932AE733C60"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <subsection id="H94D7096C1D374B69809B5494EA43A9FE">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
 <text>There is established a Legislative Assembly of the District of Columbia, consisting of Representatives who shall be elected by the registered qualified electors of the District.</text>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H289D175B93924F46A12469C325F66101"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of current Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 401(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, as amended by subsection (a), any individual holding the Office of Member of the Council of the District of Columbia as of the date of the enactment of this Act shall be deemed to have been elected to the Office of Representative of the Legislative Assembly of the District of Columbia by the registered qualified electors of the District.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDD754BD36C9B4CE581F366BF70394C63"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References in law</header><text>Any reference to the Council of the District of Columbia in any law, rule, or regulation of the United States or the District of Columbia shall be deemed to refer to the Legislative Assembly of the District of Columbia, and any reference to a Member of the Council of the District of Columbia in any law, rule, or regulation of the United States or the District of Columbia shall be deemed to refer to a Representative of the Legislative Assembly of the District of Columbia.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H93EF4DED29CC499E9FBAA1F72E2285A5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Redesignation of Chair of Council of District of Columbia as Speaker of Legislative Assembly of District of Columbia</header>
<subsection id="H2546EF6E022A4C32A72838E55AA9F9C8">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Redesignation</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 411(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (sec. 1–204.11(a) D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <quoted-block style="traditional" id="HF3EF68D3EE5348B18A269E667457A2C1"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <subsection id="HE569FB83FDEB445F9E858BCDD33C898B">
            <enum>(a)</enum>
 <text>The Speaker of the Legislative Assembly of the District of Columbia shall be the presiding officer of the Legislative Assembly.</text>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HC40B3D6B28BB4711B7B2EC7A817BDB36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of current chair</header><text>For purposes of section 411(a) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act, as amended by subsection (a), the individual holding the Office of Chair of the Council of the District of Columbia as of the date of the enactment of this Act shall be deemed to have been elected to the Office of Speaker of the Legislative Assembly of the District of Columbia by the registered qualified electors of the District.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8C707EA24F014541948DE454226EF8BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References in law</header><text>Any reference to the Office of the Chair of the Council of the District of Columbia in any law, rule, or regulation of the United States or the District of Columbia shall be deemed to refer to the Office of the Speaker of the Legislative Assembly of the District of Columbia, and any reference to the Chair of the Council of the District of Columbia in any law, rule, or regulation of the United States or the District of Columbia shall be deemed to refer to the Speaker of the Legislative Assembly of the District of Columbia.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

