<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H945E94B2488A4FDD88DA8932181180DE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7516 IH: No Funds for Forced Labor Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7516</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the United States Executive Directors at the international financial institutions to advocate for opposition to projects that make use of forced labor.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H319D2DE46A14484FB3A3D37E25DB1D7B" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H79C6FB26557B4BA1BA9010F27F3D5851"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Funds for Forced Labor Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB64E9DF6CB044AD1B452B7ED65C8FB94"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H1122BBF9545F4BC8AC2A9B12361CC7B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The International Labour Organization has expressed <quote>deep concern</quote> about the <quote>extensive use of forced labor in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H880924D656494310BFF59D6FD91F041E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In its 2022 annual report, the Congressional-Executive Commission on China found, <quote>Authorities in the XUAR (Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region) maintained a system of forced labor that involved former mass internment camp detainees and other Turkic and Muslim individuals.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE451BA5402A94F0A8BA70AEE2549202C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2022, the Atlantic Council published a report detailing that the World Bank’s private lending body, the International Finance Corporation, determined that several clients of the Corporation were active participants in the People’s Republic of China campaign against the Uyghur people and Uyghur culture in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEA8BAF238CF841E88707BBC81C22B1AB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H6E62A24D33814D63B255E853B00CCDF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>international financial institutions should not fund, finance, or provide loan guarantees to any entity that has been credibly accused of using forced labor; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C368E6FD3EC4EF7AE47EE5BCA282AE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States should work with allies, partners, and all countries around the globe to eliminate forced labor and ensure that international financial institutions do not fund projects that use forced labor.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H48388CB649824688BD7709E52D25F32F"><enum>4.</enum><header>United States opposition to international financial institution loans for projects that would use, or have a significant risk of using, forced labor</header><subsection id="HF0C88F6B24C149B7911189979EEF2464"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title VII of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262d">22 U.S.C. 262d</external-xref>, 262c note, 262e, and 262d note) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H649F21AA7DE04453AA0743F5660F2BBF"><section id="HA89EB6AE541B4BD0BA452175115FF6DD"><enum>706.</enum><header>United States opposition to loans for projects that would use, or have a significant risk of using, forced labor</header><subsection id="H82F2B241C51943C7BF70D154FE140207"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director at each international financial institution (as defined in section 1701(c)(2)) to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States, to the maximum extent practicable, to—</text><paragraph id="H31A8BE7A86F24AEBA655702E39465D1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>oppose the provision of a loan to any project that will—</text><subparagraph id="H7A2FF40FEE9C4202A18A25BDD397B4DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pose a significant risk of using forced labor; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39E18FCE010E4AE6B57E6C3E8963DD0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be carried out by a state-owned or heavily state-influenced entity in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of the People's Republic of China; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B5AE2B5E1DE4E35A7BCC5364749C0A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the institution to provide, with respect to each project supported by the institution, an explanation, specific to the project, of—</text><subparagraph id="H43EEB94485B349C89822A6D71FE6244F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the institution has vetted the project for forced labor risks; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DB9B3103101469D900F0D0EF9706D45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the actions taken to mitigate, track, and reverse that risk.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H061E1FB2ED80418D990C17A81E96718F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of forced labor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>forced labor</term>—</text><paragraph id="H34E78E31799441659DC0421255720466"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB811268E27F472D892ED4CB121E57B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes convict labor and indentured labor under penal sanctions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB1757C6F840A4F5D9FE5F61D6C6AC88C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="HCDBD4CFE5E384BD29BF07AC270CEF547"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the next 5 years, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the committees specified in paragraph (2) a written report on the implementation of the amendment made by subsection (a), which shall include details about—</text><subparagraph id="H508E6259C2064EC2B7272E6BD4377889"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any project approved by an international financial institution (as defined in section 1701(c)(2) of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262r">22 U.S.C. 262r(c)(2)</external-xref>)) in which forced labor could possibly be used; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DDB10F4E1784A85B2B4E6D6A66BD09A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the efforts of the United States Executive Director at each such institution to convince other countries to oppose any project in which forced labor could be used.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE57E63F8103B410DABA29D34A6361A6D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Committees specified</header><text>The committees specified in this paragraph are—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF3D45630C9141D792386B23145804D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EF4CA70DB154B0D9F7B0899A1D3FD17"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DB12BCEF37B4510A3E9D8AB53D1B015"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public availability</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall make the report (or an unclassified version of the report) available to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

