<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-LAN25189-GJK-RF-8V3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 507 ATS: Designating November 20, 2025, as “National Rural Health Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 507</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating November 20, 2025, as <quote>National Rural Health Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas over 66,300,000 hardworking individuals in the United States live in rural communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals in the United States in rural areas live in pursuit of the common good and keep values of the United States alive by fostering a spirit of generosity and respect among neighbors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas rural health care providers and patients showcase a selfless and community-minded spirit;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas rural areas in the United States are places of opportunity for—</text><paragraph id="id63428804a4654ce29a61d82276c3e924"><enum>(1)</enum><text>mission-minded health professionals to provide individualized care to patients and entire communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f1a2e8c807347638a91415589c9dc95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fueling innovations in rural health infrastructure, quality, and delivery of health care;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas rural health care providers are—</text><paragraph id="id3329478832e6461fab74e2fb8d31ee5a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>uniquely positioned to provide value-based holistic care; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33e85c6bf4de4bccbed91cd80ee6fb2e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>known and trusted by their patients;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas rural residents tend to experience lower life expectancy and poorer health status due to structural, behavioral, and geographic factors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas rural residents face barriers to accessing health care due to a shortage of primary and specialized health care providers, lack of reliable transportation or transportation options, increased exposure to public health and occupational hazards, and higher rates of uninsured and underinsured individuals;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas rural health facilities in the United States face systemic challenges, including clinician workforce shortages and lower volumes of services spread over fixed costs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the systemic challenges rural health facilities face have contributed to 153 rural hospital closures or hospital conversions since 2010; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas 50 percent of rural hospitals in the United States are operating with negative margins and nearly 432 rural hospitals are vulnerable to closure, further demonstrating the need to accelerate efforts to reinforce the rural health safety net;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the systemic challenges rural health facilities face make it increasingly difficult for rural health care facilities to keep their doors open to serve patients;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Rural Health Day was established to honor rural communities in the United States and the contributions and efforts of rural communities in addressing the unique challenges facing rural health care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the National Organization of State Offices of Rural Health has recognized National Rural Health Day to be the third Thursday of each November since 2011, in collaboration with partners such as the National Rural Health Association; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Rural Health Day will be recognized this year on November 20, 2025: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ida4c96a1e92134c559a65caff98524abd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates November 20, 2025, as <quote>National Rural Health Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf47bd4bb689f4e609918dc05985fa13d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes and supports the goals and ideals of National Rural Health Day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida619f02769c045df8b3e05fb158a0a30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>celebrates rural health care providers and the millions of individuals in the United States that rural health care providers serve; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id718015a4ea8c4b1a858f04d57b5c7062"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expresses a commitment to advancing policies to improve health care accessibility and affordability in rural areas of the United States. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

