<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA049711A7754594ADA2C3BBD73B1EB5" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 842 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that a statue of Charles “Charlie” James Kirk should be accepted for display in the House of Representatives wing of the United States Capitol to honor his enduring legacy of free expression, civic leadership, and unwavering commitment to the American principles of faith, family, and freedom.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 842</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that a statue of Charles <quote>Charlie</quote> James Kirk should be accepted for display in the House of Representatives wing of the United States Capitol to honor his enduring legacy of free expression, civic leadership, and unwavering commitment to the American principles of faith, family, and freedom.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas Charles <quote>Charlie</quote> Kirk was an inspirational figure in conservative politics;</text>
                </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Charlie founded Turning Point USA in 2012, with the mission of educating students on the principles of fiscal responsibility, free markets, and limited government;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas, under Charlie’s leadership, Turning Point USA encouraged open debate and emphasized the importance of civic engagement in a way that drew millions to its mission;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Charlie understood that the United States Constitution is the most important political document in history, enshrining and protecting the God-given rights of every human from the heavy hand of government;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Charlie served as an example of the best of humanity, treating everyone he encountered with respect, offering them the truth, and maintaining a willingness to engage in dialogue with anyone he encountered; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Charlie was assassinated for his beliefs and work on September 10, 2025, in direct contradiction with the right and ideal of freedom of speech on which our nation was founded: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H0D47101D4D2E4D7F8A1E751BAA7F993A"> <section id="H8D1E7F5A563D4D3F9845CAB6718387F7" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That not later than January 2, 2027, the House of Representatives Fine Arts Board shall accept a statue of Charles James Kirk and, at the direction of the Speaker, permanently display the statue in a prominent place in the House of Representatives wing of the United States Capitol.</text></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

