<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H97DDF6F112D8440E866F36124E876C20" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8926 IH: State and Local Public Sector Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8926</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to establish a grant program to modernize the technology of State and local governments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3D178CA593224B3C8F6375B070FFECDA" style="OLC"><section id="H2EDEF96055EB4BD3B4CE9E947635F23D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State and Local Public Sector Innovation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF3B9553F1BC440F78E41E756EDB99685"><enum>2.</enum><header>State and local government technology modernization grant program</header><subsection id="H3602EDEC21A149B1852007EB698025EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall establish a grant program to modernize the technology utilized by State and local governments in order to improve the security and efficacy of public services.</text></subsection><subsection id="H073027746FD54BB99AFE004322FDCD7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each fiscal year, the Assistant Secretary shall distribute among the States the total amount made available for grants under the Program with respect to such fiscal year in the following manner:</text><paragraph id="H46D7E28DC5DB41AB9424C9769F79C096"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent of such total amount shall be distributed in a manner that provides to each State the portion of such 50 percent amount that bears the same ratio to such 50 percent amount as the ratio that—</text><subparagraph id="H3B226A1A780F464B94959BB7ADFFB5AD"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the population of such State; bears to</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71FEE9318A784770B2ED83FA4C162A25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total population of all States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09665F339026425088F335BDBB5CE000"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent of such total amount shall be distributed among the States according to the needs of each State with respect to modernizing the technology of government entities in such State, as determined by the Assistant Secretary in accordance with subsection (e)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C215F54A0DA4739ABB75D4797E2D29D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recipients of grant funds</header><text>Each grant made to a State under the Program shall be provided to the State technology department of such State for use in accordance with subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCDB307BDF8AA432B8C5AACA19693BAA6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant uses</header><paragraph id="HD487994D91E942A5B1E61E8921C9DAA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State technology department that receives grant funds under the Program may use such grant funds to assist any government entity of such State, or any government entity of a political subdivision of such State, to modernize the technology utilized by such government entity in order to improve the security and efficacy of public services, including through any of the following actions:</text><subparagraph id="H86D584D110734ED0A138EAA1E0113DB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Purchasing or updating technology and related infrastructure, including technology and infrastructure related to artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F16964D1DFB400196DD220D463A44C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Conducting testing to determine needs with respect to technology modernization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1785D15ADD0948CD812E5CBB20D5ED65"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Updating permitting processes as necessary to facilitate technology modernization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A5F380541EB40AFBF045415A4C39053"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Establishing or upgrading cybersecurity systems and processes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F8A7B3821164AB098A10025229D2652"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Hiring and maintaining staff as necessary to support technology modernization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA00706748DDD4681A2053B1F3446F053"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Training staff as necessary to support technology modernization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85B9FFBC68CC48979FBA07905A62217D"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Transitioning technology to meet standards with respect to post-quantum cryptography.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20409F7C8BAA43D7B342C170C027E91A"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Complying with the covered mandates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF82E66995DF04447A8B4EC9D34586BD1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local focus</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall require, as a condition of a grant under the Program, that at least 70 percent of the amount provided for a State under such grant be provided directly to political subdivisions of such State for use in accordance with paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H455D0B3C12DA4B68BD1741F53118C878"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Set aside for covered mandates</header><text>If the Assistant Secretary determines pursuant to subsection (e)(2) that a State is not complying with the covered mandates, the Assistant Secretary may require, as a condition of a grant under the Program, that such State set aside up to 15 percent of the amount provided under such grant for actions necessary to comply with the covered mandates.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC38D24596E384D6BB40D9EAC253990E9" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Survey</header><paragraph id="H0A35D4D0DFE84096B5B204032A2BF73A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Need determinations</header><text>To determine the relative needs of States for purposes of subsection (b)(2), the Assistant Secretary shall complete, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, a survey to collect from the State technology department of each State information with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HBA6808BE72934144B319A370AB8ABB6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the technology utilized and data stored by government entities in such State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82C02FE3C5BF4540A802C4E19D7D82BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the modernization readiness, interoperability, and regulatory compliance, with respect to technology, of government entities in such State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E4B15C82C6B49BD9BB1358495CEB033"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any technology modernization planning of such State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88C6D2B7899B4FB69771161C5D4BF7BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered mandates determination</header><text>For purposes of subsection (d)(3), the Assistant Secretary shall collect from each State, though the survey completed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, information necessary to determine whether such State is complying with the covered mandates.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD67B0E033DE24D3E8B714B7285CCF743"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall make available to government entities assisted with grant funds under the Program technical assistance, including technical assistance with respect to—</text><paragraph id="H6F6C2F6AD0E64A18BBF534A2A0C9FFA3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data security best practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB6D13E391E347B6BBB2EF4791739E88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>privacy best practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76198A7CA4D646D7ABF58C8A259B4986"><enum>(3)</enum><text>cyber threat monitoring and awareness; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DAA8BCB89344CC28AF72AA644A3B79C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>compliance with the covered mandates, including related best practices and timelines.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1EE8FF9480B042B8A4FB0F1EBE838848" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall publish guidance with respect to the Program, including guidance—</text><paragraph id="HAFB10AF0A136466A838076AD71AC7473" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the use of grant funds made available under the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H654BEAE8160A411F96521BA6BFB3066A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for utilizing consensus-based technical standards in carrying out the Program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8ACF42B98B64705B4C5FB55CDE1484A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to ensure that any artificial intelligence system of a government entity assisted with grant funds made available under the Program, if used for an interaction with a member of the public, includes a notification that artificial intelligence is being used.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6ECCDF01D8EC485F9BB9491E4FD4CD16"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Assistant Secretary shall consult with representatives of the following:</text><paragraph id="H76C7873E80994408BD56CC8D48431E3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Academia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8216284BDCA74E5C9B5C9F7EFFD32FA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Scientific societies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14317FE6929A4D91A0A4D56342715394"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Industry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E46AC837BA94259A009E134B7642EB9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Civil society organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE568123E2554151B2DA0540546B75C1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>State and local government information technology experts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE591DCC590A14A2A9009DAD043B9EA22"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Other stakeholder groups the Assistant Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCBFD533B1B17454CA1CEDD3ECF55B14C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the Program, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="H5BE77E5650C74D0580F087CAB06DD02E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data on the impact of the Program on State and local government technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE93BA84B2C6344B98CDAF4A15B29EBC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any obstacles encountered in implementing the Program and how such obstacles were addressed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1A01637A934FEBAF2DE89B17B03655"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations on any additional resources necessary to support the Program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H599D7C4EA71D4060B6E3DCC0B6F710FC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an analysis of whether the Program should be authorized for additional fiscal years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H761E6A33F6AE45649A5CB0D6F8FD8B04"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the Program $500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBC9F4DEDECDA4C7DB8454376FB447E82"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H1E67EC3F68074C96A00D9CAE716AF76B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6F2646844697458CAA477CFF60D92017"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the House of Representatives—</text><clause id="HCED3E458E930496EBA2E7CC9BEA90E6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce; and</text></clause><clause id="HB5BB217FB45743828CDFBBDF77E533CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H275F35B1484B432B8BFA75219D847664"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the Senate, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57D92D5DA35D49FFB64730193DDB1D28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20BABA38882D4F26A23142450CD33B69" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90FB6DE0DF5047DD9BFFDD10A91F502F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered mandates</header><text>The term <term>covered mandates</term> means, with respect to a State, that such State, as determined by the Assistant Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H27FEB1BB0E7C4171B57B37722C64517D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a Chief Data Officer or an individual serving in a substantially similar position;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09EE257DBC0A4E878FB1851B0DCF1F16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has, and is implementing, a data privacy, inventory and classification system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H526424F8F6F9486CB6F50202BD8CE066"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has, and is implementing, data life-cycle policies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB737792A02764382AAE5457A0CB6F0CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is complying with the most recent cybersecurity and risk management frameworks of the National Institute of Standards and Technology of the Department of Commerce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85E3D61B5164465989321B327410C241"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Post-quantum cryptography</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>post-quantum cryptography</term> means cryptographic algorithms and methods that are assessed not to be specifically vulnerable to attack by a quantum, or classical, computer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D9E411B078E4DC288BC870DF82A75AA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Program</term> means the grant program established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H906EC37E8A7149719D9D752E4EBFE897"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each territory or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00777F2690AA4346B0BCD993D5A5D336"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State technology department</header><text>The term <term>State technology department</term> means the department or agency of a State that the Governor or chief executive of such State designates, for purposes of the Program, as the primary department or agency of such State with respect to technology provision and services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

