<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDFBCFE4D43764175B05655CEB4A3BB8B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8927 IH: Stop the Doxx Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8927</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the doxxing of law enforcement officers, prosecutors, and judges, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC9E467F40CE341ACAC41931895CD854C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H226086B5FF2841EC9E1C2AF0B38B38CD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop the Doxx Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA114EA36B5B34F90904A85B3DC9DAB11"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H86A3CC50BF544801A03C0E2C09386B2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Targeted harassment of law enforcement officers, prosecutors, and judges has increased significantly in recent years, including threats made possible by the online publication of personal information.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4592214F70F04F1CAEEE6BB1F766764A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The publication of home addresses, personal contact information, and family details of public servants with intent to intimidate poses a direct threat to public safety and the integrity of the justice system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6108B45F1644B46B9AE13F54CD6D7CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>No comprehensive Federal statute currently prohibits this conduct.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF3617B7DFBA94D9CBAA6ADE5E38CDC62"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on doxxing of protected public servants</header> <subsection id="H92E74500066B4007BF4D04CD4737B8AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/73">Chapter 73</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H17ABAB4927AC4866BD9B934D6DB49237" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H0B321937E87043319FBF82C03C2D1F22"><enum>1522.</enum><header>Doxxing of protected public servants</header> 
<subsection id="H1928A5DA9FD646B785D50BB2F559DA85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Offense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, knowingly publishes or otherwise makes publicly available the home address, personal telephone number, personal email address, or other personally identifying information of a covered public servant or an immediate family member, with intent to threaten, intimidate, or facilitate violence against that person, shall be—</text> <paragraph id="HB049FDCA1A494F34854CA49DF4A03873"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a first offense, fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FED903221D04063A576768BC8E5D91F">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a second or subsequest offense, fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both; or</text>
                            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED51784FD9D544279852BD34BD0EF9A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case of an offense that results in bodily injury or death—</text> <subparagraph id="H440DAAB16DC74A5584B0E7CA4A9EE16F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a first offense, fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 30 years, or both; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB1E6AC077FA46BEBB67BFADD7E89693">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a second or subsequent offense, fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 40 years, or both.</text>
                                </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5137AC84163040F8ACC9AC6A5E0CED1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text>A covered public servant or an immediate family member who is the victim of a violation of this section may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States. In a civil action under this subsection, the court may award damages, injunctive relief, and attorney's fees.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB99613CE2A684F1F9E54A2DDA6B07013"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD1CEB5396DF14E4183E364496E6235E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>covered public servant</term> means a Federal, State, or local law enforcement officer, prosecutor, or judge.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF3E7286684F7415CABC767DF9C3DE593"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>immediate family member</term> means a spouse, child, parent, or sibling of a covered public servant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23B89F26BCFE4BB5BF5F2E2C5B38B1F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>publishes</term> means to post on a publicly accessible website, social media platform, online forum, or any other digital or print medium accessible to third parties.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H2C47A4F91F504A7DB0DEC766440BF596"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/73">chapter 73</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HB66FF4238E9E4E4BBD59B934974A388A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">1522. Doxxing of protected public servants.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA6263A1682B04E4CB1A599130E3B97F1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Training for protected public servants on personal information security</header> 
<subsection id="HB01361C8CFCF4704904DED6D7BA0B2C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall establish and make available a comprehensive training program for covered public servants (as such term is defined in section 1522 of title 18, United States Code) on protecting personal information online.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB89B46C6722F4A97A92DB571E29E9C12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Delivery and Accessibility</header><text>The training program shall be—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0A2399B9126947B7A1E35ACD60129AB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>made available online and through in-person formats to accommodate Federal, State, and local agencies of varying size and resource capacity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CD8C5D008C14C4CBA3B0C1C93D115B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>updated no less than annually to reflect current threats and evolving digital environments; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H134F6629A5D140DAA7A4CE21249C292A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>offered at no cost to covered public servants at the Federal, State, and local level.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB17AF8ECA37D42D7BFC40451CE5283D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Encouragement to State and Local Agencies</header><text>The Attorney General shall encourage State and local law enforcement agencies, prosecutorial offices, and court systems to require completion of the training program established under this section as part of their standard onboarding and annual continuing education requirements.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFD54A99AC2A94CE1B56674297B0638C7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

