<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H02E4B555127344BB9377BE9B89886B04" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 816 IH: Commending and congratulating the Summerlin South Little League baseball team on winning the 2025 Little League World Series United States Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 816</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251017">October 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending and congratulating the Summerlin South Little League baseball team on winning the 2025 Little League World Series United States Championship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 23, 2025, the Summerlin South Little League baseball team (referred to in this resolution as the <quote>Summerlin South</quote>) won the 2025 Little League World Series United States Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Summerlin South Little League defeated Fairfield National Little League, winning the United States Championship 8–2;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this is the first team from Summerlin South to advance to the Little League World Series Tournament in Williamsport, Pennsylvania;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Summerlin South became the second team from Nevada to win the Little League World Series United States Championship since the State began competing in 1957;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Summerlin South is the fourth team from Nevada to advance to the Little League World Series Tournament in Williamsport, Pennsylvania;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Summerlin South won all 3 games in the Mountain Region Tournament, outscoring opponents 45–15 and winning the region finals by a score of 6–3;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Summerlin South players should be congratulated for their dedication, teamwork, and display of impressive athletic talent; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas behind the Summerlin South players is a team of parents, coaches, and league support staff without whom those players could not have been successful: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H632AE2665F2A4FA2B8F850F5455B3FAC"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF0241AF65EEC486291FBF1F7E52EFE8C"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H5998D5A2AB734A29918C79A1E8A94AF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends and congratulates Summerlin South Little League on winning the 2025 Little League World Series United States Championship and completing a successful 2025 season;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7414563B84A740D580FD1897A123E7F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the achievements of all players, coaches, parents, and league support staff who contributed to the success of Summerlin South Little League during the 2025 season; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CB267AECFBF4D9EBD3372AD973C3FF9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Clerk of the House of Representatives transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="H86B75BCC3F9849C88CF3881888DD85E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Summerlin South president Chris Mallory; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CE980B5C1FF435CABFC48A7A74F0BFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Summerlin South manager TJ Fechser.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

