<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4651104C8437489FB21565DACE1083EB" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 880 IH: Recognizing the strategic value of the historical partnership between the United States and India.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 880</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251117">November 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the strategic value of the historical partnership between the United States and India.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Republic of India achieved its independence on August 15, 1947, marking the birth of the world’s largest democracy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, for more than three decades, it has been the policy of the United States under administrations of Presidents Clinton, Bush, Obama, Trump, and Biden to strengthen the strategic partnership with India, recognizing its importance to regional stability, democratic governance, economic growth, and shared regional priorities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States-India Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership is essential to regional stability, economic growth, and global security;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to United Nations, India is the most populous country in the world, with an estimated population of more than 1,428,000,000 people;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas strong people-to-people and educational exchanges between the United States and the Republic of India cement our Nation’s ties and serve as the foundation for deeper cooperation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2004, the United States and India signed the Next Step in Strategic Partnership which laid the foundation for expanded cooperation in civilian nuclear energy, defense, and high technology;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2005, the United States and India issued the joint statement on Civil Nuclear Cooperation leading to the passage of the Henry J. Hyde United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006 and the subsequent conclusion of the United States-India 123 Agreement in 2008;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India has twice addressed joint meetings of Congress, first on June 8, 2016, under the leadership of Speaker Paul D. Ryan, and again on June 22, 2023, under the leadership of Speaker Kevin McCarthy, both times with bipartisan support from the leadership of the House of Representatives and the Senate reflecting the enduring support within Congress for strengthening the United States-India partnership;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the strength of the United States-India partnership has been reflected through historic people-to-people events, including the <quote>Howdy, Modi!</quote> gathering in Houston, Texas, on September 22, 2019, where Prime Minister Narendra Modi and President Donald J. Trump jointly addressed more than 50,000 Indian Americans, and the <quote>Namaste Trump</quote> event in Ahmedabad, India, on February 24, 2020, which celebrated the enduring friendship between the American and Indian peoples;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Mumbai terror attacks on November 26–29, 2008, led to the deaths of 166 individuals, including citizens from both India and the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on April 22, 2025, a terrorist attack in Pahalgam claimed the lives of 26 civilians and injured dozens more, and was claimed by The Resistance Front (a proxy of Lashkar-e-Taiba), highlighting the persistent threat of cross-border and proxy terrorism in South Asia;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in the wake of the Pahalgam attack, the Government of the United States designated The Resistance Front as a foreign terrorist organization and as a specially designated global terrorist underscoring the alignment of United States and Indian efforts to hold terror groups accountable;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas India and the United States maintain a dedicated counterterrorism dialogue mechanism and regularly coordinate on terrorist designations, intelligence sharing, mutual legal assistance, extraditions, and related counterterrorism cooperation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas enhancing counterterrorism cooperation between the United States and India is essential to protect citizens, strengthen regional stability, disrupt terrorist networks, and promote a rules-based international order;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States designated India as a Major Defense Partner in 2016, and a strong United States-India defense partnership is critical for United States and Indian interests in the Indo-Pacific region;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States and India subsequently signed the Logistics Exchange Memorandum of Agreement, Communications Compatibility and Security Agreement, Strategic Trade Authorization Tier 1, Industrial Security Agreement, and Basic Exchange and Cooperation Agreement to deepen defense interoperability and secure technology sharing;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the two countries launched the Initiative on Critical and Emerging Technologies in 2023 to cover cooperation in semiconductors, artificial intelligence, quantum technologies, and space which was renamed United States-India Transforming the Relationship Utilizing Strategic Technology to focus on artificial intelligence infrastructure;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States and India also cooperate through multilateral institutions, including the Quad, comprising the United States, India, Japan, and Australia, which was elevated to the ministerial level under the Trump administration and to the leader’s level under the Biden administration, reflecting bipartisan recognition of the Quad’s indispensable role in advancing regional stability, maritime security, and global cooperation;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States and India agreed to a Drug Policy Framework in 2024 agreement and Memorandum of Understanding, aimed at disrupting the trafficking of illicit synthetic drugs;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the two countries signed the Bilateral Cultural Property Agreement in 2024 to facilitate the return of stolen or trafficked cultural artifacts;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas both countries signed a Memorandum of Understanding on Cybercrime Investigations in January 2025 to enhance cooperation in cybercrime investigations, digital forensics, and intelligence;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the diverse Indian-American community, which numbers over four million individuals, is critical to the strong people-to-people ties between India and the United States and forms one of the strongest bonds linking our two countries together; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Indian Americans have made significant and enduring contributions to the United States across diverse fields, including business, academia, science, technology, medicine, health care, public service, and the arts, demonstrating through their innovation, hard work, and civic engagement the promise of the American Dream: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H4CB4949C6CE84CF1872761E75D6A6C5C"> <section id="H63F32353317F46109939EE422AA43D21" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCE0D2551109349208AC6363CDA8A04A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirms the strong and long-standing partnership between the Governments of the United States and the Republic of India, rooted in people-to-people ties, strategic interests, including upholding peace, security, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE08599A50EC4446AA1DAF21B7098F58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the United States and India to continue and expand cooperation for a free, open, and resilient Indo-Pacific, including through the Quad;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA2936FBBD6C44B0B80BC89C032CA929"><enum>(3)</enum><text>welcomes the Republic of India’s participation in economic initiatives, including through bilateral and multilateral forums, its participation in the Quad, and other venues of cooperation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D1E7236D44A41AD90442989D329DE36"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the United States and the Republic of India identifying further opportunities to deepen engagement and further defense, commercial, and investment ties;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E4C1DE40E034A5BA9F428F43FAD0850"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls for continued cooperation on counterterrorism including the swift prosecution of the perpetrators of the 2008 Mumbai terror attacks;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE809B9D3BEEF4987B309EF5246D0D0FB"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms the importance of technology cooperation between the United States and India, including through the United States-India Transforming the Relationship Utilizing Strategic Technology;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2BC3916821345B6ABA95A88BDEDF439"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of expanding people-to-people programs between the United States and India, particularly between educational institutions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA418DB77DAB4473B092E81BB8F1BF72"><enum>(8)</enum><text>appreciates the contributions of the Indian-American diaspora, and desires closer relations between the people of the United States and the people of India;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B6BDC23648B4C8293EB9D184204CE5F"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes India’s growing energy needs as an essential component of its economic development, and applauds India for increasing its purchases of United States energy resources, which enhance mutual energy security, economic prosperity, and bilateral cooperation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD854E87109C4C0CB39FC3560FC00E08"><enum>(10)</enum><text>views the bilateral relationship as holding the potential to bring significant benefit to the citizens of both nations, and to make considerable contributions to addressing the global challenges of the 21st century.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

