<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG25626-JDG-LG-750"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3406 IS: Partnering Aspiring Teachers with High-need Schools to Tutor Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3406</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a grant program for innovative partnerships among teacher preparation programs, local educational agencies, and community-based organizations to expand access to high-quality tutoring in hard-to-staff schools and high-need schools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6DC5749BCF134414B8E1847254789DCA"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Partnering Aspiring Teachers with High-need Schools to Tutor Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PATHS to Tutor Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idD79841B603C34965905386DDA157A94F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program for high-quality tutoring</header><subsection id="id94F62073A14F4494957CBBBCC164594A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="iddae4451b3c1b408b9195c4f6340e2a10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Educational service agency</header><text>The term <term>educational service agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc4b8c451f53c4df79abe8a53bf7f1ebe"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Educator preparation program</header><text>The term <term>educator preparation program</term> means a State-accredited program at a public or nonprofit institution of higher education or other nonprofit provider that prepares individuals to serve as educators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf52454e9fd984b028ee2393b61bb2be5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hard-to-staff school</header><text>The term <term>hard-to-staff school</term> means a high-need school that has a high rate of teacher turnover or a large concentration of teachers in their first or second year of teaching.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD699BB525D75432E8F75CBC45C5321C4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-need school</header><text>The term <term>high-need school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2211 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6631">20 U.S.C. 6631</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id081EF500B4CF484294521A30B8DFF354"><enum>(5)</enum><header>High-quality tutoring</header><text>The term <term>high-quality tutoring</term> means tutoring—</text><subparagraph id="idb5de422e0cb143d39b514ed06952a01c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is provided by a tutor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb88941e5648248499fb6d75a2000c825"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is one-on-one or in a small group not to exceed a ratio of 1 tutor to 4 students, or a small group ratio based on evidence determined sufficient by the State educational agency in the State in which the tutoring takes place;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id1e61dd3df8d04072aaf5bdb0cbd1251f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that includes plans and time for tutors to collaborate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c0d44a5a7ce4fabbc9e0ef82b2037c7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that—</text><clause id="id32a9ba66f71243e2a42456807ecaf3c3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes multiple sessions each week that are of sufficient length, such as the length of a regularly scheduled class or period; and</text></clause><clause id="ideaccf3a771c242ee831739ada43a7064"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0526a62ff7d8467dad674e98f8f6a1e8"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">embedded in the school schedule, preferably during the regular school day or tightly integrated to the regular school day and provided before or after school; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23ea1b58aaa84f3993d65fd12b209446"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during school vacations;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide33490f5db9a47b4ac09508c09e82114"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in which content and grade-specific tutors are matched with students;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc15333ccfe244608964859d63b26c554"><enum>(F)</enum><text>that is aligned to local standards and curriculum;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e8ec3b923044dd1a3ea98cada100b45"><enum>(G)</enum><text>that includes high-quality pre-service training and ongoing professional support;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id295238b289424612b365ae4b7dd31651"><enum>(H)</enum><text>that a local consortium facilitates by—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf877ea9206d4405a946caec2f5f5ad2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the local educational agency and schools in the local consortium supporting tutors through direct supervision and feedback; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08200a2e747c437b8596960e606c6f72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the faculty or staff of the educator preparation program in the local consortium providing additional capacity; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddc5b5c4eb2c749eeb2b8a6fddc68c182"><enum>(I)</enum><text>where tutors are adequately compensated for their work.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id89CF841849BD4CD9A687DD522D00600B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Local consortium</header><text>The term <term>local consortium</term> means a consortium consisting of community partners as follows:</text><subparagraph id="iddd4aae8f0eb544ca8c1aacc15715633f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The consortium shall include the following entities, one or both of which shall serve as the lead entity of the consortium:</text><clause id="id66a4a3312bfb4654aa11f374c75b390e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A local educational agency, an individual school, or an educational service agency.</text></clause><clause id="idE613214BFC8E4414A5DB9DF4BBD55323"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>An educator preparation program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16CE4A360A334FE08FABE36038A29B65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The consortium may include a community partner, such as—</text><clause id="id797e37ef57d64d02a60ad651c363f036"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a community-based organization;</text></clause><clause id="idd7d7ee01a44d4fa18b90d43802e62bb4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a child- and youth-serving organization or agency;</text></clause><clause id="id32b8f813863e422396044af7f642fbad"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an institution of higher education, as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="id68362fddd25f42c594541a7c02a59e59"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a foundation;</text></clause><clause id="id406a0c7c9f374118afc79d9c0d9c7018"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an educator organization;</text></clause><clause id="id11bc4be606b44d68b3e7cb2e54e5ada8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>an organization representing education professionals;</text></clause><clause id="id988da71acf844d96bf0164dc670334a7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a local government, including a government agency serving children and youth, such as a child welfare and juvenile justice agency;</text></clause><clause id="id3e4e6853987a4c579a92f23e64158a65"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>an organization representing students; or</text></clause><clause id="idfcb36fa80d9a4dd1b64d668655079544"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>an organization representing parents.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDE548FED90BC48B193B95B143959558F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7baace20f794ae99199fe78fd3d9a7a"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Mentor</header><text>The term <term>mentor</term> means an experienced educator, including a teacher-educator at an educator preparation program, dedicated to advising a tutor or administering the tutoring program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id30CD86E21EAE4A1EA1C06E69BED5175C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1881368c9923447fada3e66171b5983e"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Tutor</header><text>The term <term>tutor</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idDC68378E6D8343EAA23387FF47F21F9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a postsecondary student, including one who is enrolled in an educator preparation program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC83632F39FCB44EA9F4261E16F35B177"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a recent graduate of an educator preparation program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBDE524D079B5451AA3B43D7D355354BF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an individual serving as an education paraprofessional or teaching aide; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB455A0AFCEC84FF3AEC2283E5F0DB446"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a fully certified and licensed educator (such as a recently retired educator, an educator experiencing a gap in employment due to COVID-induced budget cuts, or an educator providing tutoring before or after school or during the summer).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD52AF58F03DE4690A4B1405012AD0B04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Demonstration competitive grant program</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to local consortia to enable the local consortia to carry out high-quality tutoring, especially at hard-to-staff schools or high-need schools.</text></subsection><subsection id="idBC70D1ADCE5445519E79A754B83083EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A local consortium that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require, including the following:</text><paragraph id="id451f1b28d4264f1e8b02f9fc02bd6dc0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the local consortium, including which public or nonprofit entity participating in the local consortium shall serve as the fiscal agent for the local consortium.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfca16712979546799584fc4c72b41818"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the strategy for recruitment, careful selection, and matching of tutors with hard-to-staff schools and high-need schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d318643d4f14acb85013ee8c19f3744"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the pre-service training and ongoing professional support for tutors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7b21cee9cdd84e1ca74e6726e0578b64"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A list of hard-to-staff schools and high-need schools, and the grades that will be supported in each school, identified by the local consortium to receive a comprehensive, coordinated continuum of services and support.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6363442c75c472f8ce7e3881555673c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of how the high-quality tutoring program plans to accelerate student learning.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id93c78580681645ecafbec8c6abe46535"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of how the local consortium will ensure that the high-quality tutoring provided under such program does not result in the tracking or negative labeling of students, or remediation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide60fa6ab36c74e508d9f6f3429435e48"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of the duration of the high-quality tutoring, including the duration of sessions, the number of days a week tutoring will occur, and the length in weeks the tutoring will occur.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c3f8713466541dfa32cfa6679da1d01"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An assurance that the local consortium will align high-quality tutoring to the local curriculum and standards of the local educational agency and school and will be designed to support student success in the classroom.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ca63496dac04e61be49735e76429dba"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A description of materials and supports and how they are aligned with the local curriculum and standards of the local educational agency and school.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0b1e4c1172d484a833196cd7c5c2763"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A description of how the high-quality tutoring program will build school capacity in the schools in which the tutors will serve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8578f718a6fa4f5dbdd534d758bfa45b"><enum>(11)</enum><text>An assurance that the local consortium will leverage tutors to supplement, not supplant, existing staff.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id818df6ffa6c5436f8509fd8b5881fccd"><enum>(12)</enum><text>A description of how tutors will be adequately compensated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6b76a336d624882985af325c3a78440"><enum>(13)</enum><text>An assurance that the local consortium will use funds to supplement and not supplant funds otherwise available to carry out high-quality tutoring and will not use any funds to replace teaching positions with tutoring positions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idada422196468456a9aaf9194ce89dab8"><enum>(14)</enum><text>A description of how the tutoring program will incorporate research-based social-emotional learning practices, trauma-informed learning practices, and culturally and linguistically responsive practices.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2f20c423f3d44d56b222f9b1091257e0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to local consortia that plan to support high-need schools in building student learning capacity by using tutors who—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id353cebab9fe544a68b4ff15d80da21e2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are postsecondary students who are enrolled in educator preparation programs; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a045f98bcbd49149e29500005d8b809"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are enrolled in a historically Black college or university (defined as a part B institution under section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>)) or another minority-serving institution (defined as an eligible institution under section 371(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8440561859934534815DB4F09DA7D4CF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A local consortium that receives a grant under this section may use the grant funds for the following:</text><paragraph id="id57558940b82140309ad1243059a77879"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Matching, training, and placing tutors with schools to deliver high-quality tutoring.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e5bdf2cbd7d4191aa77db9d0f3e874f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Supporting tutors to work with small groups of students attending high-need schools wherein tutors are providing supervision and instruction, and providing the tutors with time for collaboration with mentors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31e221f152d34ae5a1eacdea0d53c726"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Matching tutors in the high-quality tutoring program with mentors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide5dabcaa3bea446fa8cbff973f6f2088"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing stipends to such tutors and mentors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab5ccec060064493b0f6dacc27228bee"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Purchasing instructional materials and connectivity resources, including internet access and accessible devices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3da009bf7c6340c2832758b6d1520516"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Providing transportation for students attending the high-quality tutoring program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id70a2f4cd4d2244d5b86cf321fc66535e"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Providing meals and snacks for students attending the high-quality tutoring program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8376fa91e74f4c24829f601304b6ec8e"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Providing facilities for conducting the high-quality tutoring program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="ida2d336add2204fb2a032022f0c82e4f3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idFF0A852D25A54C039708686C4612138C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $500,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id55e2c5f853b345aca4d25a87663a6f1d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>From the amounts appropriated to carry out this section—</text><subparagraph id="idb2922032b6a349d7b2f89e8c5704829c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 85 percent shall be used for directly supporting students, including providing stipends to tutors and mentors in the high-quality tutoring program, providing transportation, meals, and snacks, and purchasing instructional materials and connectivity resources for students; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa8be6bb17834e6785476a44aa5e6af2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 15 percent shall be used for other uses in carrying out this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idA2E2D8D5535B4C88A8F3AF6D6F9CD41A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coordination with the Corporation for National and Community Service</header><subsection id="id6A9B4DC558F2454187882FE496F34AEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interagency agreement</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall enter into an interagency agreement with the Corporation for National and Community Service under section 121(b) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12571">42 U.S.C. 12571(b)</external-xref>) under which the Corporation shall approve tutor positions under a program funded under section 2, as approved national service positions (as defined in section 101 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12511">42 U.S.C. 12511</external-xref>)). Such interagency agreement shall specify how a degree or certificate of completion for a term of service as a provider of high-quality tutoring will be submitted to the Corporation.</text></subsection><subsection id="id41bc8cbdfbd7442c9629a4ef4f44dc97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Notwithstanding section 148 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12604">42 U.S.C. 12604</external-xref>), the Secretary and the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service shall develop a program under which national service educational awards may be disbursed to tutors upon completion of service under a program funded under section 2.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

