<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA06B2D78C140433F966ACC7F8E695D48" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9354 IH: Fair Elections Now Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9354</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reform the financing of House elections, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBA45E717263A4618A3BFDC0A15521D2E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCD320EDCFA8D46E9823DD9E5AD3D8F62" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
<subsection id="H6D1757CC6F2E46CEBBFE3C0191EF5495"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Elections Now Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE4598695FB844B87A14875F5C2E4CC44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of Contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="yes-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
<toc-entry idref="HCD320EDCFA8D46E9823DD9E5AD3D8F62" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H57DB8D8BB0B7460B84DFAE8DBC061DDD" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings and declarations.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H74DD22A3E2F24B41A29B919CDBCF0091" level="title">Title I—Fair elections financing of House election campaigns</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HFE96CA8A482041439C26CC4922095DB4" level="section">Sec. 101. Benefits and eligibility requirements for House candidates.</toc-entry>
<toc-quoted-entry style="OLC">
<toc-entry idref="HD71A2006A0184BF0B0F9EE8661ABF9F5" level="title">Title V—Fair elections financing of House election campaigns</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H5BCC16C791D14580998E2342C37B705E" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Benefits</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H7737BDD0CDB2403ABA891AAB86FB002F" level="section">Sec. 501. Benefits for participating candidates.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HB1366A0AE8B14707AD5E1F7D8EA2645A" level="section">Sec. 502. Allocations from the Fund.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H6E4BE7ABB5E740698D75F8248B565B40" level="section">Sec. 503. Matching payments for certain small dollar contributions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H9BAEB1DD949B433CA074B35B066373C5" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Eligibility and certification</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H88541B920965483B8C17BD9692615391" level="section">Sec. 511. Eligibility.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HE494D1A182AD41E28502D780AD4EE9E1" level="section">Sec. 512. Qualifying requirements.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HEC34E4E349DE48F398D13FCDC24C713C" level="section">Sec. 513. Certification.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H3936DF96DD0241B0968921394875A27D" level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Requirements for Candidates Certified as Participating Candidates</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HD4858E8E88164106907DADF4CA5AE01E" level="section">Sec. 521. Contribution, expenditure, and fundraising requirements.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H6598CFECABE24B9DA64948A43C66510B" level="section">Sec. 522. Debate requirement.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H720EEC60EA074545AFD282E6F79B2C28" level="section">Sec. 523. Remitting unspent funds after election.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HED2EC1B5681C44839BF3F50FA34B3DBD" level="subtitle">Subtitle D—Administrative provisions</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HF0245FDD4F8848FBA28AB6C41E249516" level="section">Sec. 531. Fair Elections Fund.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H1A3F4D3CDDBE4790B0451AFE3F63E8D3" level="section">Sec. 532. Fair Elections Oversight Board.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H583F10A312484E2E8618FF7F8B84B576" level="section">Sec. 533. Administration by Commission.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H1CA6F177287341B9B59C7A1265F8BEB6" level="section">Sec. 534. Violations and penalties.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H8DCD7F38F55A460094DC1D061660A773" level="section">Sec. 535. Election cycle defined.</toc-entry></toc-quoted-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H87105E36EA1E496EA8C227F3871D9C40" level="section">Sec. 102. Transfer of portion of civil money penalties into Fair Elections Fund.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H35D02E65833D4B468D46611FB18F79C3" level="section">Sec. 103. Prohibiting use of contributions by participating candidates for purposes other than campaign for election.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HE6A31D7D0F894E9996A91CC0CF2A30E1" level="section">Sec. 104. Prohibition on joint fundraising committees.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HD7FDA941F2BC4CFB8A8A74803E1892B7" level="section">Sec. 105. Treatment of coordinated expenditures by political party committees on behalf of participating candidates.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H1BD8C86B1C2140209BEF8E768B21D6BD" level="title">Title II—Responsibilities of the Federal Election Commission</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H92689FDDD1DA4541A3AC839985903128" level="section">Sec. 201. Petition for certiorari.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HDCDFC06377014519AF96898AA999A94F" level="section">Sec. 202. Filing by all candidates with Commission.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H51E149F3ECA74BA399E01B165B21E57F" level="section">Sec. 203. Electronic filing of FEC reports.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H836F91D549B1474F927E5B21B515D740" level="title">Title III—Miscellaneous provisions</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H4B0925F7DC9147DC9C45B01B7F58DC85" level="section">Sec. 301. Severability.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H14D6B65F35F445FEB59733C30420BC60" level="section">Sec. 302. Effective date.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<section id="H57DB8D8BB0B7460B84DFAE8DBC061DDD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and declarations</header>
<subsection id="H9EF6CEAC50F348BEB1DE29D109F4A5B1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Undermining of democracy by campaign contributions from private sources</header><text>The House of Representatives finds and declares that the current system of privately financed campaigns for election to the House of Representatives has the capacity, and is often perceived by the public, to undermine democracy in the United States by—</text> <paragraph id="H351CE1AD9D54465A9335499E61375B1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating a culture that fosters actual or perceived conflicts of interest, by encouraging Members of the House to accept large campaign contributions from private interests that are directly affected by Federal legislation;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFAF07D36177A44BC99C4EA90E4EAAA8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>diminishing or appearing to diminish Members’ accountability to constituents by compelling legislators to be accountable to the major contributors who finance their election campaigns;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB66C9786BAF2487096352A07D7F67077"><enum>(3)</enum><text>undermining the meaning of the right to vote by allowing monied interests to have a disproportionate and unfair influence within the political process;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDFF1BE6390B143159D022B0A191882E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>imposing large, unwarranted costs on taxpayers through legislative and regulatory distortions caused by unequal access to lawmakers for campaign contributors;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA46741641C5440DC9387243FA11735D6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>making it difficult for some qualified candidates to mount competitive House election campaigns;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBA626336A7E746139FA338D613FF487E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>disadvantaging challengers and discouraging competitive elections, because large campaign contributors tend to donate their money to incumbent Members, thus causing House elections to be less competitive; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2BEA6C80B114619844620D8B1A8EDA1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>burdening incumbents with a preoccupation with fundraising and thus decreasing the time available to carry out their public responsibilities.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4C00CBB3A3C247EEB448823FDD6E1A77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enhancement of democracy by providing allocations from the Fair Elections Fund</header><text>The House of Representatives finds and declares that providing the option of the replacement of large private campaign contributions with allocations from the Fair Elections Fund for all primary, runoff, and general elections to the House of Representatives would enhance American democracy by—</text> <paragraph id="H99B410E31FE34969B99952A9E4CC4B29"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reducing the actual or perceived conflicts of interest created by fully private financing of the election campaigns of public officials and restoring public confidence in the integrity and fairness of the electoral and legislative processes through a program which allows participating candidates to adhere to substantially lower contribution limits for contributors with an assurance that there will be sufficient funds for such candidates to run viable electoral campaigns;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H845564A07F1543DE8A18B067B5F99969"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increasing the public's confidence in the accountability of Members to the constituents who elect them, which derives from the program's qualifying criteria to participate in the voluntary program and the conclusions that constituents may draw regarding candidates who qualify and participate in the program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4840FC9683FF4B01862909C7CC54C26B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>helping to reduce the ability to make large campaign contributions as a determinant of a citizen's influence within the political process by facilitating the expression of support by voters at every level of wealth, encouraging political participation, incentivizing participation on the part of Members through the matching of small dollar contributions;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF7240E76EFC94707B2F62020B54F54E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>potentially saving taxpayers billions of dollars that may be (or that are perceived to be) currently allocated based upon legislative and regulatory agendas skewed by the influence of campaign contributions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9011C3E25A354DB4B2D7B1360E361C72"><enum>(5)</enum><text>creating genuine opportunities for all Americans to run for the House of Representatives and encouraging more competitive elections;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H97CC213D390049F586C8BACE0AF0FF6C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>encouraging participation in the electoral process by citizens of every level of wealth; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0F66EE839BB41C48030CE71AE03D31E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>freeing Members from the incessant preoccupation with raising money, and allowing them more time to carry out their public responsibilities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<title id="H74DD22A3E2F24B41A29B919CDBCF0091"><enum>I</enum><header>Fair elections financing of House election campaigns</header>
<section id="HFE96CA8A482041439C26CC4922095DB4"><enum>101.</enum><header>Benefits and Eligibility Requirements for House Candidates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The <act-name parsable-cite="FECA">Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/431">2 U.S.C. 431 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block act-name="Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971" id="HEDF8112AF29A4895A6995FCCCADCFE05"> <title id="HD71A2006A0184BF0B0F9EE8661ABF9F5"><enum>V</enum><header>Fair elections financing of House election campaigns</header> <subtitle id="H5BCC16C791D14580998E2342C37B705E"><enum>A</enum><header>Benefits</header> <section id="H7737BDD0CDB2403ABA891AAB86FB002F"><enum>501.</enum><header>Benefits for participating candidates</header> <subsection id="HEE321D17F0614704A9121377D04091B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a candidate for election to the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress is a participating candidate under this title with respect to an election for such office, the candidate shall be entitled to payments under this title, to be used only for authorized expenditures in connection with the election.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3D68A96849B34E20A133A27DB510AFEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Types of Payments</header><text>The payments to which a participating candidate is entitled under this section consist of—</text> <paragraph id="H7F0402E8119F4106B30C2BF35C7C1911"><enum>(1)</enum><text>allocations from the Fair Elections Fund, as provided in section 502; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C7739209E7D4493A6D34E88843608D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>payments from the Fair Elections Fund to match certain small dollar contributions, as provided in section 503.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB1366A0AE8B14707AD5E1F7D8EA2645A"><enum>502.</enum><header>Allocations from the Fund</header> <subsection id="HD0F9DBD007F74EBF9E093CF364BA8341"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amount of Allocations</header> <paragraph id="H2FCBC097587242ED91C84860F35E90AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Primary election allocation; initial allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (6), the Commission shall make an allocation from the Fair Elections Fund established under section 531 to a candidate who is certified as a participating candidate with respect to a primary election in an amount equal to 40 percent of the base amount.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H36CAB60C93774D83AF9C9EA7AFEDEB1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Primary runoff election allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall make an allocation from the Fund to a candidate who is certified as a participating candidate with respect to a primary runoff election in an amount equal to 25 percent of the amount the participating candidate was eligible to receive under this section for the primary election.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC39E80187AED447DAC7F6D15A5FBD98A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>General election allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (6), the Commission shall make an allocation from the Fund to a candidate who is certified as a participating candidate with respect to a general election in an amount equal to 60 percent of the base amount.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H9B3911EA140E4FB28E7DC61E483B4C6F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>General runoff election allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall make an allocation from the Fund to a candidate who is certified as a participating candidate with respect to a general runoff election in an amount equal to 25 percent of the base amount.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H238BA4C03D2C4272ADABD2FBCCB9F6A0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recount allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the appropriate State or local election official conducts a recount of an election, the Commission shall make an allocation from the Fund to a participating candidate for expenses relating to the recount in an amount equal to 25 percent of the amount the participating candidate was eligible to receive under this section for the election involved.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H4AC21377839A4B14B87FA424AD0F3F28"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Uncontested elections</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H70C9C04E53A3448CA52FB2D0FE6CCF97"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a primary or general election that is an uncontested election, the Commission shall make an allocation from the Fund to a participating candidate for such election in an amount equal to 25 percent of the allocation for that election with respect to such candidate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H86E874A093B9478E8DC1B6446609CD2D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Uncontested election defined</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, an election is uncontested if not more than 1 candidate has campaign funds (including payments from the Fund) in an amount equal to or greater than 10 percent of the allocation a candidate would be entitled to receive under this section for that election (determined without regard to this paragraph).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9A3094FE5BDE4C168BBA2556ADA6244B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Base amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The base amount is an amount equal to 80 percent of the national average disbursements of the cycle by winning candidates for the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress in the last 2 election cycles.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBE004BB37C674A47829960D3B149155D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing; method of payment</header> <paragraph id="H6A95145AC0644439B7D139310F9DCEC9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Commission shall make the allocations required under subsection (a) to a participating candidate—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF6CAB695C29B4810A644169EFBC83FF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of amounts provided under subsection (a)(1), not later than 48 hours after the date on which such candidate is certified as a participating candidate under section 513;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59BA88D60F3B4D969020D35AE729F98C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a general election, not later than 48 hours after—</text>
<clause id="HB4770F520BC64C77BC6E414C2446B08A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date of the certification of the results of the primary election or the primary runoff election; or</text></clause> <clause id="H089762FFE1CC4AF887158DC7279A0170"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in any case in which there is no primary election, the date the candidate qualifies to be placed on the ballot;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC02ECB944E2947DBA1BEA27F9FE5AA7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a primary runoff election or a general runoff election, not later than 48 hours after the certification of the results of the primary election or the general election, as the case may be; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C560E76783B4E1E9C84805DAA6A3705"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of a recount allocation, not later than 48 hours after the appropriate State or local election official orders the holding of the recount.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1EFC1134D6B44727A9715DDFDC5849CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Method of payment</header><text>The Commission shall distribute funds available to participating candidates under this section through the use of an electronic funds exchange or a debit card.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H6E4BE7ABB5E740698D75F8248B565B40"><enum>503.</enum><header>Matching payments for certain small dollar contributions</header> <subsection id="HFC35F7080A1445FBAD0F8F0677BAE5E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall pay to each participating candidate an amount equal to 500 percent of the amount of qualified small dollar contributions received by the candidate from individuals who are residents of the State in which such participating candidate is seeking election.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HEF04FE7F3C794FBB8DDDE298DE47C599"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maximum payment under this section shall be the greater of—</text> <paragraph id="H7C8FFCFEA118450DB6513B37BFEE2756"><enum>(1)</enum><text>300 percent of the allocation under paragraphs (1) through (4) of section 502(a) for that election with respect to such candidate; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAF2BB24B6B01425C87EB1025721AE00D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the percentage of the allocation determined by the Commission under section 532(c)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5BB38B70FC654EE5A564F5DA4721198A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Time of payment</header><text>The Commission shall make payments under this section not later than 2 business days after the receipt of a report made under subsection (d).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HCDD1FED3CE9F4CAE8AFCEBD1D2D1287E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header>
<paragraph id="H77458CC118BD48CCAB71FB11EF05CF2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each participating candidate shall file reports of receipts of qualified small dollar contributions at such times and in such manner as the Commission may by regulations prescribe.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD858E8FDB1B54A9586EC4091862D4E2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of reports</header><text>Each report under this subsection shall disclose—</text>
<subparagraph id="H87B9B22FC6BC4ED585DEA8EA7DE245AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of each qualified small dollar contribution received by the candidate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87E2C3EC2E5F4D3B905D9205CEF5AEB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of each qualified small dollar contribution received by the candidate from a resident of the State in which the candidate is seeking election; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H15999568014E4233A8416976AB88FE0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the name, address, and occupation of each individual who made a qualified small dollar contribution to the candidate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD5922C0F5464A96968407060374E46C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Frequency of reports</header><text>Reports under this subsection shall be made no more frequently than—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4EAF60FA814F4A2EB61041FC0E80E132"><enum>(A)</enum><text>once every month until the date that is 90 days before the date of the election;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCBD6A09710EB4D7AAB419B0373732417"><enum>(B)</enum><text>once every week after the period described in subparagraph (A) and until the date that is 21 days before the election; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H24EBEE3D036946C8B32A50FDF0416BE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>once every day after the period described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H940330E6E3F84F2582ECAFDFE5493FB7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on regulations</header><text>The Commission may not prescribe any regulations with respect to reporting under this subsection with respect to any election after the date that is 180 days before the date of such election.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF1006BEC5E474A30BAD2789B2BBE4DA0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>The Commission shall provide a written explanation with respect to any denial of any payment under this section and shall provide for the opportunity for review and reconsideration within 5 business days of such denial.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD1160F6D9C7640BE9D6B9AC78F75EFFF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualified Small Dollar Contribution Defined</header><text>The term <term>qualified small dollar contribution</term> means, with respect to a participating candidate, any contribution (or a series of contributions)—</text>
<paragraph id="H6F0467B50EEA42D0BD7DFCBFCBAEDA20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>which is not a qualifying contribution (or does not include a qualifying contribution);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8E9C90FD5D44FC3BC4F92E1BDD2FBC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>which is made by an individual who is not prohibited from making a contribution under this Act; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA3DCF7AEBEF8454AB87547F5B7C13B42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of which does not exceed the greater of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD986A4EC21CB49259E484B3F957C11D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$100 per election; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2C43E466FDD4490588A7EB2693F7614A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount determined by the Fair Elections Oversight Board under section 532(c)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle> <subtitle id="H9BAEB1DD949B433CA074B35B066373C5"><enum>B</enum><header>Eligibility and certification</header> <section id="H88541B920965483B8C17BD9692615391"><enum>511.</enum><header>Eligibility</header> <subsection id="H88B083E760B14C138191D0910523111F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A candidate for the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress is eligible to be certified as a participating candidate under this title with respect to an election if the candidate meets the following requirements:</text>
<paragraph id="H076B55A912284A1F8427F72CE8B2058A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>During the election cycle for the office involved, the candidate files with the Commission a statement of intent to seek certification as a participating candidate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CE0A152242245959B72D0C975214F5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The candidate meets the qualifying requirements of section 512.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2C62EBA2667F458CB2EABA9F6A1F6C5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Not later than the last day of the Fair Elections qualifying period, the candidate files with the Commission an affidavit signed by the candidate and the treasurer of the candidate's principal campaign committee declaring that the candidate—</text> <subparagraph id="H506FD5655EAE4FC0B9D48ECEEDFDAD71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has complied and, if certified, will comply with the contribution and expenditure requirements of section 521;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCA56EE999EC9496990B3A5C895E7AD59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if certified, will comply with the debate requirements of section 522;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H41BE3A89B057469F94F0054FE92F2C43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if certified, will run only as a participating candidate for all elections for the office that such candidate is seeking during the election cycle; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF285C001A8234F3290B19F6E23ABC807"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has either qualified or will take steps to qualify under State law to be on the ballot.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3B9BC53B742C4B2195694975A69529E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General election</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), a candidate shall not be eligible to receive an allocation from the Fund for a general election or a general runoff election unless the candidate’s party nominated the candidate to be placed on the ballot for the general election or the candidate is otherwise qualified to be on the ballot under State law.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9D2A268B50F243419BF6F29D7B217C08"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fair Elections qualifying period Defined</header><text>The term <term>Fair Elections qualifying period</term> means, with respect to any candidate for the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress, the 120-day period (during the election cycle for such office) which begins on the date on which the candidate files a statement of intent under section 511(a)(1), except that such period may not continue after the date that is 60 days before—</text> <paragraph id="H0FD5C55C5A64418C8A65C4C9516BB644"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date of the primary election; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0EDBD0CC700A46E59AC42F8C2B58E3DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a State that does not hold a primary election, the date prescribed by State law as the last day to qualify for a position on the general election ballot.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE494D1A182AD41E28502D780AD4EE9E1"><enum>512.</enum><header>Qualifying requirements</header> <subsection id="H0EB56AB0792E4B5BBC020DB1F6FB3EAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Receipt of qualifying contributions</header><text>A candidate for the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress meets the requirement of this section if, during the Fair Elections qualifying period described in section 511(c), the candidate obtains—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0B22CA27848142329E660DC0A993F030"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a single qualifying contribution from a number of individuals equal to or greater than the lesser of—</text> <subparagraph id="H52AF064801004FB490BB9C7ED8BDD694"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>.25 percent of the voting age population of the State involved (as reported in the most recent decennial census); or</text>
                                        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H71B43C080F7A4E7E95D46A7725A42FBA">
                                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>$1,500; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H4B573231DE1A4920AE0071ECD5905AA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a total dollar amount of qualifying contributions equal to or greater than $50,000.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H11F76154BA8C43F8AB64DCA04497B6E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements relating to receipt of qualifying contribution</header><text>Each qualifying contribution—</text> <paragraph id="H20EF20E4CF714EAD9AC89CF7E3B33FC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may be made by means of a personal check, money order, debit card, credit card, or electronic payment account;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE741EC87483448C0963B439C531DD0A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be accompanied by a signed statement containing—</text> <subparagraph id="HC5FB6DB47E9C4BAAA82CE09A3204B23F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the contributor’s name and the contributor's address in the State in which the primary residence of the contributor is located; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H49CD3696FDEA4194A128F026897D0CB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an oath declaring that the contributor—</text> <clause id="H711596AE811E4BB3A918DBBC06B371E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>understands that the purpose of the qualifying contribution is to show support for the candidate so that the candidate may qualify for Fair Elections financing;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC1A795C02F9C44E09D842F7B252D245B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is making the contribution in his or her own name and from his or her own funds;</text></clause> <clause id="H292349DFC83B4758B1BB8A04F49FE240"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has made the contribution willingly; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1457A68782BA4421A93EE50F6C5672F7">
                                                <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>has not received anything of value in return for the contribution; and</text>
                                            </clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H224911653E964BDB8C317C0F5CF23F9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall be acknowledged by a receipt that is sent to the contributor with a copy kept by the candidate for the Commission and a copy kept by the candidate for the election authorities in the State with respect to which the candidate is seeking election.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H52639473EB8844DE86AA486E814A888B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Verification of qualifying contributions</header><text>The Commission shall establish procedures for the auditing and verification of qualifying contributions to ensure that such contributions meet the requirements of this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2FA5B230443641F4B18A67DA434DD76D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibiting payment on commission basis of individuals collecting qualifying contributions</header><text>No person may be paid a commission on a per qualifying contribution basis for collecting qualifying contributions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9EA807BD1F634D9CA474DE24D6E032EF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualifying contribution Defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>qualifying contribution</term> means, with respect to a candidate, a contribution that—</text>
<paragraph id="HDB84E75C2A194C18B5384F5986D36A57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is in an amount that is—</text> <subparagraph id="HAD99C1D2C72141C6A6F782B1149064BE"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>not less than the greater of $5 or the amount determined by the Commission under section 532(c)(2); and</text>
                                        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8D18C4D2A11940E6ADB9DD0E3198130B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than the greater of $100 or the amount determined by the Commission under section 532(c)(2);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29D5C5115DCD45ABB2690204A26EFEBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is made by an individual—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF51E5E3F6538429A945DAD89964782BA">
                                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>who has a primary residence in the State in which such Candidate is seeking election; and</text>
                                        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB2EABD64C4264F4FA46996762962BC6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is not otherwise prohibited from making a contribution under this Act;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37B96BC4FA3D41C9B1AEE55FB901799B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is made during the Fair Elections qualifying period described in section 511(c); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2F16727BD2D2462C8706D3913BD1E43C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>meets the requirements of subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HEC34E4E349DE48F398D13FCDC24C713C"><enum>513.</enum><header>Certification</header> <subsection id="H83B791D5EBE04A679761600F0FC06C3E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deadline and Notification</header> <paragraph id="HDCA4CD3D297948AAACDAC7FA9B408B3D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 days after a candidate files an affidavit under section 511(a)(3), the Commission shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC83ECAA1D8634319BA369C77A1895C3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine whether or not the candidate meets the requirements for certification as a participating candidate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CABAC70C9494F20941F22A99A7FF917"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Commission determines that the candidate meets such requirements, certify the candidate as a participating candidate; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H70FA2A9162DC4A6E859E36EDA04D27DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>notify the candidate of the Commission's determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44A5294AA0164766A302E7F9CAFB05FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deemed certification for all elections in election cycle</header><text>If the Commission certifies a candidate as a participating candidate with respect to the first election of the election cycle involved, the Commissioner shall be deemed to have certified the candidate as a participating candidate with respect to all subsequent elections of the election cycle.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB118A5D4E9E14C938BF09807745B9721"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revocation of certification</header>
<paragraph id="H54EDBE6D7E874A6E92C00F4E0B3479E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may revoke a certification under subsection (a) if—</text> <subparagraph id="HC11C4CA901FD42CAA1585AD3D8228BEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a candidate fails to qualify to appear on the ballot at any time after the date of certification (other than a candidate certified as a participating candidate with respect to a primary election who fails to qualify to appear on the ballot for a subsequent election in that election cycle); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H353FA905641141418DB7F2ECB87994F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a candidate otherwise fails to comply with the requirements of this title, including any regulatory requirements prescribed by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H94C4FDDA98994DAD926E87996CFBB557"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repayment of benefits</header><text>If certification is revoked under paragraph (1), the candidate shall repay to the Fair Elections Fund established under section 531 an amount equal to the value of benefits received under this title with respect to the election cycle involved plus interest (at a rate determined by the Commission) on any such amount received.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H394F101F77504F5EB7104DD9D29DB314"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Participating Candidate defined</header><text>In this title, a <quote>participating candidate</quote> means a candidate for the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress who is certified under this section as eligible to receive benefits under this title.</text></subsection></section></subtitle> <subtitle id="H3936DF96DD0241B0968921394875A27D"><enum>C</enum><header>Requirements for Candidates Certified as Participating Candidates</header> <section id="HD4858E8E88164106907DADF4CA5AE01E"><enum>521.</enum><header>Contribution, expenditure, and fundraising requirements</header> <subsection id="H7AB24D951DB94FA0B13D2CEF8D0616E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contributions</header> <paragraph id="H9C474B52E8914ED58E35A2048316FF98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permitted sources of contributions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), a candidate who is certified as a participating candidate with respect to an election shall, with respect to all elections occurring during the election cycle for the office involved, accept no contributions from any source (including an unexpended contribution received by the candidate with respect to a previous election or a contribution made by any political committee or multicandidate committee) other than—</text>
<subparagraph id="H54E3755C8FC34CD881AAFF93AC97B6EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>qualifying contributions described in section 512;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD6308E74AEF448FAE22E7624D5DBEB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>qualified small dollar contributions described in section 503;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H97F13A8A67014179A5DD8CB67DC6EB37"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allocations under section 502; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H416E50E6519E413FBF2B7B877DDA2882"><enum>(D)</enum><text>payments under section 503.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HEF19EF4A16BF48018442FD7E6D06AE0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contributions for leadership and related PACs</header><text>A political committee of a participating candidate which is not an authorized committee of such candidate may accept contributions other than contributions described in paragraph (1) from any person if—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE0CF94BB689F44CDBAE34780DC4B43E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of the contributions from such person for any election during the election cycle does not exceed $100; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HAD0F2C11410C4C96844A4771563B942C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no portion of such contributions is disbursed in connection with the campaign of the participating candidate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H11DE0618E22243D6B3DA90C5064AE6DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expenditures</header> <paragraph id="H94081DC6ABE5487085198F9F059B6E71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permitted Sources for Expenditures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), a candidate who is certified as a participating candidate with respect to an election shall, with respect to all elections occurring during the election cycle for the office involved—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1F4851B8B5F046B28EBCB3A36F88E46E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make no expenditures from any amounts other than—</text> <clause id="H76E73BB579844C05AE994201DB89B08E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>qualifying contributions described in section 512;</text></clause>
<clause id="H5279B0BFC650437780A6F40E67F52C1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>qualified small dollar contributions described in section 503;</text></clause> <clause id="H6FE7B31F236E465C9CF89511ADCD35B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>allocations under section 502; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H37264E552DE84C69B83E550DFC854AE0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>payments under section 503; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H760A789F4DDB41A2A9C2756C523C5A6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make no expenditures from personal funds or the funds of any immediate family member of the candidate (other than funds received through qualified small dollar contributions and qualifying contributions).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD061E659699D457E83A1332627F12EF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immediate family member defined</header><text>In paragraph (1)(B), the term <term>immediate family</term> means, with respect to a candidate—</text> <subparagraph id="H2FBF6313BCE246A7813F9F0827176DB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the candidate’s spouse;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H14F40B47466A496FBA1615A3EBC82A86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a child, stepchild, parent, grandparent, brother, half-brother, sister, or half-sister of the candidate or the candidate’s spouse; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F6DE8D7458C4FD8BD7EE1BA602B7A38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the spouse of any person described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H06E61444E812434399A9FD40776F568D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
<paragraph id="HDCFEA48D6F9D49AAAFF2D10664CE0E22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for contributions received prior to filing of statement of intent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A candidate who has accepted contributions that are not qualified small dollar contributions, qualifying contributions, or contributions described in paragraph (a)(2) prior to the date the candidate files a statement of intent under section 511(a)(1) is not in violation of subsection (a), but only if all such contributions are—</text> <subparagraph id="H4355AC1D2C074B9982BC0F7FA65F9C38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>returned to the contributor;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6A8A895D69194A49B3BB5BEAD9664C6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submitted to the Commission for deposit in the Fair Elections Fund established under section 531; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H55E5FCFB777447ABBCC42FB59B18BB6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>spent in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6EF073786A284F7293434EEB9964DF50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for expenditures made prior to filing of statement of intent</header><text>If a candidate has made expenditures prior to the date the candidate files a statement of intent under section 511(a)(1) that the candidate is prohibited from making under subsection (b), the candidate is not in violation of such subsection if the aggregate amount of the prohibited expenditures is less than 20 percent of the amount of an initial allocation to a candidate under section 502(a)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84E60F793DA0423CB4C814E1BCBE0E31"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for campaign surpluses from a previous election</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), unexpended contributions received by the candidate or an authorized committee of the candidate with respect to a previous election may be retained, but only if the candidate places the funds in escrow and refrains from raising additional funds for or spending funds from that account during the election cycle in which a candidate is a participating candidate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3C1190C2244240879EDBEB41A133FDB9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception for contributions received before the effective date of this title</header><text>Contributions received and expenditures made by the candidate or an authorized committee of the candidate prior to the effective date of this title shall not constitute a violation of subsection (a) or (b). Unexpended contributions shall be treated the same as campaign surpluses under paragraph (3), and expenditures made shall count against the limit in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H03919EFAD85741AFB2C9A2EFA38DB5AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special Rule for Coordinated Party Expenditures</header><text>For purposes of this section, a payment made by a political party in coordination with a participating candidate shall not be treated as a contribution to or as an expenditure made by the participating candidate.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H6598CFECABE24B9DA64948A43C66510B"><enum>522.</enum><header>Debate requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A candidate who is certified as a participating candidate with respect to an election shall, during the election cycle for the office involved, participate in at least—</text> <paragraph id="H5C5E36376E6146F4A42BBECCE72771F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>1 public debate before the primary election with other participating candidates and other willing candidates from the same party and seeking the same nomination as such candidate; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA7BB26ABA35F412BB6DEBF23C13A4223"><enum>(2)</enum><text>2 public debates before the general election with other participating candidates and other willing candidates seeking the same office as such candidate.</text></paragraph></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H720EEC60EA074545AFD282E6F79B2C28"><enum>523.</enum><header>Remitting unspent funds after election</header> <subsection id="H6294024A9A8B41C2BA2ED7019B3D8CAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date that is 60 days after the last election for which a candidate certified as a participating candidate qualifies to be on the ballot during the election cycle involved, such participating candidate shall remit to the Commission for deposit in the Fair Elections Fund established under section 531 an amount equal to the lesser of—</text>
<paragraph id="HE446E1E873994722BE40C86D6421BA34"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of money in the candidate’s campaign account; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13F2C40CC9FD45D58F4B74B6FCB41331"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sum of the allocations received by the candidate under section 502 and the payments received by the candidate under section 503.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0227EBB4A72B44BCB8ED66348BC677E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for expenditures incurred but not paid as of date of remittance</header>
<paragraph id="HCCB928CE3B6743FCA5A61A38F19B2E67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (a), a candidate may withhold from the amount required to be remitted under paragraph (1) of such subsection the amount of any authorized expenditures which were incurred in connection with the candidate’s campaign but which remain unpaid as of the deadline applicable to the candidate under such subsection, except that any amount withheld pursuant to this paragraph shall be remitted to the Commission not later than 120 days after the date of the election to which such subsection applies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H312C95177561438DA104E956F07A64CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Documentation required</header><text>A candidate may withhold an amount of an expenditure pursuant to paragraph (1) only if the candidate submits documentation of the expenditure and the amount to the Commission not later than the deadline applicable to the candidate under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle>
<subtitle id="HED2EC1B5681C44839BF3F50FA34B3DBD"><enum>D</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header>
<section id="HF0245FDD4F8848FBA28AB6C41E249516"><enum>531.</enum><header>Fair Elections Fund</header>
<subsection id="HD6E5F647E29F4F9DB17F730FF8DBF8CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury a fund to be known as the <quote>Fair Elections Fund</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H911CC02BA33B4692AE4814BA65D8F479"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amounts held by Fund</header><text>The Fund shall consist of the following amounts:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HB2E7280357B1488DA353D0281DE3D819"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriated amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts appropriated to the Fund, including trust fund amounts appropriated pursuant to applicable provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC029266D01C847C8A496C0822B069FA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Voluntary contributions</header><text>Voluntary contributions to the Fund.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1F6B0DBFF1DB435B9A18EB22D7C6E7C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfers resulting from payment of civil penalties</header><text>Amounts transferred into the Fund pursuant to section 309(a)(13).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC876823E0124975A31E4CB2CD928963"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other deposits</header><text>Amounts deposited into the Fund under—</text>
<subparagraph id="H70892F3829FA466F9404B756A0F0C340"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 521(a)(3) (relating to exceptions to contribution requirements);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1599428D522E4E0C94CD714805106D56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 523 (relating to remittance of allocations from the Fund);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE2A86860B4FF4CA39B94F4BC22589610"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 534 (relating to violations); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H861DA52C2128441CBB61CBC3250C2215"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other section of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H460FA109B18D4A088360B066C0CB9A6C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Investment returns</header><text>Interest on, and the proceeds from, the sale or redemption of, any obligations held by the Fund under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A187B700715498B9727EE159EC5C4AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investment</header><text>The Commission shall invest portions of the Fund in obligations of the United States in the same manner as provided under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9602">section 9602(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H27426F66404C49E4BFB074B1D618B3AF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of Fund</header>
<paragraph id="HE0F892FDF4E4492B892AF2E56F406ADF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sums in the Fund shall be used to provide benefits to participating candidates as provided in subtitle A.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9533978CE49549A1B8EB28C67B618505"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Insufficient amounts</header><text>Under regulations established by the Commission, rules similar to the rules of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9006">section 9006(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall apply.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H1A3F4D3CDDBE4790B0451AFE3F63E8D3"><enum>532.</enum><header>Fair Elections Oversight Board</header>
<subsection id="HA1F21DCE12604A52A4E255F8DACFA8BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Federal Election Commission an entity to be known as the <quote>Fair Elections Oversight Board</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7AE4BE1FD9FC4B39AF9FF30D5472EE42"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Structure and membership</header> <paragraph id="HA809D3F712CC4EFD85703F83C7061C76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall be composed of 5 members appointed by the President, of whom—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC44EE40EACB04F49A8274A1B03BAB3C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed after consultation with the Majority Leader of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA19A9D8D2884E63B137F9F0733095AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed after consultation with the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE06E70F41DC54AA68AB73504AF4ED0D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>1 shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the members appointed under subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA26EB39D717D467A8DD45BF2E91EECF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header> <subparagraph id="H3C6868D68E524955A7C47F6F78A1D6FA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members shall be individuals who are nonpartisan and, by reason of their education, experience, and attainments, exceptionally qualified to perform the duties of members of the Board.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF5947B0B615E40F2A026E95CC809335A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No member of the Board may be—</text> <clause id="H4A24A5AF071941EC87D1EE968F5431B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an employee of the Federal Government;</text></clause>
<clause id="HAB534E898990487894DC5BD3B1E816D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a registered lobbyist or an individual who was a registered lobbyist at any time during the 2-year period preceding appointment to the Board; or</text></clause> <clause id="HCE5FC9CBB6804F9FAEE45F392C7F9974"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an officer or employee of a political party or political campaign.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H345B9215832F4F1BAD08F6928D71BD5E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Board shall be appointed not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H958B00EF2D6243DCB2DA54D7880CE8F5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Board shall be appointed for a term of 5 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H916EE077E4074AABB8725275E5F7EDFA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy on the Board shall be filled not later than 30 calendar days after the date on which the Board is given notice of the vacancy, in the same manner as the original appointment. The individual appointed to fill the vacancy shall serve only for the unexpired portion of the term for which the individual’s predecessor was appointed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32AD7CC75D3044729549AB32D37241A9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall designate a Chairperson from among the members of the Board.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC61C044AD04E4042A20519A008FC5222"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties and powers</header>
<paragraph id="HA0E47A0664644AFDB92A1F0D188C7836"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall have such duties and powers as the Commission may prescribe, including the power to administer the provisions of this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E2193F42A684F4FB502E750CDABC400"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of fair elections financing</header> <subparagraph id="H53D466D37757482398034460D38638FE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After each regularly scheduled general election for Federal office, the Board shall conduct a comprehensive review of the Fair Elections financing program under this title, including—</text>
<clause id="H2FD38C87479B4D53A22625918B1B8E4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the maximum dollar amount of qualified small dollar contributions under section 503(f);</text></clause> <clause id="H4D9716D1BAC44F45A90C45EBAA0D8D9A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the maximum and minimum dollar amounts for qualifying contributions under section 512(d);</text></clause>
<clause id="HB15FD4FD2E3F41F7B4F3F95DEC3763F3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number and value of qualifying contributions a candidate is required to obtain under section 512(a) to be eligible for certification as a participating candidate;</text></clause> <clause id="HDF00E67986B241B088430FBF5E909038"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the amount of allocations that candidates may receive under section 502;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC9985E204E4A4A908A4A908D15405C5F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the maximum amount of payments a candidate may receive under section 503;</text></clause> <clause id="HFE94E157E8DE4742BC3C8B4FD9E490A2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the overall satisfaction of participating candidates and the American public with the program; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H61576041F66243CC9598428376382080">
                                                <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text>such other matters relating to financing of the House of Representatives campaigns as the Board determines are appropriate.</text>
                                            </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H449FA38C89E848D4BCEB2D8DB1977D13"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria for review</header><text>In conducting the review under subparagraph (A), the Board shall consider the following:</text> <clause id="H3E9C6B361BE34FFAA0C5370522FF7BC1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Qualifying contributions and qualified small dollar contributions</header><text>The Board shall consider whether the number and dollar amount of qualifying contributions required and maximum dollar amount for such qualifying contributions and qualified small dollar contributions strikes a balance regarding the importance of voter involvement, the need to assure adequate incentives for participating, and fiscal responsibility, taking into consideration the number of primary and general election participating candidates, the electoral performance of those candidates, program cost, and any other information the Board determines is appropriate.</text></clause>
<clause id="H0770DED1BEAE4850B0C5086CE69EA28E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Review of program benefits</header><text>The Board shall consider whether the totality of the amount of funds allowed to be raised by participating candidates (including through qualifying contributions and small dollar contributions), allocations under section 502, and payments under section 503 are sufficient for voters in each State to learn about the candidates to cast an informed vote, taking into account the historic amount of spending by winning candidates, media costs, primary election dates, and any other information the Board determines is appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14BF207CF5B048D2B3FB777992B0F7ED"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Adjustment of amounts</header> <clause id="HFD39C50811D24FAB9CD4D7BF2EF6A97D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Based on the review conducted under subparagraph (A), the Board shall provide for the adjustments of the following amounts:</text>
<subclause id="HB507501157844F638EAED5BCBA38BC00"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the maximum dollar amount of qualified small dollar contributions under section 503(f);</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC298A3C043904072A27DF66D45BD3DDF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the maximum and minimum dollar amounts for qualifying contributions under section 512(d);</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H4C010D742F514FC38952D6DC921077A6"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and value of qualifying contributions a candidate is required to obtain under section 512(a) to be eligible for certification as a participating candidate;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0373BBAA58634EC6A679546606625B2E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the base amount for candidates under section 502(b); and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HDBC6A5A639B146D596F36C272DD99527"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the maximum amount of matching contributions a candidate may receive under section 503(b).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HFDAB34F6A9F54A668956D381369C2512"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Commission shall promulgate regulations providing for the adjustments made by the Board under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H80B0E3723AD14A01B8BD558E88405086"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than March 30 following any general election for Federal office, the Board shall submit a report to Congress on the review conducted under paragraph (1). Such report shall contain a detailed statement of the findings, conclusions, and recommendations of the Board based on such review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0433648F7EE24982B81F7E6E74A64768"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings and hearings</header> <paragraph id="H0039879CD3CA445BA426B0A7EF087AFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Board considers advisable to carry out the purposes of this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2EA21C4701A345568D8C0613E6A89D80"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three members of the Board shall constitute a quorum for purposes of voting, but a quorum is not required for members to meet and hold hearings.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA5E67EE00F3F43D8932AE8CAE5C78CCC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than March 30, 2027, and every 2 years thereafter, the Board shall submit to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives a report documenting, evaluating, and making recommendations relating to the administrative implementation and enforcement of the provisions of this title.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5D8F2B70493A485CAE0AEDD2E955ED9A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administration</header>
<paragraph id="HCB291C7C44EF4449A894C12B582436B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header>
<subparagraph id="H196076B714674F708D94AAE1F83B566B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member, other than the Chairperson, shall be paid at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the minimum annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H311DBC9952074DF383824398F0AD0EED"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairperson shall be paid at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the minimum annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5198997145E0448D96A8A9534F83288C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personnel</header>
<subparagraph id="H6E5370F145CB49569EB3563C5E6BD25A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The Board shall have a staff headed by an Executive Director. The Executive Director shall be paid at a rate equivalent to a rate established for the Senior Executive Service under section 5382 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFDA6A6060674B3E816C14CB1A4FFEA4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Staff appointment</header><text>With the approval of the Chairperson, the Executive Director may appoint such personnel as the Executive Director and the Board determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE7620A9C905E46E6A9EF18A7AC54CD74"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Experts and consultants</header><text>With the approval of the Chairperson, the Executive Director may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCED362B7DD0343D2A3E61BE033EE7E86"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Detail of government employees</header><text>Upon the request of the Chairperson, the head of any Federal agency may detail, without reimbursement, any of the personnel of such agency to the Board to assist in carrying out the duties of the Board. Any such detail shall not interrupt or otherwise affect the civil service status or privileges of the Federal employee.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEE7595E7213F45A7A23FE5EF1B92CA73"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Other resources</header><text>The Board shall have reasonable access to materials, resources, statistical data, and other information from the Library of Congress and other agencies of the executive and legislative branches of the Federal Government. The Chairperson of the Board shall make requests for such access in writing when necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H581603EAA5EC4DD593846ADF5AFBE4D8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this subtitle.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H583F10A312484E2E8618FF7F8B84B576"><enum>533.</enum><header>Administration by Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall prescribe regulations to carry out the purposes of this title, including regulations—</text> <paragraph id="H7E7AD39A052449C6918BEA0C9FE5554A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish procedures for—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF7426AD6A905450582A4E84E37814B62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>verifying the amount of valid qualifying contributions with respect to a candidate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H370274667F6546AE9ABA96E727E547F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>effectively and efficiently monitoring and enforcing the limits on the raising of qualified small dollar contributions;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4497CFA4B6454578B99A74E32522195D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>effectively and efficiently monitoring and enforcing the limits on the use of personal funds by participating candidates; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF71A560D2684469CA8B316AB97A5AF4C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>monitoring the use of allocations from the Fair Elections Fund established under section 531 and matching contributions under this title through audits of not fewer than <fraction>1/3</fraction> of all participating candidates or other mechanisms; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE60A6FDABA864FDC9B8EBA135D017A2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regarding the conduct of debates in a manner consistent with the best practices of States that provide public financing for elections.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H1CA6F177287341B9B59C7A1265F8BEB6"><enum>534.</enum><header>Violations and penalties</header> <subsection id="H73599220D965405C9B39F22A324DFA6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil penalty for violation of contribution and expenditure requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a candidate who has been certified as a participating candidate accepts a contribution or makes an expenditure that is prohibited under section 521, the Commission shall assess a civil penalty against the candidate in an amount that is not more than 3 times the amount of the contribution or expenditure. Any amounts collected under this subsection shall be deposited into the Fair Elections Fund established under section 531.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H78827BF56AA64EC3BDFFCADF48CF767A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repayment for improper use of Fair Elections Fund</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA6D05095CBC94C9F9A083818EA344733"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Commission determines that any benefit made available to a participating candidate was not used as provided for in this title or that a participating candidate has violated any of the dates for remission of funds contained in this title, the Commission shall so notify the candidate and the candidate shall pay to the Fund an amount equal to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5FE91E814A1A471AA65E5D3976D02937"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of benefits so used or not remitted, as appropriate; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H0E34B8F79B1F4E0D9BAE13121794B70D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interest on any such amounts (at a rate determined by the Commission).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB0EB57CC3D83490CB7D9C15AB451CA10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other action not precluded</header><text>Any action by the Commission in accordance with this subsection shall not preclude enforcement proceedings by the Commission in accordance with section 309(a), including a referral by the Commission to the Attorney General in the case of an apparent knowing and willful violation of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H8DCD7F38F55A460094DC1D061660A773"><enum>535.</enum><header>Election cycle defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the term <term>election cycle</term> means, with respect to an election for the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress, the period beginning on the day after the date of the most recent general election for that office (or, if the general election resulted in a runoff election, the date of the runoff election) and ending on the date of the next general election for that office (or, if the general election resulted in a runoff election, the date of the runoff election).</text></section></subtitle></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H87105E36EA1E496EA8C227F3871D9C40"><enum>102.</enum><header>Transfer of Portion of Civil Money Penalties Into Fair Elections Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 309(a) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/437g">2 U.S.C. 437g(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06DC7458CF184FE980775982A50697DA" style="traditional">
<paragraph id="H73698336101745EFBA49D860D9C20EE3" indent="up1"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Upon receipt in the General Fund of the Treasury of any payment attributable to a civil money penalty imposed under this subsection, there shall be transferred to the Fair Elections Fund established under section 531 an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount of such payment.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H35D02E65833D4B468D46611FB18F79C3"><enum>103.</enum><header>Prohibiting Use of Contributions by Participating Candidates for Purposes Other Than Campaign for Election</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 313 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/439a">2 U.S.C. 439a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H130FA0033C5A412E8A580F96D14B6CA9" style="OLC">
<subsection id="HA97EB3FA1EDC4F189A4335749F124269"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restrictions on Permitted Uses of Funds by Candidates Receiving Fair Elections Financing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraphs (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (a), if a candidate for election for the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress is certified as a participating candidate under title V with respect to the election, any contribution which the candidate is permitted to accept under such title may be used only for authorized expenditures in connection with the candidate’s campaign for such office.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HE6A31D7D0F894E9996A91CC0CF2A30E1"><enum>104.</enum><header>Prohibition on joint fundraising committees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 302(e) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/432">2 U.S.C. 432(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CA52BA714A948FBB727FF802A50B69A" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H9548E118D1F341B9AB0DAF2F183F0B2A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>No authorized committee of a candidate may establish a joint fundraising committee with a political committee other than an authorized committee of a candidate.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HD7FDA941F2BC4CFB8A8A74803E1892B7"><enum>105.</enum><header>Treatment of coordinated expenditures by political party committees on behalf of participating candidates</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H423DA6D3D2BA4976BB6A3EAB50617618"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Revision of limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 315(d)(3) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FECA">Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/441a">2 U.S.C. 441a(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HFBB4D896F8E04A20A1704CE8625A6732"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as subparagraphs (B) and (C), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H357E435193C44B71A1F572259DC7E31A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting before subparagraph (B), as redesignated by paragraph (1), the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3674ED4280504D70A6CB503EFD2D1C27" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H27ADA9FBF1774F4FAD612933F1205129"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a candidate for election to the office of Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress who is certified as a participating candidate under title V, the lesser of—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H251BFB808CBD44E8945BFB85E1861DF9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>10 percent of the allocation that the participating candidate is eligible to receive for the general election under section 502(a); or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H74AEE00FB9DB4D89940F34E469B17E85"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount which would (but for this subparagraph) apply with respect to such candidate under subparagraph (B);</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0531CBC36BD047C39E2FCA7FFB4AC032"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 315(d)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/441a">2 U.S.C. 441a(d)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H93187C520900422A857CD34C01E385CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) (as redesignated by subsection (a)), by inserting <quote>who is not certified as a participating candidate under title V</quote> after <quote>only one Representative</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C62DD4352104CF8ABD12BAC4AF6F04E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C) (as redesignated by subsection (a)), by inserting <quote>who is not certified as a participating candidate under title V</quote> after <quote>any other State</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title>
<title id="H1BD8C86B1C2140209BEF8E768B21D6BD"><enum>II</enum><header>Responsibilities of the Federal Election Commission</header>
<section id="H92689FDDD1DA4541A3AC839985903128"><enum>201.</enum><header>Petition for certiorari</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 307(a)(6) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FECA">Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/437d">2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(including a proceeding before the Supreme Court on certiorari)</quote> after <quote>appeal</quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDCDFC06377014519AF96898AA999A94F"><enum>202.</enum><header>Filing by All candidates with Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 302(g) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/432">2 U.S.C. 432(g)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEED13AC8B07B41E48C589858BF23B4EE" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H31E6F067238640998DA842202256A4BD" indent="down1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Filing with the commission</header><text>All designations, statements, and reports required to be filed under this Act shall be filed with the Commission.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H51E149F3ECA74BA399E01B165B21E57F"><enum>203.</enum><header>Electronic filing of FEC reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 304(a)(11) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FECA">Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/434">2 U.S.C. 434(a)(11)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H0D65EC6EA99F4EDB8F212DC9758CD913"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>under this Act—</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>under this Act shall be required to maintain and file such designation, statement, or report in electronic form accessible by computers.</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A0D4BE29BD84297B3A8115A63287BF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>48 hours</quote> and all that follows through <quote>filed electronically)</quote> and inserting <quote>24 hours</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H35BC86C8729B4416AD811C0FA96F1E46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (D).</text></paragraph></section></title> <title id="H836F91D549B1474F927E5B21B515D740"><enum>III</enum><header>Miscellaneous provisions</header> <section id="H4B0925F7DC9147DC9C45B01B7F58DC85"><enum>301.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or amendment made by this Act, or the application of a provision or amendment to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and amendments made by this Act, and the application of the provisions and amendment to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected by the holding.</text></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14D6B65F35F445FEB59733C30420BC60" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>302.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided for in this Act, this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on January 1, 2027.</text></section></title> </legis-body></bill>

