<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H34BE7BA0992B4837937F151C0689CBAE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6112 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish certain requirements with respect to the average monthly cost to provide coverage to an enrollee under Medicare Advantage plans.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6112</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish certain requirements with respect to the average monthly cost to provide coverage to an enrollee under Medicare Advantage plans.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H60BE1C2022DC4ACB8A57EE151DD3D717" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H53FB08D4F5CB4F6C82F4395684252EEA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishing requirements with respect to average monthly cost to provide coverage under Medicare Advantage plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1857(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4BF6B4290CAA41D9A5DA2B264562D34B"> <paragraph id="HBA38CD682D0B4E9A857AC8319FC7075C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Requirement on average monthly cost to provide coverage</header> <subparagraph id="HCA89B1BAA04C46CB9C171629A53EA6F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning with plan years beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, if the Secretary determines that, with respect to a plan year and a Medicare advantage plan, the average monthly payment amount under section 1853 with respect to coverage of individuals enrolled in such Medicare Advantage plan for such plan year exceeds the average monthly cost to provide coverage for individuals enrolled in the original Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B for such plan year, the Secretary shall not permit any individual to enroll or reenroll in such plan for the plan year immediately following such plan year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDDB125B61A3149B3AEC6D61E269939E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to a specialized MA plan for special needs individuals.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

