<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD26012914B77452BB933D9B04DF7BCB8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6984 IH: Data Center Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6984</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260108">January 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require reports on the effects of data centers on air quality and water quality, and on electricity consumption by data centers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDBC4B8345F1F4D659574CE1BCD9F784F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD620D5501F64449F98D3DD01E5363F61" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Data Center Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H4D67E8A84FB64F5EAAE32AF8E6A8A863"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports on the effects of data centers on air quality and water quality; reports on electricity consumption by data centers</header> <subsection id="H1996BA1B5F3448EAB9A7536FF256B778"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports on the effects of data centers on air quality and water quality</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section, and not less frequently than once every 3 months thereafter, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available on a website, a report that identifies, with respect to the period of 3 months preceding the submission and publication of the report—</text> 
<paragraph id="H47489005643E47D494290D9B5A488D90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total amount of water consumed by data centers located in the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64E2B3BE08DE4BE8A8A2312494786A02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how such data centers reuse water, and the amount of such reused water;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3870079CF02C4F2AAF2CF32BF4248496"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how such data centers affect local water systems, including with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="HBDB90189F0F24500B09F65DD355CFBCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the availability of potable water;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5B5EA9F10DD04925901FB5DD85666190"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the data center increased demand on local water utilities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB44BCA82AC974169AECF9435E087266D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any potential data on service disruptions for other customers of local water utilities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0914D54B90B6462A900338B0030F6D8D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any changes in residential rates for water services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H743CBD7FEEB24E5ABA2F72AC1D75583F" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the type and amount of pollutants (as such term is defined in section 502(6) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1362">33 U.S.C. 1362(6)</external-xref>)) discharged into water by data centers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA743F2DD9454AC681DB0E3C16D4B2E0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of greenhouse gases emitted from such data centers; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H47CB1128B8B14A1DB2F48AA389F19745" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the effect of such greenhouse gas emissions, including the cumulative effect on overburdened communities.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD5F9DFCFF5134740A2AE7ED1E077B630"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports on electricity consumption by data centers</header> 
<paragraph id="HEDC68A6669994532B3AFC00B36B908FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collection of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Energy Information Administration shall collect data on the total amount of energy consumed every 6 months by each data center located in the United States.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F5D289F689A48E19A4D9610AD93814B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section, and not less frequently than once every 6 months thereafter, the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available on a website, a report that identifies, with respect to the period of 6 months preceding the submission and publication of the report—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H995D69B672254CCF868748C48FE045E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of energy consumption by data centers, disaggregated by State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63B874A7086D4D838D18B63603784F03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how such energy consumption may have changed during such period of 6 months;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD3337812E7CD4CFDA0EAD214342BABBC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of data centers that began operating during such period of 6 months;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H62C2AA83F181445493DB7416D85050B5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how household energy bills may have changed during such period of 6 months; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H99C047E1ACB240C59C32F6E884C3CBAB" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the average household energy use and cost.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H51C62D7CACB84FE493F606AC2BBE1A7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data center defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>data center</term> has the meaning given such term in section 453(a) of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17112">42 U.S.C. 17112(a)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

