<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H226D6ECCF4A24BFBBDC8EE0520B6077F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7934 IH: Settlement Agreement Information Database Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7934</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260316">March 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/3">chapter 3</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, to require the publication of settlement agreements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1611C3EA56614425A6866205095D3481" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H05376B7FA38543DC88EB6A1FC6D390E4"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Settlement Agreement Information Database Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H012AD348125E49F3B0E1CE6FCB8B0FF1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Information regarding settlement agreements entered into by agencies</header> <subsection id="H92A8E6A2E9884E6B9C8901D8C81230FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for settlement agreements</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/3">chapter 3</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HBA50184CA70C4D8E8A38052AFB7382CC"> 
<section id="HDE4826167C174DE3ACD6100641ACA24B"><enum>307.</enum><header>Information regarding settlement agreements</header> 
<subsection id="H866A8DA9BF8749D795032D28AB9A8DBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H532C62E80B77488ABE3282FF9CB0BD79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9279477E08AE4E8880C7EAF562806664"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered settlement agreement</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC2C16C090D08408685B04D671E4DD40E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>covered settlement agreement</quote> means a settlement agreement or deferred prosecution agreement that meets 1 or more of the following requirements:</text> <clause id="H9D04B54EA76A42CF87F9286C9762D3DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Requires not less than $10,000,000 in total explicitly obligated payments of a settling party on the date on which the settlement agreement is executed.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H33545314449F45D6996171F3BBFC71A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Involves the appointment of a special master or monitor.</text></clause> <clause id="H1CAC77D073E2489F87F7549AE2ADF787"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Involves a party that is a State, metropolitan city, local government, county, or other unit of government that is not the Federal Government.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2CD8CC8DDEE54777B45E6AAA2A8BFD54"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Is designated as a covered settlement agreement by the Director as a result of meeting additional criteria determined by the Director as described in subsection (b)(2)(C).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0975579386FF47408BB602AEAE6EFF4A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <quote>covered settlement agreement</quote> does not include a settlement agreement that relates to any of the following:</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB44396064C64B02ABAA67821168E6A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Trustee Program.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F395C2956884F9796612532DC35F7E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal employee personnel action, including an action before the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Office of Special Counsel, or the Merit Systems Protection Board, or any other internal personnel-related matter.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24DCDE112CDC4DCE93B389BDF6CFD9B3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A non-prosecution agreement or plea bargain.</text></clause> <clause id="H4F102EEFAE884C749B6A756BE6AFDFF8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H07BF3EA0CA1A4FA89E98DDA99B75D73F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any matter that may be brought as an action pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/46">chapter 46</external-xref> of title 18.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1826B7D2192F4445A88F39A9945399C3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA416485439634095961A4B73E89E510C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>local government</term> has the meaning given the term in section 6501 of title 31.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5E76898B19544CF926B3031C27B88F5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Originating agency</header><text>The term <term>originating agency</term> means an agency on behalf of which or at the request of which another agency executes a settlement agreement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2539B957E10344878F8A671639050B2F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Settlement agreement</header><text>The term <term>settlement agreement</term> means an agreement (including a consent decree) that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCD8D399D710D4436A0520C188E61F039"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is entered into by an agency; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA2EFE1F6EEA488A9A0FA5E0CE5E97AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resolves an alleged violation of Federal, civil, or criminal law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA945AF6DF22485097F29C962A2885CF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each territory or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF5232E041AA242FB87AF6C135656A966"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered settlement agreement information database</header> 
<paragraph id="HA0F7F9CAF07B4922853C9F600CE3A7F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency requirement</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF78E438D9241404A902BDB0B1CDDB620"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the head of each agency that has entered into a covered settlement agreement shall establish and maintain a public online database that, subject to subparagraph (B), contains the following information and documents to the extent practicable: </text> <clause id="H9F20204967FC4C15B44371B68404C7E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list (in a categorized and searchable format) that includes each covered settlement agreement entered into by such agency and publishes with respect to each such covered settlement agreement the following:</text> 
<subclause id="H79F36832BC16464DB766A47D06063464" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Whether the covered settlement agreement resolves a civil or criminal claim or both.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H282EB97586A044B0B623145F4B817542"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The date on which each party settling a claim under the covered settlement agreement executes such covered settlement agreement.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD4A790F501CC40E09712984FC47744F5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Any specific statutory provision alleged to have been violated, as may be set forth in any corresponding public letter or complaint.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H03CEE9A4589F4B66BD2D73A92560038E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Any expressly denominated amount of fees and other expenses of attorneys provided by or to the United States.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBF4F98C529D940889D1310C65C540C61"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The amount, if any, each party settling a claim under the covered settlement agreement is explicitly obligated to pay as set forth in such covered settlement agreement.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H60107F8C757E45FAAD3922D09524CCA9"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The amount, if any, each party settling a claim under the covered settlement agreement is obligated to pay as expressly specified under the covered settlement agreement as a civil or criminal penalty or fine.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5765DDF8CBAB4AD396E3707B8D9A9EB4"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Any payment made under the covered settlement agreement, including the amount of any payment made to or by the Federal Government.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB5A94B7AED7F491897E9A7CFB571A5E7"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>The projected duration of the covered settlement agreement, if available.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9993398718C94F3990BAC019D99ADF2E"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>A list of any State, local government, county, or any other unit of government that is directly identified by the substantive terms of the covered settlement agreement.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9A59719FA1184120B46DCF3B8563CAA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A copy of each such covered settlement agreement.</text></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0F77ED4A1C940E3B6795B522C41707A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement to publish a copy of or any other information with respect to a covered settlement agreement pursuant to subparagraph (A) does not apply to the extent such copy (or portion thereof) or information—</text> <clause id="H8A47984B099C466296E819781E9A983E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is subject to a confidentiality provision or court order that prohibits the disclosure of such copy (or portion) or information; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4383440EF1544003A60D24133155393F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would be subject to withholding from public disclosure under section 552.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC9E2B5CCC554591992DB7D989141084"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director, in coordination with the Attorney General, shall issue, and periodically update as necessary thereafter, guidance for the head of each agency to implement paragraph (1) that includes the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H538868D7F72A428F85E7A9E5A6A54693"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specific dates by which such head shall publish information necessary to maintain the database of such agency pursuant to paragraph (1)(A), which shall be not less frequently than annually.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BE252DE4D274024B71EC6ECB3C60B16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Data standards, including common data elements and a common, nonproprietary, searchable, machine-readable, and platform-independent format, for the publication of information pursuant to paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85F225527D414450865911C2724EEF53"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Additional criteria that such head shall use to determine if a settlement agreement is likely to require significant compliance costs such that such head shall designate such settlement agreement as a covered settlement agreement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F2D8A29171C47B1996975DD76FE4278"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A requirement that such head shall use a uniform resource locator for the establishment of the database of such agency pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) that—</text> 
<clause id="H33EAFE0C966F4616BF26F28922144512"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is—</text> <subclause id="HEEE5D0327AF34F26A02F99400B01B63F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in a consistent format across agencies; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H087403E9C1D44D0BAC9EF119B5F75F68"><enum>(II)</enum><text>descriptive, memorable, and pronounceable; and</text></subclause> </clause> <clause id="H2A9E26F178A0487F96701235348E492A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be <quote>agencyname.gov/settlements</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB069CA1282D4B5AA73CECFDBFBFED81"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A process that such head may use to request certification from the Director that a database of such agency that exists on the date of the enactment of this section complies with this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H879C5D082077405A829503AF143CD00B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A process for requiring the head of not less than 1 agency to publish a covered settlement agreement on a database required by paragraph (1)(A) if—</text> 
<clause id="H959A9E47F1084B9496FC3894DDC68D70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>multiple agencies are a party to such covered settlement agreement; or</text></clause> <clause id="H544E0DBD457C4D5F9E97E3EE6E73DB49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such head enters into an additional covered settlement agreement at the request of or on behalf of an originating agency. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H195ACA9CB9924FD5B0955809BBC260C2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-disclosure transparency</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD3562B5EED2F436BABCEC1CA2F5B713C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Report on non-disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the head of each agency that establishes and maintains a database pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) shall submit to Congress and make publicly available on the website of such agency a report on covered settlement agreements that the agency does not publicly disclose in the database for the covered settlements published in the previous year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF17C49445D5F48F5867FC57067372C4C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report described in subparagraph (A) shall include—</text> 
<clause id="HC6316D3735F3440EBEC18E7A05915C39"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of covered settlement agreements that were fully exempted under paragraph (1)(B);</text></clause> <clause id="HB22C1796139840B297D418CB5A4A253B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each covered settlement agreement fully exempted under paragraph (1)(B), the specific exemption under that paragraph that applies; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB75F3059DDEE4B64995F20D1979A98D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a full exemption under paragraph (1)(B)(ii), the specific exemptions under section 552 that apply.</text> </clause> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H39A81EC7DDD34F8190D97730A7FE0D22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/3">chapter 3</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H21A91A26403C45E199D6FE1B6D82BB72"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">307. Information regarding settlement agreements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8BF2DBB7C1F4447F8A6065D14C39E14F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header> 
<paragraph id="H5256BBB9D0A7421DB568BF84BAB09107" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any information published on a database established and maintained pursuant to section 307(b)(1)(A) of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall not affect the terms of a settlement agreement or the interpretation or application of the settlement agreement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5782ED10403241F6A789212AE8A253D4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Legal rights</header><text>The inclusion or omission of information or documents in a database established and maintained pursuant to section 307(b)(1)(A) of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall not be construed as creating any legal right or opportunity for judicial review.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB8CFAA2D6B3422D8C794148EB7BC026" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Freedom of Information Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to require the disclosure of information or records that the head of an agency may withhold from public disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10FD42D1CD214DEBB6AF3FD41EC1154F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Classified information</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to require the disclosure of classified information.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7EA30F51C80849BFA3550FCBB78DF497" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall apply with respect to—</text> <paragraph id="H6E1D2B0ADC5D408594EE9587FC44C1F1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any covered settlement agreement (as defined in section 307(a) of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)) entered into on or after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36280D9F73594146B8DD4EEAE39F9D45" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practicable, any such covered settlement agreement that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCAEB1FC6EFDC4741B5E769A5F78501CF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was entered into on or after January 1, 2015; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88F6704148AC45B996B407056CE5596A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remains in effect on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

