<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3008D53F1AE64C77BACB7A27FE5AA7CA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7815 IH: Red Star Service Banner Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7815</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 36, United States Code, to establish the Red Star Service Banner as an officially recognized service banner, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5FB6BD71EF0C435B9A5421D9BB7212D0" style="OLC"><section id="H615215B3B11544489623C307F5EE5201" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Red Star Service Banner Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE5EE09E9B3E9410E8855232125D7FBDD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of the Red Star Service Banner</header><subsection id="HE5D9DF6083EA4B43B378A07E2111151C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/36/9">Chapter 9</external-xref> of title 36, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H934A07E31D204893B69F85E1DB9FA7BC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H24EA6E1EB9164DC181CCD009B1660B94"><enum>905.</enum><header>Red Star Service Banner</header><subsection id="H532DB8C7DE314A06820A0BFF7A02D94C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Red Star Service Banner is designated as a commemorative symbol—</text><paragraph id="HB73F34557E86461B94D9D823E3CBD5A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizing and remembering the service members and veterans of the United States who have died by suicide; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81796F630F16450EB600E78F44DB141F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledging the enduring sacrifice of their families.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0D7EA5809AF4DC5A50DE49328005658"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design</header><text>The Red Star Service Banner shall consist of a white field with a blue border and a single red star centered within the field, as approved by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE026EB38FB5C4EE1AE7413AACC49359C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Display</header><text>The Red Star Service Banner may be displayed—</text><paragraph id="H079E13A6CC894E6894AB32A336910CFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at the place of residence of a member of the immediate family of a service member or veteran who has died by suicide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H792F0C54279C4719A5732E2AA2694741"><enum>(2)</enum><text>within the office or building of a veterans service organization or any similar entity that supports service members, veterans, and their families;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7BD1C310EB54D9D87C90DF03A1D2D12"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the workplace or place of business of a member of the immediate family of a service member or veteran who has died by suicide, or in any business establishment that chooses to honor the memory of service members and veterans who have died by suicide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74062F54E49D4609893327496238A658"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in public buildings, including Federal, State, Tribal, and local government facilities, when displayed as part of a program, ceremony, or installation intended to recognize and support service members, veterans, and their families;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01C5484954404D41B8D5C84F1713F558"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in community spaces open to the public, including schools, libraries, places of worship, and civic centers, when used to promote awareness of the sacrifices of service members and veterans and to support surviving families; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14AE514A426349AB9581695A1A54199F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>at any other appropriate location, public or private, where the display serves to honor the memory of service members and veterans who have died by suicide.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37E4E661ADAA436F89E8AFEF13BBB435"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relation to other service banners</header><text>The Red Star Service Banner may be displayed alongside other officially recognized service banners.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9F21570E19484388A77C100A5F98AA8F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public awareness</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, may take appropriate actions to promote public awareness and understanding of the Red Star Service Banner.</text></subsection><subsection id="H58D66236DD8C4103BA3DCEA73370DF33"><enum>(f)</enum><header>First responders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Red Star Service Banner may also be displayed to honor the memory of a first responder who has died by suicide, including first responders such as firefighters, law enforcement officers, and emergency medical personnel, and may be displayed at the place of residence, workplace, or place of business of a member of the immediate family of such a first responder or in any other locations that bear the same relationship to first responders as the locations described in subsection (c) bear to service members and veterans.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2601FB28AE674897AE92FCA2AF7D354A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="HFA7202F0C99F4EE2BED3C60E2286155E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish eligibility for, or entitlement to, any benefit, program, or assistance administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs or any other Federal agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F9DF2C218B74C37907B1E5E677930B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require the Department of Veterans Affairs to administer, certify, or approve individual eligibility for display of the Red Star Service Banner; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB41145AC27B44E8D83EBC3E51E6675D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>create any legal status, designation, or classification for purposes of Federal law other than recognition under this chapter.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H58E747028C3F4532AC16881D558E7E5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for chapter 9 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H5B19E5DEFC504BC4825FC1291CC449FC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">905. Red Star Service Banner.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HFC8D67BEEA224AA0848EDCAAA8556867"><enum>3.</enum><header>No additional appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the amendments made by this Act, and the amendments made by this Act shall be carried out using amounts otherwise made available to the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

