<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H21ED5BC7C5544C17B6062F84F0C253C6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9684 IH: Pre-Apprenticeships To Hardhats Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9684</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Labor to support the development of pre-apprenticeship programs in the building and construction trades that serve underrepresented populations, including individuals from low income and rural census tracts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H52D493ECAD0F48F893FEABE716461BDE" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HF19E8F7F765D48CE9D93F8A81236AE52"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pre-Apprenticeships To Hardhats Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PATH Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80562E28BD4945ACADEA11D223545E94"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H71B604C451CB4EFBBAD9D59EED096B1C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Area career and technical school</header><text>The term <term>area career and technical school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H933DFF8C335E4506B9445E72097E2F85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federally recognized Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Federally recognized Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian Tribe</term> in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9A25F1EE27984A349341342E39EEAA66"><enum>(3)</enum><header>High school</header><text>The term <term>high school</term> means a nonprofit institutional day or residential school in a State that—</text> <subparagraph id="H1AC28CA4DFFA47FE98BE4F201A51B5F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides secondary education, as determined under State law;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCD141168A82A47FEA57B3FDF06F2ABCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>grants a diploma, as defined by the State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF6D42C281A7416BAAE4613BF7CA27BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes, at least, grade 12.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H852EDDFC19E7458EBFC8267B3DF4CF90"><enum>(4)</enum><header>In-demand industry sector or occupation</header><text>The term <term>in-demand industry sector or occupation</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H67AE987CBA1C4538984CEEB7670FED3F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Local educational agency; state educational agency</header><text>The terms <term>local educational agency</term> and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H05B471F64D6B4623ADC6EC8FA7CA7709"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Local and state workforce development boards</header><text>The terms <term>local workforce development board</term> and <term>State workforce development board</term> have the meanings given the terms <term>local board</term> and <term>State board</term>, respectively, in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1A8D2A5398544BA961A5CB55F604565"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Postsecondary educational institution</header><text>The term <term>postsecondary educational institution</term> has the meaning given the term <term>institution of higher education</term> in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5DD769BCA65043419A449AAD156BC927"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Pre-apprenticeship program</header><text>The term <term>pre-apprenticeship program</term> means a program or set of strategies that—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE39C57BEBE24922A9FA10FA12BF76EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is designed to prepare individuals to enter and succeed in a registered apprenticeship program in the building or construction trades;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1DA5323C5E6F4D7AA2ED6FE77731E8F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is carried out by an eligible entity described in section 3(c) that has a documented partnership with at least 1 sponsor of a registered apprenticeship program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BD32742920249C8AB379559FF6D63EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes training (including a curriculum for the training) that—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33CF0FEA7FF24E98A7F4C4FCC27DEC2C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is aligned with industry standards;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A73C9E3F1774EC1B8A19CF5A72AE5E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is reviewed and approved annually by sponsors of the registered apprenticeship programs within the documented partnership; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63E7BE06EE8D442F8DD665FDCB7CE09D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will prepare an individual for a registered apprenticeship program by teaching the skills and competencies needed to enter such a registered apprenticeship program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4F2AB923BBD4AEDB43B3AE4266A9D47"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Registered apprenticeship program</header><text>The term <term>registered apprenticeship program</term> means a program registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6116E7DEB5DB492AB5730DF6D219DB2F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H269C5D7FBCD44F4FB7F68FF604AAE099"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Sponsor</header><text>The term <term>sponsor</term> means an employer, joint labor-management partnership, trade association, professional association, labor organization, or other entity that administers a registered apprenticeship program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H042A366EC4704697B94ABCD192BCD260"><enum>(12)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75386D2DD57F4922A9098AA34C7D91BC"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Underrepresented population</header><text>The term <term>underrepresented population</term> means a group of individuals who—</text>
<subparagraph id="HEF78EB9444644FC39A3580193E79E15E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are members of a racial minority, women, military veterans, members of a Federally recognized Indian Tribe, or long-term unemployed; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8841375745B8426A996BABC69FB08504"><enum>(B)</enum><text>come from a geographic area consisting of a single census tract or a group of census tracts, each of which meets the criteria for a low-income community, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45D">section 45D(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="HFCCACBFBB2044649A37FCF09090C8949"><enum>3.</enum><header>Supporting the development of pre-apprenticeship programs</header>
<subsection id="HB43FC85EBACE49F8AEDB0606D6584F1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall make grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities described in subsection (c) that submit applications under subsection (e) to provide the Federal share described in subsection (g) of the cost of carrying out projects under subsection (f) that support the development of pre-apprenticeship programs in the building and construction trades.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE62C2182DA234288AED1EF2765B018A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period</header><text>The Secretary shall make initial grants under subsection (a) for periods of not more than 3 years, except that if an eligible entity demonstrates satisfactory performance under subsection (h) by the end of that third year, the Secretary may extend the grant period up to an additional 1 year for that entity.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8EEF6B8E9630441097F76DA698D918C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant from the Secretary under subsection (a), an entity shall be a nonprofit partnership that—</text> <paragraph id="H1508B3CD6D4F4F72951E8D195C79DB19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes the equal participation of industry, including public or private employers, and labor organizations, including joint labor or management training programs, and may include State and local workforce development boards, community-based organizations, educational institutions (such as postsecondary educational institutions, local educational agencies, State educational agencies, high schools, and area career and technical schools), small businesses, cooperatives, State and local veterans agencies, and veterans service organizations; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H07240A0046AA4676BFA56BF627DFC956"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrates—</text> <subparagraph id="H2DAF520A6C0846DEBD0FB95C8D4D9E7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>experience in implementing and operating worker skills training and education programs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA5FE83223B7F4AADBB52A0AB9A3ED535"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ability to identify and involve in training programs carried out under this grant, target populations of individuals who would benefit from training, and be actively involved in activities related to all building and construction trade crafts; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FDBD442802E4EE289F3E0561B8868C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the ability to help individuals achieve economic self-sufficiency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HBD537A089B234479AD18775763B3A03A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that leverage additional public and private resources to fund programs under this Act, including cash or in-kind matches from participating employers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC247D597FEE24000BCBEE71DCB652D16"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant from the Secretary under subsection (a), an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text>
<paragraph id="HFFF304585CBB488CBCDA69891CB0276E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to the proposed pre-apprenticeship program, a description of the training and curriculum described in section 2(8)(C) and how the proposed pre-apprenticeship program makes individuals who successfully complete the pre-apprenticeship program qualified to enter into an established registered apprenticeship program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A4C110C5B884CBA9613D4CECF948CB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evidence that there are or will be sufficient openings available in such registered apprenticeship program to enable the sponsor of such registered apprenticeship program to place into a corresponding registered apprenticeship those individuals who successfully complete the pre-apprenticeship program;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDA59C481C214437A8209FA3292487F44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information about the entity that demonstrates the existence of an active, advisory partnership between the partners described in subsection (c)(1) and the capacity of a training and education provider of the entity to provide the training and education services necessary for a pre-apprenticeship program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D4A025E154241E0A73AFA4EB5E6B4E7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>information about the proposed pre-apprenticeship program that demonstrates—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC57EF65BF5FD4487A752A9293B9E8AF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the program is in an in-demand industry or occupation in the region in which the project is located;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2811C72F87C64011ACB9C9D8A781583C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the inclusion in the program of career exploration focused activities, such as career information activities, and résumé preparation;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HABFC6C2A274448B0AFC6B2EC0A07E1D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the entity carrying out the project includes a high school, that the model to be used for the program leads to a high school diploma for participants without such a diploma;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB2C010CBB8C421193C4218B2E016805"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how the pre-apprenticeship program is aligned with and leverages resources of career and technical education programs, programs and services authorized under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>), or activities of entities that provide supportive services for participants in pre-apprenticeship programs; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3DB82DB4498847C495E9AB16B955FA00"><enum>(E)</enum><text>that the project aligns with an established registered apprenticeship program, including that the model used for the program leads to the attainment of skills and competencies necessary for entrance into the registered apprenticeship program for participants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4AAF158435504916B698DC027746837D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <paragraph id="H42E733041296410F917BB87EE2380A03"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall use the grant funds to carry out a project that implements a pre-apprenticeship program, including the activities described in paragraphs (2) and (3).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0384909902884787B4EE15AC72BDC683"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required activities</header><text>The eligible entity shall use such grant funds—</text> <subparagraph id="HB726C7AB303049FB83B57CFB76068E03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to pay for the cost of training or education associated with a pre-apprenticeship program for individuals from an underrepresented population;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H56A83F98FF12479A973DA2F20959B2E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for curriculum development that align with the requirements of the appropriate registered apprenticeship programs and learning assessments;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H446FF73D11AB4FFDB385968745E53627"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to maintain a connection between the pre-apprenticeship program and registered apprenticeship program;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HECCEC330E5724981A04BBBD634DEFAE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for assessments of potential participants for, and enrollment of the participants in, the pre-apprenticeship program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6CF1462F02D7493D831A235B48B25F52"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to conduct evaluations described in subsection (h)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H45A5169CA7EC40D5AB0A7FD55D140AF3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allowable activities</header><text>The eligible entity may use such grant funds for—</text> <subparagraph id="H233E0F8D269F4069A9F019F7F53E99FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>stipends for participants during work-based training in the program; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE45587B1565C49238458CF85C7B61663"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordination of activities under this subsection with activities carried out under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2301">20 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H54E5752417F04C71B16B9E230972B9D4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal share</header> <paragraph id="H9BCD017F085E485981A2268EC98997E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal share of the cost described in subsection (a) shall be 75 percent of the total cost of the projects described in such subsection carried out by an eligible entity.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33B1EA8633AE4A47BA597937D07E42C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-federal share</header><text>The eligible entity may contribute the non-Federal share of such cost in cash or in-kind, fairly evaluated, including plant, equipment, or services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1495EC5802FC4DDFBEFEAD01FEAEA3FD"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Performance</header> <paragraph id="H4FA874E53CF040F89406E15B0BD7134D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Measures</header><text>The Secretary shall identify a set of common measures that, at a minimum, include measures of entry into a registered apprenticeship program and that are aligned, as appropriate, with performance accountability measures described in section 116(c) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(c)</external-xref>) for the local workforce development area and with corresponding measures under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2301">20 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H70C6892B5E9D445999ADF7BED0597426"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant to carry out a project under subsection (a) shall arrange for another qualified entity to conduct an evaluation, or shall participate in an evaluation sponsored by the Secretary, of the project using the identified common measures, and shall, to the extent practicable, cooperate with the evaluator in any evaluations of activities carried out under paragraph.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H388A5B73755B4AE988C96539EC389ECF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extensions</header><text>The Secretary shall use the results of an evaluation for a project under paragraph (2) to determine whether to extend the grant period, or renew a grant, for the project under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H62ED2FE5403A4D449C052B71B2A7958D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2027 and each subsequent fiscal year.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

