<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL26013-FTD-V1-MT7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 583 IS: Recognizing 2026 as “The Year of The Power of Nurses” in Celebration of the 130th Anniversary of the American Nurses Association.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 583</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing 2026 as <quote>The Year of The Power of Nurses</quote> in Celebration of the 130th Anniversary of the American Nurses Association.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas nurses represent the largest segment of the healthcare workforce in the United States, serving as the backbone of our healthcare system and as trusted professionals who protect, educate, heal, and advocate for patients and communities across every setting of care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the American Nurses Association, founded in 1896, has stood as the unified voice for the nation’s nurses for 130 years, advancing the profession through advocacy, education, and standards that safeguard the health, safety, and well-being of the country;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for more than a century, nurses have been on the frontlines of every major health challenge, demonstrating extraordinary skill, courage, and resilience whether responding to pandemics, delivering primary care, conducting groundbreaking research, leading public health efforts, educating the next generation, or shaping health policy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas The Power of Nurses represents the enduring strength, leadership, and expertise of nurses, reflecting their role as caretakers, clinicians, innovators, educators, mentors, and changemakers who expand access to care and improve patient outcomes for all;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the year 2026 marks a momentous milestone, the 130th Anniversary of the American Nurses Association, providing an opportunity to honor the nursing profession’s rich legacy, recognize the countless ways nurses advance health and healing, and reaffirm their essential role in sustaining the well-being of our country; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is fitting that we dedicate the year 2026 to celebrating and recognizing The Power of Nurses, honoring their compassion, expertise, and unwavering commitment to improving lives and shaping a healthier future for us all: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H37640056E47043BD9816630C5FEED981"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDAF61FAFBC3F42A29EC383AC3501047E"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="HEEFC531C21E941C58930240BD5207B6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes 2026 as <quote>The Year of The Power of Nurses</quote> in recognition of the 130th Anniversary of the American Nurses Association; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H250716CC0733471AA0771E07A72DE38E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the extraordinary contributions of nurses to the health, safety, and prosperity of the United States of America.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

