<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HD7E81D5DD8EB438FA3CDC7F6148E4437" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1468 RH: Protect America’s Innovation and Economic Security from CCP Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 607</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1468</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–699]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250221">February 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 21, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the CCP Initiative program, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HJU00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H7C9FAFF4C7BA4FA2BD1B768D767EA822"><section id="H540B1BF7831B40EEA0B626E7114DB5B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect America’s Innovation and Economic Security from CCP Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7673D99CBB4549E9B13A7CA1F743160F"><enum>2.</enum><header>CCP Initiative</header><subsection id="HB8D6C8B351CF48A7B9A9B224BDF0622D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the National Security Division of the Department of Justice the CCP Initiative to—</text><paragraph id="HDA9622CCE962424A899EED3C2A1F96DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>curb spying by the CCP on United States intellectual property and academic institutions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61FCEA48D24C4572A6183B4641B7E417"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop an enforcement strategy concerning nontraditional collectors, including researchers in labs, universities, and the defense industrial base, transferring technology to PRC-based individuals or entities, or those acting as their agents, contrary to United States interests;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFADC7FB780EF43768439C6A84378C4F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review and take appropriate action, as part of the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, to address PRC-related risks arising from foreign investments in United States businesses and real estate; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF482C191BC6D4115968937DB123AAD15"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritize, with respect to PRC-based individuals or entities, or those acting as their agents—</text><subparagraph id="H802507086E5E4F01A0480E4687F7FD3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying and criminally prosecuting those engaged in trade secret theft, hacking, and economic espionage, including those who aid, abet, or conspire to engage in trade secret theft, hacking, or economic espionage; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94578C416B7C494FA6BE239445D3346A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protecting the critical infrastructure of the United States from threats arising from foreign direct investment, insider threats and supply chain compromises; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60E97655254349549C9EC7E57533242B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying theft of intellectual property from United States businesses; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H010FE960B53F4537BDF034D695292952"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">counter any other threats to the United States by the PRC or those acting as its agents.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A5D2A26FC4F44819E6E7BE3244D8A51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In executing the CCP Initiative’s objectives as set forth in subsection (a), the Attorney General, acting through the Assistant Attorney General for National Security, shall consult with the relevant components of the Department of Justice, and coordinate activities with the Federal Bureau of Investigation and any other Federal agency as necessary on matters including—</text><paragraph id="H2AB984007F884136970487822173F3EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying cases of concern involving PRC-based companies that compete with United States businesses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3B5433C63D04D0492AEDFAFDFE638DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying and investigating investments made by PRC-based or PRC-affiliated entities included on the Entity List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce or the People's Republic of China Military Companies list maintained by the Department of Defense; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0C08EFD8722453AAE363201E836E372"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other matters relevant to fulfill the objectives set forth in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB218A08F7E7841559C2EE879FF88C589"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the CCP Initiative—</text><paragraph id="H6C571C56BF0B4424B154CBFD3E675B0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Initiative shall be separate from any other Department of Justice initiative dedicated to countering nation-state threats; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ACF7694B7CD44D8AE89DAC5511DAC7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">resources shall be set aside for the CCP Initiative, which shall not be combined to support any other Department of Justice program, including other programs and initiatives dedicated to countering nation-state threats, except under exceptional circumstances, as determined by the Attorney General, acting through the Assistant Attorney General for National Security, in which case, resources may be combined to support other programs and initiatives dedicated to countering nation-state threats.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3814026365D4424483B1ABB9A151A704"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall submit annually a written report, with a classified annex as necessary, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, the intelligence community, the United States Trade Representative, and the head of any other Federal agency determined necessary by the Attorney General, for the purposes of the report, to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, on the progress and challenges of the CCP Initiative over the preceding year, including—</text><paragraph id="H4AC94C321E6C43FCB217A0E8D9E42BFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>its progress in accomplishing the objectives set forth in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD13D17464A34BFA88F9747AB7BF1029"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount and sufficiency of resources provided to, and expended by, the CCP Initiative;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62B0BF3C87F243E3B363EAD35980B4DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the level and effectiveness of coordination with the Federal Bureau of Investigation and other Federal agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E1F9F84C1B647CB898E193F52D418E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of efforts by and the financial intelligence capabilities of the PRC to engage in trade secret theft, hacking, and economic espionage; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H725D3CB11E1048C09AA15D7A1EAB8CF8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the use of unmanned aircraft and associated elements (including communication links and the components that control the unmanned aircraft required for the operator to operate safely and efficiently in the national airspace system) by the PRC;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0473986A7A094BE8AE9D0EE83B883F3E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the capabilities, effectiveness, and use of artificial intelligence by the PRC and its proxies to engage in trade secret theft, hacking, or economic espionage; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B1C48B0B53944BAA0CC68B25844C826" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any non-privileged findings of investigations of investments made by PRC-based or PRC-affiliated entities included on the Entity List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce or the People's Republic of China Military Companies list maintained by the Department of Defense, including findings related to subsidiaries or other entities controlled by PRC companies, whether or not such subsidiaries or other entities are registered in or operate in the PRC;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DD5B6B03F504F4B9B17F8FCA0F7031B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the impact of the CCP Initiative on those efforts of the PRC;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0B2B0B60659412193222EE67FE8323C"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the level and effectiveness of coordination and information sharing between Government agencies and private companies about economic espionage threats; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79691F4CF6144FD7B3C8FD9DD842363E"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the economic loss to the United States as a result of hacking and trade secret theft by the PRC. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D291C47C6394D5AB4D4D41F22503380"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This Act shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and cease to be in effect on the date that is 6 years after that date.</text></subsection><subsection id="H33A2E1171F2D4571A63AD55B846AE102"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the provisions of such to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection><subsection id="H07510A2709C2477A96797EF87A1733FF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H28B94B6490F5487DBF0AA4BB4E8CEB06"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>non-traditional collector</quote> means an individual who is not an intelligence collection professional but who collects sensitive technologies and information on behalf of, or for the benefit of, any foreign government, foreign instrumentality, or foreign agent. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H926E91F3001B47C0897DDF8513D1607E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>CCP</quote> means the Chinese Communist Party. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C26C3D34F6E4F369340BF7E1536DB29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>PRC</quote> means the People’s Republic of China, the government of the People’s Republic of China, and the CCP.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H394645CDBED940F5A14048F1C8D31311"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>intelligence community</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

