<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8E61000355604CB5BBFAD8880C267590" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8098 IH: To direct the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library to obtain a statue of Shirley Chisholm for placement in the United States Capitol.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8098</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library to obtain a statue of Shirley Chisholm for placement in the United States Capitol.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEFD32FD6CD3641A08DC43998C946692B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2DB9EAE92D0F43BD8567944FDDEBE60F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Placement of statue of Shirley Chisholm in United States Capitol</header> 
<subsection id="HFDBCE90730584E898EC5974476355608"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Obtaining Statue</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library shall enter into an agreement to obtain a statue of Shirley Chisholm, under such terms and conditions as the Joint Committee considers appropriate consistent with applicable law. The Joint Committee may authorize the Architect of the Capitol to enter into the agreement and related contracts required under this subsection on its behalf, under such terms and conditions as the Joint Committee may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFF8BD84964F9472A8DB9AAC44702EC3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Placement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Joint Committee of Congress on the Library shall place the statue obtained under subsection (a) in a public permanent location in the United States Capitol.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7155DD314FE644578BDDAF7622202135"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act, and any amounts so appropriated shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

