<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4D5A5D791E9642BEABB97DD84F1A12A8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 844 IH: Expressing support for the designation of October 2025 as “Crime Prevention Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 844</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of October 2025 as <quote>Crime Prevention Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Crime Prevention Council estimates that the global sale of counterfeit goods constitutes a criminal enterprise valued at approximately $2,000,000,000,000 annually, with proceeds fueling human trafficking, organized crime, and the distribution of fake pharmaceuticals (including those containing fentanyl), posing serious threats to public health and safety;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, on average a violent crime was recorded every 25.9 seconds in 2024, underscoring the ongoing prevalence of reported serious offenses;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Bureau of Justice Statistics 2023 National Crime Victimization Survey found 22.5 violent victimizations per 1,000 persons aged 12 or older, underscoring the continued human cost of crime despite recent gains;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to Vanderbilt University, researchers estimate that personal and property crimes impose an aggregate economic burden of approximately $2,600,000,000,000 annually in lost quality of life, direct victim expenses, and taxpayer costs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Federal Bureau of Investigation’s Internet Crime Complaint Center received more than 880,000 complaints in 2023 alone, with reported losses exceeding $12,500,000,000, highlighting the growing need to prevent cyber-enabled crimes;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas community-based violence intervention models, when paired with law enforcement partnerships, have demonstrated success in reducing violent incidents and generating substantial taxpayer savings;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas other evidence-based strategies, such as neighborhood watch coalitions, youth mentorship and afterschool programs, Crime Prevention Through Environmental Design, and data-driven policing, have demonstrated measurable success in deterring crime and strengthening trust between law enforcement agencies and the communities they serve;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas sustained investment in mental health services, substance use treatment, reentry support, and violence interruption initiatives addresses root causes of criminal behavior and reduces recidivism;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas preventing crime and keeping communities safe has long been a bipartisan priority across Federal, State, Tribal, territorial, and local governments;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas victims of crime and their families deserve continued support and access to services to help them recover and rebuild;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas communities across the United States benefit when government, civil society, and private partners work together to prevent crime and support victims;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Crime Prevention Council inaugurated <quote>Crime Prevention Month</quote> in October 1984, encouraging residents, businesses, educators, faith leaders, and elected officials to partner in proactive safety efforts; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas renewing national attention to <quote>Crime Prevention Month</quote> each October galvanizes Federal, State, Tribal, territorial, and local stakeholders to collaborate on innovative, evidence-based solutions that keep communities safe: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas> </preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H3D51B51A05F8440A86E9561B1B21618F"> 
<section id="H41E4B8AD6AE6471DADBBB66B344429EC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H35A7E864E8AD433987B4AE3673756A29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>Crime Prevention Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67D1B6AC538C4813B2D8BA1050A68CBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends law enforcement officers, first responders, community organizers, educators, researchers, violence intervention specialists, and volunteers whose work prevents crime and supports victims;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D07FE32CA494307B44CADEFB2064D88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages Federal agencies to support evidence-based crime prevention and violence intervention grants, including programs focused on youth mentorship, behavioral health treatment, and safe housing design;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B9B1DE6CD774AD5835FABBFEA02CCA0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages States, local governments, and Tribal nations to incorporate Crime Prevention Through Environmental Design principles in infrastructure and housing projects, and to expand public-private partnerships that revitalize neighborhoods and create economic opportunity; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18D95E35007A43F6A40DBED69AB575F7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls upon all citizens of the United States to observe <quote>Crime Prevention Month</quote> with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities that promote public safety, highlight community success stories, and reaffirm the shared responsibility to build safer, more resilient communities.</text></paragraph> </section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

