<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE62F538F68B847E6A6F43E7F053FE2FA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7907 IH: AI-Ready Bio-Data Standards Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7907</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to facilitate the establishment of definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks to ensure certain biological datasets are ready for use in artificial intelligence models, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H86D285EF444F4184907F351631A43B17" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEAF0E4202A4349DCAD78B95FEA7777E4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AI-Ready Bio-Data Standards Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6D092EDC237F47C1B3C3F441E48AB2DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks by the National Institute of Standards and Technology for certain biological datasets</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HD3DE9116F4C44E84AF74DA5EF2F6BBF3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="HA208DFEC37E94C6D98BF2D121926663C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>), pursuant to recommendations from the advisory group under subsection (f) and taking into account any feedback received under subsection (e), shall facilitate the establishment of definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks to ensure each biological dataset generated as a result of qualified federally funded research is artificial intelligence-ready.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H827DF9EB5393451F83A26C11CCABCD28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H79AD6090810444ED9E9BAEBEBBDF132D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D873099E20140ED8B43C4DCDEFE0D37"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Director shall facilitate the establishment of definitions for the following terms:</text> <subclause id="H3D5FDB87CE764780A1D2E46C5C3FE34C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Artificial intelligence-ready.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2FBFB3343C494386A767516C2AC00920"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Biomanufacturing.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H88CCC3CF926D42319EFEC51CDBD321B2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Biotechnology.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H0D636A9222DC4D46A06905B703C20736"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Qualified federally funded research.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H2A5CC81A67374C16A96D98B2ABA523D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements for definition of artificial intelligence-ready</header> <subclause id="H58DEF81654E74298B6132427B4F4F5B7"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In facilitating the establishment of the definition of the term <quote>artificial intelligence-ready</quote> under clause (i)(I), the Director shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure such definition, when applied to a biological dataset, requires such dataset be generated and formatted in a manner that—</text> 
<item id="H4FA327BAB28B42C38D3903862E270525"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>enables the effective use of the dataset for training artificial intelligence models; and</text></item> <item id="H77DC4AACBE044EE2ABFFFB86D4A90EB9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>supports advancements in research relating to artificial intelligence and biotechnology.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H805CAD6E27C14761955D545FE769565C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Discretion</header><text>With respect to a biological dataset that otherwise satisfies the definition of <quote>artificial intelligence-ready</quote> under clause (i)(I), the Director may, in consultation with the Chief Data Officer of the Federal department or agency that is responsible for such biological dataset, determine that such dataset is not artificial intelligence-ready.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H4575DD6BED634A1EA25935CC5E3163E1"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Requirements for definition of qualified federally funded research</header><text>In facilitating the establishment of the definition of the term <quote>qualified federally funded research</quote> under clause (i)(IV), the Director shall take such actions as may be necessary to include in such definition certain conditions that, if satisfied, will result in certain federally funded research being qualified federally funded research. Such conditions shall include the following:</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H40C8946F3F6F4406B69A2CF58AB4A60B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of Federal funding awarded to a recipient.</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HF6E06E4AAC2A4161B3D2B7E7B0C84B8A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The capability of the recipient to generate a biological dataset that is artificial intelligence-ready.</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HFCBFBA4488114ABF89B93110DCDD0362"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expertise of the recipient in generating a biological dataset that is artificial intelligence-ready.</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HEE5CA703DA544D59A95772B96C9CB86D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The size of the biological dataset generated by the recipient.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCAA2BC119965458EAC6CCFA84FD3F987"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Any other condition the Director considers appropriate.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB133EA1C5F3E41C492B87279F9E60D19"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Director shall facilitate the establishment of standards relating to making biological datasets artificial intelligence-ready, in accordance with the definition of artificial intelligence-ready under subparagraph (A)(i)(I).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5E5A69603E0C4065B153084A39B6DCFA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Resources and frameworks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Director shall facilitate the establishment of data management resources and cybersecurity frameworks for the following:</text> <clause commented="no" id="HB7393572B59143BFBD7A93E6EADD8604"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal departments and agencies that provide either full or partial Federal funding for research that generates biological datasets.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HE4A968AB9AB0434DB1CBDD1152468895"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federally funded researchers who are collecting, cleaning, curating, or generating biological datasets to make the datasets artificial intelligence-ready.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCE36502D5A714573A0BF34896037F33E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks referred to in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<clause id="HC32550AD561540C78FFF3AB6F01C485C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are not overly burdensome on recipients of funding for qualified federally funded research, such that the act of generating biological datasets that are artificial intelligence-ready requires resources and expertise beyond those available to the recipients; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7951B41485494930B740E4CC1DFFC17D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are tested and evaluated in accordance with subsection (c).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD45EEB25EADC44D783474B2C9125B847"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual updates</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the establishment of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks under paragraph (1), and annually thereafter, the Director shall review such definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks and, as the Director considers appropriate, shall update such definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H68DF1FC72E32462AB8D9F4EC11C50587"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To facilitate the establishment of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks under paragraph (1), and any update under paragraph (3), the Director shall carry out the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2A5DD6CB597944B1ACA2D7C9EE833C0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assess any existing standard related to biotechnology or artificial intelligence, including any standards inventoried pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(A), and, if appropriate, facilitate the incorporation of any such standards in the establishment of the standards referred to in paragraph (2)(B).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B9BE640E2A24BC7BD54DD4335A99DCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Consult with the following:</text> 
<clause id="H2A401E1D83244D0EA4D7F0B64FF04AB1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text></clause> <clause id="H4AB8141C33764B72B7A8FD3D25F5AB7D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H213F8F4973E54F189DD531606C53970D" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy.</text></clause> <clause id="HE6A5D21CD4AE428BAF3281CDA695B3D5" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCACD64C1C82C4970A9E05A0082456F70" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text></clause> <clause id="HCE81454169B847AE9F12A01D4241B420" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Administrator of the National Science Foundation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB6A6134C8220472EB5D3FE0B7327ACFC" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The head of any other Federal department or agency the Director considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C1CACA7269F47D0BDD42B8D298BED98"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Seek to consult with the following:</text> 
<clause id="H9334BFBF1C434BC2BA8ECC24C516EED7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Private sector entities from the biotechnology industry.</text></clause> <clause id="HEA885809BEFE4256BFAC9FA3B6265F6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of academia.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6060F6D26E3748218DFD3ACA249D7233"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To facilitate the establishment of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks under paragraph (1), and any update under paragraph (3), the Director shall hire staff as the Director determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H283740F57A294CCE85CAFE8288B25344"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information gathering</header> <paragraph id="H0EE30FFAD66C47939D36E1418B4528EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall inventory the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF518A303970B4C2B8A1DA0F44DB15A1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Existing biotechnology standards utilized by recipients of Federal funding for biotechnology research to generate biological datasets.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB7ED4F76C110465BB492A7692683D339"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Existing biological datasets generated by recipients of Federal funding for biotechnology research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9169D6F4272148D797961FBEE72E7EA8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the Director completes the inventory requirement under paragraph (1), the Director shall make any information inventoried under that paragraph available to the public through a website of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HDFBFC8C1C2CC4F478A94FE8C64D0117E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Test and evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall coordinate with the Administrator of the National Science Foundation to conduct a test and evaluation of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks referred to in subsection (a)(1) on a sample of biological datasets generated as a result of qualified federally funded research to determine the following:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC4BE65BCADD040B8B6E1846077784171"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether such definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks are clearly written, easy to follow, and easily applicable for the generation of biological datasets that are artificial intelligence-ready.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H4B35CA89D2F54B8393FFD76C6FE1FD46"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether compliance with such definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks when generating or curating biological datasets results in an undue burden on the recipients of such qualified federally funded research, and if so, how to modify such definitions, standards, resources, or frameworks, as the case may be, so as to reduce such burden.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H44714B85B396415E9D601AE559E7DE70"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advice and assistance related to Federal department or agency data standards</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6BF352F3DE8443DF92AC75224527C174"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of a Federal department or agency that provides funding for qualified federally funded research and that seeks to utilize a biological dataset of such department or agency to train an artificial intelligence model may make a request to the Director to provide advice or assistance with respect to developing the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HA2B3924117F14C469399D43F95B365E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Data standards for such training.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC70A5D3EFB2D4448AB23CDA0E681ABC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any data management plan related to such data standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5D9377897634D4E8D21B60D9711C0F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resources</header><text>A head of a Federal department or agency that makes a request pursuant to paragraph (1) may enter into an agreement with the Director to provide to the Director any resources as may be necessary for the Director to provide any advice or assistance related to such request.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H79BC81801AD04408B323A89BC5B6FDF5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Oversight mechanisms</header><text>The Director shall establish the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5A8CDEA2BD774296BDAD542CDA127E63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A regularly updated central repository, made available to the public as the Director determines appropriate, on which the head of any Federal department or agency may publish any data standards, and data management plan related to such standards, relating to utilizing a biological dataset of such department or agency to train an artificial intelligence model.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H2157E135D228430FA2016A984A485D75"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A publicly available database to serve as a single point of access, updated as the Director determines necessary, on which the head of any Federal department or agency may publish artificial intelligence-ready biological datasets.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5A47290CD1234B2BB24706B97E0BD571"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A mechanism available to each Federal department or agency to make a request pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64FC3D693C054B098FA58829567E3FD3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public input</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may solicit input and feedback from the public with respect to any advice or assistance related to a request made pursuant to paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H908CE73DDE1946D6ABB835EACE09551B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public input and feedback; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a)(1), the Director shall carry out the following:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6F3FF68B22C2461CB4020B976B257AE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solicit input and feedback from the public regarding the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks referred to in such subsection.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HD4978EAE4E8948ECBFBAEBA5C92B7BCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consult the heads of Federal departments and agencies that provide funding for qualified federally funded research to ensure such departments and agencies are able to develop data standards, and any data management plan associated with such data standards, related to utilizing a biological dataset of such department or agency to train an artificial intelligence model, including the following:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H8D4E6BE8563F4A3D8AC58205CC2D85B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H552D685775C74483BC2FD52D7F6C06CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H99E1B6BCA28549129D8825D817E619B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H567462EAD73F4DF08FA7EE0913048563"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HBE5C8A35CE2F418EB653B3FCB193413B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE3111BBCF7294454AD0FA38462EEF78A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Administrator of the National Science Foundation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB8C1237718C34121BE4A36C7F27A32CD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The head of any other Federal department or agency as determined by the Director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4462152B6B4D42CEA4AB38241A110F08"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Advisory group</header> <paragraph id="H656C0621194C4283A529D3D293F5A6D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish an advisory group to carry out the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H40BDD005FB4445789221E6EF74C53777"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide recommendations relating to the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks referred to in subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67639141709A426A9FC63C05EFC63CAC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Review and provide feedback with respect to any advice or assistance related to a request made pursuant to subsection (d)(1).</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB0471D4769AB47F2BAD798665EBF7A5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Provide recommendations to academic journals for guidelines relating to artificial intelligence-ready biological datasets.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8F2D1158D6734F489D1AFB5F33EBDD02"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solicit recommendations from the academic community regarding implementation of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H3C8483FF7C304D49AA48AC57D478A6BE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Provide any other guidance the Director may request.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF74C2E0B9A8344B4953205633BA26495"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2514FF7D629D43D897DB2DFBF4CB628A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory group established under paragraph (1) shall be composed of not fewer than 12 members. The Director shall carry out the following:</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4217C2F7BAE542EE9EA515DFBF721F26"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appoint representatives of Federal departments or agencies that award funds to recipients to carry out qualified federally funded research.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B97A1C7E2314F6EB5F6A34D99C9E92C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Seek to appoint representatives of academia, private sector entities, and academic publishers.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB8CFB0B178DB4616824FF31761E6AC45"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms</header> 
<clause id="HFD60183EA59646EE8D5DA058D36386D6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member shall serve for a term of 2 years.</text></clause> <clause id="H328803FCDF4B4DE6A85A3BECFF101E53"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the discretion of the Director, the term of each member may be renewed for an additional 2-year term.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD03B7AC1AF9046D9BAAA69CF220182DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5EA2CA97977F439E9E0077C9667BE86C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Chairperson of the advisory group shall be designated by the Director from among the members.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9D02B71CE09748CA9D3759F34DA6E42C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The term of the Chairperson shall be 1 year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H62B5AEF459064A30BD8D2E9748D2F933"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>Subject to the discretion of the Director, the term of a Chairperson may be renewed for an additional 1-year term.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F1EFC431B0A4C93A5C62BB15118F191"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reports</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3DA00B55DB85431FB2974934703EDBC9"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Interim report</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the advisory group shall submit to the Director an interim report that contains advice and guidance with respect to the matters described in paragraph (1).</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H114045BDF09C4542BC4403947B615B89"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the advisory group or the Director determines appropriate, the advisory group shall submit to the Director subsequent reports relating to the matters described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H605464BF4FF4432D9ADBE5F45CB0363D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal Acquisition Regulation revisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall revise the Federal Acquisition Regulation as necessary to implement the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks established under subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD81FB828E5C41D7A462E8C27DB128F3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual report</header> 
<paragraph id="H44738CA4ABB646358959631ACBD8ABC8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to Congress and the Comptroller General of the United States an interim report that includes information relating to the progress of facilitating the establishment of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks under subsection (a)(1) and any advice or assistance related to a request made pursuant to subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66834AE67395454A9EEDB902259B49AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to Congress and the Comptroller General of the United States a report that includes information relating to the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6F7B41CC052345D7BB3F2F8E0DE2C98D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment, implementation, and, if applicable, revision, of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks referred to in subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H99FC3A256F6D44448636CB21F8561E00"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any advice or assistance related to a request made pursuant to subsection (d)(1).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EA541F3A1354844837B153C898628E4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional requirement for first subsequent report</header><text>With respect to the first subsequent report under paragraph (2), the Director shall include a summary of the testing and evaluation under subsection (c) that includes information relating to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H21E3C1D77DA04EC0BD908D8A2E1ECD12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The findings of the testing and evaluation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5286C73A3BDB4EFC956808F27BFAF0B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The manner by which the Director addressed any concern identified as a result of the testing and evaluation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H49C78878C41B47CBB3BBD9536606966F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of any burden on recipients of funding for qualified federally funded research regarding ensuring that biological datasets are artificial intelligence-ready.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H0FDBDBE525F542FEA3ABF285F91267E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A cost-benefit analysis of the value of ensuring that biological datasets are artificial intelligence-ready in relation to any such burden.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE5C76723D7CD422287666AAFC1380904"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the impact of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks referred to in subsection (a)(1), including the following:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HBE072F27D08246DCA90FBC49BC90C805"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the effectiveness of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks in ensuring each biological dataset generated by a recipient of funding for qualified federally funded research is artificial intelligent-ready.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE0F0CD9ABC824433B35160D2C2F08126"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of whether the implementation of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks as the case may be, has resulted in an undue burden on any recipient of Federal funding.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC0CE4306E6194BFD8E791E61614267E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any recommendations with respect to the implementation of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4AEB98836FA448D0859D37FFC59A8248"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H47450F19A91C40FFA0CA0D944D64E569"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HBD56B3352AC94D04B9FA4B02867929E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biological data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>biological data</term> means information that is measured, collected, or aggregated for analysis, including associated descriptors, derived from the structure, function, or process of a biological system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H3764841778D940EC99521694DA78FAC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biological dataset</header><text>The term <term>biological dataset</term> means a discreet collection of biological data.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59C402CF33BD4B47BE4215179449DB51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Biological data repository</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>biological data repository</term> means any centralized data storage capacity meant for managing or storing biological data.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

