<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H82427BD6D1A64A0A93678FC2C255A647" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9203 IH: Student Protection and University Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9203</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase the transparency of colleges and universities in carrying out their civil rights responsibilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H25D5ED5100914227801D426155F6BE03" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEAFA9184A938443D9E7CBE1145EC1703" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Protection and University Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H21ABA668A78F4025A2C69A1FDFA81B3B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Compliance and transparency related to title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964</header> 
<subsection id="H0CE13C240DDB481E8437BB9B4DB0DB16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program participation agreement requirement</header><text>Section 487 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7D169F2B055846A9B8AFC3CC344AC1D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (i) and (j) as subsections (j) and (k), respectively;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C78DC57EC0B4EB3B7EF9EE1F92ACDD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H4DC539CFA1A34B14A5DA889DD01CDD9E" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC6854FE54CD6458ABBF4D5413AC5049E"><enum>(30)</enum><text>The institution will comply with the provisions of subsection (i) and provide to the Secretary an annual attestation of such compliance.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77689CB640DF4ABAA62C9ED6FF24A16D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (h) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H2C93424DB7534E32A16FDF6D6FA7D2AC" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H697DBD70377B403C9A9859001BA95BFF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Compliance and transparency related to complaints under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964</header> <paragraph id="H0F1CE2FC29854E3B8A30ACDDD8CF6B67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compliance and transparency</header><text>With respect to complaints received by an institution related to alleged violations of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), the institution shall take the following actions:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H433A795C8B7148008E807203E8A031F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Have in effect investigative processes related to such complaints, which shall include each of the elements listed in clauses (i) through (vi) of subparagraph (B), and make publicly available (including on the website of the institution), and widely distribute to students and their families (including in student orientation materials), a description of such investigative processes.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7181507E55B44023A902A7B84DF13617"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Include in the investigative processes described in subparagraph (A) at least the following:</text> 
<clause id="H7D24851629F641E78AB238D44FA573A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The processes and factors used to determine whether such complaints will be investigated by the institution and how the outcome of an investigation will be determined.</text></clause> <clause id="H84B0DF2050D147A28C6F5CCC1A7CDEAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A designation of at least one employee to coordinate its efforts to comply with title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), including any investigation of such complaints.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H410E5E6FA05B48C9BEBAB5BBD9087751"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A procedure to ensure that, for each such complaint received by the institution, the complainant will receive from the institution—</text> <subclause id="H7930CAE5CE5741178DC072ECC209FAF4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after receipt of such complaint—</text> 
<item id="H77FB4BF780A5462AAFBA83A578F21B55"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>notification of the receipt of the complaint;</text></item> <item id="H48C200B4AD00489DB703311B4CCC0590"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notification of whether or not an investigation has been opened in response to the complaint;</text></item> 
<item id="HC1CAC79C633A4F658B7CBAD95DBDB019"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>in the case that an investigation is not opened in response to the complaint, an explanation of why an investigation was not opened, including a summary of the information that was used to determine that an investigation should not be opened; and</text></item> <item id="H214E9D478ACE4AD8A4B174FE3A15817F"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>in the case that an investigation is opened, notification that an investigation of the complaint will be carried out and that the complainant will be notified of the outcome of the investigation; and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3D027E8647164323A7A8960A3B391975"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 30 days after an outcome of an investigation is reached, notification of the outcome of the investigation, including an explanation of how the outcome was reached, and any remedial actions taken in response to the complaint.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H8EB62DAF0D474164A0E051B824DAB7A9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A system for keeping and maintaining records of such complaints, including the determination and reasoning for whether or not an investigation into a complaint was opened by the institution, notifications to and communications with the complainant and, if applicable, the respondent, a record of the investigation (including the outcome thereof), and a record of any remedial actions taken in response to the complaint.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5B6EC494A9F94EAB9F3A7483B2D05E1B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The contact information and necessary steps for reporting such complaints to the institution.</text></clause> <clause id="H4D277B38FAB147FAB24647D88E248CE4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The contact information and necessary steps for reporting a complaint related to an alleged violation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) to the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education, including the hyperlink to the electronic complaint form of the Office for Civil Rights for an alleged violation of such title; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFCAB278EF77245AB84DE0D0D4484FE0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to public awareness campaign materials created and distributed by the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education relating to protections for individuals under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), display and publish such materials, as applicable—</text> <clause id="H5647394934254C3D9B5E08B43D9E8AA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after such materials are distributed;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1E4464CBA6884B7A8DC6CCDF71D71277"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for not less than 1 year or until new such materials are distributed, whichever is later;</text></clause> <clause id="H7C3D2B7A9DF948389C0BF5A715D68C63"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in high traffic, public places on the campus of the institution; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H688CAD2FAD8340048EA1698EC043A54F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on a publicly available website of the institution.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24DEFE6F08F645E3A68A47D5AEE23986"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>An institution of higher education that fails to comply with the provisions of subsection (a)(30) for two consecutive award years shall be ineligible to participate in the programs authorized by this title for a period of not less than the first two subsequent award years. To regain eligibility to participate in the programs authorized by this title, an institution of higher education shall demonstrate compliance with paragraph (1) prior to the completion of the period during which the institution is ineligible due to failure to comply with such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H04ACAC9550ED4B2AB18E722CF8BEB2B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the first day of the first award year (as such term is defined in section 481 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088</external-xref>)) beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD1B29C00B82A4F8F91F847665D581680"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office for Civil Rights requirements</header> <subsection id="H98E0E42F83AC49BBA099EE3AD08B5B91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Congressional briefings</header> <paragraph id="H17D36790CCAC40FA8CED54941BB8F674"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act and ending 2 years after such date of enactment, the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights of the Department of Education (or the designee of such Assistant Secretary) shall provide a briefing, on a bimonthly basis, to the authorizing committees about complaints alleging discrimination on the basis of race, color, or national origin in violation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) that have been received by the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education in the preceding month—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD333764263D740BD9AB3F673C87462B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a manner that—</text> <clause id="H18444CBF3E854B86853DFE35B669C65C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>protects personally identifiable information; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H06A62DE3066140D8BB3B52DC6DDB7613"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaggregates information by the basis of such alleged discrimination (including shared ancestry); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F5E174565EA4D7AB7B46FC79FB3DDD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that includes—</text> 
<clause id="HCBFD2EB941DB42EBB7F71B58B2975E69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of such complaints;</text></clause> <clause id="H7D99A8875BC345F39C358A7B4583F264"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of—</text> 
<subclause id="H9A1066A364B5476BBF43329162C397FE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the Office has addressed or plans to address such complaints; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H229D63EC528B4670BDDA9A7CE68B540A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the investigations being carried out in response to such complaints, as applicable; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HB9787EBC2D1447C8A17058EA5A9A4A38"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>data about the length of such investigations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDC113189E3E4DDFAFC8353EEE839D69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 48 hours prior to each briefing required under paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights of the Department of Education (or the designee of such Assistant Secretary) shall submit to the authorizing committees a written report that contains the information that will be presented at such briefing and that complies with the requirements of paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB755364B9D74378ABB63569748B94A5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H37A348C32651444BA4F396281405BEC8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorizing committees</header><text>The term <term>authorizing committees</term> means the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1A393B1ACAA45B5B9400863D93A772D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Office</term> means the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H164666B85A324F46AD26331468129587"><enum>(b)</enum><header>OCR process reforms</header> <paragraph id="H0EB21C8F0DC34C049ADC0C4C7BE02A22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dismissals</header><text>The Office may not close or dismiss any complaint regarding discrimination on the basis of race, color, or national origin in violation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) due to the filing of a complaint involving the same allegations against the same recipient—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H006A015CAC244A31BB4F31F6E509B124"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by an individual other than the complainant with another Federal, State, or local agency, a court, or the recipient, unless the Office determines that—</text> <clause id="H03F2CA5219AE4EE099CEB6BE400AAA6C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a court has certified a class action with respect to the alleged violation of such other individual’s complaint;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF272516DC12745E4922B7AC8694A68D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such other individual is a member of such class; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6FE868101CA44D2198B8944F7EEF3AA1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the complainant is a member of such class; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7F8CE7E00004BEDBB4B73996BDA72DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by the complainant with another Federal, State, or local agency, a court, or the recipient.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB10F0B17110E40EC961BDD026AC6746F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigations</header><text>The Office may not delay an investigation of a complaint due to the filing of a complaint involving the same allegations against the same recipient with another Federal, State, or local agency or the recipient.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE65CB81FF92747C59562B45E9AAB6081"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recipient defined</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>recipient</term> means an institution of higher education (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)) that receives funds under an applicable program (as such term is defined in section 400 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

