<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B0E242AAA95488DA9EBB8AEC6995853" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9194 IH: Build American Efficiency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9194</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To clarify the evidentiary treatment of documentation generated under a qualifying process standard for purposes of compliance with the Build America, Buy America Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4C0956D850114867B2F7AF6312FB374E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H78A39F82CA3B4E84B7F51E9D9A6684FD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Build American Efficiency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA8B344541B7741F398A0C1421FAB6BFA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Domestic content certification</header> <subsection id="HBD7BBDA2AA994FA296515BE835445230"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of administering the Build America, Buy America Act (title IV of division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8301">42 U.S.C. 8301</external-xref> note) with respect to financial assistance administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereafter referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall treat documentation generated in accordance with the Make It American Process Standard (NEMA 70901–2024), as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, or a successor version approved by the Secretary, as sufficient evidence for purposes of determining whether a funding recipient’s domestic content certification complies with applicable domestic content requirements.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5D5F9CB95533414DAEBB5C28AB8368D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="HF8992212B2F64FC0A5AAF0762D6C36BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require a recipient or prospective recipient of financial assistance administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development to use documentation generated in accordance with the Make It American Process Standard (NEMA 70901–2024) to certify that their domestic content complies with applicable domestic content requirements; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD04175D1D7FA4B299E5F054DE1FB2FB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit a recipient or prospective recipient of Federal financial assistance administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development from using any other method to certify that their domestic content complies with applicable domestic content requirements if such method is permitted by law.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC16D9017EC904085987030A8A79E8C23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Similar Standards</header><text>The Secretary may, if the Secretary determines appropriate, treat documentation produced through standards that are similar to the Make It American Process Standard (NEMA 70901–2024) if such standard provides an auditable and verifiable domestic content certification process.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

