<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D45A36131CE4200BD0384D906B12E3E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6994 IH: Mental Health TALK SAFE Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6994</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260109">January 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to modify requirements relating
      to the prescription of controlled substances by means of the internet, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H87A1A891908B41B5AEDC97EFEE45CA6E" style="OLC"><section id="HAFB18635A8404ABABE90EF7E5B0DBD8A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health TALK SAFE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBB37163B18164D38B93E099566A312AD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Telehealth prescribing of controlled substances</header><subsection id="H0DA1850ABDFA4B638F57409FDEC01B59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of valid prescription</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 309(e)(2)(A) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/829">21 U.S.C. 829(e)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3D3950531FF8410EA7CFEF6506C543D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F2C4928E60A412D9B520835F2584859"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FAA644D23A64D2281ACBE2BA0883B05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2E5DAC5BB2D14258892C1E5682C00099" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H474BAEC09565406F810EA3A7C13F676D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a telehealth practitioner who, for purposes of prescribing an approved mental health controlled substance, has conducted at least 1 telehealth evaluation of the patient; or</text></clause><clause id="HA922DFBFC22E4648AABB5AC7E2B3C27B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a practitioner who, for purposes of prescribing a controlled substance in schedule II, III, IV, or V for the treatment of an opioid use disorder, has conducted at least 1 telehealth evaluation of the patient.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A16DB43580549ACB137A1CCB032DB9F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of covering practitioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 309(e)(2)(C)(i) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/829">21 U.S.C. 829(e)(2)(C)</external-xref> (i)) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H72D0750DD7614D21B0ACB943F2782B33" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H86CCBB4D79CC489A90A2E5B52A9E3BC5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has conducted at least 1 in-person medical evaluation of the patient, an evaluation of the patient through the practice of telemedicine, or a telehealth evaluation of the patient, within the previous 90 days; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB01808857002498DB3C030629E8EAF90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 309(e)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/829">21 U.S.C. 829(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE4BD8B0C4FE14F23BAA18A633B74C9FD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HE224F763254A4448B62BCD2B73CF2920"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>approved mental health controlled substance</quote> means a controlled substance in schedule II non-narcotics, III, IV, or V that is being prescribed—</text><clause id="H4C42755714934C00BE0E23BEC0B2C428"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the treatment of a mental health disorder; and</text></clause><clause id="HF96BD112FADB46ABB86EAB41105071BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>only for the conditions, and only in the manner of administration and oversight, approved by the Food and Drug Administration.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA2A09FF56334B59B62331F883EC876F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The term <quote>exempt entity</quote> means—</text><clause id="H7D1C597ED36A4BC28BC3C8CDD77D01AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a federally qualified health center;</text></clause><clause id="H976A871169B94969AFFAD31469345FB9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a hospital;</text></clause><clause id="HA657077545374124903CC9215D7DD6FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a non-profit organization;</text></clause><clause id="HF2EA3DD3501A4FA2A024DE86EF669997"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a Federal, State, or local government agency; or</text></clause><clause id="HE586635B4D114F2FB1AA830A00444F99"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an exempt health care organization.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63AB4E3344864A5C937B5C55D7B882A6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The term <quote>exempt health care organization</quote> means a legal entity that, directly or indirectly, acquires all, or substantially all, of the stock, equity interests, or assets of, or merges with or into, a telehealth entity where such telehealth entity, as of the effective date of such acquisition or merger—</text><clause id="HEAE28D41BD3F42CA8992765AB763911C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has met the criteria to be a telehealth entity for each of the previous 24 months;</text></clause><clause id="HA80363D3637B49B98A24E76741CA274B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employs at least 250 psychiatrists who each work at least 30 hours per week for the telehealth entity; and</text></clause><clause id="H5055C82D24CB40379C0B3211C83C2B49"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has at least 75 percent of the telehealth entity’s total patient volume attributed to individuals who are direct patients of the telehealth entity.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F2614F1F9554484A6070587BAF4994F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The term <quote>federally qualified health center</quote> means an organization described in section 1861(aa)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)(4)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB9139006D7C46F18A39A9F4375A9247"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The term <quote>health care provider</quote> means any individual who—</text><clause id="H45D5D55280FE444AAE1F9FD64EDECA90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is engaged in the delivery of health care services in a State; and</text></clause><clause id="H08FFEDC1E4B344B7BC66543CD0C704B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is required by State law (including regulations) to be licensed or certified by the State to engage in the delivery of such services in the State.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFED656B3262649489E20AF729A86EE49"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The term <quote>hospital</quote> means an institution in any State in which State or applicable local law provides for the licensing of hospitals, that is—</text><clause id="H13124F8EF9B545DD9C2DA13F097AE64C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>licensed as a hospital pursuant to such law; or</text></clause><clause id="HA7A2262BD54A495D9E6B6A0D301A9CB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>approved, by the agency of such State or locality responsible for licensing hospitals, as meeting the standards established for such licensing.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FD414C860B84B4A896E81E42A946583"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The term <quote>interactive telecommunications system</quote> means the multimedia communications equipment that includes, at a minimum, audio-only or audio-video equipment permitting two-way, real-time interactive communication between the patient and the health care provider.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06E7734CAFC74077B9B1FDE67CAC6D6C"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The term <quote>nonprofit organization</quote> means an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 that is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65CF36D10B444B0C9B57E00D51CA9F3E"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The term <quote>physician</quote> means a doctor of medicine or osteopathy legally authorized to practice medicine by the State in which such individual performs such function or action.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CEAA70DD7E3436B92EBE0F70965B706"><enum>(M)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCC06D787B56946F683B8E9D0121C73BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The term <quote>psychiatric-mental health advanced practice nurse</quote> means a registered professional nurse who meets the requirements specified in clause (ii) or (iii).</text></clause><clause id="H568453671C7E4EACB38F357133A94041" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the State specifies qualifications for psychiatric-mental health advanced practices nurses, the individual must—</text><subclause id="H9E4646F8C9E64351856B81694D59849B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be currently licensed to practice in the State as a registered professional nurse; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAC868B66A1804DC1B0099C8268CCC5CA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>meet the State requirements for qualification as a psychiatric-mental health advanced practice nurse in the State in which the individual furnishes the services.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0FDE519F20E84FC08283E041956E8296" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If the State does not specify qualifications for psychiatric-mental health advance practice nurses, the individual must—</text><subclause id="H37B5DD20F76545C2A5D0D37D08492055"><enum>(I)</enum><text>meet the qualifications for nurses in advanced practice or general nurse practitioners as defined by the State; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H53FE098CAE1541C2A2A8AE3FC0DF9822"><enum>(II)</enum><text>maintain an active psychiatric-mental health nursing certification from the American Nurses Credentialing Center or the American Academy of Nurse Practitioners Certification Board.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE73997F7CD04E189274122F715ECA72"><enum>(N)</enum><text>The term <quote>psychiatrist</quote> means a physician who has completed a psychiatry residency program accredited by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education and whose practice focuses predominantly on the diagnosis, treatment, prevention, or study of mental health disorders.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEA34FA2DA384E6D86183DB0E2541849"><enum>(O)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDB78417C1CF9436CB59D3841D42ECE11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The term <quote>telehealth affiliate</quote> means as to any telehealth entity, any other legal entity that—</text><subclause id="H119C1F6007B34438B278865D71DFFA2E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>directly or indirectly, is in control of, is controlled by, or is under common control with, such telehealth entity; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HE61F1C4D60C54879A3AC5F3CA1FD2AC7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provides the majority of the administrative or business services that do not constitute the practice of medicine or any other licensed profession, to, or on behalf of, such telehealth entity.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H70AAA287D7EE47E3898538B7B44AB4E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For purposes of this definition, control of an entity means the power, directly or indirectly, to direct or cause the direction of the management and policies of such entity whether by contract or otherwise.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD16E0080767E494F83FC0671D60C7DC4"><enum>(P)</enum><text>The term <quote>telehealth entity</quote> means an entity organized and operating within the United States that employs or engages with practitioners who prescribe controlled substances via a telehealth evaluation and, except in the case of an exempt entity, meets each of the following requirements:</text><clause id="H02DEAE9103874F1A808EBA9116A03499"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The telehealth entity does not, directly or indirectly, through a telehealth affiliate or otherwise, maintain an ownership interest, investment interest, or management relationship with any pharmacy that—</text><subclause id="HF840DB4F55AE41F785E0D9D54029C9E2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>does not dispense medications from physical locations that are accessible to the public; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA35014C1E1E44E73870979849ED37E29"><enum>(II)</enum><text>fills and delivers the majority of its pharmaceutical products via the mail service.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H340DC108E7F94E2E82DA278FCF9919C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The telehealth entity does not, directly or indirectly, through a telehealth entity or otherwise, charge patients pursuant to a financial arrangement where patients agree to make recurring payments at regular intervals in exchange for medications or patient care services provided by a health care provider employed or engaged with the telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate).</text></clause><clause id="HC05A74152D9645D4BBADE503606B67A3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For the duration of any 12-month period, no more than 50 percent of all charges for patient care services provided by a health care provider employed or engaged with the telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate) are paid by patients directly on an out-of-pocket basis.</text></clause><clause id="H4E3A8FC4F9FB46D99F00D1E4F38E387F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>At least 25 percent of the total actual time spent performing patient care services by all health care providers engaged or employed by the telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate) relates to the diagnosis, treatment, prevention, or study of mental health disorders.</text></clause><clause id="H580C45D9008C48E49069F809815435B2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>At least 10 percent of all health care providers employed or engaged by the telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate), excluding any covering practitioners, are practitioners who are bona fide employees who work at least 30 hours per week for the telehealth entity.</text></clause><clause id="H36051E1B4EDD4909967CF0ECCA64F546"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>At least 25 percent of all health care providers employed or engaged by the telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate), excluding any covering practitioners, are bona fide employees of the telehealth entity who work at least 30 hours per week for the entity.</text></clause><clause id="HAAB7B9ECB0AD42D8B085739293EFF112"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The total number of advanced practice nurses employed or engaged with the telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate), excluding any covering practitioners, does not exceed two-thirds of the total number of practitioners employed or engaged with the telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate).</text></clause><clause id="H21D033A4ADA5459CB0C25E7F6F950372"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Neither the telehealth entity nor any telehealth affiliate compensates any practitioner in a manner where more than 75 percent of the total annual compensation of such practitioner varies, directly or indirectly, with the volume or value of telehealth evaluations provided by such practitioner.</text></clause><clause id="HA89221BB38D24395A97FAC56C2DDC7A2"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate) at all times employs a full-time Chief Compliance Officer who—</text><subclause id="HB23F1008066B47AD97E96DBD0109AE07"><enum>(I)</enum><text>dedicates the majority of such individual’s time working for the telehealth entity on compliance matters; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6599FC878D6E4AF28AAA765EBA992E89"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not also serve as the Chief Clinical Quality Practitioner or Chief Medical Officer.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H840455DF43F84060BC9978706F36BA04"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate) at all times employs a full-time Chief Clinical Quality Practitioner who—</text><subclause id="H1AD2111E5AB34467AC523182BA954B92"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is a board-certified psychiatrist;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB9ACEE78A5224FDC9D36AF60FF975436"><enum>(II)</enum><text>dedicates the majority of such individual’s time working for the telehealth entity on clinical quality matters; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HBB3A225A5CA849288194A8AF0E3C71D3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>does not also serve as the Chief Compliance Officer or Chief Medical Officer for the telehealth entity.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8C92E504542F48EB88BCC50A5D6EA9DC"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>The telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate) at all times employs a full-time Chief Medical Officer who—</text><subclause id="H6744D9DF53E94004A6380D2806172CFD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is a board-certified psychiatrist;</text></subclause><subclause id="H16D708106283491D9125EFF776DDCD25"><enum>(II)</enum><text>dedicates the majority of such individual’s time working for the telehealth entity on clinical quality matters; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H62C42D3A7D064C4A931E08D489C3D1E2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>does not also serve as the Chief Compliance Officer or Chief Clinical Quality Practitioner of the telehealth entity.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEB96CE69D4BA489CAB588EC32DA9086E"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>The telehealth entity conducts routine monitoring to ensure all approved mental health controlled substances prescribed by telehealth practitioners employed or engaged by the telehealth entity are prescribed only for the conditions, and only in the manner of administration and oversight, approved by the Food and Drug Administration.</text></clause><clause id="H9128422A515B45FFA532085097170CEC"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>The telehealth entity at all times maintains active accreditation from the Accreditation Counsel for Continuing Medical Education.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H817C33EF0B4A4F68B084328CB07B1F11"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>The term <quote>telehealth evaluation</quote> means a medical evaluation that is conducted in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws by a health care provider who is—</text><clause id="H802EF826FF9C4EB88AD56A46B8DB6746"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at a location remote from the patient; and</text></clause><clause id="H48B9776FBCFB4D0598BCC296D2305A7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communicating with the patient using an interactive telecommunications system.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA06DC53FD8E4102A7C9FAB8015825EC"><enum>(R)</enum><text>The term <quote>telehealth practitioner</quote> means a psychiatrist or a psychiatric-mental health advanced practice nurse who meets the following requirements:</text><clause id="HE4339CDF679F4CA080B254B5AC767049"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The individual is an employee or independent contractor of a telehealth entity.</text></clause><clause id="HA489FE7BFF49443DBD84D823CDBCD70A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Except in the case of an exempt entity, the individual works at least 10 hours per week for the telehealth entity.</text></clause><clause id="H2C6E73084891416C80EC86D435F4142F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Except in the case of an exempt entity, no more than 75 percent of the total annual compensation received by the individual from the telehealth entity (or a telehealth affiliate) varies with the volume or value of the telehealth evaluations provided by such practitioner.</text></clause><clause id="HBFA27FD987F74510B343394215C7B3A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The individual only prescribes controlled substances under subparagraph (A)(ii) for one telehealth entity in any given calendar month.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0C96DC7340FB46FF8D1D8B97A1563CF2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Minimum standards before refusing To fill a prescription</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 309(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/829">21 U.S.C. 829(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H31879436CB50418AA441640759673E92" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HD2F81C24FCE5484DB25022C989F5D939"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minimum standards before refusing to fill a prescription</header><subparagraph id="H5D2A923C141E4A158516C1117FF162CC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A pharmacist shall not refuse to fill a prescription for a controlled substance issued in compliance with this subsection based solely upon a concern the prescription was issued via a telehealth evaluation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70BB51C9D6464CFDB1A0AC6DB9CE853C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Validation of prescription</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before a pharmacist can refuse to fill a prescription based solely upon a concern with the validity of the prescription, the pharmacist shall attempt to resolve those concerns and shall attempt to validate the prescription by performing the following:</text><clause id="H22DF49EA960946C5B993488B779CBE54"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Initiate communication with the patient (or the patient’s representative) to acquire information relevant to the concern with the validity of the prescription.</text></clause><clause id="HA6CC507EF4264336886DBB36D0E26451"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Initiate communication with the prescriber or the prescriber’s agent to—</text><subclause id="H58BEADC751914ECA843B236B3DE07FF1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>describe the pharmacist’s concern with the validity of the prescription; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H55B17C3C9476431380BF9D9354715933"><enum>(II)</enum><text>acquire information relevant to the pharmacist’s concern with the validity of the prescription.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD94BC0E83644F6486E24F1956EC874F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who violates this paragraph shall, with respect to any such violation, be subject to a civil penalty of up to $25,000 per violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD2A8700976294919995FCB77D64064A3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repeals</header><paragraph id="H9A6954F4EEA54C95AF30BF8A07DF5286"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Practice of telemedicine defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 102(54)(E) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802(54)(E)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA06C454CA47540688BD6D7B78A0D410F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special registration for telemedicine</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 311(h) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/831">21 U.S.C. 831(h)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5549699AE0AC44ADB7F83405F00D533E" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2AC7C1AC9BE7462D97709598D8D5961D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Controlled substances registrations</header><subsection id="HF48577CA0E15402CBC25931BE4F3BC2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 302(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/822">21 U.S.C. 822(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB5ABCAE8E1314FF6897FE72BD73DE106" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H50F33FD09A4C4F2482253CB5745CC273" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H182BA0B630DD44F6A90B221611DB5F83"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), a registrant shall not be required to obtain additional registrations with the Drug Enforcement Administration in any additional State where the dispensing (including prescribing and administering) occurs if the dispensing is conducted via the practice of telemedicine or following a telehealth evaluation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED02730CADFF4848879BB76615BE05ED" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A registrant who is employed or contracted with a telehealth entity may use the address of such telehealth entity as the principal place of business or professional practice of the registrant so long as the registrant—</text><clause id="HF069508AE3AA4AAEA0380BE2FF6FF1AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a telehealth practitioner; and</text></clause><clause id="HF70173A086FE4BC28B4F76B54C70B3FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>only dispenses (including prescribing and administering) controlled substances via the practice of telemedicine or a telehealth evaluation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H265BEBE6C871464BA3A465294A928116" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC653AD0829E949D899BCE25218F09CB9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Psychiatrist licensure</header><subsection id="HF2D141DCBBC54CE6AFD5A136CEAC793B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a covered psychiatrist who has in effect medical professional liability insurance coverage and provides in a secondary State covered psychiatry services that are within the scope of practice of such covered psychiatrist in the primary State to a patient—</text><paragraph id="H38D608C3D2704D9598E0F0A9894ACF53"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such medical professional liability insurance coverage shall cover (subject to any related premium adjustments) such covered psychiatrist with respect to such covered psychiatry services provided by the psychiatrist in the secondary State to such patient as if such services were provided by such psychiatrist in the primary State to such patient; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EC4FE0AC614469B998A949D8517215B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the extent such covered psychiatrist is licensed under the requirements of the primary State to provide such services to such patient, the psychiatrist shall be treated as satisfying any licensure requirements of the secondary State to provide such services to such patient to the extent the licensure requirements of the secondary State are substantially similar to the licensure requirements of the primary State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H667F0210B46B4F37B59485EBFEE4454A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text><paragraph id="H96EA66BC07D04582ACEDCB4BF9B4289E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to allow a covered psychiatrist to provide psychiatry services in the secondary State that exceed the scope of that psychiatrist’s license in the primary State; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9335D4E1F271406AAF1D4D60D36DA0B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to allow a covered psychiatrist to provide psychiatry services in the secondary State that exceed the scope of a substantially similar psychiatrist license in the secondary State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44D376C4DE7C4273BDF3615244327DEA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HA15EE264B9AB4893B22D8B3E0D2D60EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered psychiatrist</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered psychiatrist</quote> means a physician—</text><subparagraph id="H90F571BFF65B4C69AF16D28D84EC3235"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who has completed a psychiatry residency program accredited by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55A91DBC80F944639FB68F379E0F6618"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whose practice focuses predominantly on the diagnosis, treatment, prevention, or study of mental health disorders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD0D88E40D054D13BAFC6D8AFD900068"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who is licensed to practice in the primary State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2B8694CAE8A432798D4881F94C8098D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered psychiatry services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered psychiatry services</quote> means medical care relating to the diagnosis, treatment, or prevention of mental health or behavioral health disorders conducted by a covered psychiatrist who is at a location remote from the patient and is communicating with the patient through the use of telehealth technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD3AF556705F4FC6999D63A892FD400C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>License</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>license</quote> or <quote>licensure</quote>, as applied with respect to a covered psychiatrist, means a psychiatrist that has met the requirements and is approved to provide covered psychiatry services in accordance with State laws and regulations in the primary State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D25394CE7114A7F908C90BDC75131B5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Primary state</header><text>The term <quote>primary State</quote> means, with respect to a covered psychiatrist, the State in which—</text><subparagraph id="HCD91100BC1A04FD197B46C8624C175F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered psychiatrist is licensed to practice; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H829FD2C98EFC4098AD7CAA52C6B4E709"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the majority of the covered psychiatrist’s practice is underwritten for medical professional liability insurance coverage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C09F2EBFFEE4CC5BD73F8896F73CC34"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secondary state</header><text>The term <quote>secondary State</quote> means, with respect to a covered psychiatrist, any State that is not the primary State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C42F62F0B3C4B23B77A8B51C548A646"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7077E20E17EA42448DE2574C974C900C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Substantially similar</header><text>The term <quote>substantially similar</quote>, with respect to the licensure by primary and secondary States of a psychiatrist, means that both the primary and secondary States have in place a form of licensure for such professionals that permits such professionals to provide covered psychiatry services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0991BD8A1254BE9B352034D9A3448CA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Telehealth technologies</header><text>The term <quote>telehealth technologies</quote> means technologies relating to the use of electronic information and telecommunication technologies, to support and promote, at a distance, health care, patient and professional health-related education, health administration, and public health.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7AD847924C340F2B46E9797AA7ACFED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7B95B58AB994467287B4E8F9384610E9"><enum>5.</enum><header>State laws affected</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of this Act (including the amendments made by this Act) supersede and preempt any State statute, regulation, order, or interpretation to the extent such statute, regulation, order, or interpretation would directly or indirectly prohibit or restrict the activities permitted by this Act (or the amendments made by this Act).</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

