<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26308-3RF-33-407"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4038 IS: Small Business Liberation 2.0 Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4038</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260310">March 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To exempt small business concerns from duties imposed by the President under section 122 of the Trade Act of 1974 and to prevent price gouging with respect to goods subject to such duties.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="id4ccca909bd574c9d953bfc9161038488"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Liberation 2.0 Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFC54DF69585A45A590A12F31D31691AB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H37D637C2C7664D9BA74C6840996FF9EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A700611365A495995B412A246695F48"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Component</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>component</term> means a good that is offered for sale to consumers through incorporation into a final good.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d89cfc7bbef48a598d09926c768c1d8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered duty</header><text>The term <term>covered duty</term> means a duty imposed under the authority provided by section 122 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2132">19 U.S.C. 2132</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA2737FA01D044F3A74BBFF40786645F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered good</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered good</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF0CE66C6C213435EA112328E44D9923E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A final good or a component that is subject to a covered duty imposed on or after January 20, 2026.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB641BF547194D0B801B888D040059DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A good that is assembled, in whole or in part, in the United States and that includes a component described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31DBA228ECCD40C5819166F1EC420E3F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A final good or a component with respect to which there is a planned duty.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74c343590a0f476d8a6a3267ff59d881"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A good that is assembled, in whole or in part, in the United States and that includes a component described in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H996A742FB6A248438CFABE7BFB3C1CC1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duty-related shock date</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40671a17dc4a4596b7f98296347b9130"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>duty-related shock date</term> means any date if, during the 30-day period preceding that date—</text><clause id="H0D7D283868014E07AE1C4265CDB673E9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>covered duties with respect to goods classifiable under 5 or more subheadings of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States took effect; or</text></clause><clause id="ida9295a8ace8d4583b16f2af89ec9313d" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>planned duties with respect to goods classifiable under 5 or more such subheadings were demonstrated by a written or spoken statement.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6054bf507b6e41f48784b811309c94fe" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration of number of trading partners</header><text>Subparagraph (A) applies without regard to the number of trading partners to which a covered duty or planned duty is applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45B0C1E5229F4665B45D12007E98E69A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Final good</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>final good</term> means a good that does not require any further assembly to be ready for sale to consumers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F37F2FAD3DB4810BC154C9B8B68071D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Good</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>good</term> means any good offered for sale in commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F69D2A0481644A6BEEA241DC03372D0" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Planned duty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>planned duty</term> means a covered duty that is intended to be imposed or increased, as demonstrated by a written or spoken statement by the President, the United States Trade Representative, the Secretary of Commerce, or another senior Federal official determined appropriate by the Commission, including by means of a press release, a comment at a press conference, meeting, or public event, or any other public communication.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb60985167c174ab3b65e8686f6bc0edc"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2FAF7939E094C4C8DB71CDF04C6AD7B"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA59DA56FFC8A49EDBD6C89B49ED01519" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Ultimate parent entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ultimate parent entity</term> has the meaning given such term in section 801.1 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></paragraph></section><section id="idedaae3c1dbf54301974a71a2cc72d265"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exemption and refunds for small business concerns from duties under balance-of-payments authority</header><subsection id="idb3feb4bdee984c6da07f2bd4f8d18593"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>A covered duty shall not apply with respect to goods imported by or for the use of a small business concern.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbec72e76e2d64b58b609c262e6b8d0a9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Refunds</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall refund the amount of any covered duties paid on goods imported by or for the use of a small business concern.</text></subsection></section><section id="ida66d22b73f6d40378a6a484311b06edd"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prevention of price gouging with respect to goods subject to duties under balance-of-payments authority</header><subsection id="HE57F5500492B49A1AE0A5CD480C4FE89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on price gouging</header><paragraph id="H84F27F616B8E4F67AF74CC55CB8B2136"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person may sell or offer for sale in the United States a covered good at an unreasonably high price during the 5-year period that follows the date on which—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39dba9218bea4e4db8ef8860a3c8f9f7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a covered duty with respect to the good took effect or was increased; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb92dfebfc424225a5ff9072b1631b7e"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a planned duty with respect to the good was demonstrated by a written or spoken statement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc306d047edd545cb969e9621c215db6f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Role in supply chain immaterial</header><text>The prohibition under paragraph (1) applies without regard to the position of a person in a supply chain or distribution network.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC15A97AD8F44D38905025878DDB1487"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unreasonably high price</header><subparagraph id="HCB812B107796417D9DB2EEC5502BE92B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, a person sells or offers for sale a covered good at an unreasonably high price if the person—</text><clause id="H514A9965349843C9AB225B3A023D213A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has raised the price of a covered good that is a final good by more than the amount of—</text><subclause id="HC09136D13DA440DBBC1F1FC723C8F2F7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the costs directly generated by the imposition of or an increase in a covered duty with respect to the good; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3F41EB67A18F4AA2A4A2F7C645748676" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">additional costs incurred by the person in providing the good that demonstrate that the covered duty was not used by the person as a pretext for a price increase; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFA9882F7354E4482A99A89E00AD196DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has raised the price of a covered good that is or includes a component by more than the amount of—</text><subclause id="H5149CCD381874F74A59B6B3B8D6FD52F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the costs directly generated by the imposition of or an increase in a covered duty with respect to the component; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H98639AD52BC34AA4BFA59B4545B2C010"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">additional costs incurred by the person in providing the good that demonstrate that the covered duty was not used by the person as a pretext for a price increase.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d97e57bc7964a8fa35c2536e7a6bb24"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Planned duties</header><text>With respect to a covered good, no costs may be determined to be directly generated by the imposition of a covered duty with respect to the good before the date on which the covered duty takes effect with respect to the good.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6E8F4456F5E40E29A160CBD469FBE0B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Baseline price determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the price of a covered good before the date on which any covered duty or planned duty applicable to the good took effect or was demonstrated by a written or spoken statement, as the case may be, shall be determined by reference to the average price of the good during the 180-day period preceding that date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92A8901593644DDA8EF1FDD1E91EDFDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption for small businesses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) does not apply to the sale, or offering for sale, of a covered good by a small business concern.</text></subsection><subsection id="H12F1E6F8957C44ABA10F5A83DA77AC94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Presumption of violation</header><paragraph id="H61A2B9889F0B41F78C18D89392861D45" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any duty-related shock date, a person shall be presumed to be in violation of subsection (a) if a preponderance of the evidence demonstrates that the person—</text><subparagraph id="H2C8D041375B54FA2AFCC63A1596D4B92" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has unfair leverage (as described in paragraph (3)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0DCBC9049134129B297061F3EE811BF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sold or offered for sale on that date a covered good at a price that was greater than the average price of the good during the 180-day period preceding the date on which the most recent covered duty or planned duty applicable to the good took effect or was demonstrated by a written or spoken statement, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4899EFFF695486D98EE2EDFC67C2605" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rebuttal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person may rebut a presumption under paragraph (1) if the person demonstrates by clear and convincing evidence that the relevant increase in the price of a covered good is attributable, in full, to—</text><subparagraph id="H48659F4AF49D44158CD423BCE423EDFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">costs directly generated by the imposition of or an increase in a covered duty with respect to the good; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A63CC5E676E4F1FAE419E6D79AB7364"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional costs incurred by the person in providing the good that demonstrate that the covered duty was not used by the person as a pretext for such increase.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8180738F60C14D1A830809A7CC1C8F90"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unfair leverage</header><subparagraph id="HE1697FCD6C45451EA0CECC0A3463FB27"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Characteristics</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, a person has unfair leverage if the person or the ultimate parent entity of the person—</text><clause id="HFDCDF329DE4A46D1B8B0490C42BB5751"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not a small business concern; or</text></clause><clause id="HF3F726A02BF34D11931782065BDCD8FA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>satisfies another characteristic set forth in a regulation promulgated by the Commission with respect to determining unfair leverage.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45A715AF1A474FE1AE862F3EFDBC88C3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>In January of the first year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall adjust the amount specified in subparagraph (A)(i) by the percentage change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics with respect to the 12-month period preceding the date of such adjustment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7800839912214EE38B89D0F47A4C4B45" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In promulgating regulations under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Commission shall consider the capacity of a person to do the following:</text><clause id="HC5FB98F76FCA416DA7BF22DD19459FFD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Absorb, in whole or in part, costs directly generated by a covered duty.</text></clause><clause id="HB08435795DA1443697E5A6582107E9CA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Increase production, in the United States, of a good that is identical or substantially similar to a covered good.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47D932EDBF124342B671AD5FC5C02D4A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="H4A5EF2A6F1E64E4CAAEC6D645FD8A1CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may promulgate, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FEDDAFB66AE4C68AD41800F362D6C31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interagency consultation</header><text>The Commission, in promulgating regulations under this subsection, shall consult with the United States Trade Representative, the United States International Trade Commission, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and the Commissioner of the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAEC2F58E18E646BEB3A4F203575BF480"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement by Commission</header><paragraph id="HFEF14EE87CD54542AB3177DD1C4E395E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section or a regulation promulgated under this section shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H000461263CA54C62BF7171B4681BFCCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce this section and the regulations promulgated under this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section. Any person who violates this section or a regulation promulgated under this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88C8617F990C4E228D64DB282BF64E81"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F40DCCB102E42BBA4195E44C2227D42" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Actions by States</header><paragraph id="H387086DF88874470919E26F4180DDDE6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency of a State, has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of such State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by an act or practice in violation of this section or a regulation promulgated under this section, the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text><subparagraph id="H2C2AD4DD34D046BEB82C87C05515842D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin such act or practice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF01D1B3DDEED4EB18AB5C4E346950C46" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with this section or such regulation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H412F69D16DC343AA93267D2E18CA1EDC" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H226E8E6DC50D4B28B1655A392743762B" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain such other legal and equitable relief as the court may consider to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BA30EA09C33480682528F8C19C6A9CF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Before filing an action under this subsection, the attorney general, official, or agency of the State involved shall provide to the Commission a written notice of such action and a copy of the complaint for such action. If the attorney general, official, or agency determines that it is not feasible to provide the notice described in this paragraph before the filing of the action, the attorney general, official, or agency shall provide written notice of the action and a copy of the complaint to the Commission immediately upon the filing of the action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1ADD5CB5B4A4275AA43F900B25A209C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority of Commission</header><text>On receiving notice under paragraph (2) of an action under this subsection, the Commission shall have the right—</text><subparagraph id="HD98ECE945D9E4EF4B595D79509E32AC4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intervene in the action;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B967F14D063412EA1B050C510C68959"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon so intervening, to be heard on all matters arising therein; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ACE3042E83E433D9CD77646F158C2D0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to file petitions for appeal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DE0F7DA761F4ED98B68F9EF9E2019BE" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><subparagraph id="HD17A312A3D8546C5AA54CB698FA7F674"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exercising of certain powers</header><text>For purposes of bringing a civil action under this subsection, nothing in this Act may be construed to prevent an attorney general, official, or agency of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general, official, or agency by the laws of such State to conduct investigations, administer oaths and affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35D2A3E137E84D689DB26EBB3537CEBE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State proceedings</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prohibit an authorized official of a State from initiating or continuing any proceeding in a court of the State for a violation of any civil or criminal law of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F628D46FE304A6084371C6B95F583D9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to preempt or otherwise affect any State or local law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDA6B74BFAEE74795B0DED519B4002495"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reporting by consumers and related investigations</header><paragraph id="HE685D1ECADCC44058C7FE3AA6D382257"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall establish a mechanism for consumers to report to the Commission potential violations of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2B292F7C7D945259CA7217B2F37622D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The mechanism established under paragraph (1) shall allow a consumer to report a potential violation by a variety of means, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8DB330EFFB054D558D8F96C25C24A34A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A telephone number.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAC8F11448BB4504BA7DB66DD9E58F7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A mailing address.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7047356A69FF477289D609B2225C818E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A website.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D518076B04D4CAE8DC9C6E43C9FDB38"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate regulations establishing, and providing a detailed description of, the process by which the Commission shall consider reports provided through the mechanism established under paragraph (1) and, if applicable, open investigations into potential violations of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6653ED536EDE4A77926B9BF5C508C818"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to preclude the Commission from unilaterally initiating an investigation of a potential violation of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB7E161212A074DF4825E6615A386C4C8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports<editorial/></header><subsection id="H819A97B5271147FD9F9A2AB5D32787CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>International Trade Commission and Bureau of Labor Statistics report</header><paragraph id="HF638C5F85211412DA50E5B556ADEB226"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the United States International Trade Commission and the Commissioner of the Bureau of Labor Statistics shall jointly submit to Congress, and make available to the public, a report on the prices of goods sold by any entity that is not a small business concern, with a focus on identifying changes in the prices of covered goods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E215A8DFEE34005B9E290EA054A83E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sufficiency of surveys</header><subparagraph id="H2C32D83B6AF443B4B78E1D2A8A59BD84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before submitting the first report required by paragraph (1), the Commissioner of the Bureau of Labor Statistics shall identify whether the existing surveys of the Bureau collect sufficiently granular data with respect to pricing decisions and consumer prices to effectively identify price increases for covered goods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56F4CC2C4EE1471682B0346F2BF99007"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Development of new surveys</header><text>If the Commissioner determines under subparagraph (A) that the surveys of the Bureau are insufficient, the Bureau shall develop and include in such surveys new questions to collect the data necessary for the report required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA24BBC2B605A4DC0BD0DE37E14157D4D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Trade Commission report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall submit to Congress, and make available to the public, a report on the enforcement activities of the Commission under this Act, which shall include an assessment of the impact of the enforcement of this Act on consumer prices, both for covered goods and all goods.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

