<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD2FDFAFFF5C14C3781537F2CF2834D15" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9633 IH: Birthright Citizenship Clarification Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9633</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260709">July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 301 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to clarify those classes of individuals born in the United States who are not nationals or citizens of the United States at birth.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2EDA063D999B478D80DF2CD2668F6F42" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5093F3BD3CBF42F0BA604804ABE38E2A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Birthright Citizenship Clarification Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBB1BCD5E3FA94719BBB6A6A998DF5047"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H992E02DC97E34124AEA4CEBDAC706AD9">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the phrase <quote>subject to the jurisdiction thereof</quote> in section 1 of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States reflects a principle of allegiance and obedience, not mere geography;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F895EF3C5474527ADB678BFCCFCFA08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>United States v. Wong Kim Ark, 169 U.S. 649 (1898), involved a person born in the United States to alien parents permanently domiciled and residing in the United States, and described historical exceptions for children of foreign sovereigns or their ministers, persons born on foreign public ships, children of enemies within and during a hostile occupation, and children of members of Indian Tribes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7044D6D81E64D82840A99780DB07EF6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress later addressed the Indian Tribe exception through the Indian Citizenship Act of 1924 and carried forward the words <quote>born in the United States, and subject to the jurisdiction thereof</quote> in the Nationality Act of 1940 and the Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952, now codified at section 301(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1401">8 U.S.C. 1401(a)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB01C9F27F7004342A1A797790A66A2F7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Justice Kavanaugh, concurring in the judgment and dissenting in part in Trump v. Barbara, concluded that Executive Order 14160 conflicted with section 301(a), but explained that Congress could establish exceptions for children born to foreign citizens unlawfully or temporarily in the country; this Act exercises that authority to clarify citizenship at birth and deter birth tourism and visa manipulation.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H07BA18F596F2470682BF3C9EAB70BBBF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCD38B5CC4C3F4EE2BBE68F33D9FFB9B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to preserve in Federal statutory law the historical exceptions to citizenship at birth for children of foreign sovereigns or their ministers, persons born on foreign public ships, and children of enemies within and during a hostile occupation of part of the territory of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56D5960F3FA0441CB8765D1A553CAAA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to amend section 301(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1401">8 U.S.C. 1401(a)</external-xref>) in the manner identified by Justice Kavanaugh by establishing statutory exceptions for persons born in the United States to foreign citizens unlawfully or temporarily present in the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70295F559270437C8C4DA613AD8FB4A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to define lawful but temporary presence by reference to temporary presence categories reflected in Executive Order 14160, including the Visa Waiver Program and student, work, tourist, and other nonimmigrant visas.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H7DC5DDCBF32B484EB9ADEA4B72CEFFA8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Citizenship at birth clarification</header> <subsection id="H81A2AC931EF146A79B8C4977DDDA08E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1401(a) of title 8, United States Code, is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H0DCA56FAD0244756852FCC1B2F8F2BE6" style="USC"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">: <italic>Provided</italic>, That a person born in the United States shall not be considered born subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, and shall not be a national or citizen of the United States at birth under this subsection, if the person is described in subsection (i);</text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H65C6136C0526404C90B839DD1976671E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certain persons not subject to jurisdiction</header><text>Section 1401 of title 8, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H62252C3CF90B4333A4B30C771D1C5382" style="USC"> 
<subsection id="HA74E5AEAD5724EBB89D8D8E0B0117E51"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Certain persons not subject to the jurisdiction of the United States</header> 
<paragraph id="HD369FC5250AA4E0986A9F696DABEA199"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), a person born in the United States shall not be considered born subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, and shall not be a national or citizen of the United States at birth under subsection (a), if, at the time of such person’s birth—</text> <subparagraph id="HA26BFB47F31948E0863FF67F6EB591A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the person is a child of a foreign sovereign or a minister of a foreign sovereign;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6618FB3556C84F39AECDA267BB225CB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the person is born on a foreign public ship;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7CE687A928DE40778DF5727997011A69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the person is a child of an enemy within and during a hostile occupation of any part of the territory of the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0332481D36A2484BAB9F196BB7FC3129"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the person’s mother is an alien who is unlawfully present in the United States, and the person’s father is not, at the time of such person’s birth, a citizen or national of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE13AB464C6294591B46AEB587D46F29A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the person’s mother is an alien whose presence in the United States is lawful but temporary, and the person’s father is not, at the time of such person’s birth, a citizen or national of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H80A51BF96E4744CEB740E3C5F35E5ED5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H6456FD683CEA457697E589A7788EA501"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>alien</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(3).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB5E7FE0D00664D8AA795EF1FDE58938D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(20).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7AE1624F985F492B889381E4FC369FF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <quote>mother</quote> means the immediate female biological progenitor.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA549E45AC7464BA990A95F7C17AB6B88"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <quote>father</quote> means the immediate male biological progenitor.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4DC7DEF428A74008A8A429FC3D5E59DF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The term <quote>foreign public ship</quote> means a vessel or aircraft owned, operated, or commanded by a foreign sovereign and used exclusively for a sovereign, public, noncommercial governmental purpose.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H62FE1B73B14C4C6FAB6288555AAB1DD5">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>The term <quote>hostile occupation</quote> means the actual hostile control of any part of the territory of the United States by the Armed Forces, agents, or instrumentalities of a foreign enemy during a war, invasion, or armed attack against the United States.</text>
              </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF59134A0F9E4E0D950A8B6B283EDF8F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The term <quote>minister of a foreign sovereign</quote> means an ambassador, public minister, diplomatic agent, or other official representative of a foreign sovereign who is recognized by the United States and entitled to diplomatic immunity under Federal law or treaty obligation. For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>foreign sovereign</quote> means a foreign monarch, head of state, head of government, or other sovereign authority of a foreign state recognized by the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F3B38EDF06042D4AE8B3883BDDADC13"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The term <quote>unlawfully present</quote> means, with respect to an alien, that the alien—</text> 
<clause id="HFE1716E44D2D4F6DB3883A5FB743A417"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is present in the United States without having been admitted or paroled;</text></clause> <clause id="H6A83F9E4A2684F3D9C4F7B5A13763DF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>remains in the United States after the expiration of the period of stay authorized by the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA629B9A40C374CDBA5D3C001CBF1B067"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is present in the United States in violation of the terms or conditions of admission, parole, status, classification, or other authorization to remain; or</text></clause> <clause id="HB9A63D6D790F46D68CEF6FDF62F55D63"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>otherwise lacks lawful immigration status under the immigration laws.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BD7BE7231DC4FB88A8D2C2E33631977"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The term <quote>lawful but temporary</quote> means, with respect to the presence of an alien in the United States, presence that does not constitute lawful admission for permanent residence and that is pursuant to—</text> <clause id="H9160C8AEBDEA402E8D14C65DE2DFE57D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Visa Waiver Program under section 217; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6C6A16010C9C4C0A8E5BCDCBF803E9CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a nonimmigrant visa or nonimmigrant classification under section 101(a)(15), including a student, exchange, tourist, business, work, temporary worker, crewman, transit, treaty trader, treaty investor, intracompany transferee, or other temporary nonimmigrant visa or classification.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H94EA9EB681D54CF39F4A5D88A1C467FB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date; prospective application</header> <subsection id="H17FA8C5A24274F9CA76C39FE1B29A45A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this Act shall apply to persons born in the United States on or after the date that is 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1DE20A7BBEA94288A423FB300ED45567"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prospective application</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to deny or impair citizenship or nationality at birth to any person born before the date described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H5B6F4F14BE4340929BB6227EE176A3BF"><enum>6.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional or otherwise invalid, the remainder of this Act, the amendments made by this Act, and the application of such provision or amendment to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

