<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H42A987B4844F46658C9F4549437F2A1C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9285 IH: HEAT AI Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9285</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a Heat Illness AI Surveillance and Response Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFCC4AA48CB4144F886B58E5F24881B72" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6E0263203E3F48759AE59A7B8752A406" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Heat Emergency Assessment and Tracking using AI Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>HEAT AI Act</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8509BF0AB53A4A47B52104D4DA5E02F2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAE5E7A48F7B64AE0B1E1B0BCB21E0630"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">heat-related deaths and illnesses are significantly under reported due to—</text> <subparagraph id="HC5AD53531513476D9FB7DE2E98402BC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the limitations of coding under the International Classification of Diseases; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H664030D3AA934D28BB2A714063B59555"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inconsistent documentation by medical practitioners; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB23D05E8E6A2474E823645F308012267"><enum>(2)</enum><text>artificial intelligence, including large language models, can analyze unstructured clinical data and local weather information to identify likely heat-related cases missed by current systems.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H3473C5F693124B5CB14FDDB89CF076A4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on heat-related illness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall conduct a study on the incidence of heat-related illness and death in the United States, including coordinating with State departments of health and vital statistics to determine how many deaths in the United States may be attributable to heat-related illness as a primary, secondary, or tertiary cause of death. </text></section> <section id="H73D1480AFF1D44F1935BF86556BE69A4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of pilot program</header> <subsection id="H5B63A876EF3D4053993C26917D1996D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a program under which the Secretary will make grants to not fewer than 3, and not more than 5, eligible entities. Such program shall be known as the <quote>Heat Illness AI Surveillance and Response Program</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2999A29DC6554CE28E690BBA3E17CB50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header> 
<paragraph id="H9FBFAD583AAC4D39B35FBBBA4A222E9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under the program, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form and manner, and containing such information, as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C99FEF6919C4169B125543334B38747"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An application of an eligible entity referred to in paragraph (1) shall contain, at a minimum—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5815353AC9E646A199164807C4C393FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an implementation plan developed by the eligible entity to carry out activities specified in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F5D5A51037E466E8F3FCAA26C80048E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of the partners the eligible entity will work with to develop or use an AI tool described in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4C6580E8B2CB497ABCBA861370215F3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if such AI tool has been previously developed, an identification of the AI tool; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A57C07F448947E89BF6D35B80F86DDB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the steps the applicant will take to ensure that use of an AI tool described in subsection (c) by the applicant is in compliance with applicable Federal and State privacy laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0C67D47719B441F0AAAA920CB3935048"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under the program shall use the amounts of the grant—</text> <paragraph id="HB24E54AB8F774D6EA187F554FFADDDAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to develop and test AI tools that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HABB4465081E44ECCA5FEFC3F28659DC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are capable of analyzing medical records, death certificates, and coroner reports for indications of heat-related illness (including if heat-related illness was a primary, secondary, or tertiary cause of death); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8EE4BC408144CDFB1BCCD38BE8722E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integrate localized weather data and occupational information to improve accuracy;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E0D8004C0C84C58B66B73A3BDF6E521"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to implement such AI tools for the purpose of conducting surveillance of heat-related deaths and illnesses; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C733200D2DC443D83A84F3A2AA4F9D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop heat response protocols to reduce and prevent heat-related illness and death;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H112653AB9A76415788DA056B045D0BDC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to conduct clinician training on the identification, diagnosis, and management of heat-related illness; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0ABEDB52178541FEB1CE800AA8766106"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to conduct community outreach to increase awareness of heat-related illness symptoms, risk factors, and available prevention and treatment resources to develop heat response protocols.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0698CE89C5594DCF84B5F5359699FF44"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection of grant recipients</header> 
<paragraph id="H1090FB18746F47D1A3B5FE0A3410240C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities under the program on a competitive basis.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3E4BF1890D540FCA8D12B494C03B2C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In awarding such grants, the Secretary select eligible entities that represent diverse climates and populations and shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE994CA06C97645E2A001CDC8A7059B54"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one urban community; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF60A4EF413DE437E974A11B86CE0983B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least one rural community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7C4222F9F168434CAC74A4F5D7AA4A24"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall consult with—</text> <paragraph id="HA42E1829C3F84B53B408A9326DAA6296"><enum>(1)</enum><text>medicolegal death investigation professionals of the Department of Justice;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCF23D557D3443A5B60DA84A2015CBBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regional, State, and local departments of health; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77C7F5D494F14006B963A8212FDDB85E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>relevant stakeholders, including utility companies.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1656FC25AA124CE6860C928F51E665C9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Privacy and ethics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H4AD7661970F0486F8587D4C2B62ACC4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish requirements to ensure compliance with regulations promulgated under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (commonly known as <quote>HIPAA</quote>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/191">Public Law 104–191</external-xref>) and other applicable Federal privacy laws and regulations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0505C2F66B8E4006B59221EF755DE7D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish an AI advisory board to ensure transparency, community input, fairness, accuracy, and equitable performance of AI models across demographic and geographic populations.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H428609B88DCA464C98ABB2BE390B89C9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports to congress</header> <paragraph id="H1142886EFDB0464C9540B32B48AB9744"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Progress reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the date of submission of the final report under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing a description of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H28700E6102134B0AA4F74B050E6DD1A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the progress made by the Secretary in establishing and implementing the program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H46BF93C9ECE64A8D8420CCC7AACA5FEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the accuracy of data collected under the program relating to heat-related deaths and illnesses; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6F8BF55FF534DB0B2227415CFDA29AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public health outcomes, including trends in heat-related morbidity and mortality and the effectiveness of AI-enables surveillance and response interventions. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2229244A3224BC8999FDF855E8B32D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2031, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a final report containing—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1FA3F2ECB2624BE184FD34471DA0599F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the overall effectiveness of the program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4F8B67B74EB469E9B9FBBA5546020A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the costs and benefits of individual activities carried out under the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H582A5529CF6145379C009F02C8C3C7A3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Issuance of national guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall issue national guidelines to standardize documentation and reporting of heat-related illnesses and deaths, including improved use of external cause codes used under the International Classification of Diseases. Such guidelines may be issued at such time as determined appropriate by the Director, regardless of the date upon which the program under this Act concludes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0915F7F3D1E34182942032F5D2CC6E3F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2031, the Secretary shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HA355A3AFCCC14308B1D1FB9AE8CBC228"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue recommendations based on the results of the program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8791ED23579A4841B1ABE6DECAA843C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using such recommendations, advise Federal department and agencies on broadly deploying AI technologies for the purpose of tracking heat-related deaths nationwide, including best practices for the design, acquisition, development, modernization, use, operation, sharing, risk management, auditing, and performance of such technologies for such purpose.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H347191BC4A01490C9CB884911EA9C43E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H0B260EA8258D41A0A9292D78722C1093"><enum>(1)</enum><header>AI</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>AI</quote> refers to artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B6EE072DB7C4752898C84F76EAA49D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>AI tool</header><text>The term <quote>AI tool</quote> means a software application that uses AI.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBB76647F29C44DFA9D4677B58D1C54E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>artificial intelligence</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78177B5EF2B74B4CA18E39D096722D5F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a public or private entity (including a hospital system, academic medical center, State or local health department, or qualified research institution) that has demonstrated capacity to carry out activities under the program, as determined by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H209978566C2A42BB8DCAEE215459D52B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>program</quote> means the Heat Illness AI Surveillance and Response Program referred to in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF97A2DDB1654AB3B2930B7740490BAA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8D394AF9E4884D56B2637BC6C400214D"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

