<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26526-5TD-6X-2K3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4290 IS: Retirement Annuity Supplement Clarity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4290</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260414">April 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 5, United States Code, to require that a court decree, court order, or other similar process expressly provides for an annuity supplement payment.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id15149679712F4B33BABD25CE5D89713A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Retirement Annuity Supplement Clarity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id0578b001e1b9495b88d823f38945e70c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Court orders</header><subsection id="id02f1491e80ad4f9a81c29f9922cfdc1d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Court orders</header><text>Section 8467 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id922df67d0ebe4252ae9c8af08b66bc70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d66a507d8214bcaa7d03f8b1d441952"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5dd4289a5672462c90fd0465e3b84228"><subsection id="id96974c8f384f4bf387b17517a8bca934"><enum>(c)</enum><text>If a court decree, court order, or agreement described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a) expressly divides an annuity under subchapter II, an annuity supplement payment made under section 8421 shall be included in the computation of that division, unless the court decree, court order, or agreement expressly excludes division of the annuity supplement.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfae19dcab0204b6db42a2ee38b40c735"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>Section 8421 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="id5a921c85121c4b01a7611f1b24cef19c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><paragraph id="idcf4b13e6dab54b98859ce1b16118e63e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to all annuity supplement payments under section 8421 of title 5, United States Code, that begin on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a9a729e46f74727a61dd70a67b85b0c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retroactive payments</header><subparagraph id="id7ede094c89db412ab228e202ef68c2e5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="id4d6adf875d794c43b03d0ec092176605"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annuity supplement</header><text>The term <term>annuity supplement</term> means an annuity supplement under section 8421 of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="id631a63e80b4943bab55e7b283199e83b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Covered annuitant</header><text>The term <term>covered annuitant</term> means any annuitant—</text><subclause id="id814c6d718194400faf9ee38b9a9e8cd4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>who was retired on or before the date of enactment of this Act;</text></subclause><subclause id="id7a67a7b3faad4cf5831586b520b5ae65"><enum>(II)</enum><text>who is or was entitled to an annuity supplement;</text></subclause><subclause id="iddffec43658bd4f91a6acd3ee15cff397"><enum>(III)</enum><text>whose annuity was subject to a court order described in section 8467(a)(1) of title 5, United States Code, that was silent regarding the annuity supplement or that included language that expressly excluded the annuity supplement from division; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id6fd43cff9080434ab32ebfcb2c60c619"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>whose annuity supplement was recomputed by the Office of Personnel Management during the period beginning on June 30, 2016, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act to retroactively include the annuity supplement in the division of the annuity.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddecbf2aaf0ab489fbcb7367c4ba3705e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>The Office of Personnel Management shall pay a one-time payment from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund established under section 8348 of title 5, United States Code, to a covered annuitant who received an annuity supplement under section 8421 of title 5, United States Code, before the date of enactment of this Act an amount (without interest) equal to the amount deducted from the annuity of the covered annuitant as a result of including the annuity supplement in the computation of a court-ordered division or other scenario described in subparagraph (A)(ii)(III).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id74183cb3c8f743938df0b8d532acbd42"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No repayment</header><text>Overpayments paid to a covered annuitant, or any overpayments of apportionment paid to a former spouse of a covered annuitant (as the case may be), before the date of enactment of this Act, which resulted from excluding the annuity supplement of the covered annuitant in the computation of a court-ordered apportionment, shall be waived.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

