<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25C34-WV4-TP-L8J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3384 IS: Fraud Risk Assessment of Obamacare Subsidies Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3384</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251208" legis-day="20251204">December 8 (legislative day, December 4), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to complete fraud risk assessments of the advance premium tax credit, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fraud Risk Assessment of Obamacare Subsidies Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9489dae52c72409e82fcf5a912076af0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fraud risk assessment</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide884091149c14391820e7fa6593aa1b5"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2025, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall prepare a fraud risk assessment of the advance determinations under section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18082">42 U.S.C. 18082</external-xref>) of premium tax credits allowable under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, including a complete list of any controls used by the Secretary of Health and Human Services for purposes of preventing fraud with respect to advance premium tax credit claims, and submit such assessment to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc6b1fd7b81e4301a26391a1e82132ed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcf3901c120f443ed9805b0a616b4ff6d"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Finance, the Committee on the Budget, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96a4b084f47648ab87d640b6591151df"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on the Budget, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d520dc147f4422185724b4aa04e3f09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each fraud risk assessment under subsection (a) shall be conducted in accordance with the principles of the report of the Comptroller General of the United States titled <quote>A Framework for Managing Fraud Risks in Federal Programs</quote>, issued in July 2015.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

