<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3517F89AD43B4D52BFAF950C09098B56" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9416 IH: Ocmulgee Mounds National Park Redesignation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9416</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000311">Mr. Jack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To redesignate the Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park as the <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0C3B8A11198C4685B66C3B5542D0A9F8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H96B7B3666BFC414DACC5D7644908ACED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park Redesignation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H629916B8FAD44AC2AE11AAB66F4A40AC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0462A4D258A54D0C9A6F985250E71032"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian tribe</term> means an Indian tribe, as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>), that has a cultural affiliation, as defined in section 2 of the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3001">25 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref>), to the Ocmulgee Mounds region, to be determined by the Secretary after appropriate tribal consultation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98AED7101F634D1DB3AABFA42960BF2D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means map titled <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park</quote>, numbered 363/193026, and dated May 2026.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2333D47F789E48479C2965284E196258"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7AA35B304AF475AAFB442F8A9A79046"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Georgia.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HDB7A9989D2CA41A7A11369F8A3FD4694"><enum>3.</enum><header>Redesignation of Ocmulgee Mounds National Park</header> 
<subsection id="HBA059F64C7914D63BC4A064DF4363439"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Redesignation</header> 
<paragraph id="H7E4B9D9E0BF7454793F963B8AD5EB808"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park designated by section 2102(b)(1)(A) of the John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/410yyy-3">16 U.S.C. 410yyy–3(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) shall be known and designated as the <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDFD846B151D4802A4D482E987826EFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Historical Park</quote> shall be considered to be a reference to the <quote>Ocmulgee Mounds National Park</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBAD4DD809C084950BB9BC7107E806F7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map</header> 
<paragraph id="H2C3C45EEEFDE4995865420AD1B268D33"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Corrections</header><text>The Secretary may make technical corrections to the Map.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC565D5F977444803AE68595CF2F796DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H65148E8E20494BAB994B89D8722F7D33"><enum>4.</enum><header>Administration of Ocmulgee Mounds National Park</header> 
<subsection id="H9EA4AD16D074478F874479E2115999AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Ocmulgee Mounds National Park shall be administered as a unit of the National Park System in accordance with this section and the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—</text> <paragraph id="H25E6DB24A0D64DAF8A1C72C6F967C140"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of title 54, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56141FFDBAD04C6598727F4C19D2A91C"><enum>(2)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3201">chapter 3201</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA959C4F673CF43EDB6FA9FBC45734FD9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fishing</header> <paragraph id="H65059A1E394B45248A91EE7514507A21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall allow fishing on waters under the jurisdiction of the Secretary within the boundaries of the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37F80F79ADDB49BF9AF2F5A686331691"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary may designate zones in which, and establish periods during which, no fishing shall be allowed for reasons of public safety, administration, fish or wildlife management, or emergencies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BA292D4EED341E59BD78E5EFDF4CB99"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure any regulations prescribing restrictions under this subsection shall be put into effect only after consultation with the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED6B0B6A67FC45CBBE83C217222B633C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Private land</header><text>Nothing in this subsection prohibits hunting, fishing, or trapping on private land in accordance with applicable State and Federal laws.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD06C528BB8064615A1DEA62820A7AF17"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Congressional intent</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to enlarge or diminish the authority, jurisdiction, or responsibility of the State to manage, control, or regulate fish and wildlife on lands and waters, including Federal lands and waters, within the State.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAE9DB3DA28224D82BCA701547E893431"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hiring preference</header><text>The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable and consistent with applicable law, seek to increase employment opportunities for members of Indian tribes in the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAD230FAABF844A74A2B9DA1244792AF1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tribal consultation</header><text>Nothing in this Act prevents continued consultation with Indian tribes pursuant to Executive Order 13175 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> note; relating to consultation and coordination with Indian tribal governments) and other applicable laws.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H730F7E99C22A451C942D0B9C5C9FAC7C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sacred and cultural sites</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure the protection of traditional cultural and religious sites within the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park and provide access to the sites by members of Indian tribes who have ancestral connections to the Ocmulgee River Corridor, in accordance with the laws (including regulations) applicable to the Secretary concerned.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HAB61A026CC7D45888ABB0DEF5EA1F65E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Agreements</header> <subsection id="H8D60448826B1476786A169C9E972A017"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may seek to enter into memoranda of understanding, cooperative agreements, or other legally authorized agreements with the Muscogee (Creek) Nation and other interested Indian tribes to address issues pertaining to the management, conservation, and preservation of natural and cultural resources within the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E8D6D26E7A647D9A48F430F57DA9B1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary shall promptly notify the parties to an agreement described in subsection (a) of any requests received from other Indian tribes seeking similar agreements concerning the management, conservation, and preservation of natural and cultural resources within the Ocmulgee Mounds National Park.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA3E18EB312FC494DABABD33530893BE3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Land to be held in trust for the Tribe</header> <subsection id="HDDFF6E22B74C40E6B2C9A52DF65F6E1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon request of the Muscogee (Creek) Nation, not later than 180 days after receipt of such request, the Secretary shall take into trust for the benefit of the Muscogee (Creek) Nation the approximately 133.88 acres of land held in fee by the Muscogee (Creek) Nation, as generally depicted as <quote>The Muscogee Creek Nation - Fee</quote> on the map titled <quote>Muscogee Creek Nation Fee Lands</quote> and dated June 16, 2026.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H41789B7AF341490792B9869F39129D15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Status of land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The land taken into trust under subsection (a) shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H4D9D5354EC1B4629A31031423850E92E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>part of the Muscogee Creek Indian Reservation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3C0EF951AF946CD8108446605814B3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>administered in accordance with the laws and regulations generally applicable to property held in trust by the United States for the benefit of an Indian Tribe.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE914FC8229F64F34BB3D056947AF1E1E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Gaming prohibited</header><text>The land taken into trust under subsection (a) shall not be used for any class II gaming or class III gaming under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (as those terms are defined in section 4 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2703">25 U.S.C. 2703</external-xref>)).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

