<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM25677-N11-JM-RY8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3340 IS: 21st Century STEM for Girls and Underrepresented Minorities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3340</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to local educational agencies to encourage girls and underrepresented minorities to pursue studies and careers in STEM fields.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HDA9238F57EF34093B7744D378149CE0E"><section section-type="section-one" id="H5B46FF52328944D3A4A42E3E550D62FE"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century STEM for Girls and Underrepresented Minorities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H41F0E45C20614DBDA8E0533AEF07EC22"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to prepare girls and underrepresented minorities</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id191be05820d149e898f5939d959b9194"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" act-name="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965" id="HD018D8FAD02C4834A87D5D53130FE5F6"><part id="H17D26F242E80420F99F308664ACA668F"><enum>G<?LEXA-Enum G?></enum><header>Preparing girls and underrepresented minorities for the 21st century</header><section id="H3F37BC354F1A49E7857DA82E0DEABBC3"><enum>4701.</enum><header>Program authority</header><subsection id="HD78FEA0E0B994CA484A89FA5FEFD35F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this part, the Secretary shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes grants to qualified local educational agencies, on a competitive basis, to pay the costs of carrying out STEM education activities for girls and underrepresented minorities as described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H0024CC6DAE4246C0B032A39193E70230"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="H1B58168C7F3343168798D83BAE22226C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this part, a qualified local educational agency shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require. At minimum, the application shall include a description of the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H98890493E90D4FE8924EA63FDF8C0467"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The educational program that will be carried out by the local educational agency using the grant, including the content of the program and the research and models used to design the program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF0079C7EE4FC44A99AA406C7136BD5EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How elementary schools and secondary schools served by the agency will collaborate to fulfill goals of the program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEA95F1108FE4ECFA5A409B396AD4975"><enum>(C)</enum><text>How the agency will ensure that there is a comprehensive plan to improve STEM education for girls and underrepresented minorities in grades kindergarten through grade 12.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H956B4C4C5D1B496595FEE0BAFE9A2CBD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The process that will be used for the recruitment and selection of students for participation in the program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF66A75C352614B689086EF5728193DAC"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The instructional and motivational activities that will be included as part of the program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1A2BEAEDF18437188461241AB1752C1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any expected collaboration among national, regional, or local institutions and organizations for the purpose of fulfilling the goals of the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2D307AEF702F4CDEA2DC679DC133332D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting among applications submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give priority to qualified local educational agencies that partner or coordinate, to the extent practicable, with national, regional, or local institutions and organizations that have extensive experience and expertise in—</text><subparagraph id="HD5BA7127F9804662B325B850FADDE4F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increasing the participation of girls or underrepresented minorities in STEM fields; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE925EE56576944928E40BF59F0EBA683"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducting research on methods to increase such participation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H550B9F43C05F495E8EDA6EA7CBA23ECE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualified local educational agency that receives a grant under this part shall use the grant to carry out a STEM education program for girls and underrepresented minorities from elementary schools and secondary schools served by the agency. The program may include the following activities:</text><paragraph id="H16B928DCAE3B49C1B2913E2C61F5E20E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Preparing girls and underrepresented minorities for careers in STEM fields and the advantages of pursuing careers in such fields.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18C74D4AA1F942BCB69224EE4EE44B53"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Educating the parents of girls and underrepresented minorities about the opportunities and advantages of STEM careers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E74A293864E4ACBA532C3C09343CC9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enlisting the help of the parents of girls and underrepresented minorities—</text><subparagraph id="H091E3A89BBDD4039B98C1FA0C4D5D7F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to overcome the obstacles faced by such groups; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C4C5607029B48AE84B6DD21A74806DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to encourage their child’s continued interest and involvement in STEM subjects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39680FCC04D34A1AB5E401D56B747C86"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing tutoring and mentoring programs in STEM subjects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24BBF6141C824092AEBC2546FB4C8993"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Establishing partnerships and other opportunities that expose girls and underrepresented minorities to role models in the STEM fields.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD5B8ECA820184D0E94DB3A9C85A8ED67"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enabling female and underrepresented minority students and their teachers to attend events and academic programs in STEM subjects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D7E78B6081C43BD9DE4A0504427CAFE"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing after school activities designed to encourage interest and develop the skills of girls and underrepresented minorities in STEM subjects.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H78C4AF687A71418C8652C58F9335D170"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Summer programs designed to help girls and underrepresented minorities—</text><subparagraph id="H3094CD4E81794EC79A75A33EEC4FEE87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop an interest in STEM subjects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0102886B4774E7B945D3BBEAA7DE0AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop skills in such subjects; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D0C9FD2FF16437AB01876A7430B972C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>understand the relevance and significance of such subjects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BAD6C08588749F7A221306B1AB8E7AE"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Purchasing—</text><subparagraph id="H0C8C6DBCEBA24CBB9F46ADD49064CC9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educational instructional materials or software designed to help girls and underrepresented minorities develop an interest in STEM subjects; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2159F167CA704DBDA3A5D29EE98532E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>equipment, instrumentation, or hardware for teaching STEM subjects to girls and underrepresented minorities and encouraging their interest in such subjects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC7E178922D4FEAA3A1CFA6E609799E"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Field trips to locations, including institutions of higher education, to expose girls and underrepresented minorities to STEM activities, encourage their interest in such activities, and acquaint them with careers in STEM fields.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB736A367AD524A3F8ABFB1BBD60F939E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Providing academic advice and assistance in high school course selection to encourage girls and underrepresented minorities to take advanced courses in STEM subjects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46B6E1F4C43E409982B7A1109873CA9B"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Paying not more than 50 percent of the cost of an internship in a STEM discipline for female and underrepresented minority students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A20F032A1244B5E821C5F594EF3E407"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing professional development for teachers and other school personnel, including with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HD279C34121C1485CADBFB4C2E2E7ED16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eliminating gender and racial bias in the classroom;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E172D38A4E74DC786CAA69AAD210D47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sensitivity to gender and racial differences;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B010AE54F8C4DDFB56FC8DDE6FB1690"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engaging students in the face of gender-based and racial peer pressure and parental expectations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE74847D4F494A8883141927FFAF5F3E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>creating and maintaining a positive environment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF385B74E88F48C693FDFEBB8F8A5D90"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encouraging girls and underrepresented minorities through academic advice and assistance to pursue advanced classes and careers in STEM fields.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H174336CB276741AAAB17FE6DBDF24F9C"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Such other STEM-related activities as the local educational agency determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF234A392C1634F1DB2D1A6A0F9B2E2B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant duration and amount</header><paragraph id="H2B460C610A2E419491638B96CED9D8DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each grant under this section shall be made for a period of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBB01C6C5F83453BAE2078C0A3E384B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of each grant under this section shall be $250,000 for each year of the grant period.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H314C8C9AE9C74F9ABF69EBE63B576B4E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualified local educational agency that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant only to supplement, and not to supplant, other assistance and funds made available from non-Federal sources for the activities supported by the grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE5EE0091C1114EF390C897941878B881"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual evaluations</header><paragraph id="H12BAA880B8034652A6093D434B7973B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation required</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the last day of each school year for which a qualified local educational agency receives a grant under this section, the agency shall submit to the Secretary a written evaluation of the program carried out using the grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE94DA3F75F1482E8D85DE6BA720FBAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The evaluation required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HD0C549C2B72C4151BF67DD5C33905223"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the program and activities carried out using the grant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H988FB1AC865945FF9C86E80FF1F75404"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the curriculum and any partnerships developed using the grant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H238F83557F95419BB9CDBA98EEF26203"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the percentage of time that students who participated in the program spent directly engaged in STEM activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F7690B9406D49DEBF6F4B84C450F029"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of the academic progress made by such students during the program, which shall be based on an evaluation of each student at the beginning of the program and after the student completes the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8008C14F512F4801BD1266637ED5DC9A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95C09A4B91ED48258AB081E600C8088B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE9E7DB1356E44A6CA40F2BFC30CBF25D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency that—</text><subparagraph id="HEC34DBCBE2CB4671BB074236663C44C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives funds under part A of title I; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42B1FAD978034A85AE6E5E6CE32341F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serves a total student population of which not less than 40 percent are children who are eligible for a free or reduced price lunch under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF57953E871E644A9BCF8B690D9997EF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>STEM</term> means science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H7F9FDABC69F24788A1E5298427ADD7D4"><enum>4702.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029.</text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc2aff2ec47f54083931a6abfb07c47a0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4644 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id9e9e68da-3e61-415a-ab1a-3afbffef7cfc"><toc><toc-entry level="part" idref="H17D26F242E80420F99F308664ACA668F">PART G—Preparing girls and underrepresented minorities for the 21st century</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H3F37BC354F1A49E7857DA82E0DEABBC3">Sec. 4701. Program authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H7F9FDABC69F24788A1E5298427ADD7D4">Sec. 4702. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

