<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25B85-VNY-2T-15W"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 511 IS: Supporting the goals and principles of Transgender Day of Remembrance by recognizing the epidemic of violence toward transgender people and memorializing the lives lost this year.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 511</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and principles of Transgender Day of Remembrance by recognizing the epidemic of violence toward transgender people and memorializing the lives lost this year.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Transgender Day of Remembrance was created following the 1998 killing of Rita Hester, a transgender woman of color, whose murder has yet to be solved;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the following year on November 20, 1999, Gwendolyn Ann Smith created the first Transgender Day of Remembrance in honor of Rita Hester and other transgender people whose lives were lost due to violence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Transgender Day of Remembrance 2025 honors the memory of the lives of transgender people tragically lost in acts of violence between October 1, 2024, and September 30, 2025;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States is currently experiencing an epidemic of violence against transgender people;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas at least 27 transgender or gender nonconforming people were violently killed in the United States so far in 2025, a number many believe to be much higher due to the prevalence of underreporting or misreporting violence against this community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the lives of Rick Alastor Newman, Jay Floris, Quanesha Shantel (<quote>Cocoa</quote>), Kyla Jane Walker, Ra’lasia Wright, Cam Thompson, Tahiry Broom, Sam Nordquist, Amyri Dior, Linda Becerra Moran, Ervianna Johnson, Kaitoria Bankz, Jax Gratton, Kelsey Elem, Shy’Parius Dupree, Karmin Wells, Hope Lyca Youngblood, Laura Schueler, Christina Hayes, JJ Godbey, Kamora Woods, Dream Johnson, Blair A. Sawyer, Rosa Machuca, Onyx Cornish, Kasí Rhea (<quote>Kaeyy Holmes</quote>), and Tiara Love Jackson (<quote>Tori</quote>) were tragically lost in acts of violence between October 1, 2024, and September 30, 2025;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the remains of Aubrey Dameron and Jay Lee were found in 2025; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, to date, at least 241 transgender or gender nonconforming people have been lost in acts of violence worldwide in 2025, according to the Transgender Day of Remembrance memorial page from Trans Lives Matter;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on October 13, 2025, Miss Major Griffin-Gracy, a pioneer transgender activist who participated in the uprising at Stonewall in 1969 and served as the Executive Director of the Transgender Gender Variant and Intersex Justice Project, passed away;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas violence against transgender people of the United States disproportionately impacts transgender women of color;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Black transgender women are the most targeted group to experience violence in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas transgender people of the United States face barriers to health care, such as lack of health insurance, stigma and discrimination, higher rates of unemployment, and, in an increasingly higher number of States, legal barriers to accessing medical care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas transgender people disproportionately suffer from higher rates of homelessness, with reports suggesting as many as one-third of transgender women and one-half of transgender women who are Black, Middle Eastern, multiracial, or undocumented have ever experienced homelessness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas almost half of all transgender people in the United States will attempt suicide at least once, and over 1 in 20 will attempt suicide each year, a rate that is almost 10 times higher than the rest of the United States population;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over half of all transgender youth in the United States have considered attempting suicide at least once in the last year, and over a quarter have attempted suicide, almost 2.5 times that of United States youth as a whole;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas asylum seekers and refugees who are transgender experience disproportionate rates of violence, including sexual violence, as they seek safety;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas transgender immigrants have died in detention centers in the United States due to medical neglect, injury, and abuse at the hands of staff;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas transgender people in institutional settings such as jails and prisons are subject to high levels of violence and discrimination, especially when they lack access to appropriate facilities and care based on their gender identity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas transgender students are significantly more likely to experience bullying or harassment at school due to their gender identity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas understanding and addressing the challenges faced by transgender people of the United States is hampered by a severe lack of data;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress and the executive branch must act to protect and preserve the lives of all people of the United States, including transgender people, through inclusive legislation and policies that treat everyone with dignity and respect;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the continued introduction of anti-transgender legislation and Executive orders have fueled violence against transgender people of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas efforts to restrict access to gender-affirming healthcare has stripped many transgender people of access to medically-necessary care, led to a spike in poor mental health and suicidality among transgender youth and adults, increased bullying and assault in schools, and left parents afraid their children may be removed from their homes because they support their transgender child;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the transgender community has shown great resilience in the face of adversity in all aspects of their lives, including housing, education, employment, and health care; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the transgender community has demonstrated tremendous leadership since the courageous actions of many community members, including Marsha P. Johnson and Sylvia Rivera, at the Stonewall uprising of 1969: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H13CE66E9E607484C88726A229EC71794"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H4037081720D24BE7B67010CC4015C536"><enum/><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="H75AE07FA29CE4F869DAC7B23B7048076"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and principles of Transgender Day of Remembrance by recognizing the epidemic of violence toward transgender people and memorializing the lives lost this year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92640CDD67F049858A5F8E83392F98CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that the alarming trends of increased violence against transgender people of the United States, particularly transgender women of color, are unacceptable, and that finding solutions to these issues must be a pressing priority for the United States Government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F96668C58C1413AB18BF735583ED93E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports efforts to study, respond to, and prevent violence against transgender people;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9286C434A57644D7BDDDC4428C73CE88"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affirms the principle that every person is endowed with basic human rights and that the commitment of the United States to this principle must encompass every single individual;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FDEC1C304B2458A8FBBB3B43F2FEB48"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes the bravery and resilience of the transgender community as it fights for equal dignity and respect; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H023659D413A54BAEA5035DF07A6E7D2F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recognizes the multitude of contributions and cultural impact the transgender community has had on the society of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

