<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA26208-M4D-9J-S9F" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 676 ATS: Recognizing and honoring National Mushroom Day and the contributions of Chester and Berks Counties to the national mushroom industry and to healthy diets.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 676</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260416" legis-day="20260414">April 16 (legislative day, April 14), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committee discharged; considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and honoring National Mushroom Day and the contributions of Chester and Berks Counties to the national mushroom industry and to healthy diets.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas June 1 is National Mushroom Day;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, since the cultivation of mushrooms began in France in 1651, the cultivation of mushrooms has been developed and advanced through the hard work of mushroom growers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1885, a successful florist in Kennett Square, Pennsylvania, conceived the idea of growing mushrooms beneath his greenhouse benches, leading to the first dedicated mushroom growing operation in the area;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 60 percent of United States mushrooms are now grown in Chester and Berks Counties, Pennsylvania;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the mushroom farms in Chester County include both large and small farms, including multigeneration family farms, demonstrating the region’s support for small businesses and local producers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the local mushroom growers meet and collaborate, leading to the innovation that distinguishes the region and its mushroom industry; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the mushroom growers and the farmworker community contribute substantially to the local economy, employing nearly 10,000 workers and bringing an estimated $2,700,000,000 into Chester County;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the year-round production of mushrooms and the associated industries support continuous employment, stable farm operations, and sustained economic activity by providing reliable jobs and supporting agricultural supply chains;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mushroom production represents one of agriculture’s most successful examples of a circular economy, utilizing agricultural byproducts that reduce inputs and environmental impacts and using innovative practices that protect local ecosystems;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mushrooms are celebrated by home cooks and chefs because of their versatility, affordability, savory umami flavor, and nutritional qualities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mushrooms are a dietary staple due to their nutritional value; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mushrooms are fat-free, cholesterol-free, low in calories, low in sodium, and an important part of a diet rich in whole foods: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFB017AEA67B24CA9863F85D783E24776"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H82209168E2F54E22AD1E5F133EE4F5D7"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="H3AECA930B0CD4D1FA2F7EDDF1D3BD77A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the recognition of National Mushroom Day; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D808EB43C7C4CD1A881A0267033C922"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania for its unparalleled contributions to the national mushroom industry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide803c59f5de548b4aa7b6e7cca2a4112"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the role mushrooms play in a healthy diet that is rich in whole foods.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

