<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HE5EFF1E53CDC4D6683998475F8E3A774"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5249 IH: Limit on Sweeping Executive Reorganization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5249</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250910">September 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To restore and affirm the constitutional prerogative and responsibility of Congress to exercise the exclusive legislative powers of Congress under article I of the Constitution of the United States to make all laws that are necessary and proper for carrying into execution the powers of Congress under article I and all other powers vested by the Constitution of the United States in the Government of the United Sates, or in any department or officer thereof.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Limit on Sweeping Executive Reorganization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35856666586b471bb460cc27f3fc9ab9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67ca64a6e13a41d790bdd59d4a042c5b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 6 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1bdd520ce27a48799f444930c079dce2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>The term <term>employee</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2d2892abfb7454791a82aab36cabc5f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Independent reorganization review panel</header><text>The term <term>Independent Reorganization Review Panel</term> means the panel established under section 5(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id093f5a5185cf44d397ec9ec8bc600744"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval</header><text>The term <term>joint resolution of approval</term> means a joint resolution—</text><subparagraph id="ide40becbcbbfa45b0a1291ba37ce9c666"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is introduced during the period—</text><clause id="id1927136f6b214030889e1bc72e885de6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>beginning on the date on which the Independent Reorganization Review Panel submits to Congress a report relating to a major executive reorganization in accordance with section 5(c); and</text></clause><clause id="ideaec24c4b9a440018aa24d2a0f3c5bbd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ending on the date that is 7 days after the date described in clause (i);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd5ee524ca0c4dd5aa3102e94e1622e7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>Joint resolution relating to ____</quote>, the blank space being filled in with a description of the major executive reorganization described in subparagraph (A)(i);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7714f3496b2f48d6847637a2bebb0e89"><enum>(C)</enum><text>which does not have a preamble; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc88ab2829b5d4bf68ac7c0060e847a01"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the matter after the resolving clause of which is <quote>That Congress approves of the major executive reorganization described in the reorganization impact report submitted by the President relating to ____, and such major executive reorganization may take effect.</quote> (The blank spaces being appropriately filled in).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id156d883da1f64023a92ad11f1338e19a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>The term <term>labor organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 7103 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc425d259cf01435485ba24a42e5775dc"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Major executive reorganization</header><text>The term <term>major executive reorganization</term> means an action taken by the executive branch of the Federal Government that—</text><subparagraph id="id1b116ddb39dd48638ba2d80b303a232c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>combined with other reorganizational efforts, reduces the number of employees of an agency by not less than 5 percent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b42191d7ba84976a609a9557e86dfa7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>combined with other reorganizational efforts, reduces the operating budget of an agency by not less than 10 percent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6dce6bf8c08143f8bd212ce7b48fca56"><enum>(C)</enum><text>eliminates, merges, or closes an agency, component of an agency, or regional office of an agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b89819f64da44eda8ccb63f5f791b37"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transfers the operational control of a Federal data system, platform, or administrative function to a non-Federal entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f7b5149f1d14d6cbed3dab0db48cf20"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Reorganization impact report</header><text>The term <term>reorganization impact report</term> means a report submitted pursuant to section 3(a).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id57eafce7ab4949c4afd3993f177e3f57"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reorganization impact reports</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2ef747f6bb64bc2bd32138a632d230b"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may submit to Congress and the Independent Reorganization Review Panel a reorganization impact report relating to a proposed major executive reorganization.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e7b235c680b45e5b570c05ed102ae7b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A reorganization impact report submitted under subsection (a) shall include, with respect to a proposed major executive reorganization—</text><paragraph id="id595d0617a4284b42b43c43a8f5f1fbe8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the purpose and justification for the major executive reorganization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf5b43c7249e24dc481f7ef5785bc63f1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number and roles of employees affected by the major executive reorganization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd86e20a3b782496d968a4aab0a17c38a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the impact of the major executive reorganization on the service delivery and mission performance of any agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id73603a2352124d79827db549c00cb724"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a summary of any consultation performed with each labor organization affected by the major executive reorganization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideca5b599b8704060b9e9ab7773fce815"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a budgetary analysis and a description of the costs of transition relating to the major executive reorganization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec5d6d7499444474a205d02b1084be09" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any proposed reassignment of Federal information technology, human resources, or financial systems under the major executive reorganization.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idc6f8204595ce45c0890a0688c595daca"><enum>4.</enum><header>Congressional approval required</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A major executive reorganization may not take effect until the date on which—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a99bb8a922e49ccaace040c9884dea5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President submits to Congress a reorganization impact report relating to the major executive reorganization under section 3(a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93e1cbf1cff9459e995e15abe093a251"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress enacts a joint resolution of approval providing that the major executive reorganization may take effect.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idefee1572c0e34d92bb6a74d7cd2a06b6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Independent Reorganization Review Panel</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf24f46f6dfd249f19d16f5d171611506"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Independent Reorganization Review Panel for the purpose of reviewing reorganization impact reports.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf3b36970ada04772af27cce77ac8806a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Independent Reorganization Review Panel shall include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12a7ee4843f34fbbb1c30e7a23601518"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a1bafb92ae34e47a1fb56060b5f6d72"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Office of Personnel Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbffc6aac399b40b697c9763406b30159"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Government Accountability Office; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id668c76b307fe41f381fa6b6e65d32887"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Congressional Budget Office; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3c1c34faf4ec4c01aa69f5dac304ddb2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>1 representative of a labor organization that is the exclusive representative of a unit of employees (as defined in section 7103 of title 5, United States Code).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d4ce9a96ef049498cea27c2dde8ec67"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Independent Reorganization Review Panel receives a reorganization impact report relating to a major executive reorganization pursuant to section 3(a), the Independent Reorganization Review Panel shall submit to Congress a report that includes a non-binding advisory opinion with respect to the major executive reorganization.</text></subsection></section><section id="id667b377faf584698881d0ac10305327b"><enum>6.</enum><header>Employee and labor protections</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93719642465b41399a52fb46286d9b2c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each agency shall, with respect to a major executive reorganization carried out by the agency—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5cb8c092e7c4dc09010e702c6a81ffa"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 60 days before the date on which the agency begins carrying out the major executive reorganization, provide notice regarding the major executive reorganization to each employee of the agency who will be affected by the major executive reorganization;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e3385f595be4d1389a0d398f9a83d67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fulfill all obligations of the agency under each collective bargaining agreement (as defined in section 7103 of title 5, United States Code) to which the agency is a party; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida94660bf823546869952eba4c7d9f4fe"><enum>(3)</enum><text>undergo a review conducted by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to ensure that the major executive reorganization complies with merit system principles.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef45d6beeb8746d483063ae21a259e7c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to diminish or otherwise affect the procedural protections provided under section 3502 of title 5, United States Code, or any other similar provision of law.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide215a2e980af447db8a402f06a4c03f0"><enum>7.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f0630516a864d73b2265a0c9eb23550"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, after investigation, the Special Counsel determines that an officer or employee of an agency knowingly authorized, directed, or carried out a major executive reorganization in violation of this Act, the Special Counsel shall take appropriate action under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, with respect to the violation.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21c19b4e130f454883dce26cd2ae312c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>An officer or employee of an agency against whom an adverse action is taken under subsection (a) shall be entitled to the procedural protections that apply under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, with respect to the applicable adverse action.</text></subsection></section><section id="idf1c6f6f0c636437e9cf8f378b2783cad" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Legal standing and judicial review</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6930a5ff89e74125a76628a0ecf7b73d"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A labor organization or employee may bring an action for a major executive reorganization, or any executive action, carried out in violation of this Act in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia for injunctive relief.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idefe84bc490ff46e7b2c22c1fe8d36e51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expedited review</header><text>The United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall provide expedited review for an action brought under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="ided9f0e740451404b882b9752b0e4e653"><enum>9.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person, entity, government, or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, or the application of such provision to all other persons, entities, governments, or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

