<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA26698-0H6-83-L23"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4934 IS: National Fab Lab Network Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4934</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the National Fab Lab Network, a nonprofit organization consisting of a national network of local digital fabrication facilities providing universal access to advanced manufacturing tools for workforce development, STEM education, developing inventions, creating businesses, producing personalized products, mitigating risks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HE647AAF8F32A4F5CB014C107053699A5"><section section-type="section-one" id="H34E2F4AF68674902916929619E26891E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Fab Lab Network Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB919E4D0ECB64984BA6F9E9498A69924"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H44860EAF25764956895288EAF919F51F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Scientific discoveries and technical innovations are critical to the economic and national security of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D67BC78D96141CD862183DFFFDE2711"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Maintaining the leadership of the United States in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics will require a diverse population with the skills, interest, and access to tools required to advance these fields.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H875CDA320B8642AEA2E2692607E25637"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Just as earlier digital revolutions in communications and computation provided individuals with the internet and personal computers, a digital revolution in fabrication will allow anyone to make almost anything, anywhere.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A22B53C2DFB404A8674E7AE64C94AAC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>These creations include elements of a typical household basket of goods (furnishings, apparel, food production equipment, shelter, transportation, education and communication, recreation, and other goods and services), personal technology, means for personal expression, the production of digital fabrication machinery, community design, and manufacturing capability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB753CF8C1F3E4B139A45D3F291FF8ECF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Center for Bits and Atoms of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (CBA) has contributed significantly to the advancement of these goals through its work in creating and advancing digital fabrication facilities, or <quote>fab labs</quote> in the United States and abroad.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEC638ADA4354138A4FC28979366E97D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Such digital fabrication facilities may include MakerSpaces, Hackerspaces, and other creative spaces that use digital fabrication as a platform for education, innovation, entrepreneurship, personal expression, public access, and social impact.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5319F13F8B9E4EA1A92D4D8D9B365FC3"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such digital fabrication facilities provide a model for a new kind of national laboratory that operates as a network, linking local facilities for advanced manufacturing, providing universal access, cultivating new literacies, and empowering communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72605D93068844479B9F1BF998A75728"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The nonprofit Fab Foundation was established to support the growth of the international network of digital fabrication facilities, to amplify the educational, entrepreneurial, and social impacts of digital fabrication facilities, and to support the development of regional capacity building organizations to broaden impact as well as address local, regional, and global challenges through the use of digital fabrication technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA908CFDACC2442ABB13247B6EA4194B4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A coordinated array of national public-private partnerships will be the most effective way to accelerate the provision of universal access to this infrastructure for workforce development, science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education, developing inventions, creating businesses, producing personalized products, and mitigating risks.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H57A279244E5D4D428F077972153839F3"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Fab Lab Network</header><subsection id="HBBC50E4CA5314E9BB97377FB3B673680"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>fab lab</term> means a facility that—</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56B2C0593CB249D7B4A474499271C017"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contains the range of capabilities required to create form and function from digital designs, including—</text><subparagraph id="HC0BDA52C26DE4D4AB429FFDF1C44DB08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>computer-controlled machines for additive and subtractive fabrication processes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H823A8CADFAAF4C79AF85778D3451174C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>tools and components for manufacturing and programming electronic circuits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H512D7742C4F049099031548C71F25D1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>materials and methods for short-run production; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7D791DB90A64134A1A4BB4C8BD1C12C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>workflows for three-dimensional design and digitization; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09D0B75F01CE446B8A51BBE594B7C6F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is committed to supporting education, innovation, entrepreneurship, personal expression, self-sufficiency, and social impact for its community through digital fabrication.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF275C98F0292477DADA5C84E6BC5621E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is hereby established a nonprofit corporation to be known as the <quote>National Fab Lab Network</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>corporation</quote>), which shall not be an agency or establishment of the United States Government. The corporation shall be subject to the provisions of this Act, and, to the extent consistent with this Act, to the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act (D.C. Code, section 29–501 et seq.).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB9BB4F1EE1E9400C95407B81601C0891"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Goals and activities</header><paragraph id="H54AADBF0DE9D4DE584A36258CD5E9BE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The goals of the corporation are as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H3510462A26D848BEBE8E16C2F1423638"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To provide universal access to digital fabrication.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0694F44ECEF74E97BA173D35628F553F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To foster current and future fab labs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF637187CFB97401AA2D7D3AB7CF6B66B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To create a national network of connected local fab labs to empower individuals and communities in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB7E7343C9344637A7459962E141C044"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To foster the use of distributed digital fabrication tools—</text><clause id="HD0252386D6EE4B43B0A749B658B733E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to promote science, technology, engineering and math skills;</text></clause><clause id="H21AB21BE948644D995912F301FCDDCB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to increase invention and innovation;</text></clause><clause id="HB98A3FB13FFA4956927319C3FC13CCAB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to create businesses and jobs;</text></clause><clause id="HDF33E7304D7D4CBFB4AFA17549AB07E8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to fulfill personal, professional, and community needs;</text></clause><clause id="H5456256A6F23432A95C867A9BA815F6E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to create value and mitigate harm;</text></clause><clause id="H18F1819F7E994945BD4071BB69F73A6F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to increase self-sufficiency for individuals, households, and communities; and</text></clause><clause id="H891F585DF5D9463C9F53E0BB21E4824C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>to align workforce development with new and emerging jobs.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDC448547D374AA4B46AFEA5BDD02E38"><enum>(E)</enum><text>To provide a platform for education and research, to catalyze new methods in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education, and to introduce digital fabrication as an essential new literacy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5DF4B12DF3E4EBC80D63813EDF63459"><enum>(F)</enum><text>To create new ways of educating the workforce that will enable workers to compete in a 21st century global marketplace.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0720E01AE8294ECBAE5EFA1EA3C8A627"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>To attain the goals described in paragraph (1), the corporation shall carry out activities, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H54A07FB4651B45C28478ECCC3A8553A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Seek to establish a minimum of one fab lab in each congressional district, prioritizing underserved communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BA75D6E1714471FA179F93AD36DF335"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Seek to establish additional fab labs within the network created under paragraph (1)(C), in response to local demand, and provide guidelines for their sustainable operation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC59EF6FD60944ABA5E0B3BE38B296E2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Link fab labs into a national network and promote further expansion of fab labs across the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02535D5130E5479AB6D6074633F085CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Serve as a resource to assist diverse public and private stakeholders with the effective operation of fab labs and the training of fab lab leaders and mentors.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F6F65C98F8B496A98F9063E8CF8CAB9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Maintain a national registry of fab labs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B43ED5F5EBC4C37826BFF0A95C488A0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Provide standards and protocols for connecting fab labs regionally, nationally, and globally.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95941BAD8CCB44428012D283B36E0F89"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Assist existing fab labs in producing additional fab labs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H603BD827C83549CEB919934615A1AB3C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership and organization</header><text>Except as provided in this Act, eligibility for membership in the corporation and the rights and privileges of members shall be in accordance with the laws governing tax exempt organizations in the District of Columbia.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC94DE0CD82E14795AB394A93AD145569"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Governing body</header><paragraph id="H2F435FF5CD8D4820B5EAFCE582FE0C6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), directors, officers, and other staff of the corporation, and their powers and duties, shall be in accordance with the laws governing tax exempt organizations in the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H913EE404ECE444CEB8F93B99F432FE08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Board membership</header><subparagraph id="HECBD7467C6C740158796331868F4E784"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The board of the corporation shall be composed of not fewer than 7 members and not more than 15 members.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF53C37B6F1F1401BBE24B56DA5819DC3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Representation</header><clause id="H649CA0A69B0D4DB48222382022E155E1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The membership of the board of the corporation shall collectively represent the diversity of fab labs.</text></clause><clause id="H5791A21099574D61A4CC08992E111863"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>At a minimum, the board of the corporation shall be composed of members from geographic regions across the United States, Tribal communities, educational and research institutions, libraries, nonprofit and commercial organizations, diverse demographic groups, and the Fab Foundation.</text></clause><clause id="H8B94E58C68174C7DB7B30069180079FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Individual representation</header><text>An individual member of the board of the corporation may represent more than one board role and additional roles may be added to reflect the diversity of the fab lab ecosystem.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF24ED119F3EA4AD7BA2A30C23F7122B1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The initial board of the corporation shall be chosen, in consultation with representatives from the Fab Foundation and in accordance with subparagraph (B)(i), as follows:</text><clause id="H3A7A966294D14ADCAFDDD8123522EB24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Two shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate.</text></clause><clause id="H94328B01E4ED4E4593A4083C460CF55A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Two shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate.</text></clause><clause id="H1105E581B7D1401DB8DCB2DB23B28FE3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Two shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</text></clause><clause id="H84280F45CC1B443D8A8A1B96889C6987"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Two shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D17CA3F48A942B09AA8D31635E8DCE8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Powers</header><text>The corporation may—</text><paragraph id="H1051A6C848D84B07AC5E350EBCB299F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate the creation of a national network of local fab labs in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5E2E5B34B304849B7351E589823A847"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue guidelines for the sustainable operation of fab labs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA85DEE13413E4B63A350C3D800E48768"><enum>(3)</enum><text>issue standards and guidelines for fab labs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2F890EEF4964174B0C5638706827A33"><enum>(4)</enum><text>serve as a resource for organizations and communities seeking to create fab labs by providing information, assessing suitability, advising on the lab lifecycle, and maintaining descriptions of prospective and operating sites;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42247859F7F740B485D7F7A7DB8E666B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>accept funds from private individuals, organizations, government agencies, or other organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76F08EF9524A4E9E9CFBCA641355D9E1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>distribute funds to other organizations to establish and operate fab labs as members of the corporation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76517482C1E44AAE980D5A3F54879AA4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>facilitate communication between other organizations seeking to join the corporation with operational entities that can source and install fab labs, provide training, assist with operations, account for spending, and assess impact;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA9EE4EB1FA24097B81626BE91DAE494"><enum>(8)</enum><text>communicate the benefits available through membership in the corporation to communities and the public;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A46D4E5CBD94670A728938C2F02EA67"><enum>(9)</enum><text>facilitate and participate in synergistic programs, including workforce training, job creation, researching the enabling technology and broader impacts of such programs, and the production of civic infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F928A749A074B93B06AB923E744B7EC"><enum>(10)</enum><text>develop processes and methods to mitigate risks associated with digital fabrication;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H211CDA56096048AAA985C8726ACF6C1D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>develop and amend a constitution and bylaws for the management of its property and the regulation of its affairs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18A128E71B4F4EBD823D01D5C7E5CFC5"><enum>(12)</enum><text>choose directors, officers, trustees, managers, employees, and agents as the activities of the corporation require;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C0657E0497B4EDC929D3516848CC7D7"><enum>(13)</enum><text>make contracts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H079F3A8331C4498D9671517B716B92EE"><enum>(14)</enum><text>acquire, own, lease, encumber, and transfer property as necessary or convenient to carry out the purposes of the corporation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D81F056F7304B0BB82CA0405DF55C02"><enum>(15)</enum><text>borrow money, issue instruments of indebtedness, and secure its obligations by granting security interests in its property;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ABC52CBB73144088AF6B7787B3D61CD"><enum>(16)</enum><text>charge and collect membership dues and subscription fees; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FA4983717524C70811C6479E266EF36"><enum>(17)</enum><text>sue and be sued.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H014FCB6B37BC4876AB40C48F89F35B60"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exclusive right to name, term, seals, emblems, and badges</header><text>The corporation and its participating digital fabrication labs have the exclusive right to use—</text><paragraph id="H94286878732D47F89A7B179E51EF0EF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name <quote>National Fab Lab Network</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2568EFBD1AC5408085E755A32A4C502B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any seals, emblems, and badges the corporation adopts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00560DF2D13B4BD0B449788CB7526427"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><paragraph id="HF9A4D24CFE9642308360471D8F9CAB35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Stock and dividends</header><text>The corporation may not issue securities of any kind or declare or pay a dividend.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE4C4DEA50894591BDF615B49ADAA8AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution of income or assets</header><text>The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a director, officer, or member during the life of the corporation under this Act. This paragraph does not prevent the payment of reasonable compensation to an officer or reimbursement for actual necessary expenses in amounts approved by the board of the corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H002F2CAA1BDF461CBBAF13A44700E583"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Loans</header><text>The corporation may not make a loan to a director, officer, or employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F8C70A5B0C340FD966707F34DDE2989"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Claim of governmental approval or authority</header><text>The corporation may not claim congressional approval or the authority of the United States Government for any of its activities, but may recognize establishment of the corporation pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H835DF553F574420B9BC362BD57D638FC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Records and inspection</header><paragraph id="H8091DE08EEDA44358F02687306EEDF82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The corporation shall keep—</text><subparagraph id="H966BD93C0C10425BBE2AA56EA7990E08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>correct and complete records of account;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8BEABE439654058B367D14184941C29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>minutes of the proceedings of its members, the board of the corporation, and committees having any of the authority of the board; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A92298F41EE419E8456C90FA7A2EB5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at its principal office, a record of the names and addresses of its members entitled to vote.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A8FE828D43344DF89BC53AC83B12EBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inspections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member entitled to vote, or an agent or attorney of the member, may inspect the records of the corporation for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57BAFD7F89884257A16070ABE3EAA743"> <enum>(j)</enum> <header>Annual report</header> <text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the corporation shall submit to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives</committee-name> a report on the activities of the corporation during the prior fiscal year.</text>
            </subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

