<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL26640-K1G-FW-3W4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4941 IS: Modernizing Opioid Treatment Access Act 2.0 of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4941</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To expand access to methadone through alternative care models using pharmacies.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing Opioid Treatment Access Act 2.0 of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id617f28dd03604feb9f63dee447a36749"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of methadone for opioid use disorder through prescribing and pharmacies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303(h) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idb0ca27a5600545a0979abd963e801e52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="idd3ca6203969a45f2ae236ce395caf5fd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>(i)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id857dc1f3cdde470bb0d144c1cbc184eb" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>(ii)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f3905ba3ba448f1802b1ca7c5497e79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) as subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id010d370875cd472ab9d5d1fc2d3ddc90"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(h) Practitioners</quote> and inserting <quote>(h)(1) Practitioners</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e8bc44da1374909b0893ca29e1b2b1a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcf146705f7f443c0bab5d88892f55163"><paragraph id="idb02a4d02548849f58d9fb1df0972e20d" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id2d286b8c03144f2b903a619bf2c0f3d3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The requirements of paragraph (1) applicable to methadone medication for opioid use disorder are waived, and the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, shall separately register practitioners described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph to prescribe methadone for opioid use disorder to be dispensed through a pharmacy to individuals for their own supervised or unsupervised use.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62137296950b4a0aa2f62bc7d457e025" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Practitioners described in this subparagraph are persons who—</text><clause id="id80b4ecd0f8434e088ada1f48387f2307"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are licensed, registered, or otherwise permitted, by the United States or the jurisdiction in which they practice, to prescribe controlled substances in the course of professional practice; and</text></clause><clause id="idcd474a66954b4790bb45d12660ea0ca2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf24f51883aa44fa9b1c4d75de72beb30"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">addiction medicine physicians or addiction psychiatrists who hold a subspecialty board certification in addiction medicine from the American Board of Preventive Medicine, a board certification in addiction medicine from the American Board of Addiction Medicine, a subspecialty board certification in addiction psychiatry from the American Board of Psychiatry and Neurology, or a subspecialty board certification in addiction medicine from the American Osteopathic Association; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd067afda5fa7477da6eb784d18fa6e38"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise determined by the Secretary, under standards established by the Secretary, to be qualified to prescribe methadone for opioid use disorder.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03a4d4af50b64fbaad2488cec9c1a582" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The prescribing of methadone pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be—</text><clause id="ida17b2d13b9c448cfb0d7bf1d7f0d6ae0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exclusively by electronic prescribing and dispensed to the individual treated pursuant to subparagraph (A);</text></clause><clause id="id90a74be6e61e40deaf103a85dba698f4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in compliance with applicable Federal and State law respecting the quantities of methadone for opioid use disorder that may be dispensed to individuals pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="idbdd8ea6246904553bd5921c0debf105d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for a liquid or dispersible tablet formulation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idccd579835d874f1990539f04e0a2ff5d" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The dispensing of methadone to an individual pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be in addition to the other care that the individual continues to have access to through an opioid use disorder treatment program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9afdacc993b5447b94d0e62056a2bc1f" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Practitioners registered pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="idefa6c6f8768349e59e4de2ddb654bacf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure and document, with respect to each individual treated pursuant to subparagraph (A), informed consent to treatment; and</text></clause><clause id="idae89c596033f4dab8baa5d6d9735f78e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include in such informed consent, specific informed consent regarding differences in confidentiality protections applicable when dispensing through an opioid treatment program versus dispensing through a pharmacy pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id073e14db6d084444aadef8b9068b105d" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>At the request of a State, the Attorney General shall—</text><clause id="id7b8a6a73b7bd481488c391ae50657780"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cease registering persons in the State pursuant to subparagraph (A);</text></clause><clause id="id0ad286f505094329893a57e310cff2f1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>revoke any such registration in effect for a person in the State pursuant to section 304; and</text></clause><clause id="id30827bb481514bce907f06705399478c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>deny any pending application for such registration from a practitioner in the State pursuant to section 304.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a599d22be604fef93c740ec4738d7a6" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Maintenance treatment or detoxification treatment provided pursuant to subparagraph (A) may be provided through the practice of telemedicine.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf5b3f7fe9d60402984268cfc0cdad186"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A pharmacy shall not be required to obtain a separate registration to dispense methadone medication for opioid use disorder to an individual who has been prescribed that medication by a practitioner registered pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id36bcd45256ea40abb49849ac1aafbac5" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, and annually thereafter, the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration shall submit to Congress a report that includes, for the reporting period—</text><subparagraph id="id7786ba5a61ba4c22a640ba1cc8894cc7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of practitioners registered pursuant to paragraph (2)(A) in each State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4017bfd9ae0b4714a6aa493d23f4f88b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of States for which the Attorney General received a request pursuant to paragraph (2)(F);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf75ce26c096244aebce8f93d5a999859"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of revocations or suspensions of registration issued pursuant to section 304, based on violations related to the prescribing of methadone for opioid use disorder by practitioners who are registered pursuant to paragraph (2)(A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6ba368c95384dbdbf3883b53239937e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of pharmacies that ordered methadone in liquid or dispersible tablet formulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id5950daab9e85412dbfd0e7acf3f69339"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

