<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAF15E97720304CB0BDBF41FB1A22E19F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7403 IH: No Foreign NIL Funds Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7403</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260205">February 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit foreign investment in relation to name, image, and likeness agreements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFA1A6AE0DFFD417BA0CB2D59D8A2C858" style="OLC"><section id="H13A77335459A4954A5A20259F038401B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Foreign NIL Funds Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBD4C078B01244C598DD66C50B0EF9349"><enum>2.</enum><header>Foreign investment in NIL agreements</header><subsection id="HB08EC9D4C6FB4807A3B334E2E2A019AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibited compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any national or entity of a foreign country may not provide, regardless of value, a covered entity with a benefit or a contribution (monetary or in-kind) in relation to a name, image, and likeness agreement.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBC054B964A8442DBA4CC9DD8087AFE07"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transparency requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any covered entity solicited by an entity under subsection (a) in relation to a name, image, and likeness agreement shall document with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Education such solicitation attempts.</text></subsection><subsection id="HECCB8AFED30540AFB10619957CFCD3CC"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Authority To investigate institutions</header> <paragraph id="H3D806D156861452C9712C9C16EC86C15"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Education, shall investigate suspected violations of subsections (a) and (b) by institutions of higher education.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H024ED9D46A014226AEDC30FAD49144FC">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Notice; appeal</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Education, determines that an institution of higher education is in violation of the requirements of subsection (a) or (b)—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HF7751612B4FC4140A99F6E31932BBF2B">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the Attorney General shall notify the institution of such determination not later than 30 days after such determination is made; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7217535B7D644677AD9D407C43E7CAF0">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the institution may appeal such determination by filing an appeal with the Office of Hearings and Appeals of the Department of Education.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1C2B9054722E40F585F8A68ECC3E395F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Program participation agreement</header><text>Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF28B229D941A48ACB2830DAEFA4DB1C4"><paragraph id="H6B82A3FD57DA4C85AEA8088EA3AB04F7"><enum>(30)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0B14065D8F854A6A8E5EA9AE3F418EAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution will comply with the requirements of the No Foreign NIL Funds Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63215A41A8FF4FD5BD1F7FF787EA4984" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution certifies that the institution has in effect a policy to—</text><clause id="HAED10D72D48F456F9A2CB63C73C2CB69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prohibit student athletes who violate the requirements of the No Foreign NIL Funds Act from participating in intercollegiate athletics at the institution for a 1-year period;</text></clause><clause id="H0805BDCF6A7A45EE96794A15E0491B06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify students who have committed to participate in a varsity sports team of the requirements of such Act and of the prohibition described in clause (i); and</text></clause><clause id="H0850BB1B4C274F999A669536066BBE98"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">annually notify student athletes of the requirements of such Act and of the prohibition described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF0B284F971A44B78DD8E2BF16A0E886" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In the case of an institution described in subparagraph (D), the institution will—</text><clause id="H73F80D2FC85B4140AC80BA96E090E5B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be ineligible to participate in the programs authorized by this title; and</text></clause><clause id="H1BD151CB879E44B59E1168BBD245D052"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in order to regain eligibility to participate in such programs, submit to the Attorney General and the Secretary of Education a report detailing compliance with all the requirements of such Act, including the divestment of any prohibited funds.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42D119931E1445AEA5ECC94878B47E1D" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution described in this subparagraph is an institution that—</text><clause id="H60A39037103B4E3491BE616EC2611163"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, determines to be in violation of section 2 of the No Foreign NIL Funds Act pursuant to section 2(c) of such Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H65D9775428DD4435A922C2761C6C600C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an institution that appealed such determination pursuant to section 2(c)(2)(B) of such Act, was unsuccessful in appealing such determination.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4FCD2AABF74A4ED785DB332834BF2D39"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Penalties for covered entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered entity who commits a violation of this section shall be subject to the penalties imposed under subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE8172624C3A848AF9D7CCC8691EF850C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on Certain State-Controlled Investments in Collegiate Athletics Revenue Streams</header><subsection id="H7DBB6590264E4875BBCFCB70BAE77393"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No institution of higher education, athletic conference, media rights distributor, or bowl or post-season football organization may—</text><paragraph id="H013E475EC45C4CC08787E0039A01249B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enter into, renew, or maintain any contract, partnership, joint venture, naming-rights agreement, sponsorship, or media-rights arrangement that involves direct or indirect financing, ownership, or material participation by a foreign country; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C4730FD98BC4C4A8A83B2D4CD2F9A6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>engage in covered activities with a foreign country.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H377606B6C45240D6A6A91A44FA52391D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person subject to subsection (a) shall annually disclose all contracts and ownership information for any entity of a foreign country that provides such person with financial consideration for covered activities to the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, and the Secretary of Education.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB49A9BF0BADA4341AF4569F5E6A1AADE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who commits a violation of this section shall be subject to the penalties imposed under section 206(b) of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1B90225FD66C44709EA06E491677D939"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HD428E5636DCF48188DB4ACA0EA9D7DD5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Athletic conference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>athletic conference</term> means any organization that is not an athletic association and that—</text><subparagraph id="HF1DE9011DDE3475DA96F6C90239D2935"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has 2 or more institutions of higher education as members; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35840F37CD8340AF807A71518FC79346"><enum>(B)</enum><text>arranges championships for college athletic competition or sets rules for college athletic competition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4411634DFC044AA69658798302EDEE82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bowl or Post-season Football Organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>bowl or post-season football organization</term> means any legal entity, association, partnership, or other organization that contracts with one or more institutions of higher education or athletic conferences for the purpose of administering, organizing, producing, promoting, or broadcasting post-season intercollegiate football competitions recognized by the National Collegiate Athletic Association or its successor, including the College Football Playoff.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E71F3304BA2440D81D45139A8E67B59"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered activities</term> means any activity generating or affecting revenue in intercollegiate athletics in relation to the National Collegiate Athletic Association Division I men’s or women’s athletic programs, including—</text><subparagraph id="H9A0EE5C4C5274E0BB18BEE2F2F764816"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the naming rights to conferences, post-season events, or athletic facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3894DBEE834F4A0498DDD381F4FA4C6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sale or licensing of broadcast or streaming media rights;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB32A2E3E10444D69E93AE70FE961090"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a conference-wide or institutional sponsorship agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26142F2E551F4101B8F1C145E4AF0D68"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a joint venture or capital investment related to athletic media, data, or a content platform; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD528A340856A404AA864B126C98BAFFA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amateur athletic competition, contest, tournament, or match (both competitive or exhibition).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7884D16144CF4D4EA12619814E8FDD91"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H73F4E0ADCA7D475FB2622E6D4DE0946D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC03716A8781540709EABF9F869A892C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A student athlete.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6861E4E518340F29E4D627092496A84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An organization, collective, booster group, agent, or any other entity that solicits, receives, or manages funds on behalf of, in affiliation with, or under the direction of an institution of higher education (including an athletic department or varsity sports team of such institution) for the purpose of funding, or creating or identifying opportunities relating to, name, image, and likeness agreements for the student athletes of such institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BE7FAC975F14412B422F98E602A2B56"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Entity of a foreign country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>entity of a foreign country</term> means a corporation, partnership, association, or organization—</text><subparagraph id="H43AFFF1993AA435F803AD22FD2930ADE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supervised, directed, owned, controlled, financed, or subsidized, in whole or in part, by a foreign country; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF6314CF5A3748F3849BDC2C12B08EC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not organized under or created by the laws of the United States or of any State or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and does not have its principal place of business within the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70FB82DA47274BA78DB055AA271628B9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Foreign country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foreign country</quote> means any country except the following:</text><subparagraph id="HE509B0B7FDF94CD78FFBE59754DDA1C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A country that is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EE7EBB7DAB34D42BAA7B872E3175695"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Australia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41839BFAB3FE487BB7CA57D183ABA75A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>New Zealand.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E99DB8616144F1EB36712CE89BCBB2D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Ireland.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA49A79E907AB46D9A064D48C40B44BCD"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1F61A88A0C8414DADDABFBB64F6A4B7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Media Rights Distributor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>media rights distributor</term> means any entity, including a broadcast network, cable network, streaming service, digital platform, satellite service, or other distributor, that acquires, licenses, sublicenses, or otherwise controls rights to transmit, stream, broadcast, exhibit, or publicly distribute college athletic competitions or related content.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7A49B7D54B6478DA1C778A1C0C5AAF9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Name, image, and likeness agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>name, image, and likeness agreement</term> means a contract or similar agreement under which a student athlete licenses or authorizes, or a contract or similar agreement that otherwise is in relation to, the commercial use of the name, image, or likeness of the student athlete.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4D920C37F504F05851482261FBF06BB"><enum>(10)</enum><header>National of a foreign country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>national of a foreign country</term> means any individual who is a citizen of a foreign country but is not a citizen of or alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States of America.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8ABA5623D26C4A438E7020F0019AED5B"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Student athlete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>student athlete</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H9EF59902C0E34F1D933AFA06CA208779"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is enrolled at an institution of higher education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61184416784F4E7E8CD905E4B91BC06F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>participates in a varsity sports team of such institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5488E92CE8544CEEAE2004912C7F4DAD"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Varsity sports team</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>varsity sports team</term> means an entity composed of an individual or group of individuals enrolled at an institution of higher education that is organized by such institution for the purpose of participation in intercollegiate athletic competitions.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

