<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE2BC191E0A3647FE8D2421678D696E67" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6123 IH: Promoting Diplomacy with Australia Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6123</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Assistant Secretary of State for East Asia and Pacific Affairs to report on the current capacity and ability of the United States Mission in Australia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H93996A2900254B209A3438D59D891189" style="OLC"><section id="H8CAE29FDF7D14CDF82FAEF1F686DB71B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Diplomacy with Australia Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7050167825854E26ACE68E5DD9AE1D8A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on United States mission in Australia</header><subsection id="H9D0F55ABD32D48ED8055E782610EDFF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of State for East Asia and Pacific Affairs shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the current capacity and ability of the United States Mission in Australia, including through the International Cooperative Administrative Support Services system, to manage and provide sufficient administrative and operational support to all United States government personnel under the authority of the head of the United States Mission in Australia as chief of mission.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9663A4270E5A41A1B7F1EC074C46C326"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall also include the following:</text><paragraph id="H3EABE17BC279425C82121DDADCCE4E4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Details regarding increases in staffing and operations for planned mission growth from 2025 to 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD839694207054A7481F05DD4C3079041"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Details regarding the interagency’s growth in Australia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8510C3D691EE498F95C9BA35668B2610"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Details regarding the additional administrative and operational support systems necessary to meet the growth trajectories described pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H974EEB0CFB3044379C1B1DF681E77A15"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An analysis of resource gaps that could undermine mission capacity and United States objectives, including advancing the United States-Australia alliance and AUKUS security partnership.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CABC14AC4A54A26AA8FC275BA4BCB36"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A recommendation for additional facilities, staffing, and resources needed to execute on critical mission growth.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H296B0E4D6E4842BA81E9209C21716503"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An analysis of the additional funding required to meet the recommendations described in paragraph (5).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51237CC7D69545A890247E04F0925147"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form and may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

