<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA863AA4803FA48E986B536F29E82302A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9421 IH: Ban Abortion by Mail Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9421</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit a REMS-certified provider from prescribing mifepristone without an in-person visit and a medical license in the State in which the patient resides, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9227865E3B9D4AD38F38255B2FB59122" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE90C71679B7A464F9490C3B1B731BC74" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ban Abortion by Mail Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H90BD54324F4B40C2AE19C848B9C227AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD30D949629864EAA97B13E2623D63675"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mifepristone can only be prescribed by a health care provider certified under the Mifepristone Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategies (REMS) Program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H91C194A33FC1447A91C398E0C4F367B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Medical experts have advised that patients should be closely observed for signs and symptoms of adverse effects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9755FF1E2B174AFAA4F05F7841CE1124"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The purpose of Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategies (REMS) is to ensure the benefits of a drug outweigh its risks, especially for drugs with serious safety concerns.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H314DEDD2672B40C79D2F97A55A076068"><enum>3.</enum><header>Health care provider REMS-certified status</header> 
<subsection id="H291FC89E0023453B8AE7F1B7EA34FC53">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In-Person visit required</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any REMS-certified provider that knowingly prescribes, dispenses, or administers mifepristone or any other abortion drug without an in-person visit with the patient for whom such drug is prescribed shall lose REMS-certified status, with respect to such drug, for a period of not less than 2 years.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0410D1DE41014E2F80DB10EAAA62B355"><enum>(b)</enum><header>License in patient’s State required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any REMS-certified provider that knowingly prescribes, dispenses, or administers mifepristone or any other abortion drug to a patient residing in a State where the provider does not have a medical license shall lose REMS-certified status, with respect to such drug, for a period of not less than 2 years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAD964CEAAA9E45E7A36469A53AF8A8CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, on an annual basis, submit to Congress a report listing each REMS-certified provider who has lost REMS-certified status due to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H53C45F6349884ED5888A3DA4264A52A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a violation of this section; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H785477DE2FAD4F76A307631E586A030D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improper or unsafe prescribing of mifepristone or any other abortion drug.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD073467E3D394CC9AE07B8BF9D9DA061"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H9753E27BF1FF46F7B70B1B97A742436C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abortion drug</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>abortion drug</term> means any drug, substance, or combination of drugs or substances that is intended for use or that is in fact used (irrespective of how the product is labeled) to intentionally kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant, or to intentionally terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD01A95CABD4E48D69AE6F5F878F3DBBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to produce a live birth;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3249A340B3AD4A699807CA755F7D47FF"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>to remove a dead unborn child; or</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFF8720D9D4884EFF841D1A5DA99EEEDB">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>to treat an ectopic pregnancy.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H480238EC312A4CAF8D2C4C118F45E740"><enum>(2)</enum><header>REMS-certified status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>REMS-certified status</term> means, with respect to mifepristone or any other abortion drug, the certification of a REMS-certified provider by the Secretary to dispense such drug pursuant to a risk evaluation and mitigation strategy under section 505–1 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355-1">21 U.S.C. 355–1</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9DAF80066944E43BAD226C9AD88ED38"><enum>(3)</enum><header>REMS-certified provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>REMS-certified provider</term> means a health care professional who has successfully completed the FDA’s Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategy (REMS) certification program for prescribing mifepristone.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D7CBD98BE52405B8CD4D946A1FA7833"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

