<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEF3414D15767454A81837AAA0BE668AB" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1136 IH: Supporting the goals and ideals of “Long COVID Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1136</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the goals and ideals of <quote>Long COVID Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas long COVID is a serious illness that can affect the functions of multiple organs in an individual and can last for months and years after an individual first contracts COVID-19;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas over 400,000,000 individuals worldwide have been impacted by long COVID;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas incidence of long COVID remain high, even among vaccinated populations and with more recent variant strains;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas each additional COVID infection contracted by an individual increases the risk that the individual will experience long COVID, even among those individuals who are fully vaccinated;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas long COVID patients experience poor quality of life, extreme fatigue, and functional limitations;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas individuals with long COVID are limited in their ability to work;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the burden of long COVID is projected to cost the United States economy $3,700,000,000,000 over a 5-year period due to reduced quality of life, increased medical spending, and billions of work hours lost;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas long COVID disproportionately impacts women and Hispanic/Latine, Black, transgender, and disabled individuals;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there is currently no specific treatment for long COVID; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the month of March has been recognized as <quote>Long COVID Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H269F74F619844CB29C8DA3032A74DD15"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA6C7BBA394324BA79E51C009A4DA9F8B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4A91A54D16DD45269DFA46C3DCA5E6ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the goals and ideals of <quote>Long COVID Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80DB78FF148043A3990685FCFC0E756F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of bringing awareness to the challenges of living with long COVID; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87F1CC1F284E44FFA07FEB4801988934"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expresses support for more medical research on the causes of and treatments for long COVID.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

