<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9DEC26EDE9DE480BB4377DB2796F2979" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9404 IH: VA Home Loan Navigator Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9404</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide support services to veterans in navigating housing loan benefits administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0C1CE538C6604C069CF169003AC2C977" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCB35BA300BE24DF581A7B982AF6FCAF3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Home Loan Navigator Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEAF426B2FB1D41AFA622A4F5C7CE11C5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Borrower support services for housing loans administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="H3ECA34E92860449685A51647DE3DFBEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">Chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3737">section 3737</external-xref> the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HF815B6A895B946ABA3794D061F3BA512" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H5872E45DFF9341C8912F9085D83862B3"><enum>3738.</enum><header>Borrower support services for housing loans</header> 
<subsection id="H0BB4E72DBF95489CA8C581B132AE9CF2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall provide services described in subsection (b) to veteran borrowers and other eligible borrowers to assist such borrowers in navigating the housing loan benefits under this chapter.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5A8EB8931BAF46D59EB295E6015266FF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorized services</header><text>The services described in this subsection include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCD9822102FE647E9A518616CD616463C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>education regarding the housing loan benefits under this chapter;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83414357EFE54BDC9087923CA9716887"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assistance obtaining or resolving issues relating to a certificate of eligibility for such benefits;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAA871F4893F44D7B64E27C74B6E03FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>counseling regarding the origination, refinancing, and closing processes for housing loans;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H548ADDF7E3694EEAB8B90016359B1AF6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>guidance regarding appraisal requirements, property standards, and loan documentation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2229E2B3484A4FC3A49DEE0F4E3583A4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assistance navigating loan servicing matters;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B535B9AE27E4EF1A6FDF28929FDF493"><enum>(6)</enum><text>counseling relating to loss mitigation options and foreclosure prevention;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H182FE93A9C384149B3259267A5690AF8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>coordination between borrowers, mortgage servicers, and the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE17ABF3D596A4EABABE5956A958F9954"><enum>(8)</enum><text>education regarding costs, fees, and financial obligations associated with housing, including commissions of brokers.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE233C85361614435AC32E353338F340E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Voluntary; no cost</header><text>Receipt of services described in subsection (b) shall be provided only to borrowers who choose to receive them and shall be provided at no cost to the borrower.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA080325418A440B3BA649E8127C5B626"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of entities designated by the Secretary</header> <paragraph id="H4ECA1976D8A34C908D9BAD595C936556" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary may provide the services described in subsection (b) through entities designated by the Secretary under subsection (e) and may enter into contracts or other agreements with such organizations to provide such services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE148E6B5640E4522B0F8A2EA54C52A52" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In providing such services, an entity so designated—</text> <subparagraph id="H4482F962B5A149F3AE4DB1574946E596"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall act solely as an independent, neutral intermediary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81EFD86D0AD942809495DD0C6286F59C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may not act as an agent of, or on behalf of, any mortgage lender, servicer, or real estate professional.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H7C1FB3DC65D949058D39CA8488D1E28F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Designation of entities</header> <paragraph id="HA256D013DB87455FA6C23165003B00C2" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary may designate an entity under this subsection only if the entity—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9BCD8737EEB541AAB29B74B5734C07B3" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is approved by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development as a housing counseling agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6136EDAAABC4B6A894710634FC26D4A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a nonprofit organization with a primary mission of serving veterans, members of the United States Armed Forces, or military families;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H38BDE67C9B5B4F08B76523D17BD64ECC" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrates expertise in Department of Veteran Affairs home loan benefits;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13AAD0DEA6354012B09BFF8D291545A0" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>demonstrates expertise in housing counseling, financial literacy, foreclosure prevention, rental guidance, and housing issues affecting the military and veteran community; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCCFCA18F90324417BBDF971D529D3997" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>demonstrates the capacity to provide services on a multi-State or national basis;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A5B93D4CB1E4C908DFD35B2CEB936C3" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>demonstrates the capacity to develop, administer, and oversee training, certification, and performance standards for the individual counselors providing services under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CA083B9B00A446CB2205BAA72F5F341" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In selecting entities for designation under this subsection, the Secretary shall prioritize entities with demonstrated experience delivering housing counseling and financial literacy services to the military-connected community.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7279829498474B25B074DF88FD72064D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Certification of individual counselors</header> <paragraph id="HCB5DB75E262D4CB091D18F54C6A345A3" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, certify individuals as counselors authorized to provide services under this section. In doing so, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H210FC2E26DC74F388C2FC2753CEBC559" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specify the requirements that the individual must meet for initial certification and recertification, including requirements relating to continuing education and ongoing training; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H435711C7A01C48EDAA90453546766181" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require such an individual to be recertified not less frequently than every three years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H770FAB0A4F394CE98677FC3618756AE6" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary may enter into contracts or other agreements with nonprofit organizations to carry out the activities under this subsection.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HB77B72499F864B929B40C7F773398434"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Independence of services</header> <paragraph id="HC6A2434D4D6B4C8AB2D9A2D2240490B9" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity providing services under this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAF41DD0E7145430EB4037BD9D552E089" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall ensure that such services are operationally and financially independent from mortgage origination, servicing, and real estate brokerage activities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BBBFF85D5E74D45BEF1F0A900A24C48" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not refer or direct any borrower receiving such services to any entity affiliated with or related to the entity providing such services. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H01669BFA2EEA435EB59CD8DF3BC48715" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) does not prohibit an entity that provides services under this section from maintaining separate lines of business, including affiliated entities engaged in mortgage or real estate activities, as long as the entity has implemented firewalls or other controls as the Secretary considers appropriate and all other requirements of this section are met.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H7790A530E08C4A0D9EE51D90ADC1D9C3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Conflict-of-interest protections</header> <paragraph id="H28C2F4632788491D812AD7E87145F59C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An entity designated under subsection (e), and any employee, officer, or contractor of such an entity, shall not—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2DEE663600EC4F16AB34C09311D180C8" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receive any compensation, referral fee, or other remuneration, directly or indirectly, from—</text> <clause id="H6B6D4E2CEB1747B0B0F77C8874B259DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a mortgage lender or mortgage servicer;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6A8F5DE8C12B4457BD975269A0F042A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a real estate broker or agent; or</text></clause> <clause id="HF7607705051F4064B3B1EBE0F2EC26C8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any entity providing loan modification, refinancing, or foreclosure-related services;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAD96969D6094BFEB50F5C7C81CE44F4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">refer a borrower to any specific commercial provider in exchange for anything of value; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60160A73B6C64222820450A1E61654E1" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engage in any activity that compromises the independence of the services provided under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H311FB0F221CD4D2995668F6DD55D1D75" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each entity designated under subsection (e) shall provide clear and timely disclosure to borrowers and to the Secretary of any actual or potential conflicts of interest, including any affiliated business relationships.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF23484637D64CA1B8C5AB2D5C12CC3F" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures to ensure services under this section are provided in a manner that preserves borrower choice, ensures full transparency, and complies with applicable Federal consumer protection laws.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H64BC04C5972246B497D74C9182F830D5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Coordination with Housing and Urban Development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall carry out the activities under this section in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and in a manner that makes effective use of the housing counseling activities of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, including the certification, training, and reporting activities of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, subject to any changes that the Secretary considers appropriate to account for the authorities, missions, and operations of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1D4B778B4B8B41F3913198D59DBB3012"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4AC4836693C74770BC6FD8AA6DFA2EE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>suspend or revoke the designation of any entity, or the certification of any individual, under this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA21841B5B9144446A608C20CDEED0ACD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>refer cases of fraud, abuse, or unlawful activity to the Attorney General.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A0B878B96674BA08D8E071D5A2D9F22"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and on annual basis for each of the next four years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the program under this section. The report shall evaluate the effectiveness of the program with respect to—</text> <paragraph id="H98E1CD285B5B4FA4B1CC9D81219E2FD1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>borrower satisfaction;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCB9657922D141FDB64D219F649E79BC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>utilization of housing loan benefits;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F3F6F69B3A044518D8E28C54087F1EA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>foreclosure prevention outcomes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3911382B628642ABAF32512471BABA6A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>loss mitigation completion rates;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63AF21C8179A4840B01D0BFB42D5F53C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>redefault rates following loss mitigation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4CAB5B570D048FAB7EF9A608D710D48" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>cost-effectiveness of services provided.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H025771145FAE432B85D2F6FC6F47BBF9" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3737">section 3737</external-xref> the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H99F404406F9949DBAB382D2DEA0C45D1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">3738. Borrower support services for housing loans.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

