<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H55A01B83DF384324BA39DBD49E76D182" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7636 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish the individual tariff refund credit.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7636</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish the individual tariff refund credit.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAA9C7FB2914641D99B2CBC8EA7E30E5C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5E317A5B2D01446DA7995AA626F591D5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Individual tariff refund credit</header> 
<subsection id="HC484F93FFE3346A9AAB56C4F65985D30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter B of chapter 65 of subtitle F of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H66BF42681C2446FD862BFACE8B08BDD4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HE2C8A0FD9795469C91CFFB4B76F10584"><enum>6436.</enum><header>Individual tariff refund credit</header></section> <subsection id="H0325C9E85CA84E50945300F9E768E490"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible individual, there shall be allowed a credit against the tax imposed by subtitle A for the covered taxable year in an amount equal to the applicable tariff refund amount.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43D610810987444697AB241F7E7E6FE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of credit</header><text>The credit allowed by subsection (a) shall be treated as allowed by subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7859A37AAB4A457EBEE8F6EA2EAA348E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>eligible individual</quote> means any individual who, on the date on which any covered court order is issued, is an individual other than—</text> 
<paragraph id="H314BE45510BB48E08AB3099F0D5BF03D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any nonresident alien individual,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72CD9E5C5E5D4DBDA9D7BA691872113B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any individual with respect to whom a deduction under section 151 is allowable to another taxpayer for a taxable year beginning in the calendar year in which the individual's taxable year begins, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10F3A7E98408451CB4C2096DD65337AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an estate or trust.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE04724EA3A1542068E8A6004D39D491F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Covered taxable year</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>covered taxable year</quote> means, with respect to an individual, the most recent taxable year of such individual ending before the date on which a covered court order is issued.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEAA70849D0184A5995C893514A0E2DBB" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covered court order</header> 
<paragraph id="H4B4731EB51634919A75988A0FB697151" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>covered court order</quote> means a final court order which requires the Federal Government to repay tariff revenues collected pursuant to an unlawfully imposed tariff.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF6E0E64B9EA4655AE43F85E199C89FB" commented="no"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Unlawful tariff</header> <text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <quote>unlawful tariff</quote> means a tariff imposed unlawfully after January 20, 2025, and before the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
                        </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD5553B9738B44399BE9AB803E8200CB1" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Covered tariff revenues</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>covered tariff revenues</quote> means the aggregate amount of tariff revenues required to be repaid by the Federal Government pursuant to a covered court order.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1F1CA58BD91242F18BB196A3FF3A3AEC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Applicable tariff refund amount</header> <paragraph id="H9BCB00DF10B04CC0BD0719B01B7CA6B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the term <quote>applicable tariff refund amount</quote> means, with respect to any individual, an amount equal to—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="H777125ADA6D84566B8D3B212D6C68E49">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the individual tariff refund amount, multiplied by</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F21A0F851774A8EB6085487D57A2779"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of individuals in such individual’s household.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB139FA9FDAB45B8A253F8F8E206E404"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Household</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the number of individuals in an individual’s household for any taxable year is equal to the sum of—</text> <subparagraph id="HC9902D21ADD14EF6A2168C6D5E8DE2DC"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>1 (2 in the case of a joint return), plus</text>
                            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4FA9C6E53FDF44F2A4F0FE0907E9EE59"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of dependents of the individual for such taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99FE2C16472D4A34AD44BA3920D97226"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Individual tariff refund amount</header><text>The term <quote>tariff refund amount</quote> means the amount that the Secretary determines is equal to the quotient of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H541712E496214FB1AE7907EE1B7E4022">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the aggregate amount of covered tariff revenues, divided by</text>
                            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CC5EA71E717438098CF045530057B38"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate number of individuals in the households of eligible individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9188C7E6FA8D45779A7D7CC2B67CCB34" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Coordination with advance refund of credit</header> <paragraph id="HCEB99E834D5A437E913BA02CA1DDBD4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reduction of refundable credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the credit which would (but for this paragraph) be allowable under <internal-xref idref="HAA9C7FB2914641D99B2CBC8EA7E30E5C" legis-path="6436.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the aggregate refunds and credits made or allowed to the individual (or, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any dependent of the individual) under <internal-xref idref="HAA9C7FB2914641D99B2CBC8EA7E30E5C" legis-path="6436.(g)">subsection (i)</internal-xref>. Any failure to so reduce the credit shall be treated as arising out of a mathematical or clerical error and assessed according to section 6213(b)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F940ECFF77E45C3A8E4E917D2515BE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Joint returns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, in the case of a refund or credit made or allowed under <internal-xref idref="HAA9C7FB2914641D99B2CBC8EA7E30E5C" legis-path="6436.(g)">subsection (i)</internal-xref> with respect to a joint return, half of such refund or credit shall be treated as having been made or allowed to each individual filing such return.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF54E214526BD40999A480CA8A8E34023"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Advanced payment</header> <paragraph id="H9DE5E22D94064B438A9967875ECE4B46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible individual shall be treated as having made a payment against the tax imposed by chapter 1 for the covered taxable year in an amount equal to the amount of the credit allowed to such individual under subsection (a) for such covered taxable year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0FA2EA5AF79C41A48CB23228A0E45727"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing of payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, subject to the provisions of this title, refund or credit any overpayment attributable to this subsection as rapidly as possible.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6AAD4DD27BD3475C96F894BD11EA12B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No interest shall be allowed on any overpayments attributable to this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17922A7250774FD1B423230DD81C1379"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice to taxpayer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 days after the date on which the Secretary distributed any payment to an eligible individual pursuant to this subsection, notice shall be sent by mail to such individual’s last known address. Such notice shall indicate the method by which such payment was made, the amount of such payment, and a phone number for the appropriate point of contact at the Internal Revenue Service to report any failure to receive such payment.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H65549D53925F441BA5A68B584F6304B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of deficiency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6211(b)(4)(A) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and 6433</quote> and inserting <quote>6433, and 6436</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H232DBF55A7A64D2E8A76938860F48D04" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of certain possessions</header> 
<paragraph id="H4BAAFDF0ADF44EA0B454D060560878AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments to possessions with mirror code tax systems</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to each possession of the United States which has a mirror code tax system amounts equal to the loss (if any) to that possession by reason of the amendments made by this section. Such amounts shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury based on information provided by the government of the respective possession.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA93DD46A93E342E59F35A6EE03DB893C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payments to other possessions</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to each possession of the United States which does not have a mirror code tax system amounts estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury as being equal to the aggregate benefits (if any) that would have been provided to residents of such possession by reason of the amendments made by this section if a mirror code tax system had been in effect in such possession. The preceding sentence shall not apply unless the respective possession has a plan, which has been approved by the Secretary of the Treasury, under which such possession will promptly distribute such payments to its residents.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E8E9A96E5AD4FD9823965474D827499"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusion of administrative expenses</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to each possession of the United States to which the Secretary makes a payment under paragraph (1) or (2) an amount equal to the lesser of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD0A9297487524D3D8ECDC7D707A53309"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the increase (if any) of the administrative expenses of such possession—</text> 
<clause id="H9E3B2346E5D54C4B8992DB3DBFFC38F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a possession described in <internal-xref idref="H4BAAFDF0ADF44EA0B454D060560878AB" legis-path="2.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, by reason of the amendments made by this section, and</text></clause> <clause id="HB8ACC09D4D894509A660599D17CDDDDE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a possession described in <internal-xref idref="HA93DD46A93E342E59F35A6EE03DB893C" legis-path="2.(b)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>, by reason of carrying out the plan described in such paragraph, or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB2286C2D97D4BA38ED0B4F5409D5CCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$500,000 ($10,000,000 in the case of Puerto Rico).</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The amount described in subparagraph (A) shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury based on information provided by the government of the respective possession.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C3C7D7C529C4E4AA45BDDCCFF57D0CC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination with credit allowed against united states income taxes</header><text>No credit shall be allowed against United States income taxes under section 6436 of such Code (as added by this section), nor shall any credit or refund be made or allowed under subsection (i) of such section, to any person—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4112690F202B458B8851484B3A4A9B02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to whom a credit is allowed against taxes imposed by the possession by reason of the amendments made by this section, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15D863AB64004F45B1263978C5457748"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is eligible for a payment under a plan described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD63BE0F5DC8A4344ACA008375EB1448D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mirror code tax system</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>mirror code tax system</quote> means, with respect to any possession of the United States, the income tax system of such possession if the income tax liability of the residents of such possession under such system is determined by reference to the income tax laws of the United States as if such possession were the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF2DF049E47F47A184D5FE5B4076BC50"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment of payments</header><text>For purposes of section 1324 of title 31, United States Code, the payments under this subsection shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from a credit provision referred to in subsection (b)(2) of such section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H18E202E556B9419A8D925E821C03221B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subchapter B of chapter 65 of subtitle F of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H131DC3930F47429B95387264F4D50629" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry idref="HE2C8A0FD9795469C91CFFB4B76F10584" level="section">Sec. 6436. Individual tariff refund credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H5AC9C5309B014CAABD936B95203AB883"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1324(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>or 7527A</quote> and inserting <quote>7527A, or 6436</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4C8BDC5126DB496EA0BBBFB80D6A5754" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this sections shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2024.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF97274DE239849A6B4C1614BFE110E9F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Excise tax on certain tariff refunds</header> <subsection id="HF0D7A1E7CC2D47E8AAAACC52030E6943"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/42">Chapter 42</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subchapter:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H596A054A0BD9460FAFA364DAF8894258" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subchapter id="H999899745AC442EFB28C28E0456F29F8"><enum>I</enum><header>Excise Tax on Certain Tariff Refunds</header> 
<toc container-level="subchapter-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H999899745AC442EFB28C28E0456F29F8" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H87DBD8250BA04A93A5835EAF565A7931" level="section">Sec. 4969. Excise tax on certain tariff refunds.</toc-entry> </toc> 
<section id="H87DBD8250BA04A93A5835EAF565A7931"><enum>4969.</enum><header>Excise tax on certain tariff refunds</header> 
<subsection id="HBD9620D2D6A44760818D06E3107C2D89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby imposed on each covered taxpayer for the taxable year a tax in an amount equal to 100 percent of the non-qualifying tariff refunds received by such taxpayer.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6ED6D2EF531F4910AB7439C814A42A99"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Exception for costs not passed On to consumers</header> <paragraph id="H88E4E1DA180D420A9B3DA9AD2033FD7A"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to a covered taxpayer if such taxpayer can demonstrate that any increase in price of products sold by the taxpayer during the covered period did not exceed 50 percent of the amount of the tariffs imposed on such products on any input used by the taxpayer to produce such products.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H3D67021965B24E45A73E1F5C773C673B">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Covered period</header>
 <text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <quote>covered period</quote> means the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date on which a covered court order is issued.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                                <paragraph id="H952817997353495F98F3035ED7067AE7">
                                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                                    <header>Treatment of price increases attributable to
                                        inflation</header>
 <text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the amount of the increase in the retail price of any product shall be determined without regard to so much of such increase as is attributable to inflation.</text>
                                </paragraph>
                            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCFE830743EEF46E89468166480AFE305"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HBD46CECD5C0C4EA18FA95DDE0D68FBC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered court order</header><text>The term <quote>covered court order</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 6436.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H553CA3E6DDE34827A409F76AA26796D4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered taxpayer</header><text>The term <quote>covered taxpayer</quote> means a corporation or taxpayer which does not meet the gross receipts test of section 448(c), determined by substituting <quote>$1,000,000,000</quote> for <quote>$25,000,000</quote> in paragraph (1) thereof.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0865BB49829C4C4C9B0F0E82357C0B98" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-qualifying tariff refund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>non-qualifying tariff refund</quote> means a repayment made pursuant to a covered court order of tariff revenues which were collected from the taxpayer in the course of the trade or business of such taxpayer.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE8AC9F23AD89457CAB89960013E91D1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of subchapters for chapter 42 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H611A3F5E7BEF4A5C851DBB96A210D915" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">I. Excise Tax on Certain Tariff Refunds</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H68225ECD0C1E4DF291996A06E5499C30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts received after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

