<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3EC5471E53A243BDB9805F25ACD4C0A6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7783 IH: AI-Ready Networks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7783</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to publish a report on the integration of artificial intelligence into the commercial telecommunications infrastructure of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCBF3DBD8D8434099B14880E4DC0A86AA" style="OLC"><section id="H6A6EAD6619B74A64B1D3E0494F0073FA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AI-Ready Networks Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBDE5A4F628C944188C9AD3DE546CEE34" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on integration of AI into commercial telecommunications infrastructure</header><subsection id="H92230EC222AA47248653D47842079152"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register and on the website of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, a report on the integration of artificial intelligence into the commercial telecommunications networks of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA68469E1A8AE439989A20F6B396445CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H23E7EEBB4AC64841B2C7CDE5FC4D9644"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the status of international and industry-led standards-setting bodies in setting standards for artificial intelligence in telecommunications networks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H334584278A5B4B13A3BA24F49CCC2927"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification and analysis of voluntary, industry-driven use cases for the integration of artificial intelligence into telecommunications networks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H763C5CFC3A114E73B48F7F2C04C1ED84"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for addressing workforce trends and needs in the telecommunications industry as the telecommunications industry integrates artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EDF62FE8A084A66B021223E0FB6AD88"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations on how to leverage artificial intelligence to enhance the security, integrity, and availability of telecommunications networks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA19C5C035FA4B1483A2F680751B1FFF"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations on how voluntary industry best practices, government guidance, and existing laws may support transparency, accountability, and public trust with respect to artificial intelligence deployed in telecommunications networks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7CACF25BCF2482FBB98AD93C6FC8017"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations on modernizing the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) to reflect advancements in artificial intelligence, including the integration of artificial intelligence into telecommunications networks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF455A28D63F240B4AAAA0DBA338552EB"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for how to best work with entities across the Federal Government, State governments, local governments, and Tribal Governments to facilitate the safe and effective integration of artificial intelligence into telecommunications networks.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0AA6DF89911B48FAB0C125C24A5E17D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Draft report; public comment</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HBDF9EF48A79849918698FA0B37F23BA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, publish in the Federal Register and on the website of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration a draft of the report required by subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA35C48C08AB4B84B0BFFC6FBC11D505"><enum>(2)</enum><text>accept public comments on such draft and take such comments into consideration in preparing the final version of such report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77FD4DBB67EB486AB19E772968BA0A77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing the report required by subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary shall consult with the following:</text><paragraph id="H46DACA8301CD4CA4A5DA8A3639C29DD3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF6AED5D54A648A587C5C3E0DFBE03EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H199BAF03896043919A3BBD10E710D776" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H129CFFE8843C49AD8550885B4D2D601A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EBC3CC2CD6A443EAFA4C99206FE9A54"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The heads of other relevant Federal agencies, as determined by the Assistant Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA90CB964AB1744D4921FCBAAE0D09540"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Relevant State, local, and Tribal government entities, as determined by the Assistant Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DD05E63B6FD4D68A47BC08A0A3A55CA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Trusted telecommunications companies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B515BD6A6694FC09764003C0FF1B260"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representatives from academia, public interest organizations, and international standards-setting bodies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AB0BF2D8D8244B89C19DE12E2D48B98"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3C3DA80880D742C281A71C4661BE757D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>artificial intelligence</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47FCDF4ED6A341A698DC91FDE3058396"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D6572FC882A4F1289F3BDEF3D8B8DB5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/153">47 U.S.C. 153</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1C1ED505A354D03BCF24A2AD2979C2E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Trusted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>trusted</quote> means, with respect to a company, that such company does not produce or provide any covered communications equipment or service (as defined in section 9 of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1608">47 U.S.C. 1608</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

