<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN26390-D7T-8F-RW4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>104 S4920 IS: Secure Access for Essential Reproductive Health Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4920</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To ensure the privacy of pregnancy termination or loss information under the HIPAA privacy regulations and the HITECH Act.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H1861512D76544A3F8CD1B25131E70CF6"><section section-type="section-one" id="H9E16EC4452E54422A8B0E9C27E23343F"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure Access for Essential Reproductive Health Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFER Health Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5059560BDBED4A88A548D9A10FF5BAF0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring the privacy of pregnancy termination or loss information under the HIPAA privacy regulations and the HITECH Act</header><subsection id="HF7ECD7A97E6E4374A463B1A203444F31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H268C6E6118D545A381D724C426FCED89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on disclosure</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2) and notwithstanding any regulations promulgated pursuant to section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/191">Public Law 104–191</external-xref>), a covered entity or a business associate of a covered entity may not disclose pregnancy termination or loss information of an individual in Federal, State, local, or Tribal proceedings, including civil, criminal, administrative, legislative, or other proceedings, without the valid authorization of the individual made in accordance with section 164.508 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71A9FE8A5E0E422A8FD925A0077A7407"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of a disclosure of pregnancy termination or loss information of an individual by a covered entity or a business associate of a covered entity if—</text><subparagraph id="H2ED75E6CC5084432AF51D1BB0108868C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the pregnancy termination or loss information is necessary for use in defense of a professional liability action or proceeding against the covered entity or business associate and the pregnancy termination or loss information is disclosed by—</text><clause id="HF9A1A647305544D68509B133635AE5F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the covered entity or business associate to the covered entity’s or business associate’s attorney or professional liability insurer or insurer’s agent; or</text></clause><clause id="H2F20AE7B12654D27AD5C3DEF087BBFEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the authorized attorney of the covered entity or business associate to a court or body hearing the action or proceeding; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBA62E9E713A4DC191A5F3DAC3F464CC"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id30C53832AA364A81A635987FDB57D919"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the pregnancy termination or loss information is necessary to investigate physical harm to the individual by another person directly relating to the loss or termination of the pregnancy; and</text></clause><clause id="id50EFD186F29B4AB39BC88CEFE6BC47AF" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the individual is unable to provide consent due to death or incapacity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2D5D87DA2494B388DCAE45FA53C0E53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>HITECH</header><paragraph id="H728628666B1B4687AED98D02EBB6E039"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Privacy exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall revise section 171.202 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, to clarify that an entity’s practice of not fulfilling a request to access, exchange, or use electronic health information in order to comply with subsection (a) shall not be considered information blocking (as defined in section 171.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)) if the information is pregnancy termination or loss information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H146A6968F5714E579B982C6DD106E006"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Greater security</header><text>The Secretary shall revise section 170.401 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, to require that as a condition of certification (as described in that section), a health IT developer (as so described) shall implement practices that allow for the segregation of data relating to pregnancy termination or loss information to ensure compliance with subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB28D248B9694FA8B669B1C2FFA97F88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preemption; modification of State preemption exceptions</header><paragraph id="HE7C1688779F244B69772EA290E154537"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preemption</header><subparagraph id="id128B18517BE64000963A8D7BC1EBBF46"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section shall preempt any State law to the extent that the State law conflicts with or prevents application of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCC419B3EAFE54E5DA4D3425F35552002"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed to preempt a State law to the extent that the State law provides greater privacy protections for pregnancy termination or loss information than provided under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD9AC81374E2457DB213BED84873C793"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modification</header><text>The Secretary shall revise section 160.203 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, to ensure that no exception to the general preemption rule stated in that section applies with respect to pregnancy termination or loss information other than the exception described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E23AF81A96F4F51AA75F09E0BA13E16"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct an outreach campaign to ensure that covered entities, business associates of covered entities, the public, and affected individuals are aware of the requirements of this section and any revisions to regulations made pursuant to this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2F3B64DE7C174B83997C742C626F7FD9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Procedure</header><paragraph id="id253978A45B5142119F96B88F71378C31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim final rule</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall revise each regulation as required by this section through publication of an interim final rule in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC32061C711AE4615A705E10FFD2771E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date on which an interim final rule is published under paragraph (1), the Secretary, after providing opportunity for public comment, shall publish in the Federal Register a final rule with such modifications as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H375EBD16B7C249E3ABD4384151DEE950"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H9F913288A1944D64B3EC5026507D4729"><enum>(1)</enum><header>HIPAA terms</header><text>The terms <term>business associate</term>, <term>covered entity</term>, and <term>protected health information</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H265DCD897CD541F8AEE31116FD06204F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pregnancy termination or loss information</header><text>The term <term>pregnancy termination or loss information</term> means protected health information of an individual that relates to information that could reveal having or seeking an abortion or care for pregnancy loss, including, without limitation, any request for, or receipt of, items, services, education, counseling, or referrals relating to the termination or loss of a pregnancy of the individual, including abortion, miscarriage, stillbirth, and ectopic pregnancy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8B7B476894104AE9B14BB137E84BCE4C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

