<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H322D77DBED5D44D5BA5C74CE5866B11D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 900 IH: Expressing condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of the victims of the crash of UPS Airlines flight 2976.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 900</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of the victims of the crash of UPS Airlines flight 2976.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on November 4, 2025, UPS Airlines flight 2976 tragically crashed taking off from Muhammad Ali International Airport in Louisville, Kentucky;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this tragedy took the lives of all 3 souls on board, and those of 11 more members of the greater Louisville community;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the first responders of the Okolona Fire Protection District, Louisville Fire Department, Louisville Muhammad Ali International Airport Fire Rescue, Kentucky Air National Guard Fire &amp; Emergency Services, Kentucky National Guard 41st Civil Support Team, Louisville Metro Police Department, Jefferson County Emergency Management, and more than 20 other fire departments and emergency response units from across the city and State acted swiftly and selflessly in responding to the crash and assisting in the aftermath;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Federal, State, and local officials have cooperated to respond to and investigate this disaster; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas those officials and everyday Louisvillians have come together to support and bring peace to those who have lost friends, neighbors, and loved ones: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD255332E0648404187BF4522EA4945F3"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB941D30BD7A34103A546FDEACB66E3E2"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDB19F71D934241B195845344F41AEEE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses heartfelt condolences to the families, friends, and loved ones of the victims of flight 2976;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63842AC5CE744DA8897D97154265EEA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors those who lost their lives in this tragedy, including Angela Anderson, Trinadette <quote>Trina</quote> Chavez, Tony Crain, Captain Dana Diamond, Louisnes Fedon, Kimberly Asa, Carlos Fernandez, John Loucks, John Spray, Jr., Matthew Sweets, First Officer Lee Truitt, Captain Richard Wartenberg, Megan Washburn, and Ella Petty Whorton;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76744BE02F464A719FCA861F29EBE67C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conveys its deepest sympathy to the people of Louisville and the Commonwealth of Kentucky; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DFA78DD53864876B3310CFEE74658BE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends those heroic first responders and emergency personnel who ran into the fire.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

