<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL26455-5XY-PF-47G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4438 IS: Promoting Access to Broadband Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4438</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Federal Communications Commission to establish a program to make grants available to States to inform individuals of potential eligibility for the Lifeline program of the Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H7E46AAC98B874AB9BAB7BA5D7DC8CEE4"><section section-type="section-one" id="H65387790C31F43709A3FB7491AE31887"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Access to Broadband Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H058E48E87ED84B2489A5690BADDCB45D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Lifeline enrollment outreach grants</header><subsection id="H779AEBD6163442A489B81BCA28EBED15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b80081f306549228fbc6827792bc1e3"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE3DE6B54B4B443CD871A21E714C304E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28667ac2abbd4948b312dd9bf730d877"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an eligible-but-not-enrolled individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfaf9d1b6447a4e67bb0c78307a7a9942" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the potential to be a qualifying low-income consumer under 54.409 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, due to the eligibility of the individual, a dependent of the individual, or the household of the individual to receive benefits from or participate in, as applicable, a program described in such section 54.409.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9BF40EECEAE412CBFEE8AD423FBBF7B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible-but-not-enrolled individual</header><text>The term <term>eligible-but-not-enrolled individual</term> means an individual who is a qualifying low-income consumer under section 54.409 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, but is not enrolled in the Lifeline program.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e9469bb4cea4b40abac3f9e13b558e8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian tribe</term> in section 4 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7539bffc70d47419a6fe1a7d2d1b758"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lifeline program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Lifeline program</term> means the program set forth in subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD8BA3E33994147CA86A32A2354DFFA90"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reach</header><text>The term <term>reach</term> means, with respect to an individual, to inform the individual of potential eligibility for the Lifeline program and to provide the individual with information about the Lifeline program, as described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A333194EFD642D4BC6ABFE70450509F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD605242C6A35459B983F312E292E915D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall establish a competitive program to make grants available to States to inform covered individuals of potential eligibility for the Lifeline program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H737BEE212D26454F83E6AC11A9AA7BA0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="H145D7390CDF743ADB8944B7D33A95883"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may only award a grant under this section to a State that submits an application at such time, in such form, and with such information and assurances as the Commission may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6B495F2BD50846119FBDE220BE22CB44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters required to be included</header><text>An application submitted by a State under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H55DF1A5F358F46EDB1F204E03DE31799"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of covered individuals in the State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8CF62C7915BA4AF598AB20242C4D2752"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a plan for the activities that the State will conduct using grant funds, including a list of each agency within the State that will assist in carrying out those activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF88B548E5CEB473B8C715B44D6BF4348"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an estimate of the percentage of eligible-but-not-enrolled individuals in the State who will be reached by those activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD36BAD2BC88E487EAA6B8AE979F133A0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection</header><paragraph id="H265C71320D3E410CB94B928C4A50C065"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Minimum number of States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall award grants under this section to not fewer than 25 percent of the States that submit an application under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD954BFFDFAD8406ABB03529F9685E655"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors for consideration</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Commission shall give favorable consideration to—</text><subparagraph id="H9E8DB5D2B9494440BE41A597274A1DE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>States that have higher numbers of covered individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H40A3C308B417448E85A9EAAE91D76723"><enum>(B)</enum><text>States proposing, in the plans submitted under subsection (c)(2)(B), to conduct activities that have the potential to reach higher percentages of eligible-but-not-enrolled individuals in those States, as determined by the Commission, taking into consideration the estimates submitted under subsection (c)(2)(C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60D49478BA2F47759705CC35A33F08FB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Geographic diversity</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Commission shall, to the maximum extent practicable, select States from different geographic regions of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B5B98A517464B17B4EC90692614CF5B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="id8256BDA4544140A896BDB4C28BFA871F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this section shall use grant funds, in accordance with the plan included in the application of the State under subsection (c)(2)(B), to—</text><subparagraph id="H059FAB948C934BAC97D8FACF655D4F7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inform covered individuals and organizations or agencies that serve covered individuals, as the case may be under the terms of the grant awarded to the State, of potential eligibility for the Lifeline program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1583520886BD418EB4CBBE123C04C557"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide covered individuals with information about the Lifeline program, including—</text><clause id="H14AB3C869B29436C913FF7AACEA0A3AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how to apply for the Lifeline program; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HE0EEA751DC344983A50E6BBB77DB6454"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the prohibition on more than 1 subscriber in each household receiving a service provided under the Lifeline program; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idD73E359636DE44DBBA6E47E3351055BF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>partner with nonprofit and community-based organizations that have a proven track record of working with covered individuals in implementing digital inclusion initiatives to provide covered individuals with—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id238432423b8844c4b324e1bb26b9e788"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance applying for the Lifeline program; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id195fed0453e842988915221390a3a2d5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about product and technology choices.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idC4CF77B3ADA148E4A4271325321E8490"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Multiple State agencies</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this section may provide grant funds to 1 or more agencies located within the State, as identified under subsection (c)(2)(B), to carry out the activities under the grant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA3D7FE2A27EE4CDCBB09ADD7C89BFE65"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Outreach to States regarding grant program</header><text>Before accepting applications for the grant program established under this section, the Commission shall conduct outreach to States to ensure that States are aware of the grant program and how to apply for a grant under the grant program.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b5c4ff6b9bd4a5a8dfc2efdc3ff12e0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate regulations to implement this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide67d81ff2aad4b218946f117beb6a0ea"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04aa752b9b1b44b6a5f7df53e0983186"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>A violation of this section or a regulation promulgated under this section shall be treated as a violation of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) or a regulation promulgated under that Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd01bba7444b249bbbcfc6244e9fe24f8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manner of enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce this section and the regulations promulgated under this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id388e354b13054858835c1ce81b324edd"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><paragraph id="id0d6acd1019764ab7a78ba4355cb80141"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certain rulemaking requirements</header><text>Section 553 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to a regulation promulgated under this section or a rulemaking proceeding to promulgate such a regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52002c0a10c049b49894c954e8347e6a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Paperwork Reduction Act requirements</header><text>A collection of information conducted or sponsored under the regulations required under this section shall not constitute a collection of information for the purposes of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE72627066B1C45FFBCAE3F3C098FE0E2"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><paragraph id="H0DD54E58E09347EF81CF57B1C8978833"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after establishing the grant program under this section, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report evaluating the effectiveness of the grant program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F743FC2FFE14F3395D91F98F364FD4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H4CE4EC3A4B5A4D51951D01C17D5E8412"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals notified of Lifeline program eligibility by States receiving grants under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E9235B441904E8CBBE1FF30D179243F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of new applicants to the Lifeline program from States receiving grants under this section, including the number of those applicants who enrolled in the Lifeline program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12B8A0A0E0DF4E4DB62306C125DA7ABC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the cost-effectiveness of the grant program established under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D7F2ACC61A6403780B051A56903ACD5"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section for the first 5 full fiscal years beginning after the establishment of the grant program under this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="ideb7a3029e0b54125be34e63d69a64e54"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to States to strengthen National Lifeline Eligibility Verifier</header><subsection id="ideb70b9d1b1404792a0125d28d4752cc8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a06bff679374e8d859b8af2936f54ee"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40c9ea26920e489cb6257122cf4aa278"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State that, not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, submits to the Commission an application for a grant under this section containing such information as the Commission may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4c908fc9fb234341a2554c6300e33cdf"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39331ac9de984692b1ac06aebfb97214"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall establish a program to provide a grant, from amounts appropriated under subsection (e), to each eligible entity for the purpose described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="idf2a1908a9d5d4db4bdabfc5270fd8a77"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Commission shall make a grant to each eligible entity for the purpose of establishing, renewing, reestablishing, or maintaining or amending a connection between the databases of the eligible entity that contain information concerning the receipt by a household, or a member of a household, of benefits under a program administered by the eligible entity (including any benefit provided under the supplemental nutrition assistance program under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>)) and the National Lifeline Eligibility Verifier so that the receipt by a household, or a member of a household, of benefits under the benefits program—</text><paragraph id="idf607257ecfd843259618586874099152"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is reflected in the National Lifeline Eligibility Verifier; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8448bf1e43344df6b0dce661808343c6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>can be used to verify eligibility for the Lifeline program set forth in subpart E, part 54, of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id83bfcc6f8b0c4b93921e96eb8b42c1dc"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Disbursement of grant funds</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which the Commission establishes the program under subsection (b), funds provided under each grant made under that subsection shall be disbursed to the eligible entity receiving the grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide3a70e5336b24f1b98f04616145bfabb"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

