<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B985A4A36C3499DA2FA3B748BEC85B4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7750 IH: Protecting Our Integrity and Nation from Tyranny Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7750</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260302">March 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent election interference.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD67753C6A4734DE9B18F051288E233F2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H550988383A4B4E078649F35FBAFB51B5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Our Integrity and Nation from Tyranny Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>POINT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H87C2E81CBDC14311BD0A7A8AF8471005"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prevention of executive power to influence an authorized State election</header> <subsection id="H1721E10ED65D42A2A55D6D98FA288780"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/13">Chapter 13</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/245">section 245</external-xref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H15AADE52D61D4025A278FC9A91170EF5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HB9FEE6B7769A47978C96348582B1A3F2"><enum>245a.</enum><header>Prohibition on executive election interference</header> 
<subsection id="H2ABA40CA43A0455DBADED6D70B1024BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, being a covered individual, knowingly engages in election interference, or uses, provides, or loans any government property, personnel, or resources for the purpose of engaging in election interference, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5B84746360374AEAABF545B85AA8947F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBABE062FC93648CAA6EAAD116D26BB60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>election interference</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H2225E28AC1F14685A662B530A28BAD4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means conduct by a covered individual that—</text> 
<clause id="HF6923DA5AAB5409BB59F5D8348537663"><enum>(i)</enum><text>violates Federal criminal, voting rights, or campaign finance law; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA074B0ECEDD04BD58335DDCDDDEAED1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes any fraudulent, deceptive, or unlawful act or attempted act, or knowing use of information acquired by theft, undertaken with the specific intent to significantly influence voters, undermine public confidence in election processes or institutions, or influence, undermine confidence in, or alter the result or reported result of, a general or primary Federal, State, or local election or caucus, including—</text> 
<subclause id="H4783719AF8DD4551A34C8180CD6BBDD6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the campaign of a candidate; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H59B27F843A7944D7AE3303A7BA2625F7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a ballot measure, including an amendment, a bond issue, an initiative, a recall, a referral, or a referendum; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84ADDFAFD5AE4DA6973FE41B6E2445A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text> <clause id="HBAC8B376CFC64BB8B2CA4A89E18CB87D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>causing or inciting the obstruction of the certification of electoral votes by Congress;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9FFA87BB7C4D43D8BA62033993F61831"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communicating to a Federal, State, or local official with the purpose of influencing or altering vote results or the delegation or nomination of electors;</text></clause> <clause id="HA4A8E76F1AD949B18B38EBC290F546BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>communicating to a Federal, State, or local official with the purpose of publishing or disseminating unsubstantiated claims of fraud, criminal activity, errors, or mismanagement associated with the conducting of a Federal, State, or local election;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1EE8A0EF20A240579271DB277ACC64B7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>communicating to a Federal, State, or local official with the purpose of causing the postponement, prevention, or delay of a Federal, State, or local election; or</text></clause> <clause id="HE17DBC4C298A4DFC8D2A46401BAE4C85"><enum>(v)</enum><text>except to the extent permitted by the Voting Rights Act of 1965, soliciting or ordering the use of personnel, appropriations, or other resources of the Department of Justice to cause the postponement, prevention, or delay of an election, or in order to influence or alter vote results or the delegation or nomination of electors.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3588296025A244CEA25515C1A54FA09C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered individual</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H38D298CC576348E281CEA42452321C48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBEA6D011531F4A92821B9EEF872D8E8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Vice President;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H250AD1B3B2264204B3CFA58D55514FBC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an employee of the Executive Office of the President;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7BAD6493680C4FAAB5939314CB5B6B11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Attorney General;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC661358FAD1422D9CC01EFF19BEF0C6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0483A55E5C344A72BEE659A6085D37B3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Director of National Intelligence; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H164121AA5B2E4799BBAE2338BA804A86"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a cabinet secretary, agency director or any subordinate thereof in a managerial position in such department or agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89ECF13657DE410AABCAC07EB3254E8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>government property or resources</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HC35FFF80053E494DAFDCA466DF160568"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any building, land, vehicle (including aircraft), or other real property owned, leased, or occupied by any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States (including the White House (except for the Executive Residence), the Department of Defense, the United States Postal Service, or the National Park Service), or any other instrumentality wholly owned by the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE54DF9844604808833527D3E432E406"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an information system used or operated by any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States, by a contractor of any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States, or by another organization on behalf of any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA93AABD81D0466BA4870890D42E5933"><enum>(C)</enum><text>funding appropriated by Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H349C343518394950907BF6EEF4F6892E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/245">section 245</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H09DE836A39934A898E7F4317891686A5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">245a. Prohibition on executive election interference.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> </section> <section id="H55A7E60A37B54E8494EFFE3F4115AFAB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on use of Armed Forces in the United States</header> <subsection id="HC3AE9660EBD54180AB3AEF5EE8183505"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not deploy members of the Armed Forces or exercise Federal law enforcement authority of the United States in a State where such deployment or exercise of authority would likely disrupt, postpone, delay, prevent, or influence the result of an election (including a referendum or a ballot question), except as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H49F4FBBD9EA6414C9F4F30D10C76FD57"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of enforcing the Voting Rights Act of 1965.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A50A892F7B349219201580C66341AD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an election held or conducted by a State that directly relates to secession from, or armed rebellion against, the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB1CC8CF7A4E9421E8B40634A8DA227FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Judicial review</header> 
<paragraph id="H657FE64BB8A74F99B9651D2688F00147"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Right of review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any State in which the President deploys members of the Armed Forces or exercises the Federal law enforcement authority of the United States in violation of subsection (a) may bring an action against the United States in the appropriate district court of the United States for appropriate relief, including injunctive relief.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H001FFF9CC8504FDA8B36E8F8DBF1CCD1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in an action under this section, the President shall have the burden of proving that such violation did not occur.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9941BB77C2CF447FAE8C89498509A418"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expedited appeals</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5D99F68342244052B4BD6BA54309C8F8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Time for appeal to court of appeals</header><text>Notwithstanding section 2107 of title 28, United States Code, a notice of appeal of a final judgment issued in an action brought under paragraph (1) may be filed not later than 15 days after such judgement is entered.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H671C83F65F9642F7B0543EE527391E58"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Time for petition to Supreme Court</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 2101 of title 28, United States Code, a petition for a writ of certiorari may be filed not later than 15 days after the court of appeals enters a final judgement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CD5E8BF0C7347228E526F9B45621767"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expedited consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be the duty of the applicable district court of the United States, the applicable court of appeals of the United States, and the Supreme Court of the United States to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of any matter brought under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H08BEAD4A0BD2480EA36D8AF022588C87"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prevention of President or Congress from preempting a State’s constitutional rights</header> <subsection id="H59A6B0B5A0E44FB59BDAE8315EE7DFED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><text>A State harmed by a violation of any of the rights described in subsection (b) may bring an action against the United States in the appropriate district court of the United States for appropriate relief, including injunctive relief.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H08AEDB2BB2264ED0A579FE87A15FA3BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rights</header><text>The rights described in this section are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H11F68C630A9546329A0ADCDC4C4DEA07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Full Faith and Credit Clause (Const. Art. IV Sec. 1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEFD583233E5B4482B990C66EA027241A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The right of a State legislature to consent to the formation of a new State within its jurisdiction, or the formation of a State within its jurisdiction with two or more States or parts of its State (Const. Art. IV Sec. 3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45D7285DD7AC4E59B10E8A7BA852FFC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The guarantee by the United States to every State of a republican form of government, protection against military invasion, and upon application of the legislature, or of the executive (when the legislature cannot be convened) against domestic violence (Const. Art. IV Sec. 4).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D1900F37D2849AB908B22D79EE41A9A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The rights of three fourths of the several States to ratify an amendment to the Constitution and the right of a State to not be deprived of its equal suffrage in the Senate (Const. Art. V).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H371BE4B155E64C2DB248D354ED2B08D1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The reservation to the States respectively, or the people, any powers not delegated to the United States by the Constitution nor prohibited by it to the States (Const. Amendment X).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57638A11F87F4885B4171EB1941D61CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The right of lawfully chosen electors for President and Vice President to meet in their respective States in order to vote by ballot, and to prepare a signed and certified list of ballots cast for transmission under seal to the seat of government, directed to the President of the Senate (Const. Amendment X).</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H59BB6C32CF9F47658C37285D2BB1D3B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expedited appeals</header> <paragraph id="H5F83EBBC54CB426EA044C2153197667C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Time for appeal to court of appeals</header><text>Notwithstanding section 2107 of title 28, United States Code, a notice of appeal of a final judgment issued in an action brought under subsection (a) may be filed not later than 15 days after such judgement is entered.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEED16BE948364D36B5278439F09728BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Time for petition to Supreme Court</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 2101 of title 28, United States Code, a petition for a writ of certiorari may be filed not later than 15 days after the court of appeals enters a final judgement.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC92E2B2CD55E4236AD48557C6E304EC3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expedited consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be the duty of the applicable district court of the United States, the applicable court of appeals of the United States, and the Supreme Court of the United States to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of any matter brought under this section.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

