<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9B0F67FC820B43249E983831733F9E64" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1304 IH: Recognizing on Memorial Day, May 25, 2026, the denial of voting representation in Congress and full local self-government through statehood for active duty servicemembers, National Guard members, reservists, veterans, and their families who are residents of the District of Columbia.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1304</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing on Memorial Day, May 25, 2026, the denial of voting representation in Congress and full local self-government through statehood for active duty servicemembers, National Guard members, reservists, veterans, and their families who are residents of the District of Columbia.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on the last Monday of May, the Nation observes Memorial Day, a Federal holiday commemorating the members of the Armed Forces who died in the service of their country;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the service and sacrifice of active duty servicemembers, National Guard members, reservists, veterans, and their families are unparalleled;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas active duty servicemembers, National Guard members, reservists, and veterans have risked life and limb to protect the American people and uphold the rights and freedoms of the people of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 30,000 veterans are residents of the District of Columbia and do not have voting representation in Congress or full local self-government in the District of Columbia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas residents of the District of Columbia fought in the Revolutionary War, which resulted in the creation of the United States and was fought under the slogan of <quote>no taxation without representation</quote>, and have served in every war since;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 635 District of Columbia residents were casualties of World War I, a casualty figure greater than that observed by 3 different States during that war;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 3,575 District of Columbia residents were casualties of World War II, a casualty figure greater than that observed by 4 different States during that war;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 547 District of Columbia residents were casualties of the Korean war, a casualty figure greater than that observed by 8 different States during that war;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 243 District of Columbia residents were casualties of the Vietnam war, a casualty figure greater than that observed by 10 different States during that war;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas almost 200,000 District of Columbia residents have served in the military since World War I; and</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas the District of Columbia statehood bill (H.R. 51 and S. 51), the Washington, D.C. Admission Act, has 207 cosponsors in the House of Representatives and 43 cosponsors in the Senate: Now, therefore, be it</text>
 </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H2D81E677558848D68ABEEC068B8C2128"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1FE7DBE625124F9F8F895AE3427568A1"><text>That—</text><paragraph id="H7A713C06F43540B685E87F0232781975"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">District of Columbia residents have earned voting representation in the House of Representatives and Senate and full local self-government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFD7D92F71F14E168C307479C43BBA23" commented="no"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>on Memorial Day, the House of Representatives recognizes that active duty servicemembers, National Guard members, reservists, veterans, and their families who are residents of the District of Columbia deserve passage of the Washington, D.C. Admission Act.</text>
            </paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>


