<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDEB83595507D4DFFBC1E1CCCA36B12E5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9544 IH: Saving Medicare Enrollees from Deceptive Insurers and Creating Ample Resources for Everyone Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9544</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure appropriate payments under Medicare Advantage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H07E9B1AE86DB4AD5B78AD284A1B64E1D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H058A451E88554B298EC33E67EB95C393" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Saving Medicare Enrollees from Deceptive Insurers and Creating Ample Resources for Everyone Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Save MEDICARE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB9CBE5A5E5904A418E8F6CA26EAFC3FB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Risk adjustment</header> 
<subsection id="H321A834260B74FE79CFDA0FA258FBA37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>As part of the annual rulemaking cycle for Medicare Advantage for payments applicable to 2028 and subsequent years, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services—</text> <paragraph id="HFD0375B7E36D42009C659EFC1AEAC2F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall include an analysis identifying diagnosis codes with a high rate of differential coding between equivalent enrollees in Medicare Advantage and Medicare beneficiaries not enrolled under a Medicare Advantage plan, a high rate of discretionary coding, or limited treatment implications; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61C1121C6FD14F128E804ABCF32C03D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall exclude or adjust diagnosis codes that the Secretary determines are most likely to be subject to coding variation by Medicare Advantage plans from diagnosis data submitted to the Secretary for purposes of determining appropriate payment adjustments for health status.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H551CFF448E3F4DEDAF0ADB91A2E51328"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusion of diagnoses collected from chart reviews and health risk assessments</header> <paragraph id="H6CB6ABAA3CEE4D31AFFC198FCE1E2D25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Medicare advantage plans</header><text>Section 1853(a)(1)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-23">42 U.S.C. 1395w–23(a)(1)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HA86F4718095A4474ADEB64EF3FCEFF4C" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H47BA623A064449FD85E8C49101F2FB00"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Exclusion of diagnoses collected from chart reviews and health risk assessments</header> 
<subclause id="HCF9A15E34D694891A6B178D07D09C767"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For 2028 and each subsequent year, for purposes of establishing the payment adjustment factors and adjusting payment based on health status under clause (i), the Secretary shall not take into account a diagnosis collected from a chart review or a health risk assessment.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H232C0318F77C42FCB26C2E32B9F57660"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Identification of diagnoses collected from chart reviews and health risk assessments</header><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures to provide for the identification and verification of diagnoses collected from chart reviews and health risk assessments.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H294B35FCD7924049AA335058495F1510"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prescription drug plans</header><text>Section 1860D–15(c)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-115">42 U.S.C. 1395w–115(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HB0F9EFE9F8A14C669152F7003CC8436A" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H8BCF7BFE566E4F799CDB410FAADF2AA9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Exclusion of diagnoses collected from chart reviews and health risk assessments</header> <clause id="HCDAF8F50713948D0869E90C9D945FDC2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For 2028 and each subsequent year, for purposes of establishing the methodology and adjusting the standardized bid amount based on health status under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall not take into account a diagnosis collected from a chart review or a health risk assessment.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H032F54BEB5BC4BD6BEE1E52DED691BFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Identification of diagnoses collected from chart reviews and health risk assessments</header><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures to provide for the identification and verification of diagnoses collected from chart reviews and health risk assessments.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCC927D4B8DB5476FA7E1F450A3B7E5F3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Medpac study and report</header> <paragraph id="HC65E9975D980490EBDCFC4FA313A73A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Medicare Payment Advisory Commission shall conduct a study to determine how results from a Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CAPHS)-sized survey could be extrapolated across all enrollees under a Medicare Advantage contract for the purposes of calculating risk adjusted payments. Such study shall include recommendations on methodology, modifications to the CAPHS survey questions, and CAHPS survey sample size.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04C849C1C8B949918CE61364AAC5ABB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H704123C4957141BD9DC24B442A46AD8C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Quality bonus program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1853(o)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-23">42 U.S.C. 1395w–23(o)(1)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>and ending with 2028,</quote> after <quote>2012</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HA69673EFFA654F619C6F54BF79BDAC1F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Benchmark payments</header> 
<subsection id="HFD4C4C50572B4CB58FEFFBE057ABE661"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eliminating the county quartile system</header><text>Section 1853(n)(2)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-23">42 U.S.C. 1395w–23(n)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF2660941036045BEB3766450E4391C9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as subclauses (I) and (II), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB94AF40FDC0642AEA745C1263CCABBFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>is the product of</quote> and inserting</text> <quoted-block id="HA90B725A62564654A5D42A0114327209" style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is—</text> 
<clause id="H0B84233EC6E0447E9EA6834ED25AB077"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each of 2012 through 2027, the product of</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B94ECE6A3494EE68E2405B7CE14D1FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HFE043A04ED084C8AAC117046FA1DB8A4" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H7CC229B88F9346D8B2414C8275B5EC7A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for 2028 and each subsequent year, is the base payment amount specified in subparagraph (E) for the area and year adjusted to take into account the phase-out in the indirect costs of medical education from capitation rates described in subsection (k)(4) and, for 2021 and subsequent years, the exclusion of payments for organ acquisitions for kidney transplants from the capitation rate as described in subsection (k)(5).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2C70F5AAD50B410E984588D27D73FD4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modifications to base payment amount</header><text>Section 1853(n)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-23">42 U.S.C. 1395w–23(n)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H828A9CA585B34B189880954D5671232E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>subparagraphs (F) and (G)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (F), (G), and (H)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6323141B4104D97839DE9EBB9DB9AA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H254F1ECB83B0430F8A86FC895ECA60D3" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HA2DD12935F6140EEB93C8282096A88B9"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Adjustment for favorable selection</header><text>For 2028 and each subsequent year:</text> <clause id="HEB11942B1AAF45448E6BE0A8D8086692"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The base payment amount specified in subparagraph (E) for a year shall be adjusted to account for favorable selection between Medicare Advantage and the original Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B in accordance with this subparagraph.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H299BC3D9A9B0468CA81F4FFDCC10F1D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Analysis</header> 
<subclause id="H44E34B8D4F9F464BB17395BFDEB86632"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to ensure the accuracy of the adjustment under clause (i), the Secretary shall annually conduct an analysis of any differences in selection between Medicare Advantage and the original Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B described in such subclause and publish the results of such analysis on the internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services in plain language and in research-downloadable files. The Secretary shall conduct such analysis among subgroups of the Medicare population, including by at a minimum race, gender, zip code, income level, and health condition.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H302264A1E7534D7D9021BEE4912A6D34"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall complete such analysis by the date necessary to ensure that the results of such analysis are incorporated on a timely basis into the base payment amount for 2029 and subsequent years.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA4770FFECCA943FEAE4799031C756AB4"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Data</header><text>In conducting such analysis, the Secretary shall use data submitted with respect to 2025 and subsequent years, as available and updated as appropriate.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H0C572E2BAC944D6C9A6FEA552F7E2430"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text>In calculating the adjustment under clause (i) for each year, the Secretary shall apply the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission’s method for estimating favorable selection into Medicare Advantage as described in its March 2026 report to Congress. Applying such method, the Secretary shall calculate a <quote>selection percentage</quote> to adjust for favorable selection between Medicare Advantage and the original Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B. The selection percentage shall be calculated before the intervention of Medicare Advantage plans as the ratio of expected spending for the national average Medicare Advantage beneficiary relative to expected spending for the national average fee-for-service beneficiary, after standardizing for measured risk A value of 1 indicates no difference in expected spending while values below 1 indicate lower expected spending in Medicare Advantage than in fee-for-service Medicare for beneficiaries with the same risk scores. The base payment amount specified in subparagraph (E) shall be multiplied by the selection percentage to yield a selection-adjusted base payment amount. The selection-adjusted base payment amount shall replace the prior base payment amount in all calculations of payment benchmarks for Medicare Advantage.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6446A39A65B040DE8C47D202A6511BEF"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Medpac review</header><text>The Medicare Payment Advisory Commission shall conduct and publish a review of the analysis conducted under clause (ii) and any adjustments made under clause (i) based on such analysis not later than 2 years after implementation of this subparagraph and biennially thereafter.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE3CBD3A0D0604BBF8C57E5B62FB38EB4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Risk adjustment data validation</header> <subsection id="HD4CFA243819D4DE6AD1C6DB0EE2E11DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Risk adjustment data validation reforms</header><text>Section 1853(a)(1)(C) of the Social Security Act is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H9AE3CDFB8E584B0788EABD9D4A236833" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H79BC3BA7A4A24920A49A195AC04F2095"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Improving timeliness of RADV audits and appeals</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, the following requirements shall apply with respect to the Medicare Advantage Risk Adjustment Data Validation Program:</text> <subparagraph id="HA140E3949A0749F79C0CA53F3D4D6A3E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Contract-level audits</header><text>The Secretary shall complete contract-level audits within one year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C657E48F49C497E80E99149A316D23A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Medical record reviews</header><text>The Secretary shall complete RADV medical record reviews within 60 days.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H82754EF47ECE4B05A988FB1A5F34EA8C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deadline for completion of stages 1 and 2 of appeals</header> <clause id="H39454D9C00E64D36881823577C406A54"> <enum>(i)</enum> <header>Stage 1</header> <text>The reconsideration stage described in section 422.311(c)(6) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), shall be completed within 90 days.</text>
              </clause> 
<clause id="HBB82B3918A9B4A01A71D04681F1C31AE">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
                <header>Stage 2</header>
 <text>The hearing stage described in section 422.311(c)(7) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), shall be completed within 90 days.</text>
              </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4368587D0DB45B29086B5107AC12792"><enum>(D)</enum><header>User fee</header><text>The Secretary shall reduce the payments to Medicare Advantage organizations under section 1853 by 0.02 percent for the purpose of carrying out Risk Adjustment Data Validation audits.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCD554E1DB3D4D4F88089B1B9BE69918"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limitation on review</header><text>There shall be no judicial review under section 1869, section 1878, or otherwise of any determination of the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services under the Risk Adjustment Data Validation audit program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF5A3EDEF6534E3D8DE7B75A36F928C0"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Authority to extrapolate</header><text>The Secretary may extrapolate the results of audited samples to the general Medicare Advantage population and retroactively, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H5FFF501E66BA4E909B1D236B095065FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enhancing audit process</header><text>Section 1853(a)(1)(C) of the Social Security Act, as amended by subsection (a), is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H84E3A70A199D426A8F7037A967B6F823" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H856D52AF17BF48D2B5F7F6FDF9EC1228"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Identification and recoupment of overpayments</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6873A458E41C429095C187B33FE33989"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into contracts with one or more recovery audit contractors under section 1893(h) for the identification and recoupment of overpayments, including penalties as defined under subparagraph (B), with respect to items and services for which payment is made under this part.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53F2F299077F423E98D0A5B97864FEF3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>With respect to any overpayment identified under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall provide for the imposition a penalty in an amount equal to the total amount of overpayment and the rate of interest as defined under section 405.378(d) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA66289F3D474492BAFDAB7177A88E7F0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contingency fees</header><text>The Secretary may provide contingency fees to recovery audit contractors in an amount equal to no more than 20 percent of recouped overpayments made by such contractor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H818FEB233AAD44C295DF8C13916A1F83"><enum>6.</enum><header>Guard Veterans Health Care Act</header> <subsection id="HE38C31BD86864A90A5D2E115338D3CE5"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Cost-Recovery from Medicare Advantage and Medicare prescription drug plans</header> <paragraph id="H3D297A962DE04F06BD59F8D81705DE32" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cost recovery</header> <subparagraph id="HC38FCA7DC38A4FBFB2B8F2D9AD0134DE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1729B">section 1729B</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
            <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="H8AE645CE72444AE59BEC1C05718E370A">
              <section id="H2341B47106E5408E8BF7EC012D0A47CF">
                <enum>1729C.</enum>
                <header>Cost-recovery from Medicare Advantage and Medicare prescription drug
                  plans</header>
                <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="HE9B03E63CF654D0E9F58655324A51AB0">
                  <enum>(a)</enum>
                  <header>In general</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding sections 1814(c), 1835(d), and 1862(a)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395f">42 U.S.C. 1395f(c)</external-xref>, 1395n(d), and 1395y(a)(3)), if the Secretary provides under this chapter any health care item or service (including for a service-connected disability or a non-service-connected disability) covered under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>), including outpatient and inpatient care, prescription drugs, medical devices, lab testing, and items or services delivered in post-acute and long-term care settings, to any individual who is enrolled in a Medicare Advantage plan, including an MA–PD plan, offered by a MA organization under part C of such title or a prescription drug plan offered by a PDP sponsor under part D of such title, such organization or sponsor shall, to the extent such item or service is covered under such Medicare Advantage plan or prescription drug plan, reimburse the Secretary for such item or service regardless of any additional documentation, utilization management, or other administrative requirement the plan may impose on the item or service.</text>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="H59344DC115464CE39E28AB2A611D8EAA">
                  <enum>(b)</enum>
                  <header>Recovery of amounts</header>
                  <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="HA7FB22BBBDB0491B9312D15FF6C34402">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall recover amounts required to be reimbursed under subsection (a) through the use of procedures under section 1729 of this title to the same extent as those procedures are used to recover amounts authorized to be recovered under that section.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="H30D8E02A8F544A0384D8C56705EBC45B">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Amount and process</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (1), recovery under that paragraph of amounts reimbursed under subsection (a) shall be in such an amount, and occur in accordance with such procedures, as the Secretary shall prescribe for purposes of this section.</text>
                  </paragraph>
                </subsection>
                <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="H4F86B60E070448899CA2DBD42E6F5DB4">
                  <enum>(c)</enum>
                  <header>Application</header>
 <text>The provisions of subsection (a) shall apply to Medicare Advantage and prescription drug plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028.</text>
                </subsection>
                <subsection id="H3356303490A4469F9A6F0DFBA4DEA90E" commented="no">
                  <enum>(d)</enum>
                  <header>Treatment of amounts</header>
 <text>Amounts reimbursed to the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be deposited in the Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Care Collections Fund under section 1729A of this title.</text>
                </subsection>
              </section>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H1851560389D74B14BBB1842BDAAFCF81">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Clerical amendment</header>
 <text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1729B the following new item:</text>
            <quoted-block style="USC" id="HA50166D708AB4393804EF4CB59518E48">
              <toc>
                <toc-entry level="section" idref="H2341B47106E5408E8BF7EC012D0A47CF">1729C.
                  Cost-recovery from Medicare Advantage and Medicare prescription drug
                  plans.</toc-entry>
              </toc>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HDF4D18ADD6894B8EB77ADE01AB353301">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Medicare conforming amendments</header>
          <subparagraph id="HEDCF43D1C6CD47ADBE8D21793B80D0B8" commented="no"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Part A</header>
 <text>Section 1814(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395f">42 U.S.C. 1395f(c)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and section 1729C of title 38, United States Code</quote> after <quote>section 1880</quote>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H4C5472AE06474A04BDD8E6E7518DC601" commented="no"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Part B</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1835(d) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395n">42 U.S.C. 1395n(d)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and section 1729C of title 38, United States Code</quote> after <quote>section 1880</quote>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7D112A8835D448A5BC20F0922F660577" commented="no"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Exclusions from coverage</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1862(a)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>in the case of items and services and prescription drugs for which reimbursement is made under section 1729C of title 38, United States Code,</quote> after <quote>section 1880(e),</quote>.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H47E283D0DD8C42CCAEC0BD5DCADA328B">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Modification of authority for recovery by United States of reasonable charges for
          certain care or services furnished to veterans for non-Service-Connected
          disabilities</header>
 <text>Section 1729 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H97884E438C3E4B738ED63A8F84C8BC20" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in subsection (a)—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H7150EFFFCD4A4FA4BCD058646E5D62D7" commented="no"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F5DA4323B9B47B8B1CBF268E5904449"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22642F2C32A64D87BA0A2BB416B1BD8F" indent="up1"> <enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7D6F4C912C9344519EAD5E6400082B9F"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>Subject to the provisions of this section, the United States has the right to recover or collect the reasonable charges for care or services that the United States is required by law to furnish or pay for under this chapter for a non-service-connected disability.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="HB9E5FF96B90C4881898581C80BB53184" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has the right to recover or collect from a third party the reasonable charges for care or services furnished as described in subparagraph (A) to the extent that the recipient or provider of the care or services would be eligible to receive payment from a third party.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"
                  id="H5CD4030671084600872AEC2427304DD0">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The right to recover or collect reasonable charges for care or services under this section shall apply to any and all causes of action or recovery rights in tort or under any policy, plan, or contract providing benefits for health care or injury, which accrue to the individual to whom the care or services were furnished, or to the legal representatives of the individual, as a result of the non-service-connected disability that necessitated the care or services.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7B9CE8EF336A495597869185978CD28C" commented="no"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="H6C0A27606A79425185397C8863FCFDBB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HB9339EC407D34FBA9FDFF9EEFD6EC8F3" commented="no"
              display-inline="no-display-inline">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (E)(2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H63B8F128599748358A21F2E75A859B94" commented="no"
              display-inline="no-display-inline">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE51AF7B77FE74864B36BE8B8018DAC80"> <subparagraph id="HBF6F3246405445059031270A5583DBCE" indent="up1"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>that is incurred by an individual who is entitled to care (or payment of expenses of care) under circumstances creating a tort liability upon a third party.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
              </quoted-block>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFA865EAC5EF94B7894338063E1AE01E9" commented="no"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (b), by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7CF83619AF14C78A76FE5AB7FA331B3"> <paragraph id="HD06261A1217C45969AC84AB77095D68D" indent="up1"> <enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB1E944DC520C4F0F9EEDC2A570997433"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>The United States may take any action necessary to enforce the subrogation interests of the United States under this section, including by intervening or joining in an action or proceeding.</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="H263CCD3FFA154F0AB17576CDC61A1900">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proceeding under this section may not be brought after the end of the six-year period beginning on the last day on which the care or services for which recovery is sought are furnished. Notwithstanding the previous sentence, subject to section 2415 of title 28, and except as otherwise provided by law, any action for money damages under this section brought by the United States or an officer or agency thereof that is founded upon a tort shall be barred unless the complaint is filed within three years after the right of action first accrues.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4FA57A4FA70147D0923311901D1DAD33">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (c)(1), by inserting <quote>or penalty</quote> after <quote>claim</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HA72106D22BC142429DD3AC6EC1E95EE6">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>by redesignating subsections (h) and (i) as subsections (l) and (m), respectively;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB79399F48499449E89BE496DA2E27E28" commented="no"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (f) the following new subsections:</text>
          <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="HF167F90C33664A508FE7060420F267F2">
            <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="HCCBF6924A4A145EF8073434338ED7133">
              <enum>(g)</enum>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"
                id="HDDDFC11B32994D1281994DA2171E1378">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 45 days after receipt of a claim to recover or collect the reasonable charges for care or services described in subsection (a), or in the case of a tort, not later than 45 days after settlement, judgment, award, liability determination, or resolution relating to the cause of action, a third party shall—</text>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="HA1C5E063A30141988D05D34CF4052228" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pay a clean claim for reimbursement in accordance with this section;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"
                  id="H729A7AACB290495E99CD1A0E5E381671">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pay the amount agreed to in writing by the Department; or</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"
                  id="H2A751586CB4E4D1E9AFAB32822F2D3AA">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide notice of the date the third party received the claim and include a statement that—</text>
                  <clause id="HAA17AD3085BB425892DAC9553536807E">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the third party refuses to reimburse all or part of the claim and specify each reason for the refusal to pay; or</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="HFCCC446DD8754860A406E61E91B751DC">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>additional information is necessary to determine if all or part of the claim will be reimbursed and what specific additional information is necessary.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H187D8BF2EA9948F38DEF64ED59B049EA" indent="up1">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a claim if there is a good faith dispute about the legitimacy of the claim.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HFEF67DC525744152926A1A3921E8AD15" indent="up1">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"
                  id="H85471E9E323A4053B109605BDAB469C6">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>If any third party fails to comply with paragraph (1), such third party shall be required to pay interest to the United States at the rate established by the Secretary of the Treasury under section 3717 of title 31 per month on the amount of the claim that remains unpaid at the end of the 45-day period specified in such paragraph.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="H1B48EE4F2D2D45549EFC7C4A9A285FC6">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The interest paid pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be included in any late reimbursement from a third party without requiring the Secretary to make any additional claim for such interest.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HD822DF21BEE945B4BF13CDA20C9E5571" indent="up1">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"
                  id="H5C8C6DA265754276812156366E8043AC">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Upon receiving a request for additional information by a third party pursuant to paragraph (1)(C)(ii), the Secretary shall provide the additional information, if determined relevant by the Secretary, not later than 45 days after receipt of the request for additional information.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="H8D07DC2238A24001AE199E2D226215DE">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Failure to furnish relevant information within the time required under subparagraph (A) shall not invalidate or reduce any claim in connection with such information.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H5D39289520434CDF863A82E2653734E9" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
                  <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"
                    id="H5F594D00535E49A0A36A97818445D854">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>Not later than 15 days after receipt of additional relevant information under subparagraph (A), a third party shall pay a clean claim in accordance with this subsection or send a written or electronic notice that—</text>
                    <subclause id="H0DCCF38E2C064703B8E9041D1EA5D4F1" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>such third party refuses to reimburse all or part of the claim; and</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause id="H908C527D048B4C539D3C6987AA163289" indent="up1">
                      <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>specifies each reason for refusal to pay.</text> </subclause> </clause> <clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0877FF1E74A4B75834D300EACDB957A"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any third party that fails to comply with clause (i) shall pay interest to the United States on any amount of the claim that remains unpaid at the rate established by the Secretary of the Treasury under section 3717 of title 31.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HBA4A4C6074CC4043AD21054E06211265" indent="up1">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>A third party shall not be entitled to request a refund to correct a payment error to the Department if the request by the third party for such payment correction is submitted more than 18 months after the date that the Department received payment from the third party.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="H3D8B01573E9A4EF0A1D3723BBD654D4E">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any claim by the Department under this section shall not be subject to non-Department claims processes, policies, or forms.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H9993219A660A4491BCC847C13F2131F0">
              <enum>(h)</enum>
 <text>The recovery rights of the United States under this section are not limited to the amounts paid to non-Department providers and are not subject to non-Department fee schedules or non-Department reimbursement rates, including those administered under workers’ compensation plans or automobile accident reparations insurance.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H110C69E6850B4F91BB8A9218031A381D">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"
                id="H5E1C12F572F64F22BFF882DB973B439C">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>A third party shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H39E71F19AC5C4543B0238738991C380B" indent="up1"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>determine whether a recipient of care or services covered by this section (including a recipient whose claim is unresolved) has received benefits under this chapter; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HEC23DB41DFC34535A17720F866876350" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>submit the information described in paragraph (2) with respect to the recipient to the Secretary in a form and manner (including frequency) specified by the Secretary.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H1A6333177F014F09BC8B1059A300F517" indent="up1">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The information required to be submitted under this paragraph with respect to a recipient of care or services is—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H966DCF6873404CE3B5223E23AFC45EAE">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the identity of the recipient; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H24048C7A7D5C45D9B7950417A2685C6F"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>such other information as the Secretary shall specify in order to enable the Secretary to make an appropriate determination concerning coordination of benefits, including any applicable recovery claim.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HD70649784DBB4CA58B8E4CDA27D7194D" indent="up1">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>A third party shall submit the information required under paragraph (1)(B) with respect to a recipient of care or services covered by this section (including a recipient whose claim is unresolved) not later than 30 days, or such other time period as prescribed by the Secretary, after the date on which the third party knows or has reason to know that the recipient has received benefits under this chapter.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="H5EA3BE6CDD1149BAA3F90653C5725E28">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>A third party shall not distribute proceeds of a settlement, judgment, award, or other payment in connection with a recipient of care or services covered by this section (including a recipient whose claim is unresolved), regardless of whether there has been a determination or admission of liability, without satisfaction of a claim by the Department.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H254C3B96E5C04DD4B48F15DDC4ADA9D3">
              <enum>(j)</enum>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"
                id="H74F6988B343B418E8B4CE9A70AFA9CF5">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>A third party that fails to comply with the requirements under this section, including any regulations prescribed to implement this section, with respect to any individual receiving care furnished or paid for by the Department as described in this section, shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount published on a website of the Department for each day of noncompliance with respect to each claim violation. A civil penalty under this paragraph shall be in addition to any other penalties prescribed by law.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HE9D9E5F4881149BD89005EFACAEBF9BC" indent="up1">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"
                  id="H123CDBDFB90949448B9DC2D4AB556F14">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>A third party that willfully fails or refuses to pay a clean claim under this section, including any regulations prescribed to implement this section, with respect to any individual receiving care furnished or paid for by the Department as described in this section, shall be subject to paying the higher of triple the amount of the claim or an amount not to exceed $50,000, which may be adjusted for inflation, for each claim violation.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="H4E61AECC010A4CCDB111FC234E8AF369">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>A penalty under subparagraph (A) is in addition to any other penalty under this subsection and any other penalty prescribed by law.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="H863158B1AF784FE0BCF52270D197E0B0">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before enforcing any penalty under this paragraph with respect to a third party, the Secretary shall provide to the third party written notice of the amount due and a 30-day opportunity to pay the clean claim, including penalties, interests, and costs.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H44D0575D52414BAB894952D8255C883F" indent="up1">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Notwithstanding any other applicable civil or criminal remedies, the United States shall have a cause of action for damages (which shall be in an amount double the amount otherwise provided) in the case of a third party that fails to provide payment, or appropriate reimbursement, for the reasonable value of the care or services furnished, to be furnished, paid for, or to be paid for in accordance with a clean claim.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HB069F45754314ED3AB9E783F415D629B">
              <enum>(k)</enum>
 <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may implement this paragraph by prescribing regulations, program instructions, or otherwise.</text>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H03755FAB9EE7458AABF356BC0EFDE9CD" commented="no"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (m), as redesignated by paragraph (4)—</text> <subparagraph id="H2F2CCBC112C14D669F1B862B4FAB6443" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3)—</text>
            <clause id="H0463F86FCA91472D874EDD7E6813C020" commented="no"
              display-inline="no-display-inline">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HD948C98449C749548834B81C33932752" commented="no"
              display-inline="no-display-inline">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H354223165E5444F18252E18126BFF4E8" commented="no"
              display-inline="no-display-inline">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20507AA33A044C62871E3D95A0B5AAF1"> <subparagraph id="H8E765378EBF8456CBF6A14EAC32766CE"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>a person or entity responsible in tort for damages incurred as a result of negligence; or</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HCA074B429809464BA410DE792ED2185B">
                  <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>a person or entity responsible for payment of medical expenses other than under a health-plan contract, including medical expenses coverage, medical payments coverage, or underinsured motorist coverage.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
              </quoted-block>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC46FF7E005734835982566C68BD4054D" commented="no"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58D5C42473AA45AF80163E141AC0B557"> <paragraph id="H82293FE380D54BEA953F6CF1EAEE25B8"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>The term <term>clean claim</term> means a claim to recover or collect reasonable charges under subsection (a) that can be processed without obtaining additional information. </text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H3B5EC8019D0645CDA3D9D0F8D6577C56">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>The term <term>non-service-connected disability</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEA67DCC06084378AC8E4B80B09021FD"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a non-service-connected disability, injury, illness, health care need, or condition; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="HBFCF5E72DB664773A978962AF2CC4FAD">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an aggravation or exacerbation of a service-connected disability.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H15454C67B496478880EF09D33AAD57B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1853(c)(1)(D)(iii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-23">42 U.S.C. 1395w–23(c)(1)(D)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(before 2028)</quote> after <quote>for a year</quote>.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="HABB3444B20034843AED6305270BE8B75"><enum>7.</enum><header>Allowing States to enforce Medicare Advantage plan requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1856(b)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-26">42 U.S.C. 1395w–26(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDE3E3DB92AB2499598562B25EF046950"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The standards</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF05EC37540A94904B037FF8C881C44DA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H9E29FAA54EF940629B136EBDBA4D36F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), the standards</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB75587EC19F4F75BA36F913111A69C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7CB7C06DD4AC470F99AFED8AA20C1CC4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H2A87670CDE7D4E11B83E8821BD0126BE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State may require that MA organizations that issue, sell, renew, or offer MA plans in the State meet the requirements of this part with respect to such MA plans.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8A5DF0FA7AEF4398A7E894DA13F12FC6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Coordination of enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall coordinate enforcement of the standards established under this part with the State in which an MA organization is licensed and any State in which the MA organization issues, sells, renews, or offers MA plans. The Secretary may enter into a collaborative enforcement agreement with any State to further coordinate enforcement.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="HA8997F4804A34DC983BE02EBC55A4A91"><enum>8.</enum><header>Provider incentive contracts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1857(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HDE1A8F7B6E09484ABBDC8ED95D35BEF4" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H672D71E0B7E94A0AA4E68D20F9506CC5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Prohibiting percentage of premium contracts or other financial incentives for coding</header><text>Beginning with plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, a contract under this section with an MA organization shall prohibit the use of percentage of premium contracts or other financial incentives for providers related to coding items and services furnished to enrollees under this part.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

