<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5702C631F74B400594C387FBF0233599" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8653 IH: Accelerating Demonstration Approaches for Protecting Transportation Assets Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8653</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a grant program for demonstration projects that make critical transportation infrastructure resilient to natural hazards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H71754DD3C74E4E55B0A309DA8B0C2CDE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H73C363AC83EF4D89A78A88E344FD616A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accelerating Demonstration Approaches for Protecting Transportation Assets Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ADAPT Assets Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H2A022D71ADA647CA8361DF9619AC618F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Accelerating Demonstration Approaches for Protecting Transportation Assets Program</header> <subsection id="HBF15A51E36DF4E17AF2DCA66FD7B14CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall establish and carry out a competitive grant program, to be known as the <quote>Accelerating Demonstration Approaches for Protecting Transportation Assets Program</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>), to provide up to 10 grants to eligible applicants for demonstration projects that make critical transportation infrastructure resilient to natural hazards.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H03F040183EDE4C519547443D25BA4DE3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible applicants</header><text>An eligible applicant under the Program is—</text> <paragraph id="HC7B09371A8BF4D1A90C7EBE45ECDFBFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a metropolitan planning organization (as defined in section 134 of title 23, United States Code);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3CEBD140B0C4EFCBA6CC357C8B01F0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a State;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89BF5859225347ACA98E094259FC40A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a unit of local government;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB91EC159EF1446F4B02D01684725442D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a public transportation agency or authority;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC5B717938B243A18764B640E479CE62"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a port or public toll authority that owns or operates eligible transportation assets;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H484CD189F3B249AEB6E357EBE26639A7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a Tribal government; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23CAEF1D57EA462799079B6D0B57DA83"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a consortium of 2 or more entities described in paragraphs (1) through (5), including a consortium led by a metropolitan planning organization, so long as the applicants demonstrate a regional partnership and governance structure for project delivery.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA492A9D9E0FE44DC8375BB22685F5A22"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application requirements</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an eligible applicant shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE5ED00FBCB384B15A3395D8015340997"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Project selection criteria</header><text>In selecting projects under the Program, the Secretary shall consider, at a minimum, the extent to which the project—</text> 
<paragraph id="H766FF1E1C0A54E8F83BE909D0F186B88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>addresses existing or predicted recurring damage or asset failure of a high-risk transportation asset or corridor based on documented exposure to hazard risk;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD479844EC89044E9A35502D41C066FE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides transportation system benefits, including preserving or enhancing regional or statewide mobility, economy, goods movement, safety, and emergency response access;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB8E57F27EA74D799F03893624CBF703"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides additional benefits, including enhancing resilience of adjacent communities, the environment, and other critical infrastructure;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F4CE7036539491E8A238A79A54C04A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is consistent with a resilience improvement plan authorized under this Act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2AEAF91F4D344C1B17A27509A1AA151"><enum>(5)</enum><text>demonstrates readiness to proceed, including through—</text> <subparagraph id="H01C6D1217C6B43FD8205F8D89AF872BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrating that it is supported by a regional partnership and governance plan that identifies roles, responsibilities, and decision-making processes across affected facility owners, land owners, funders, jurisdictions; and modes; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C2331C444CE43A6AC5F23845530FC60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>completion of planning activities carried out in a manner consistent with section 168 of title 23, United States Code, or other key predevelopment milestones, or a credible schedule to complete such milestones; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DA314CEEBDC492C9FE54022313730B3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>advances innovation and replicability, including approaches that can be scaled by other regions.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H100E5FF762DE4B2BA0F23BF0879072A4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible uses</header> 
<paragraph id="HA9AD9828FAC646BF807DD5E882C65D54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants under the Program may be used for a project or suite of projects within a region that, taken together, constitute a large-scale resilience investment to protect, elevate, adapt, relocate, or otherwise improve the resilience of transportation assets eligible for assistance under title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89178047AA9648BB816EB563CBA95503"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible uses</header><text>Funds provided by a grant under the Program may be used for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H645757FE19D449C8A37F48C9EB5385CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>predevelopment activities, including data collection, engineering and design, environmental review, permitting, right-of-way activities, and procurement planning; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFDDA5393D0F047898B39BC15974E4223"><enum>(B)</enum><text>capital construction and implementation activities to harden or adapt transportation assets, including—</text> 
<clause id="HFCD8F91B6DCB434194BE58E64BBC9A43"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protective features described in section 119(k) of title 23, United States Code;</text></clause> <clause id="H77E9BE29F130439EA5447A2C5078EACC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">system resilience improvements described in section 176(c)(3)(C) of title 23, United States Code;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAF3C3CB970E2431CBC646CD3524CA988"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>levees, including engineered levees and levees utilizing natural infrastructure; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC46961B079DF4B849BD8166CE809D463"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other resilience improvements that are functionally connected to making an eligible transportation asset more resilient to extreme weather, natural hazards, and disaster risks.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDCEFB38CACD9412BB45F61E415B21342"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Multiyear project requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="H0908B65D98B74637BF0D4CC2584C52C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Multiyear agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may enter into multiyear grant agreements to fund an eligible project under the Program across multiple fiscal years, including agreements that provide predictable funding for programmatic delivery of related resilience improvements.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H141A5ACF970F41CB9A4F1D0363B517E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible for funding under a multiyear grant agreement described in paragraph (1), the project or suite of projects shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H68D19CB4FBD24B8788F0759BC952F8C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have an estimated total cost of not less than $500,000,000, except that the Secretary may reduce such threshold for Tribal applicants, rural regions, or insular areas; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86798029F8B941BE9BF82EDC835AE30A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>involve delivery challenges or institutional, regulatory, or funding barriers that are not routinely addressed through existing surface transportation programs and, if successfully resolved through the demonstration, would provide a replicable model for other projects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB934AAEAA114CF687900DA5E057DA0D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible barriers</header><text>To be considered eligible under paragraph (2)(B), the barriers described in such paragraph shall include 1 or more of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HA7EA991F753340D883EDC993CAADEE18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Multiowner or multioperator governance and delivery structures.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2735B9A42F84A459B7975924A1538B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Integration of natural or nature-based infrastructure into transportation projects subject to Federal environmental review or permitting.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35A9200C38114142937EDE286A704339"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Resilience investments located outside the transportation right-of-way that reduce risk to an eligible transportation asset.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC366AB077BD4982A1452662A8C6852C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Projects that protect or enhance transportation assets while also benefitting communities and other critical infrastructure systems.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4F4860F840443EBB24F141F2C7BD8A9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Projects requiring coordinated funding across two or more Federal departments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43A7AD9A61D54296BE40F55BFD4C4069"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal share</header> 
<paragraph id="H1CE311CCAD8A4CB89C08FDBE4AEC03DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out with a grant under this section may not exceed 80 percent.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E43EDC995314EC6B5B03BECAF59CE76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other Federal funds</header><text>Other Federal funds may be used to satisfy the non-Federal share only to the extent specifically provided for under the law authorizing the use of such Federal funds.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF386FC0634D405BB97FAA26FD45FE82"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administration</header> 
<paragraph id="HEFF870BBFDDE47CB8813749047176C66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of funding opportunity</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall publish a notice of funding opportunity for grants under the Program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H817A318B84C946F886B1A4AE0AC197D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall coordinate with other Federal departments and agencies, including the Environmental Protection Agency, Federal Emergency Management Agency, Department of Interior, Department of Commerce, and U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, to ensure Federal activities related to resiliency and Federal funding are streamlined and coordinated to allow for comprehensive solutions across Federal agencies to mitigate impacts from natural hazards on infrastructure, the economy, and the United States population.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1CDA74FA77A4937BF8C09C1F5F0DFD1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relationship to other Federal programs</header><text>A grant under this section may be used in combination with funds made available under other provisions of law administered by the Department of Transportation, including funds for formula, discretionary, and emergency relief programs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF3B628B683A4160B58803710612A1D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Dashboard</header> <subparagraph id="H289B5B07B0084DA1A3C56D1F79128C00"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall make publicly available in an easily identifiable location on the website of the Department of Transportation a dashboard containing the following information for each project in a grant agreement under this section:</text> 
<clause id="HC5275EDDDAAC45449F24A2E96403E979"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Project name.</text></clause> <clause id="HC9D53E3342C145FF92C2E58785259C9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Project sponsor.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5514D4D88B1C4C3E8E2F755AA87BF8DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>City or urbanized area and State in which the project will be located.</text></clause> <clause id="H7BB476B72DA64311BB42EB6385896861"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Project type.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H45765F3E3DEC4936A1741B092CBAF90E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Anticipated total project cost.</text></clause> <clause id="HB1662FB84D994EDEA4A59B6BCD858A36"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Anticipated share of project costs to be sought under this section.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H55E3E63B0D0B4C6C880488841A48CC33">
              <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text>Date of compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H8A1CAA81E5524E1CB38B7BE7EA084433"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Date on which the project entered the project development phase.</text></clause> <clause id="H1048B2A95E054C7CA6999560CA9A4D49"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Date on which the project entered the engineering phase, if applicable.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0449F97DD9714292A1DE60F9C729AF26"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Status of each permit necessary for the project to proceed, the Federal agency with principal responsibility for review of each necessary permit, and any participating agencies involved in the review of each necessary permit.</text></clause> <clause id="HC102A1C688504B24AB8494A2EC79135A"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Status of the project sponsor in securing non-federal matching funds.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2C92D2A6D33B41E78503C402876DFE17"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Date on which a project grant agreement is anticipated to be executed.</text></clause> <clause id="H2142980CC1DF430E92A9F1DDE1B242C1"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal grant programs for which the project would also be eligible, if applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E41FC5823BA4859B72CBF415FCE4451">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Updates</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall update the information provided under subparagraph (A) not less frequently than monthly.</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H22CCF7AD574A40B5AF294D7DF8F28672"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Project profiles</header><text>The Secretary shall continue to make profiles for projects that are receiving assistance under this section publicly available in an easily identifiable location on the website of the Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HACC6C7ED13B14B6DB642A4ACEBEDEC6F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish an interagency working group to develop and submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6E5A2718FF2F4EFC9663E9C2566ED972"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes projects selected and funded under the Program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60F697F8A00A4CF4865E195EFA09D3F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluates the benefits of the projects’ integration of natural and nature-based features in improving infrastructure resiliency;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0D7C6D6F95340C68BF76E68F24B46AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evaluates program outcomes and best practices;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8E2178AC72F41E798D10692F242EBE5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provides recommendations regarding whether and how to scale the Program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68115E4D9F3B47ABA624C6DE61C43925"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides a benefit-cost analysis of each project selected and funded under the Program that uses the best available data, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H17E00DB746224E94ADE853075C66DE1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>annual maintenance costs necessary for the upkeep of the project’s components;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FF28E094109478B9656CD3BB7F29CB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>risk to structures and infrastructure mitigated by the project;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF35E15522DFB42A6AF140EE38F0CAFF4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>level of protection provided by the project;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9842941C9C9A4625ADFDB6897ED69CAB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>historical damage at the project location;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39C4AD3F19B64A959493B11EEFF2B64B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>information on the benefitting area of the project; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E52E84A5808448495C3C8628AD6E556"><enum>(F)</enum><text>additional data, as applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H82544EB8324A489EA1BD13C7F2758D87"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031, to remain available until expended, of which not more than 2 percent may be used for administrative expenses and technical assistance.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H671832B323034EBF8F2820128A4FCD91"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H38922951C82D491294C65E0215453519"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible transportation asset</header><text>The term <quote>eligible transportation asset</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0ECD03050EA247569F500770CA12E955"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a highway project eligible for assistance under title 23, United States Code;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9DC4412A0E7249F68870E1CF7B737378"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a public transportation facility or service eligible for assistance under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H101B2192CFC2450B9877C48DCA4FE82B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a port facility, including a facility that—</text> <clause id="HD66952BEBEC44A8AACC3AA7FBAE5C9AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>connects a port to other modes of transportation;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H43BC7E25FEBE4C21A2E919DB7C45F6F9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improves the efficiency of evacuations and disaster relief; or</text></clause> <clause id="H7DF93CDDAEA249A28BA97C2C05C6244E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>aids transportation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FEB40476616494182AC4EF67CF2DD8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Region</header><text>The term <quote>region</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H783A6B52F4994328BD03D33324AAC272"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the geographic area served by a metropolitan planning organization;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H624B8B09685F405D941CC3F27B814E53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a multijurisdictional area defined by a consortium of eligible applicants; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6C1983F3AD848EB92A8F6CB71999CD7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other area as the Secretary determines appropriate to address transportation system risk at a corridor or system scale.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

