<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B0FD796222C40B7A8E7FFC94C5FD5DC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6663 IH: Campus Free Speech Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6663</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to ensure that public institutions of higher education eschew policies that improperly constrain the expressive rights of students, and to ensure that private institutions of higher education are transparent about, and responsible for, their chosen speech policies.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H13B788127FCA4A63A07425A83DAE7D89" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H59561260DB2043D6BFD575F3ACFAE76C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Campus Free Speech Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3AED063E3D064FD199D9917C214D8671"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protection of student speech and association rights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 112(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011a">20 U.S.C. 1011a(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBB72C519BDF9424C9C9EA5F0BA844491"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (3); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14D91BADB9D2489AB527D2D6C1BFF3BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BBED444AF534FC78164976D207EBC9A"> 
<paragraph id="H18D54F4199164593A3954C498809A2AD" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB03E3559A3CD49F4B60C8F500CCD6DA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>every individual should be free to profess, and to maintain, the opinion of such individual in matters of religion or philosophy, and that professing or maintaining such opinion should in no way diminish, enlarge, or affect the civil liberties or rights of such individual on the campus of an institution of higher education; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HECCEA500D94B46D28E94133E9286F322"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no public institution of higher education directly or indirectly receiving financial assistance under this Act should limit religious expression, free expression, or any other rights provided under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95907E5D570B49F6A836243486AFCE07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>free speech zones and restrictive speech codes are inherently at odds with the freedom of speech guaranteed by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E8895C704F742A7A3AB24A637EFF9BA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>bias reporting systems are susceptible to abuses that may put them at odds with the freedom of speech guaranteed by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87C603B2171D48639358FCAD1AA3883B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>no public institution of higher education directly or indirectly receiving financial assistance under this Act should restrict the speech of such institution’s students through improperly restrictive zones, codes, or bias reporting systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H1BA5280F3ADF4D139B0C45B7E073C599"><enum>3.</enum><header>Campus speech policies at institutions of higher education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HCA1464381C01431BAA9C34F857C303DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 487(a), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57FFECD607E041468F14D525CE964ECE"> 
<paragraph id="H0E0D4498AA4D425A85430228E626F637"><enum>(30)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H32F96EF7DED046D5AB24CD37FFE84D47"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a public institution (other than an institution described in section 494A(b)(4)), the institution will comply with the expressive activity protections described in section 494A. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06A430B4E1D644BD999BC8B47B1F91D2" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a private institution (other than an institution described in section 494B(e)), the institution will comply with the expressive activity requirements described in section 494B.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9287BC7E5685494097A8673D540C56E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in part G, by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B96B448130B4AD2A1BE22FFAC0D0A51"> <section id="H7342E4B11CE2432AA92ACFF306AC7482"><enum>494A.</enum><header>Campus speech policies at public universities</header> <subsection id="HE3518890902B45D0AB4A567C3955C145"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of expressive activities</header> <paragraph id="H7779CBE5DE444DB9B4BA492B24605473"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <term>expressive activity</term> includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA71E0494F1D24D4981A0D46D31318E65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>peacefully assembling, protesting, speaking, or listening;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E690FAF1FED47CD8541A709496445EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>distributing literature;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB086476B31FB427BBC0E8E3551FC6D67"><enum>(C)</enum><text>carrying a sign; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC68A157DFA704C18A528153BC99BEE66"><enum>(D)</enum><text>circulating a petition; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCDA3913F8E36403484929CE5A3837F14"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other expressive rights guaranteed under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, including religious rights.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38A198C6823047ABA51BA6E78279E990"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>In this section, the term <term>expressive activity</term> does not include unprotected speech (as defined by the precedents of the Supreme Court of the United States).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA666510A4984486294C166D971281E6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expressive activities at an institution</header> 
<paragraph id="H88F258718B1E4429B01ACF47ADB1340F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each public institution of higher education participating in a program under this title may not prohibit, subject to paragraph (2), a person from freely engaging in noncommercial expressive activity in a generally accessible area on the institution’s campus if the person’s conduct is lawful.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E9520B81DB2454584DE2B702D18E78B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>An institution of higher education described in paragraph (1) may not maintain or enforce time, place, or manner restrictions on an expressive activity in a generally accessible area of the institution’s campus unless the restriction—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5924284D702646B7BD94EE1F9A12A6EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is necessary to achieve a compelling governmental interest;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFEB01A93DBBC4F1EA3A062786BE2E7E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is the least restrictive means of furthering that compelling governmental interest;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H44A1AE7BE1DE4D6295989CA7AAD3070C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is based on published, content-neutral, and viewpoint-neutral criteria;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52C02F422E814E609A182DF5A13130DC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>leaves open ample alternative channels for communication; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H073846B2E72E43CE884F5C47B61105AE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provides for spontaneous assembly and distribution of literature.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA1FA719748C4579A01A338E6E9723F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The protections provided under paragraph (1) do not apply to expressive activity in an area on an institution’s campus that is not a generally accessible area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF343EFF7452A4967B5F6D104CEE043E1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nonapplication to service academies</header><text>This section shall not apply to an institution of higher education whose primary purpose is the training of individuals for the military services of the United States, or the merchant marine.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H034C6E991875478F8817E1FD7962BF75"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Causes of action</header> <paragraph id="H91D93B6C48914622AC0BA810104EE08B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The following persons may bring an action in a Federal court of competent jurisdiction to enjoin a violation of subsection (b) or to recover compensatory damages, reasonable court costs, or reasonable attorney fees:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H95D343DA11F044B7B27813A42EE419DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Attorney General.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D924AB8235F4D7B96FAE43FC9471969"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A person claiming that the person's expressive activity rights, as described in subsection (b)(1), were violated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57FE30E7D8D5413285F25550DE438368"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in an action brought under this section, the Federal court shall decide de novo all relevant questions of fact and law, including the interpretation of constitutional, statutory, and regulatory provisions, unless the parties stipulate otherwise. In an action brought under this subsection, if the court finds a violation of subsection (b), the court—</text> <subparagraph id="H57404B722A5B4D0C915BD2977373EB80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall—</text> 
<clause id="H9B84575EA2864851B1757C3FC116C03A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enjoin the violation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8601F59B10C940909DFE2FEFEE21F69B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if a person whose expressive activity rights were violated brought the action, award the person—</text> 
<subclause id="HD86A4C99FF72457FBE1C14F92A2B57E1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than $500 for an initial violation; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H276884E3FCFE4A2D9B34E6EAE629A45C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the person notifies the institution of the violation, $50 for each day the violation continues after the notification if the institution did not act to discontinue the cause of the violation; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE48A333F73F43BEB84CE6A391E505EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may award a prevailing plaintiff—</text> <clause id="H2BEC4DEA4BDD46BCADA756E2CE6A720D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>compensatory damages;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H810294187C2844BEA2B8D35825722B1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reasonable court costs; or</text></clause> <clause id="HAF40F9FAC1304364B583DC42A7F02EA7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reasonable attorney fees.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H614A0F9B73934749A97E6A1696F06D4F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Basis for enactment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection is enacted as an exercise of the enforcement power of the Congress under section 5 of the Fourteenth Amendment to the Constitution to protect expressive activities. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H045CB2072F9844118291301EEE58C8C1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header> <paragraph id="H9EA38EB8322B4DE78B89A722C23FC89F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), an action under subsection (c) may not be brought later than 1 year after the date of the violation. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2093D52C2824B61A67456CF14C4C814"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuing violation</header><text>Each day that a violation of subsection (b) continues after an initial violation of subsection (b), and each day that an institution's policy in violation of subsection (b) remains in effect, shall constitute a continuing violation of subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H292480CE86284D849D5662114B6DDDEF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>For a continuing violation described in paragraph (2), the limitation described in paragraph (1) shall extend to 1 year after the date on which the most recent violation occurs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5676532EBD384A40B3B53859D60407C7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal review of speech policies</header> 
<paragraph id="HBF21688CD614486F80E50D2E30290E62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No eligibility for funds</header> 
<subparagraph id="H0C926FD98B56414AA49587DE8522AA8C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No public institution of higher education shall be eligible to receive funds under this Act, including participation in any program under this title, if the Secretary determines that the institution—</text> <clause id="H4BBE15BA61E44B50BA5F5D34FB6234F7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintains a policy that infringes upon the expressive rights of students under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H570D4D88A7EA4A73B7442CF43F7595B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintains or enforces time, place, or manner restrictions on an expressive activity in a generally accessible area of the institution's campus that do not comply with subparagraphs (A) through (E) of subsection (b)(2). </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5124A42FD2854669BB959748D8A6E60C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not conduct an investigation for purposes of making a determination under subparagraph (A) with respect to an institution of higher education, unless such an investigation is conducted under paragraph (4) with respect to a complaint received under paragraph (2). </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H92A12AD0A93A427A879095D53FC9A14D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Court review</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary’s determinations under this subsection shall be reviewed de novo with respect to all relevant questions of fact and law, including the interpretation of constitutional, statutory, and regulatory provisions, unless the parties stipulate otherwise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H987D7DFD4E1946568AA8AD7BF7A40F14"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation of an employee to receive complaints</header><text>The Secretary shall designate an employee in the Office of Postsecondary Education of the Department to receive complaints (whether electronically or by mail) from students or student organizations at a given public institution of higher education, or from any other person or organization, regarding policies at the institution that meet the description of clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H313C867529AF458181BB3A5F85CA6DA6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Complaint</header><text>A complaint submitted under subparagraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H64C3211594FD453281247225D1C0AA4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include the provision of the institution’s policy the complainant believes meets the description of clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (1)(A), along with any evidence regarding the operation and enforcement of such policy the complainant deems relevant; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H64CD30A01A8345109C399EB57496D1AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include an argument and any other supplemental information as to why the policy in question meets such description.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29C1AC2B0BCC49D79EF6E60BE3A04006"><enum>(4)</enum><header>System of review</header> <subparagraph id="H804B665FB22F480ABE3575D09E5C682E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First stage review</header> <clause id="H6D6B39E8710345A2878325871658A109"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Request for response</header><text>Not later than 7 days after the date of receipt of a complaint under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall review the complaint and request a response to the complaint from the institution.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H54BF8D44043F4B3083E9EA6CDA8C0669"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Institution response</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date the Secretary requests a response under clause (i), the institution shall—</text> <subclause id="H35FD02EFA0664EA382D63D76F5FDCB8E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>certify to the Secretary that the institution has entirely withdrawn the policy that occasioned the complaint;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H300858D24F804B2C9812050A6AC94D10"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit a revised policy for review by the Secretary; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF9559DD41ADC44A788E5DD745D5C07B6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>submit a defense of the policy that occasioned the complaint.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H716FCECCAB624AC2ABB23302C069E145"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Availability to complainant</header> 
<subclause id="HA994FC524A5F4BF891D9B64DD3A5C190"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 7 days after the date of receipt of a revised policy or defense of the original policy as submitted by the institution pursuant to clause (ii), the Secretary shall make available to the complainant a copy of such revised policy or defense. </text></subclause> <subclause id="H356E8268DBDB4B75846B15A46405C118"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Response by complainant</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of a revised policy or defense of the original policy under subclause (I), the complainant may submit to the Secretary a response to the revised policy or defense of the original policy.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD8E497A992B44AD6B2ABA3018737BF00"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Submission to the institution of response</header><text>Not later than 7 days after the date of receipt of a response under subclause (II), the Secretary shall submit to the institution a copy of such response. </text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H2102460DF3E444138F69A0AB07B6C961"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Determinations</header><text>If the institution declines to entirely withdraw the policy that occasioned the complaint and either submits a revised policy for review or submits a defense of the policy that occasioned the complaint, the Secretary shall, not later than 60 days after the date of the deadline for a response by the complaint as described in clause (iii)(II), make one of the following determinations:</text> 
<subclause id="H308D91AC2399487490439106A9447BF9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Determine that the complaint in question has insufficient merit to proceed to Second Stage Review described in subparagraph (B).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0D47955723F2428FBEBF54062763E1B3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Determine that the complaint in question has sufficient merit to proceed to Second Stage Review described in subparagraph (B).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H18BC712238FE4B4A816D1FFB7C31E2F6"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 7 days after the date the Secretary makes a determination under clause (iv), the Secretary shall notify the institution and the complainant of such determination. </text></clause> <clause id="H3629F128A5FF4ACFAABD381F7A6F8805"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>End</header><text>The determination under clause (iv) shall constitute the end of First Stage Review.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C72615F36564734889F042CF5233AD9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Second stage review</header> 
<clause id="HE332C8760F4C49BD981B06142F130D2F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a Second Stage Review, the Secretary shall notify the institution and the complainant of the commencement of the Second Stage Review, and shall give the institution the option of entirely withdrawing the policy that occasioned the complaint or submitting a revised policy for review within 30 days of the commencement of the Second Stage Review. In such notification submitted to the institution and complainant, the Secretary shall indicate the relevant sections of the institution’s policy in question and explain why these sections may be out of compliance. </text></clause> <clause id="H753086D0409E4AA680DC336FE01A7474"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>Not later than 90 days from the commencement of the Second Stage Review, the Secretary shall determine whether the policy that occasioned the complaint, or the revised policy submitted during the First Stage Review, or the revised policy submitted within the first 30 days of the Second Stage Review, is in violation of student rights under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States or of the restrictions on the regulation of speech by time, place, and manner set forth in this section, thereby ending Second Stage Review.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3FC49F423EA348F9ADAB45B28B3F3CD6"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>During Second Stage Review, the Secretary may conduct an investigation in which further information may be sought or requested from the complainant, the institution, or any other pertinent source.</text></clause> <clause id="HE7A8F5D65DAD4B26985B88C298C74AB7"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Certification of withdrawal</header><text>At any point during the Second Stage Review, the institution in question may certify to the Secretary that it has entirely withdrawn the policy that occasioned the complaint, thereby ending the Second Stage Review.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4D5F08C8CFA34F30B7A8DADF9D28CD1C"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Notification and justification</header><text>If the Secretary determines by the conclusion of Second Stage Review that the policy that occasioned the complaint or the revised policy submitted for review during First Stage Review or Second Stage Review is consistent with the expressive rights of students under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and the restrictions on the regulation of speech by time, place, and manner set forth in this Act—</text> <subclause id="H85531085E6E243809B0782C0E40C45E1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary shall notify the complainant and the institution of such determination not more than 7 days after the date of the determination; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6BF6067A45BC459DB79D5FB31912D648"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary shall explain and justify such determination in a written decision citing relevant legal precedent, copies of which shall be sent to the complainant, the institution, the authorizing committees, and made available for public inspection, including for online reading by the public.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H81463B00DC5F4EB2936D45D2B7009CFB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination that institution is out of compliance</header> <clause id="H857FCBEC626C4FCEA6A4056EF4E75A9D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, upon completion of the Second Stage Review, the Secretary determines that the policy that occasioned the complaint, or the revised policy submitted for review during the First Stage Review or Second Stage Review, violates the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States or the restrictions on the regulation of speech set forth in this section, the Secretary shall notify the complainant and the institution not more than 7 days after the date of completion of Second Stage Review that the institution is out of compliance with the requirements for receiving funds under this Act, including participation in any program under this title, but will be granted a grace period of 120 days to return to compliance before being formally stripped of eligibility.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5DBC88B14F804A6AB5D681387B27E2A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Posting; explanation; final review</header><text>As part of the notification under clause (i), the Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="H88031D3379FC4D9296C66621A26578E7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>require the institution to post the determination of the Secretary on the website of the institution within 2 clicks of the homepage, without a paywall, email login, or other restriction to access;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFDCEBCD14DA041C59FA8372FA9B22F6C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>explain and justify the determination of the Secretary in a written decision citing relevant legal precedent, copies of which shall be sent to the complainant, the institution, the authorizing committees, and made available for public inspection, including for online reading by the public; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFFA095375A4C4231A0F1A2DE27B49DB9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>inform the institution that Final Review has begun and that the institution must either certify to the Secretary that it has entirely withdrawn the policy that occasioned the complaint, or submit a revised policy for review to the Secretary not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of notice of the conclusion of Second Stage Review.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E04A8712FDA4091B4825D682494B011"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Final review</header> 
<clause id="HA549EA213E6D4E66B93C408EFC2861F5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an institution submits a revised policy for review as described in subparagraph (C)(ii)(III), the Secretary shall review such revised policy and determine not later than 120 days after the date of commencement of Final Review whether the revised policy is consistent with the expressive rights of students under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and with the restrictions on the regulation of speech by time, place, and manner set forth in this section.</text></clause> <clause id="HCEE76DB3F6E74DF69982D49B4D49D0AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination of compliance</header><text>If the Secretary determines, as described in clause (i), that the revised policy is consistent with the expressive rights of students under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and with the restrictions on the regulation of speech by time, place, and manner set forth in this section, the Secretary shall notify the complainant and the institution of such determination not more than 7 days after the date the determination is made, thereby ending the final Stage Review.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H67B30EC1B74742BFBFA98AEFE6ED62D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Determination of violation</header><text>If the Secretary determines, as described in clause (i), that the revised policy violates the expressive rights of students under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States or the restrictions on the regulation of speech by time, place, and manner set forth in this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="HFD4D614E9C324F75815E2A040F885F0A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify the complainant and the institution of such determination not more than 7 days after the date the determination is made, thereby ending the final Stage Review; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8ADE5A271E354B3C9D10324B7D35DD7D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>explain and justify the determination in a written decision citing relevant legal precedent, copies of which shall be sent to the complainant, the institution, and made available for public inspection, including for online reading by the public.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8056BFE7C2BA4ABD8DAEFBE4ADB765EE"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Loss of eligibility</header> <clause id="H70005914BB494CA286E0693EF4EF735C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary determines, during the Final Stage Review, that the institution’s policy in question violates the expressive rights of students under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States or the restrictions on the regulation of speech by time, place, and manner set forth in this section, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subclause id="HF90A954A3FAB45CBAF691F40764C0C00"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify the complainant and the institution not more than 7 days after the date of the determination that the institution will lose eligibility to receive funds under this Act, including participation in any program under this title, in accordance with this subparagraph;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE2D65F8D282544A4A904A60F4B474B0E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the institution that the loss of eligibility shall take effect beginning with any student notified of acceptance for admission to the institution during the award year subsequent to the award year during which the determination is made, and that no restoration of eligibility for ineligible students in subsequent award years will occur prior to the beginning of the third award year subsequent to the award year during which the determination is made;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H80921D82E1474EB684D5C6767010055F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>explain and justify the determination in a written decision citing relevant legal precedent, copies of which shall be sent to the complainant, the institution, the authorizing committees, and made available for public inspection, including for online reading by the public; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H104457B260B5440C87994404616439E4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>require the institution to post the determination of the Secretary on the website of the institution, within two clicks of the homepage, without a paywall, email login, or other restriction to access.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HC1B58FCF75C8435FA5A00A9F6093932D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Continued eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each student enrolled at the institution during the award year in which eligibility is lost as described in this subparagraph, and each student notified of acceptance for admission to the institution during the award year in which eligibility is lost as described in this subparagraph, shall continue to be eligible to participate, through the institution, in programs funded under this Act during the 3-year period after the date of the loss of eligibility.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32597E17C54A4E50BDFA130E11F2E733"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Restoration of eligibility</header> <clause id="H5DADDE4FCC514F3AB7359A79D37D365E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 7 days after the loss of eligibility under subparagraph (E), the Secretary shall inform the institution that the institution may restore eligibility, either by certifying to the Secretary that the institution has entirely withdrawn the policy that precipitated loss of eligibility, or by submitting a revised policy for review at any time following the failure of the Final Review.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H80F13CD7E3B3412EA2062DE64A674621"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Review of revised policy</header><text>The Secretary shall review a revised policy submitted for review after the loss of eligibility and determine not later than 120 days after the date the revised policy is submitted whether such policy is consistent with the expressive rights of students under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and with the restrictions on the regulation of speech by time, place, and manner set forth in this Act.</text></clause> <clause id="H215FB19655B34DDDA3FA6C1D9D639C96"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>While conducting a review to restore eligibility under this subparagraph, the Secretary may conduct an investigation in which further information may be sought or requested from the institution, or any other source the Secretary determines pertinent.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA10E1F5FF5C54A8295AC5BA8C68FE240"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Written decision</header><text>In making a determination of whether a revised policy submitted for review after the loss of eligibility is either consistent or inconsistent with the expressive rights of students under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and with the restrictions on the regulation of speech by time, place, and manner set forth in this Act, the Secretary shall explain and justify the determination in a written decision citing relevant legal precedent, copies of which shall be sent to the complainant, the institution, the authorizing committees, and made available for public inspection, including for online reading by the public.</text></clause> <clause id="H079D4BD1516A4DC58F931AA3F2E87565"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Limit on review</header><text>The Secretary may conduct not more than 1 review to restore eligibility for a single institution in any given award year.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1537FE95488C42D3B2ECAC6828176E25"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text>If an institution certifies to the Secretary that the policy that precipitated the loss of eligibility has been entirely withdrawn, or if Secretary determines that the revised policy submitted for review is consistent with the expressive rights of students under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and with the restrictions on the regulation of speech by time, place, and manner set forth in this section, the institution’s eligibility to receive funds under this Act, including participation in any program under this title, shall be restored not earlier than the beginning of the third award year following the year in which notification of loss of eligibility was received.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H383935D20E2A4D7D80F8C0403C92B3A2"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Good faith representation</header> <clause id="H7BFF0082BE84455E8F95A1DFEC4DBB3E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall inform any institution undergoing review of its campus speech policies that it expects the institution to represent its policies, along with any proposed revisions in such policies, in good faith.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE0C503D7B7C6403682687480F8EA54E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Misrepresentation</header> 
<subclause id="H527834EE4390436D986FFCDCBD62BAEE"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Complaints</header><text>A student, student organization, or any other person or organization may file, with the employee in the Office of Postsecondary Education of the Department designated by the Secretary under paragraph (2) to receive complaints, a complaint that an institution has substantially misrepresented its speech policies, or withheld information requested by the Secretary during an investigation, or attempted to circumvent the review process by reinstituting a policy under review in a substantially similar form without informing the Secretary.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD1564D49467A43879AF0FE3CF3679D3F"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Loss of eligibility</header><text>If the Secretary determines upon investigation, or after receiving a complaint under subclause (I), that an institution has substantially misrepresented its speech policies, or withheld information requested by the Secretary during an investigation, or attempted to circumvent the review process by reinstituting a policy under review in a substantially similar form without informing the Secretary, the institution shall lose eligibility to receive funds under this Act, including participation in any program under this title.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HAD258D9526AD41CBA4D6A44FA33DBFC7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Loss of eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an institution loses eligibility under clause (ii), the Secretary shall notify the institution, not later than 7 days after the determination, that the loss of eligibility shall take effect beginning with any student notified of acceptance for admission to the institution during the award year subsequent to the award year during which the determination is made, and that no restoration of eligibility for students admitted in subsequent award years will occur prior to the beginning of the third award year subsequent to the award year during which the determination is made.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA41BBFB9705F4200BDD383C71EDB2A10"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Retaliation prohibited</header> <paragraph id="HA0BFE93FEC4541D2895D42798DA4AC63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person may intimidate, threaten, coerce, or discriminate against any individual because the individual has made a report or complaint, testified, assisted, or participated or refused to participate in any manner in an investigation, proceeding, or hearing under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A9E2D4A49F3454788725732E63A632C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific circumstances</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB8B1019BC79848599952B8E97E1BE77B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exercise of first amendment rights</header><text>The exercise of rights protected under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States does not constitute retaliation prohibited under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9E7FEFCB41584FF98B5C229023CC31F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Code of conduct violation for materially false statement</header><text>Charging an individual with a code of conduct violation for making a materially false statement in bad faith in the course of a grievance proceeding under this section does not constitute retaliation prohibited under paragraph (1). A determination regarding responsibility, alone, is not sufficient to conclude that any party made a materially false statement in bad faith.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H00151B30D3FE414E927266725ED9B0F4" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A public institution of higher education participating in a program under this title may seek judicial review of an agency action under this section in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H38A677FE69CA46C5BF27E2B81DF2932D"><enum>494B.</enum><header>Campus speech policies at private universities</header> <subsection id="H3A892D6C46E34E00A8EDBC11D609929B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each private institution of higher education eligible to receive funds under this Act, including any program under this title, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H69BF280C83DA4CFCAD5BD087B6F03205"><enum>(1)</enum><text>post in one place on the website of the institution all policies that pertain to the protection and regulation of the expressive rights of students, including the right to submit a complaint under this section, within 2 clicks of the homepage, without a paywall, email login, or other restriction to access; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D4D62BD414F45D6883259C2F2E3B619"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include a copy of such policies in a handbook distributed to new students.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD09FE6053A954680A0AEB2B52BDFE956"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibility for full policy disclosure</header><text>Each private institution of higher education described in subsection (a) shall include with the copy of the policies described in subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H34D6A60E92084698ABBAA49BAF66179E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement affirming that all policies pertinent to the protection and regulation of the expressive rights of students have been disclosed in the manner required by this section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FEBD8C3675B4135891BECBA5F8C36E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement affirming that publication of such policies as required by this section and instructions for students on how to contact the employee designated in the Office of Postsecondary Education in the Department under subsection (d)(1) to file a complaint.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE664C18BE7154A32AB90C84A4345363C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cause of action</header> <paragraph id="HA6F2CBB6649942449444BD898A5981C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A student claiming that a private institution of higher education in which the student is enrolled has violated published policy regarding expressive rights imposed by this section may bring an action in a Federal court of competent jurisdiction to enjoin such violation or to recover compensatory damages, reasonable court costs, or reasonable attorney fees. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27CD6DDCE18B4B16BECFE3E35B07201E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in an action brought under this subsection, the Federal court shall decide de novo all relevant questions of fact and law, including the interpretation of constitutional, statutory, and regulatory provisions, unless the parties stipulate otherwise. In an action brought under this subsection, if the court finds a violation of subsection (b), the court— </text> <subparagraph id="HE9D5473F27E14AFEB2D6D12AA6F1CB8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall—</text> 
<clause id="H751DAE7C5C8848F38E0F54E460AF0DEA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enjoin the violation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8842A1680B5E484C8609E77051686507"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>award the student—</text> 
<subclause id="H7A3E80CC6103487EA210B63026017318"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than $500 for an initial violation; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H18FAD004214640D1A4FF8DD879E6EBC4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the student notifies the institution of the violation, $50 for each day the violation continues after the notification if the institution did not act to discontinue the cause of the violation; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2344481D8A454540BB7DC6432BA97BC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may award a prevailing plaintiff—</text> <clause id="H58A808528D3642CA94A5CCA09E4DFF8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>compensatory damages;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H869837EF43204F69945ECE98706C84B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reasonable court costs; or</text></clause> <clause id="H1BCDF52CF2334254B8E5B778C9DC1F8C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reasonable attorney fees.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3079070D12B3438EAEB27B9FDB0FA462"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Secretarial requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HB0C8B3F9B19B4F6F83CF0F492578BE28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation of an employee</header><text>The Secretary shall designate an employee in the Office of Postsecondary Education in the Department who shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H6AC15BA975994EEDBD67CBF6DD96283B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receive copies of all complaints pertaining to the protection and regulation of the expressive rights of students at private institutions of higher education that receive funds under this section, including any programs under this title;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE378D03AE25479E9ACB86014D789436"><enum>(B)</enum><text>preserve all records of such policies for a period of not less than 10 years;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H530517BA53C14BA6B11163FD12200700"><enum>(C)</enum><text>receive complaints from students, student organizations, or from any other person or organization, that believes a private institution of higher education has not disclosed a policy pertaining to the protection and regulation of the expressive rights of students as required by this section, is enforcing a policy pertaining to the expressive rights of students that has not been disclosed as required by this section, or has failed to make a full policy disclosure, for the enforcement of speech policies, as required by this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E3BDF238BFF4B39B1414FFFD60FDA20"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not more than 7 days after the date of receipt of a complaint under subparagraph (C), review the complaint and request a response from the institution;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CF838E217C942F48539142F54AF6B2B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>undertake an investigation, in response to a complaint under subparagraph (C), to determine whether a private institution of higher education has failed to disclose a policy pertaining to the protection and regulation of the expressive rights of students as required by this section or is enforcing a policy pertaining to the expressive rights of students that has not been disclosed as required by this section; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94AA8C98D28F4B30BD6A3221AD034DDE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>determine, not later than 120 days after the date of receipt of a complaint, whether the private institution of higher education in question has failed to disclose a policy pertaining to the protection and regulation of the expressive rights of students as required by this section or is enforcing a policy pertaining to the expressive rights of students that has not been disclosed as required by this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF71F59AF5D4498BABF0649757EFB8B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Loss of eligibility</header> <subparagraph id="H2ADC49D8BF904038B53A00F4B0BAF682"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a private institution of higher education has failed to disclose a policy pertaining to the protection and regulation of the expressive rights of students as required by this section or is enforcing a policy pertaining to the expressive rights of students that has not been disclosed as required by this section, the Secretary shall notify the institution and the complainant, not more than 7 days after the date of such determination, that the institution is out of compliance with the requirements for receiving funds under this Act, including participation in any program under this title, but will be granted a grace period of 60 days to return to compliance before formally losing eligibility for receiving funds under this Act, including participation in any program under this title.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C208E66C8A044F490BD03CCF09B67DA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specifications in notification</header><text>As part of the notification under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall specify which policies need to be disclosed and published in order for eligibility to be restored.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H672A0936FD274C3AAEA8608439C75E7D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification of loss of eligibility</header> <clause id="H3355B438A6BF4D8FB69B2674FD80F10E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary determines that, 60 days after being notified that the institution is out of compliance as described in subparagraph (A), the institution has failed to return to compliance by making the appropriate speech policy disclosures, the Secretary shall notify the institution and the complainant, not more than 7 days after the date of such determination—</text> 
<subclause id="H0E7D853424B74DC587AA40C1A9C85439"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that the institution will lose eligibility to receive funds under this Act, including participation in any program under this title;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF8BF2EA00C5340B88068DCA17A771D08"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the loss of eligibility shall take effect beginning with any student notified of acceptance for admission to the institution during the award year subsequent to the award year during which the determination is made, and that no restoration of eligibility for ineligible students in subsequent years will occur prior to the beginning of the third award year subsequent to the award year during which the determination is made; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9538365F81854E69BBCB202B9507EBD9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>that the institution shall post the determination of the Secretary on the website of the institution, within two clicks of the homepage, without a paywall, email login, or other restriction to access.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H81A575496E0944B593D1361C166F084D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Continued eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each student enrolled at the institution during the award year in which eligibility is lost as described in this subparagraph, and each student notified of acceptance for admission to the institution during the award year in which eligibility is lost as described in this subparagraph, shall continue to be eligible to participate, through the institution, in programs funded under this Act during the 3-year period after the date of the loss of eligibility.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC87A6BFB110A41A09DD1FCDE1BC1B634"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restoration of eligibility</header> 
<subparagraph id="H17E4419BB34B484EB0E20A724416F485"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 7 days after the loss of eligibility under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall inform the institution that the institution may restore eligibility by making the appropriate speech policy disclosures, as directed by the Secretary in conformity with this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4F4FCEFB08649C68EDF925774D7CDA5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Secretary shall review any policy disclosures and determine whether the policy disclosures are sufficient to restore eligibility for receiving funds under this Act, including participation in any program under this title, not later than 120 days after the date of receipt of such disclosures or statement.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H459AD7164D92469FB854C2A23D4017E0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>While conducting a review to restore eligibility under this paragraph, the Secretary may conduct an investigation in which further information may be sought or requested from the institution, or other source pertinent to the case. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83B9E3F17FD5435597D3F5ADE5D26112"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text>If the Secretary determines that the institution under review to restore eligibility under this paragraph has made the policy disclosures as required by this section, the institution’s eligibility to receive funds under this Act, including participation in any program under this title, shall be restored not earlier than the beginning of the third award year following the year in which notification of loss of eligibility was received.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H95268FCBAFFA429FA21D2E13CBF247E8"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limit on review</header><text>The Secretary may conduct not more than 1 review to restore eligibility for a single institution in any given award year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H577AFC1EBDBF46619E84D00D2FC87C3E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not conduct an investigation under this subsection for purposes of making a determination under paragraph (2)(A) with respect to an institution of higher education, unless such an investigation is conducted with respect to a complaint received under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0D36E13D1DB14253A1598090737686F7" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Nonapplication to certain institutions</header><text>This section shall not apply to an institution of higher education that is controlled by a religious organization.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDB3D9F33EFA44E9A9AB47FEB2764AC8E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A private institution of higher education participating in a program under this title may seek judicial review of an agency action under this section in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>


