<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBB9178E8849D4B51BB4608EBBBB5AE9E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9617 IH: Coordinating and Harnessing America’s Recovery of Minerals Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9617</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260709">July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to coordinate a National Critical Mineral Recovery Strategy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD8DF4563FD384A789545777680C28DD4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC82EEEA7476B4F12A40926B667867616" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Coordinating and Harnessing America’s Recovery of Minerals Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CHARM Act</short-title></quote>. </text> </section> <section id="HA87A16EBBD0E4ADCBA4609B9F1FE47F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Critical Mineral Recovery Strategy</header> <subsection id="HE7DA294E0E5544209E719191959BDAF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle B of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6911">42 U.S.C. 6911 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H4D0CDBD0D3834133B0EF71B25E79D0A3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7A6EEF30BEA6415BA47AB1F925A6C512"><enum>2009.</enum><header>National Critical Mineral Recovery Strategy</header> 
<subsection id="H61AD45655A6C497A8B4FD0EDF201634B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy</header> 
<paragraph id="HA12CFB7C5BEA4E43829782E5E07FA665"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall, in consultation with the heads of other Federal agencies that the Administrator determines to be relevant, develop and carry out a National Critical Mineral Recovery Strategy (in this section referred to as the <quote>Strategy</quote>) for the purpose of coordinating Federal efforts to recover critical minerals from discarded materials. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4B4A9143AD4414D92C76A8F32D6D26F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>In developing the Strategy under paragraph (1), the Administrator, in consultation with the heads of other Federal agencies described in paragraph (1), shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H64F19EB7ECAF472B9C7E4D0BDF2AAADD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify programs administered by, and authorities of, the Administrator that relate to the recovery of critical minerals from discarded materials;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E4594B22CB04FB088D4237C00A918AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify programs administered by, and authorities of, the other relevant Federal agencies that relate to the recovery of critical minerals from discarded materials;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF87768B433A54E17BF0934D1C7153F07" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify, and consider for inclusion in the Strategy, opportunities that expand the recovery of critical minerals, as well as that address legal, technological, and other barriers to recovering such critical minerals from discarded materials;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F802D44015145268D7AFDF32ED60CFE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identify, and consider for inclusion in the Strategy, opportunities to recover critical minerals from discarded materials that are mining waste or residuals or metal processing waste;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97A3B224278046868A2785E9CD80C839"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identify discarded materials that are potential sources of critical minerals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H11D61A1DB8E74E3BAEC43A877D6E6476"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identify potential critical minerals that may be in discarded materials;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4911891332749FB819836A9580F20D5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>evaluate the role of recovered critical minerals, and the sources from which such critical minerals were recovered from discarded materials, in strengthening domestic supply chains of critical minerals; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H313C608BE9DB4ACAA3A7963BFE3F8DE0"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify opportunities to recover critical minerals from discarded materials in a manner that minimizes risk to human health and the environment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC9410BFAAC504705A046506AEA7DB318"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="H76239EC647D94810A664C33FB6DE30D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, and every 2 years thereafter, the Administrator shall transmit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, and make publicly available, a report that contains the Strategy and a description of activities carried out pursuant to subsection (a). </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69F1CEAB61E04DB29C8CC6EA4630C8C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The Administrator shall include in the report transmitted under paragraph (1) a description of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H865544C5394449DB96B9095D71472A42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any actions taken by the Administrator to facilitate the recovery of critical minerals from discarded materials pursuant to the Strategy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDAD0E665ADE405289ED8EC404C061BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any actions taken by another Federal agency, in coordination with the Administrator, to facilitate the recovery of critical minerals from discarded materials pursuant to the Strategy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA2C97B89FCC417A85098230DB313D55"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any ongoing or planned actions by the Administrator to facilitate the recovery of critical minerals from discarded materials pursuant to the Strategy; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7598B18849C242DE946A5DC9C3631646"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations for legislation to support the developing and carrying out of the Strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E812C02D0674107B8509B8E197AC6AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Critical mineral defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>critical mineral</term> has the meaning given such term in section 7002(a)(3) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(c)(3)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H443D7EB7F2084699830FBDF5D30DC5E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents contained in section 1001 of the Solid Waste Disposal Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2008 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H297B1B131C65475EA1AB04EF3754F847" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2009. National Critical Mineral Recovery Strategy.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

