<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE126F185727D4907A0AB6F1DB82B9EC3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6980 IH: No Occupation of Venezuela Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6980</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260108">January 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the availability of Federal funds for certain United States assertions with respect to Venezuela, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4D0C504773D34A618BB81A4943660156" style="OLC"><section id="H2F163598784546488A5D71ED507201D6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Occupation of Venezuela Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NOVA Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H142B329558AD4EED91447689DAE80104"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on availability of Federal funds for United States occupation or internal administration of Venezuela</header><subsection id="HCC55CDB3C230433A93651587F51C8FAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), no Federal funds may be obligated or expended to support, directly or indirectly, any assertion of United States possession, supervision, jurisdiction, control, or sovereignty in and over the territory or resources of Venezuela, including through the deployment of the United States Armed Forces in Venezuela.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD2E5B502A37C4E5987F8208D8C8960E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Property for diplomatic purposes</header><paragraph id="HB1D4C3B34E1842E3921A1531C557B979"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority to acquire</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever, after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President of the United States may find that any properties in Venezuela, owned by the Government of Venezuela or by private persons, would be suitable for a diplomatic or consular establishment of the United States, notwithstanding the prohibition under subsection (a), the President may, with the approval of the such Government and in exchange for the conveyance of title to the United States, purchase or otherwise acquire such property, including by transferring to such Government or such private person title to any properties of the United States in Venezuela.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F5A8D5600E340BFB7A165B6C1C24B83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to use previous acquisitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever, after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President of the United States may find that any properties of the United States in Venezuela would be suitable for a diplomatic or consular establishment of the United States, the President shall designate the same by the issuance of a proclamation or proclamations, and title to any property so designated shall continue to be vested in fee simple in the United States notwithstanding the prohibition under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2883E37AC8CA4AF5B19368AC81BCC957"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Previously acquired United States property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to property of the United States in Venezuela, the title to which was conveyed to the United States prior to January 1, 2026.</text></subsection><subsection id="H81A178EF0A974DDFABBE251F0B12B8BD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (a) may not be construed to alter or affect any authorization, limitation, or other provision relating to the availability of Federal funds for the provision of emergency humanitarian aid.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

