<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6882012E9BB746C7A5D3E3ED307B2053" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8117 IH: Fair Treatment of Religious Organizations Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8117</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure fair treatment of certain charitable organizations and recipients of Federal financial assistance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0F4B73910672444A8828207C0AF002F7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H608AB75E6E9A4A6C9E4E729B24035D80" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Treatment of Religious Organizations Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC49F0E11616F4782840493DEBBFAEC0B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Determination of religious purpose for purposes of tax-exempt status</header> <paragraph id="H3F23C254009A48E0854170AD0F546FCB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">Section 501</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF6B86DDB86D346E4B4FF7656A6CCCF4B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H8F40679301A3442980DE009D5214AC2E"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Determination of religious purpose</header> 
<paragraph id="HA559F1EC2EFB4597A0C67084CF8B191B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, any determination of whether a purpose is a religious purpose shall be made without regard to the organization’s religious beliefs or practices concerning marriage, sexuality, or gender identity, and without regard to whether such beliefs or practices are otherwise inconsistent with law or public policy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08A97D90A88F40BC893A6A2296E774EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interpretation of religious belief</header><text>A belief shall not fail to be treated as a religious belief for purposes of paragraph (1) merely because such belief is not compelled by or central to a system of religion.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2A402C893474DC28F9678E671C12A00"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="H86489FF9112A4C49A160B1BC484956C4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Nondiscriminatory Federal financial assistance</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">No branch, department, or agency of the Federal Government shall, with respect to any employer that is a religious corporation, religious association, religious educational institution, or religious society that applies for or receives Federal grants, loans, or other financial assistance under a contract or subcontract, grant, purchase order, or cooperative agreement with the Federal Government, discriminate against or disadvantage such employer for employment actions or practices consistent with the right to employ persons who share the religious beliefs and comply with the religious standards of the employer, including the exemptions and defenses described in sections 702(a) and 703(e)(2) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-1">42 U.S.C. 2000e–1(a)</external-xref> and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-2">42 U.S.C. 2000e–2(e)(2)</external-xref>), section 103(d) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12113">42 U.S.C. 12113(d)</external-xref>), the Religious Freedom Restoration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000bb">42 U.S.C. 2000bb et seq.</external-xref>), and the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

