<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE94CD7E7ABE84D9B9CB8C51C2284AA65" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1322 IH: Condemning racist rhetoric targeting Indian and Chinese Americans, reaffirming that immigrants from all backgrounds are vital to the United States, and calling on all elected officials to refrain from language that promotes racial or ethnic division.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1322</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260522">May 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning racist rhetoric targeting Indian and Chinese Americans, reaffirming that immigrants from all backgrounds are vital to the United States, and calling on all elected officials to refrain from language that promotes racial or ethnic division.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas immigrants from all over the world contribute every day to the Nation’s economy, security, culture, and prosperity;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all communities in the United States, regardless of race, national origin, ethnicity, or religion, deserve to live freely without hateful rhetoric, hate crimes, and bigotry being targeted at them;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Indian Americans and Chinese Americans have long histories in the country, including waves of immigrants in the early 1900s and mid 1800s respectively;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas economic research has found that Indian and Chinese immigrants and their descendants contribute hundreds of billions of dollars to the Nation’s GDP through spending, support millions of jobs, and own hundreds of thousands of businesses, thereby strengthening the long-term fiscal outlook of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas rhetoric that targets individuals based on national origin or ethnicity undermines the fundamental American values of equality, pluralism, and opportunity, and leads to increased violence and discrimination against these communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there has been an alarming rise in anti-Chinese sentiment across the United States since March 2020, driven in part by misinformation and rhetoric that has stigmatized individuals of Chinese origin in connection with the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since the 2024 Presidential election, there has been an alarming surge in anti-Asian hate online, including the proliferation of slurs, harassment, and threats of violence across major social media platforms;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this surge has been driven in significant part by an increase in anti-South Asian rhetoric, with online slur usage rising by approximately 75 percent between November 2024 and January 2025, including documented increases in hate messages targeting Indian immigrants across platforms such as TikTok, Instagram, YouTube, Facebook, and X;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on or about April 22, 2026, the President amplified a post on Truth Social that characterized individuals from India and China in sweeping and derogatory terms;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the content amplified by the President stated that <quote>a baby here becomes an instant citizen, and then they bring the entire family in from China or India or some other <quote>hellhole</quote> on the planet</quote>, portraying their presence in the United States as degrading the Nation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President shared racist language that suggested that immigrants from India and China are <quote>not like the European Americans of today and their ancestors</quote> and asserted that <quote>the idea of the melting pot is long over</quote>, invoking discriminatory comparisons between immigrant groups;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the racism promoted by the President further described those aligned with protecting birthright citizenship as <quote>gangsters with laptops</quote>, in the context of a broader attack that repeatedly singled out immigrants from India and China as abusing the system and <quote>turn[ing] us into a colony of China … [and] also India</quote>, thereby reinforcing a narrative that casts immigrants and their advocates, particularly those of Indian and Chinese origin, as organized, predatory actors undermining the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the content further asserted that individuals from India and China lack loyalty to the United States and invoked harmful stereotypes tied to national origin that are not based in fact: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H42622580BBF4472A895EB31E02B9D16E"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2DDC251EF7A945B1A39B958DA6ADD083"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H9EE1B1C9B87A47EB9D04E26C4D28DD99"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the racist language propagated by the President against individuals of Indian and Chinese origin;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0ED8312A3C994C51A2F6D748DF97C269"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affirms that immigrants, including Indian Americans and Chinese Americans, are vital to the fabric of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBA1FA2A70BB4A74A4BCBE839F3129A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on all elected officials, including the President, to refrain from using language that promotes racial or ethnic division or stereotypes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0277A51FE2C4E129795E92EDBC423E2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affirms that attacks based on national origin or ethnicity are un-American; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FD0BBE27D434211888FD2AB8B3CA5E1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>condemns in the strongest possible terms all forms of hate against communities across the United States, including Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

