<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0A670CA84F594021BD8DB2D388F97038" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9349 IH: Voting Systems Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9349</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 52 and title 18, United States Code, to ensure the integrity of voting systems.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H61A653E6673741E5BC83A7F9A30EFFB2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H07D44DC0090D47D1B86A9264C75863D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Voting Systems Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H87ACFA5CDE564E73A17311B217434E8F"><enum>2.</enum><header>State official oversight of seized election materials</header> <subsection id="HF46883B0E2E948CC85C80112C6054D7C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/52/20">Chapter 20</external-xref> of title 52, United States Code, is amended by adding after section 20701 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H03BD6D72959A461B9E31B131D3C911DF" style="USC"> 
<section id="HA3BB4CD167F2405C9BA8E7C94DB04788"><enum>20702.</enum><header>State official oversight of federally seized election materials; warrant requirement</header> 
<subsection id="H345D0C1C68514C4F86A5537D9EAC22C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement of State Oversight</header><text>In any case in which the Federal Government, including any Federal agency, department, bureau, or instrumentality thereof, seizes, takes custody of, or otherwise removes—</text> <paragraph id="H2C844B0F39F84B858C034F15EDF5F9F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any voting machine, voting system, or component thereof;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7B42F14FDC24CEB83E5E274CBBD7CD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any voter registration roll or voter file;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3100868FA68645E9B4A03B6F5F1D1ED7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any ballot, whether cast, uncast, spoiled, or provisional;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H329E30F1D68A4ED6A7FBF0D4E07FA120"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any election equipment, software, hardware, or related technology; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF0A7132A1B4407D8A30AE9558DF8F6C"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>any election record, log, tally, or related documentation,</text>
                            </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">the Federal Government shall permit a designated State official to be present during and maintain continuous oversight of the handling, transport, storage, examination, and chain of custody of all such seized materials for the duration of Federal custody.</continuation-text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4A74F01FFA574FBCBEE1819C179392DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of State Official</header><text>The Secretary of State of the affected State, or an official designated in writing by the Secretary of State, shall serve as the State oversight official under subsection (a). In States without a Secretary of State, the chief State election official shall designate an appropriate official. The designated official—</text> <paragraph id="HEFC6CF71DE87432CB762611595D224B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall have the right to observe all handling and processing of seized materials;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F9B369128CB4020A9CF021C4343BB5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be provided access to all locations where seized materials are stored or examined;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84BEF203A1EB420E941F3775AAEDA1DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may document, photograph, or otherwise record the condition and handling of seized materials, subject to any applicable court order; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E7ECA632EC64601BDFD7D92A90287EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall countersign all chain-of-custody documentation related to the seized materials.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2DFDB98D7B5544E2BEC1516262359311"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Warrant requirement</header><text>A Federal agency or entity may not conduct a seizure described under subsection (a) except pursuant to a warrant duly issued by a court.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C9E4AA32AD741D1A31D0C1C5A91EA37"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal Facilitation</header><text>The Federal agency or entity conducting the seizure shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2C8CCC04315043A9B02B8BFF3CE60744"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide reasonable accommodations to enable State official oversight under this section;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD435AC9678944AABCDA7336EB2B4BDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>bear any reasonable costs associated with State official travel and access; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AADF64D1A6F433DB173DFAFD877FA7E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not impede, obstruct, or delay the State official from exercising oversight functions under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block/></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC38B8D3916A14387933BA0230CC6E968">
      <enum>3.</enum>
      <header>Criminal penalties for tampering with or destruction of election materials by Federal
        officials</header>
      <subsection id="H513557FA8D8E4780A345DDECA4F806B4">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In General</header>
 <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/29">Chapter 29</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding after section 594 the following new section:</text>
        <quoted-block id="HD60A7ADB5BED4577B7D5A437366B8CB9" style="USC">
          <section id="H88CBD08B110343A5856E41142BB7C75D">
            <enum>594A.</enum>
            <header>Tampering with or destruction of seized election materials by federal
              officials</header>
            <subsection id="HA8E930D07ED649EFADC603643EA94C83">
              <enum>(a)</enum>
              <header>Offense</header>
 <text>It shall be unlawful for any Federal officer, employee, agent, or contractor, or any person acting under color of Federal law, to—</text>
              <paragraph id="H5F5C0947650A4EC8BA36A5BCB2289C08">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>tamper with, alter, damage, or destroy any voting machine, voting system, voter roll, ballot, election equipment, election software, or election record that has been seized or taken into Federal custody;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H15F13D824C9C4BD5B9F7F6AC16F4F537">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>intentionally mishandle or fail to maintain the chain of custody of any such materials;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H7B7582BFD8544DA4B337CA97242C62F3">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>falsify or alter any record, log, or documentation related to seized election materials; or</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H347B4A8E09654A04AB8AAD6310494DFB">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>obstruct or interfere with State official oversight as required under section 20702 of title 52.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HE4A4F13CFCB1493497672B2968089E73">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Penalties</header>
 <text>Any person who violates subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H48602C739465461E99DDAB51AC5E8917"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both, if the violation was committed knowingly and willfully;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HDE7828895AF544BAA7D1CD7EF4493B29">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>shall be fined not more than $250,000 if the violation was committed negligently or recklessly; and</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H29BBB0129B254A618BDC82EB48E8B9CA">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>shall be permanently disqualified from holding any Federal office or position of Federal employment.</text>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H6B512EBAEB07417083355F103BF3DD3D">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Statute of Limitations</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a prosecution for a violation of this section may be commenced at any time within 9 years after the commission of the offense.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H395D1584B68C4DC9968E4916FDEACD9A">
              <enum>(d)</enum>
              <header>Civil Cause of Action</header>
 <text>Any State that suffers harm as a result of a violation of this section may bring a civil action in any United States district court for damages, including costs and reasonable attorney’s fees, and for any appropriate equitable relief.</text>
            </subsection>
          </section>
          <after-quoted-block/>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="HC47DE4F1219941EDB6FAF9F05DB67CE7">
      <enum>4.</enum>
      <header>Notification requirements prior to Federal seizure of election materials</header>
      <subsection id="H6E4F128006A44E08828A149617EEEB05">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>48-Hour Advance Notification to State Officials</header>
 <text>Not fewer than 48 hours before any Federal seizure of election materials described in section 20702(a) of title 52, the Federal agency or entity seeking to conduct the seizure shall provide written notification to the Secretary of State, or equivalent chief election official, of the affected State. Such notification shall include—</text>
        <paragraph id="HB5A57615830C4F039506DA20A1C06EC7">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the specific categories and description of the materials to be seized;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF1743754A724BDEB17F171F9F67AECA"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>the legal authority and factual basis for the seizure;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H02B38A5564E341949586CE0E54B6CB77">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>the anticipated duration of Federal custody;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFA5DB8DC83A41CEBAA2DEE45A665E73"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>the Federal agency or entity conducting the seizure and the designated Federal contact official;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF81AF78903ED45D785B2196D071F7A42">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>the planned location or locations of storage and examination; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4950E547404B4C73B790243C9CC10F18"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>any court order or judicial authorization authorizing the seizure, if applicable.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H2230A3716D7F4C899CB18DD60881F721">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Simultaneous Notification to Congressional Committees</header>
 <text>At the same time notification is provided to State officials under subsection (a), the Federal agency or entity conducting the seizure shall notify—</text>
        <paragraph id="H847A1FCA4400450EA4C271EE39CD0B2F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the Chair and Ranking Member of the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H60E202E6FC00424F985A9A50FE7928FB">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the Chair and Ranking Member of the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H14ADE383EF4E49C997C0457FA7B50904">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>the Chair and Ranking Member of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H251CC954CA8A4B38865D4621DBC15EA0">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>the Chair and Ranking Member of the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H2B8D306BA4064BB3BD7977DC037D314F"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Form and Delivery</header> <text>All notifications required under this section shall be—</text>
        <paragraph id="H1B48B115231445A7ACAA94C539DDA2D0">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in writing;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E7BF4214BDF48968D3F0DA1DEF6C06B"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>transmitted via electronic means and confirmed by certified mail; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD2085307FCAA492187A15E114879A082">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>transmitted simultaneously to all required recipients.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H3CC7AF589ACD485493AE9B114A386935"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Emergency Exception</header> <text>In the event that exigent circumstances prevent provision of advance notification under subsection (a), the Federal agency or entity shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="HCF1B1D30754749608DBC871F82603943">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>provide notification to all required recipients as soon as practicable, but in no case later than 6 hours after the seizure is initiated; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H30F3E525D3054E7B892AAC3F7E527163">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>include in such notification a detailed written explanation of the emergency circumstances that necessitated immediate action.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H6FE35BAF51174DFB8FAA0F9A2CBD2A0C">
        <enum>(e)</enum>
        <header>Failure To Notify</header>
 <text>Any Federal official who willfully fails to provide required notifications under this section shall be subject to the penalties described in section 594A(b) of title 18, United States Code.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H969CDE34337C440CB08AA18309C0942A">
      <enum>5.</enum>
      <header>Restriction on Federal seizure of election materials in proximity to a Federal
        election</header>
      <subsection id="H8D7642A8B96A4A9B8509A7E83A6E3B8E">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Restricted Period Defined</header>
 <text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>restricted period</quote> means the period beginning 120 days before any Federal election and ending 120 days after such election.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HC0F99448E2DA445698FD75386E5FC5C0">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>General Prohibition</header>
 <text>During any restricted period, no Federal agency, department, bureau, instrumentality, officer, or employee of the United States may seize, take custody of, or otherwise remove any election material described in section 20702(a) of title 52 from any State, county, municipality, or election jurisdiction.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HBE918CD86C8943CA9841B7926F5768ED">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Exception for Imminent Harm</header>
 <text>The prohibition under subsection (b) shall not apply if—</text> <paragraph id="HFD2899A2BD264C73A67041DF2CF28774"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>there is clear and convincing evidence of an imminent threat of harm to the integrity of the Federal election, public safety, or national security arising directly from the specific election materials to be seized;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0BD495946A804D7584FD360C122B5242">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>a Federal district court judge has issued an order, upon application supported by affidavit, specifically authorizing the seizure during the restricted period upon a finding of such imminent harm;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4DFA5AAC04E04A7C93FAA38577E37578">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>the Federal agency seeking the seizure has made a good-faith effort to provide the notifications required under section 5 of this Act, notwithstanding any reduced timeframe necessitated by the emergency; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H98E9BA1CE4464A6CAF8095BEFA219F34">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>the scope of the seizure is narrowly tailored to address the specific imminent harm identified.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="HFF8542372C804277ABD6548406B68098">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Judicial Review</header>
 <text>Any State, or the Secretary of State of any State, may seek expedited judicial review of any seizure, taking of custody, or removal of election material in violation of subsection (b) in a Federal district court of any seizure occurring during a restricted period. The court shall have authority to—</text>
        <paragraph id="HF21BE6A94F894CAEB830DE71DE43F9BE">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>issue a temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction halting or limiting a seizure pending full hearing;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H575BA0BCDEB54406A123BABE7075241C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>order the return of seized materials if the court finds the seizure was not authorized under this section; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6081399682E44F3AA44EFC56E5F17663">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>award attorney’s fees and costs to a prevailing State party.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H6B2B090076B4429ABB3A489EB95EF7CD"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Civil Penalty</header> <text>Any Federal official who knowingly authorizes or conducts a seizure in violation of this section shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than $50,000 and not more than $500,000 per violation, in addition to any criminal penalties under applicable law.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section> 
<section id="H03E9EF44FF324275B8326220ACADFD66"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rulemaking and implementation</header> 
<subsection id="HEF419C3AC33F4A2886D3FBAFFBE06022"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Election Assistance Commission, shall promulgate regulations implementing this Act, including establishing standardized forms and procedures for notifications required under section 5.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB8158199A2414E11873B20D0A9CDD4E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Attorney General shall develop and implement mandatory training for all Federal law enforcement personnel on the requirements and procedures established by this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HFB6419B0ED914FEA82ABB5C4C6752E40"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H9ED363D94215400A81608149C1F04320"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Voting machine; voting system</header><text>The terms <quote>voting machine</quote> and <quote>voting system</quote> mean any device, apparatus, software, firmware, or combination thereof used or intended for use in the casting, recording, tabulating, transmitting, or reporting of votes in a Federal election, including direct-recording electronic devices, optical scan systems, ballot marking devices, electronic poll books, vote tabulation systems, and any component, peripheral, or module integral to the operation of such devices or systems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD76BFC58D42D4F5F8B339B787A9A8AC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election equipment and records</header><text>The term <quote>election equipment and records</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H2418469DA00541CD9A7812BF2C9580D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any voting machine or voting system as defined in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H874B701A2E394CD698CACCF39448E442"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any voter registration roll, voter file, or poll book, whether in electronic or paper form;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84873B682DC148D3801E243805E143B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any ballot, whether cast, uncast, spoiled, provisional, or absentee;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C63B2036BA1403C9267025E69BBDD34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any tally sheet, canvass record, certification document, chain-of-custody log, or audit trail associated with a Federal election; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F4E22688ABE4454BEC915764F07CC26"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any software, database, server, storage media, or network infrastructure used exclusively or primarily in connection with the administration of a Federal election.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65A4F153F18F4C55AD317928A1869649"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Imminent harm</header><text>The term <quote>imminent harm</quote> means a specific, credible, and documented threat that—</text> <subparagraph id="H0F6B63B6EF5240AA93345BE4FECDD3E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is likely to occur imminently if the relevant election equipment and records are not seized;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF08CF9E96A14E67BC70770BF4D3A2CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>would result in material harm to the integrity of a Federal election, public safety, or national security; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E0C566D914048AAB19DBBD3A73B9CD3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>cannot be adequately addressed through less intrusive measures than physical seizure of the relevant materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C5E797E0970457FA16E708B9BC95911"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Restricted period</header><text>The term <quote>restricted period</quote> means the period beginning on the date that is 120 days before any regularly scheduled Federal election and ending on the date that is 120 days after such election. Where multiple Federal elections occur in close proximity, restricted periods shall be calculated independently for each election and shall not be merged unless they overlap.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H011ED86207C94F1C86C6E2205A65AD7A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State official; chief election official</header> <subparagraph id="HE6CD1DFCDEFA4971AC27A11FEFE1D366"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>State official</quote> means the Secretary of State of a State, or, in States without a Secretary of State, the officer designated by State law as the chief administrator of State elections, or any officer or employee expressly designated in writing by such officer to act under this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6AF6D01512A94A7BBB7ED5E52329758E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>chief election official</quote> means, with respect to a State, the State official as defined in subparagraph (A), and, with respect to a political subdivision, the highest-ranking election administrator of that subdivision responsible for the administration of Federal elections.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0D83D7AFDF341F3BACAD8C7F441CC7F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Seizure; takes custody of</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>seizure</quote> and <quote>takes custody of</quote> mean, in the case of any election equipment and records, any action by a Federal agency, department, instrumentality, officer, or agent, whether pursuant to legal process or otherwise, by which the Federal Government obtains physical or constructive possession, control, or access to such election equipment and records, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H92520BA32BDC4EBFBC2965A8A35D8C1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>physical removal of such materials from State or local custody;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9934977C4B57416585C63EEC072E232D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issuance of a hold, preservation order, or other directive that restricts a State or local official’s authority to access, use, or dispose of such materials;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC837239632384EC08A6FF83728DC1602"><enum>(C)</enum><text>execution of a search warrant, subpoena, or civil investigative demand that results in the removal or imaging of such materials; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4DC16AD0BAD45C186E147E50CBF0375"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other exercise of Federal authority that effectively deprives a State or local official of full control over such materials, whether temporarily or permanently.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H61EF417336A74C74AD1A51B67F44F27C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of its provisions to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</text></section> <section id="H5943D0A44E9B43C8AB90F99F8A49656C"><enum>9.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

