<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN26189-1KW-3P-GF2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4327 IS: Securing America’s Drug Supply from Communist China Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4327</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260416" legis-day="20260414">April 16 (legislative day, April 14), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require regulatory review of pharmaceutical products from Chinese entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing America’s Drug Supply from Communist China Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idac48e4248bbd459ea278bde0622ecb1b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulatory review of pharmaceutical products from Chinese entities</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id784ffe537fa347d3ae5a68061815eed7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idc94de80ec2d842eda378aa2eb22e69e1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chinese entity</header><text>The term <term>Chinese entity</term> means an entity organized under the laws of the People's Republic of China or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of the Government of the People's Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c57560407cd42139215c7ee6a9e810c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Drug application</header><text>The term <term>drug application</term> means an application submitted under subsection (b) or (j) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) or subsection (a) or (k) of section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id470eb82fa9bc417dac80533241a6b9ab"><enum>(3)</enum><header>PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc09f7a5a68fe4eaca996e2e41159d0d8"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The term <term>PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity</term> means any entity that receives support directly or indirectly from the Government of the People’s Republic of China, the Chinese Communist Party, or the People’s Liberation Army, including—</text><clause id="idb18781d256fb41c2a9bc36f2c5097604"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an entity owned or controlled by the Government of the People’s Republic of China or an entity owned or controlled by such an entity; and</text></clause><clause id="id46ca77e139b84012bfc10d9083e44fd8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity that has on its board of directors one or more individuals described in subparagraph (B) who collectively hold an ownership interest in the entity.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f204d1b2fcf4c1088438475239e1464"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Individuals described</header><text>An individual described in this subparagraph is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2aa04879b66c495593fabc0a3858c6b0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an official of the Government of the People’s Republic of China, the Chinese Communist Party, or the People's Liberation Army; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb765c8600964c939836b2b271717ec3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an executive officer of an entity owned or controlled by the Government of the People’s Republic of China, including the president or vice president of, or any other executive officer who performs a policy-making function for, the entity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81173bd8304a41068646d32bf71c8699"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id793c4448a43f455c8f2700a36ced0f45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of certain new drug applications submitted on or after enactment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2853771e7594616a9dae5186fe39301"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Office of National Security of the Department of Health and Human Services, shall review each drug application submitted on or after the date of enactment of this Act by a sponsor that is a Chinese entity, or an entity licensing a product owned by a Chinese entity, to determine whether such sponsor is a PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity. In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary may review any Drug Master File referenced by such an application.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5287a791bd21439684ae3adc0a22fce0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denied approval of certain applications</header><text>The Secretary shall not approve any drug application submitted on or after the date of enactment of this Act if the Secretary has determined under paragraph (1) that the sponsor of such application is a PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id14c642121f564858a3d9220cf45804fb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of certain new drug applications submitted prior to enactment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a28188430354292a61d4e7de3dfeb27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Office of National Security of the Department of Health and Human Services, shall review each drug application submitted during the period described in paragraph (2) to determine whether the sponsor of the application and, if applicable, the holder of the approved application, is a PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity. In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary may review any Drug Master File referenced by such an application.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id958e73ab8a5f44b4866733b175afd067"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Period described</header> <text>The period described in this paragraph is the period beginning on January 1, 2016, and ending on the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id29a625937cbb4db4a86e897f9d693a77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Refusal of certain drugs offered for import</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c89fd52f56441688fa310c1be387978"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 801 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/381">21 U.S.C. 381</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following;</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00d9dbe5d402498996db5d858b8c52c6"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e857f5698fe42c899560fe24e8f841a"> <enum>(v)</enum> <header>Import of drugs sponsored by PRC-, CCP-, and PLA-Affiliated entities</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6dfdbef238d4164af02696cb5126fda"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> <text>The Secretary shall furnish to the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection a list of drugs for which the sponsor or holder of an approved application is determined under section 2(c) of the <short-title>Securing America’s Drug Supply from Communist China Act</short-title> to be a PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                id="idb9d57ea9bf5f45feac2722d4318f71af">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Refusal</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If it appears that a drug imported or offered for import into the United States is a drug for which the sponsor or holder of an approved application is determined under section 2(c) of the <short-title>Securing America’s Drug Supply from Communist China Act</short-title> to be a PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity, then such drug shall be refused, except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4), and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall destroy, without the opportunity for export, such drug.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                id="id2259f6d08ac0471cbef2c463be4225bc">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
                                <header>Compliance</header>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                    id="idb1df89b8937644939f1502bd2cdaea4e">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
                                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a process under which the sponsor of a drug described in paragraph (2) or the holder of an approved application for such a drug, as applicable, may—</text>
                                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                        id="id73f940d006b54a00b6c947c8b3331f98">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate to the Secretary that it is no longer a PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity; or</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                        id="id8e67ff12ff0a4903a9539df3e0c45a4e">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>within 180 days, sell the approved application for such drug to an entity that is not a PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity.</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                    id="id00e150d49a4340ac9b6373e53b666948">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
                                    <header>Requirement</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process established under subparagraph (A) shall include the opportunity to appear before the Secretary and introduce testimony.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                    id="id2a72997facb844ca94363c8fd0575e1c">
                                    <enum>(C)</enum>
                                    <header>Notification</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary is satisfied with the action taken under clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall notify the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                id="ida49d962b5be34508ac24f2719afc33b3">
                                <enum>(4)</enum>
                                <header>Waiver</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may waive the requirements of paragraph (2) and authorize the import of a drug described in such paragraph if the Secretary has determined that the refusal of the import would create or exacerbate a drug shortage in the United States.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                                id="id0ee4995e5a7b4ea9865fe96a0f051be7">
                                <enum>(5)</enum>
                                <header>Definition of PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity</header>
 <text>In this subsection, the term <term>PRC-, CCP-, or PLA-affiliated entity</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2(a) of the <short-title>Securing America’s Drug Supply from Communist China Act</short-title>.</text>
                            </paragraph>
 </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0fb9a96caee8486a90454fde81431dbd"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section and the amendments made by this section $5,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

