<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFF2E356A7A0F4104833E0135C4FABD19" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7272 IH: Pipeline Cybersecurity Preparedness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7272</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to carry out a program relating to physical security and cybersecurity for pipelines and liquefied natural gas facilities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H41435002199D44FB8707BFD583087D5C" style="OLC"><section id="HDC9742BAC4E747F5AE0F1CA8351586BD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pipeline Cybersecurity Preparedness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4E1310BBFA864F9F9C2223F7BC123AA8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Physical security and cybersecurity for pipelines and liquefied natural gas facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy, in carrying out the Department of Energy’s functions pursuant to the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), and in consultation with appropriate Federal agencies, representatives of the energy sector, the States, and other stakeholders, shall carry out a program—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H4D62993D7EB6401DBF6314EDE44AB2EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to establish policies and procedures that improve coordination among Federal agencies, States, and the energy sector, including through councils or other entities engaged in sharing, analysis, or sector coordinating, to ensure the security, resiliency, and survivability of natural gas pipelines (including natural gas transmission and distribution pipelines), hazardous liquid pipelines, and liquefied natural gas facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99AA6BB4B97A4F2A82AB7B466168ECB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to lead the coordinated response and recovery by Federal agencies, States, and the energy sector, to physical incidents and cyber incidents impacting the energy sector;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31262388CC7246FA9612F85D3B93AFF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop, for voluntary use, advanced cybersecurity applications and technologies for natural gas pipelines (including natural gas transmission and distribution pipelines), hazardous liquid pipelines, and liquefied natural gas facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7549D7C8E0A4F25B64BE8144BE12292"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to perform pilot demonstration projects relating to physical security and cybersecurity for natural gas pipelines (including natural gas transmission and distribution pipelines), hazardous liquid pipelines, and liquefied natural gas facilities with representatives of the energy sector;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9E658283681465C9FAB2447EE13F7E0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop workforce development curricula for the energy sector relating to physical security and cybersecurity for natural gas pipelines (including natural gas transmission and distribution pipelines), hazardous liquid pipelines, and liquefied natural gas facilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B88A121C6154CE68799B75B1AFFF353"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide technical tools to help the energy sector voluntarily evaluate, prioritize, and improve physical security and cybersecurity capabilities of natural gas pipelines (including natural gas transmission and distribution pipelines), hazardous liquid pipelines, and liquefied natural gas facilities.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3533C19EBB0B4F8A9A66CC30512D335D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to modify the authority of any Federal agency other than the Department of Energy relating to physical security or cybersecurity for natural gas pipelines (including natural gas transmission and distribution pipelines), hazardous liquid pipelines, or liquefied natural gas facilities.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

