<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26045-XNG-95-RG7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3610 IS: No Funding for Foreign Agents Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3610</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260108" legis-day="20260107">January 8 (legislative day, January 7), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the provision of United States financial assistance to any entity that is controlled by an agent of a covered foreign principal.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Funding for Foreign Agents Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idcf57b5d0ad0a465485a7b83ef1760473"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id006b746841db42f2be4e490ff2cf106c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agent of a covered foreign principal</header><text>The term <term>agent of a covered foreign principal</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id86c069743612424ea9c944a603371f6c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any person who acts as an agent, representative, employee, or servant, or in any other capacity at the order, request, or under the direction or control, of a covered foreign principal or of a person any of whose activities are directly or indirectly supervised, directed, controlled, financed, or subsidized in whole or in major part by a covered foreign principal, whether or not that person represents the interests of such foreign principal before any agency or official of the Government of the United States or engages in any official activity within the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f929b2eafbd43efa4e060def164b5b3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any duly accredited diplomatic or consular officer of the government of a covered nation who is so recognized by the Department of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1bc228cd615e43b79dd9e0abc8009cba"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any official of the government of a covered nation whose duties are known by the Department of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id867091c27cb345f89e095cc07324e3c1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any member of the staff of, or any person employed by, a duly accredited diplomatic or consular officer of the government of a covered nation who is so recognized by the Department of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idac8b1c28f03c41c09eb98bf734c5e17b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any agent of a covered foreign principal who engages in lobbying activities and has registered or would be required to register under section 4 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93aa552699314bb6ac50b001b50cc49e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any person who has provided notice to the Attorney General as an agent of a foreign government or would be required to provide such notice under section 951 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfdd53fd541c2464db85e372d145a8bd9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Controlled</header><text>The term <term>controlled</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>control</quote> in section 80.208 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, provided that any officer, executive, proprietor, director, partner, senior manager, or combination of agents who together own a majority or a dominant minority of the total outstanding voting interest, of an entity shall be understood to control it for purposes of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd979b9d53bc24e319d60b5433240986e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered foreign principal</header><text>The term <term>covered foreign principal</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d138411ea964f9f852329c9c3854ada"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the government of a covered nation and any political party in a covered nation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7fc527718db647caaa00249c254bde78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person in a covered nation, unless such person—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0dae820f984448d5982003dce6178034"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id97357da7f4f842cbbaee2c4e58146ba6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an individual citizen of, and domiciled within, the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ff8bd1677a844728d9a47ea2e70dea4" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not an agent of a covered foreign principal; or</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3d1cce0285c41369e342a6616c38419"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id8f4ec3fa1add4dd395a4356ad8c41731"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not an individual;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda123dc0328a4e28a0e3eb7c527169b1" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is organized under, or created by, the laws of the United States or of any State or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id623fa3c0d65b463a9d278a7e2e441629"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has its principal place of business within the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb1ca268221d84990be092991be9bb06d"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>is not controlled by an agent of a covered foreign principal;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id82aee4bba66a4438806cb71113cff02b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a partnership, association, corporation, organization, or other combination of persons organized under the laws of, or having its principal place of business in, a covered nation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9dfb7b32005b48a2805aa44f5d1b12c3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any organization named in section 1003 of the Anti-Terrorism Act of 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/5202">22 U.S.C. 5202</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4bf9c4eb29344022a844566638fa6b46"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered nation</header><text>The term <term>covered nation</term> means the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, the People’s Republic of China, the Russian Federation, the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Islamic Emirate of Afghanistan, Burkina Faso, Myanmar (formerly known as <quote>Burma</quote>), Chad, Republic of the Congo, Equatorial Guinea, Eritrea, Haiti, Laos, Libya, Mali, Niger, Sierra Leone, Somalia, South Sudan, Sudan, Syria, or Yemen.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8ae1ca890c042ddba09a1f9e5aa340e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Direct financial assistance</header><text>The term <term>direct financial assistance</term> means financial assistance from the Government of the United States that is received by an entity selected by the Government or a pass-through entity, including any contract, grant, loan, cooperative agreement, or other agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id199fec605cfe498cb049e4e3b4b3a9f7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Entity</header><text>The term <term>entity</term> means any partnership, association, corporation, organization, or other combination of individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9998d10f72d34773a9f21a33fe9096c3"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Indirect financial assistance</header><text>The term <term>indirect financial assistance</term> means financial assistance from the Government of the United States that is received by a service provider which is paid by means of a voucher, certificate, or other means of Government-funded payment provided to a beneficiary who is able to choose a service provider.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id727f89c37f0c4f66ac131b81116b2ed9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Pass-through entity</header><text>The term <term>pass-through entity</term> means any entity, including a nonprofit or nongovernmental organization, acting under a contract, grant, loan, cooperative agreement, or other agreement with the Government of the United States or with a State or local government in the United States that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3132215e678f45c5a9f1055b2e0751a4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accepts direct financial assistance as a primary recipient or grantee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23843cfd38b74f7ea9586d0d4c6196d8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">distributes such assistance to other organizations that provide services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id33d46d06af1c41aeb951f0ba81737c49"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means any individual, partnership, association, corporation, organization, or other combination of individuals.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id917cb880ce93434680ab4dc9e0d569c3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restriction on United States financial assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any entity that is controlled by an agent of a covered foreign principal is ineligible to receive direct financial assistance or indirect financial assistance.</text></section><section id="ida604a3875da4447f86f800d051533f70"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to terminate—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c40bd797f0841b7b15aeb8f22dcb8ee"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States financial assistance to entities that are not controlled by an agent of a covered foreign principal; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93a90868c0fa41e3b2686e95bc7dd22a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any foreign assistance (as defined in section 634(b)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2394">22 U.S.C. 2394(b)(1)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

