<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H98387563B40A4B7F912A2120E6355EB3" resolution-type="house-concurrent">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HCON 90 IH: Directing the Architect of the Capitol to place motor vehicle gas price trackers in the Hall of the House of Representatives and the Chamber of the Senate.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 90</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260423">April 23, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Directing the Architect of the Capitol to place motor vehicle gas price trackers in the Hall of the House of Representatives and the Chamber of the Senate.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body id="H8FB2CE8AB14449DB837BC62F2F13C799">
<section id="HD945304C049642B2BA290839C723C727" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Placement of motor vehicle gas price tracker</header>
<subsection id="H2F10BFEB154C4846918498C6F0DA33AB">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Locations</header>
 <text>The Architect of the Capitol shall design, construct, and maintain a motor vehicle gas price tracker, which shall be adjusted on a continuous basis to reflect the average cost of a gallon of regular gasoline in each State and Territory of the United States, in each of the Hall of the House of Representatives and the Chamber of the Senate.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="H85340189BC5F4B29AB9A1DDC5147CE55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No appropriated funds</header><text>No appropriated Federal funds may be used for the design, construction, or maintenance of a tracker specified in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8BB5470C8709427881702F4A830729E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Gifts and bequests</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol may accept, use, and dispose of gifts and bequests of money from individuals for the purposes of this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0F0149F22EAE4996B8F830A97E77BDCA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Architect of the Capitol shall submit to the Speaker and the minority leader of the House of Representatives and the majority and minority leaders of the Senate an annual report that contains an accounting of the acceptance, use, and disposition of gifts and bequests of money under this section, including an accounting of the amounts of money accepted and used under this section and the sources of such money.</text></subsection></section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

