<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26H53-4C6-VK-JS7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4954 IS: Citizenship Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4954</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To declare that any person who enters the United States without authorization or for the purpose of engaging in birth tourism is considered an invader and to amend section 301(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to exclude the children of invaders from birthright citizenship.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Citizenship Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4542704abcd04d3a96dec55583110073"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="ideb179ca73aba4638a6078f99c5258623"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 4 of article IV of the Constitution of the United States imposes a constitutional duty on the United States to <quote>protect each [State] against invasion</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3847d32edfeb45d7a6412fc9db187e83"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States gives Congress the power to <quote>establish a uniform Rule of Naturalization</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa35a384467a4d25b7f68032d3330d08"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to James Madison, the naturalization power given to Congress under article I of the Constitution of the United States was designed to protect States from being forced to accept liberal immigration policies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7c3d4ba089a4c84a01c9eb2a1f01576"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Illegal immigration into the United States has become a national security crisis.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1787e5107e854f849a569402205a9424"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Biden administration, millions of migrants flooded our Nation’s borders or were otherwise permitted to enter the country, including known cartel members, violent criminals, and terrorists.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id644841eb88a94236b4cfc330d659261d"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">President Biden abused emergency temporary immigration programs, such as parole and temporary protected status, to allow millions of otherwise illegal aliens to remain in the United States and receive public benefits.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b7882a7fae44cada9731db96f062ef1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Trump administration has worked hard to secure the southern land border of the United States and is carrying out the largest mass deportation effort in our Nation's history.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f3d90bd74904dc29d107e06f670c727"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Notwithstanding, such efforts, as many as 15,000,000 illegal aliens remain in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67cd09428dc1455dadd7f546e26059b8"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nearly 16 percent of the population of the United States is foreign born and most of the recent increase in foreign births can be attributed to illegal immigration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idda3207b781454095a38821ec2f46748b"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Illegal immigration has downstream consequences for many aspects of American life, including increased housing prices, depressed wages, threats to public safety, and fewer jobs for United States citizens.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6836b6f33aa4b9aa094df675b5c35f2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Worldwide, mass migration has increasingly been used by migrants’ countries of origin to exert control over foreign territory, which has been referred to by scholars as the global <quote>weaponization</quote> of migration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d4f53b8e2294b899fd9914241107214"> <enum>(12)</enum> <text>Some Mexicans view migration to the United States as a method of reconquering territory acquired by the United States during the nineteenth century. Mexican politicians sometimes refer to certain United States cities as <quote>occupied territories</quote> or <quote>migrant land</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id8173c55ea4f84277a3634d3dcd5bfb77"><enum>(13)</enum><text>An estimated 1,500,000 nationals of the People's Republic of China have acquired United States citizenship by being born in the United States by surrogates, a practice that has been encouraged by the Chinese Communist Party.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc869ef9215a74a80b0e9778ba7e0e889"><enum>(14)</enum><text>On January 20, 2025, President Donald Trump declared that the mass unlawful movement of persons into the United States constitutes an invasion. The governors of multiple States have also declared a state of invasion at the southern border.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb440da4a3afa4d5eab2c17d2bbe39873"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The United States, at various times, has treated private, non-state actors, including pirates, slave traders, and terrorists, as enemy combatants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e36d4fb28ba469390089c0ec9d2a177"><enum>(16)</enum><text>While millions of illegal aliens remain in the United States and birth tourism is allowed to be exploited by foreign adversaries, this invasion remains ongoing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1586d8aaba354eab8da6c717023410a1"><enum>(17)</enum><text>As confirmed by Federal courts and judges, including California v. United States, 104 F.3d 1086, 1091 (9th Cir. 1997); Padavan v. United States, 82 F.3d 23, 28 (2d Cir. 1996); Chiles v. United States, 69 F.3d 1094, 1097 (11th Cir. 1995), and United States v. Abbott, 110 F.4th 700, 726–29 (5th Cir. 2024) (Ho, J., concurring in part), the determination of the existence of an invasion is a nonjusticiable question committed to the political branches and is not reviewable by the Federal courts. Similar to other political questions, a determination of invasion involves <quote>a lack of judicially discoverable and manageable standards</quote> that courts can use to adjudicate such determinations. Zivotofsky ex rel. Zivotofsky v. Clinton, 566 U.S. 189, 195 (2012).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6fcd71bab5054e20bb176251392d04d6"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Children of foreign invaders who are born on United States soil are not entitled to birthright citizenship under the Fourteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59ebc8acbf35475697722949f51bf8a8"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Birthright citizenship did not apply to children born to invaders under the British common law, and the framers of the Citizenship Clause of the Fourteenth Amendment understood the clause to exclude the children of invaders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2829082212ff4118a13f1f250773993d"> <enum>(20)</enum> <text>Although the United States Supreme Court broadened the meaning of the Citizenship Clause in Trump v. Barbara, 609 U.S. _ (2026), the court did not hold that children born to invaders are entitled to birthright citizenship. The Supreme Court reaffirmed United States v. Wong Kim Ark, 169 U.S. 649, 658 (1898), which held that <quote>children within territory in hostile occupation</quote> are not entitled to birthright citizenship. 169 U.S. 649, 658 (1898).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id00ae9781e84e4fa588ed2ee25c1459ca"><enum>(21)</enum><text>It is therefore consistent with the holding in Barbara v. Trump for Congress to invoke its constitutional authority by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91748b7e3ff645a0ba0b46cca601e612"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">codifying President Trump’s declaration of an invasion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79fe0abf0d19443a862bdd31c56551b8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revoking birthright citizenship from children who are born in the United States to a woman who is unlawfully present or to a woman engaged in birth tourism.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id2990830e83a94f30a1e2d277df1c23c2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional declarations</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd10a2c8eefa74d1294d9744cb1578b67"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Invaders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress declares that all of the following persons are designated invaders while remaining in the United States for purposes of section 301(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by section 4:</text><paragraph id="id5c3e62439d9547b9bd12ba75042fe5c9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any person who has not been lawfully admitted to the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(13)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(13)(A)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id709ce186156c4fc28c6fe8e8d256764b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any person who is otherwise unlawfully present under section 212(a)(9)(B)(ii) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(9)(B)(ii)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f99cc6055ca447680c7c62dc73f5ec7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any person seeking admission to the United States under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) who, in the opinion of the consular officer at the time of application for a visa, or in the opinion of the Attorney General at the time of application for admission or adjustment of status, is seeking admission or adjustment of status for the purpose of giving birth to a child in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id70e3116110ef4d5db00018c8de9496cb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commercial surrogacy contracts</header><text>Congress declares that any person who is a national of a covered nation (as defined in section 4872(f)(2) of title 10, United States Code) and enters into a commercial surrogacy contract with a person in the United States, or with a surrogacy broker who arranges a commercial surrogacy contract with a person in the United States, for the purpose of having a child birthed in the United States shall be designated an invader for purposes of section 301(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by section 4.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75f5f9f948574c5abb05e6b1d154e761"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f6c816b70ce45e8825efb17464d0ac6"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Not lawfully admitted</header> <text>Subsection (a)(1) shall be construed to include all persons who were never lawfully admitted to the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(13)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(13)(A)</external-xref>)), regardless of when such persons entered the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde47a94be168425893945a785631a97a"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not lawfully present</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a)(2) shall be construed to include all persons unlawfully present under section 212(a)(9)(B)(ii) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(9)(B)(ii)</external-xref>), regardless of when such persons entered the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0bf1654b85054eee9a66478b7259080f"><enum>4.</enum><header>Children of invaders not entitled to birthright citizenship</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 301(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1401">8 U.S.C. 1401(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0c827e6bbf2404ab85ba098bedf1781"><subsection id="ID8A80037882F24DAEA7D2971E032CEC5E" indent="down1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person born in the United States, and subject to the jurisdiction thereof, which shall not include any of the following persons:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida880f149e46b47c7873c0375e2702b06"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who was born to an invader (as defined in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 3(a) of the <short-title>Citizenship Act of 2026</short-title>) if such person’s mother was not lawfully admitted to the United States or was otherwise unlawfully present in the United States and such person's father was not a United States citizen or a lawful permanent resident of the United States at the time of such person’s birth.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5e6328156e342359ff58730220686e9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who was born to an invader (as defined in section 3(a)(3) of the <short-title>Citizenship Act of 2026</short-title>) if such person’s mother sought admission to the United States or adjustment of status in the United States for the purpose of giving birth to a child in the United States and the father was not a United States citizen or a lawful permanent resident of the United States at the time of such person’s birth.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77d57806a7264ad9ae046de0d61a7fd5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person born to an invader (as defined in section 3(b) of the <short-title>Citizenship Act of 2026</short-title>) as the result of a commercial surrogacy contract.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idf5ad1e183e094c4ca9e2b0ae56bfc1d9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No court is authorized to review a determination by the President or by Congress of the existence of an invasion.</text></section><section id="id2a083d1ff4ef4026b8f31ee7488b65e5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47d3b1497a774562915f374901fddb93"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to revoke the criminal or civil jurisdiction of the United States, or of any State, over invaders for violations of Federal or State law.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cbfcae45df5429582bb256cd5b51c47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Military force</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to authorize the use of military force under the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f84ea65298f4ed0a86d6003481624f1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall apply to all children born after the date of the enactment of this Act to a person who, at the time of such birth, was designated as an invader pursuant to section 3.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id00db6189dcaf40c78ec0187203dd2625"><enum>8.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any provision of this Act, including any amendment made by this Act, which is held to be invalid or unenforceable by its terms, or as applied to any person or circumstance, shall be construed so as to give it the maximum effect permitted by law, unless such holding shall be one of utter invalidity or unenforceability, in which event such provision shall be deemed severable from this Act and shall not affect the remainder of this Act, or the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other, dissimilar circumstances.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

