<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H069C5C83C2264FCCB8D5C8DEA1CF52AF" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3410 : Supersonic Aviation Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3410</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow for the operation of civil supersonic flight in the national airspace system under certain conditions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HA7A2CBB7B27E433ABAD7C160A273582C"><section id="H0E712E24EE454C3CB7113DCADAD50B57" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supersonic Aviation Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4DED440CCECF4C2E904441DB08188B7B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Allowing for the operation of civil supersonic flight</header><subsection id="H7CB96B336C0746E196A2C3F55A7C9334"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall issue or revise such regulations, such as section 91.817 of part 14, Code of Federal Regulations, as are necessary to allow for the operation of civil aircraft (as defined in section 40102(16) of title 49, United States Code) without special authorization within the national airspace system at a Mach number greater than 1 so long as the aircraft is operated in such a manner that no sonic boom reaches the ground in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEFF5C3712F9C40AABD93057EF9EFB903"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance with noise standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than April 1, 2027, the Administrator shall issue a final rule establishing noise standards under part 36 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, requiring civil aircraft granted authority to operate pursuant to subsection (a) not to exceed the most recent takeoff and landing noise levels required for subsonic aircraft currently in operation on the date of enactment.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEB902F5E08D1446182A783033582C6FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Periodic review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing the final rule issued under subsection (b), the Administrator shall further specify a process for periodic review and update of the rule to reflect future advances in aircraft noise reduction technology and relevant regulatory changes, as determined by the Administrator. </text></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260324" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 24, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

