<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H921D268E03A8405A9048B5428EE4E056" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 969 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week beginning on September 8, 2025, as “National Hispanic-Serving Institutions Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 969</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251219">December 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week beginning on September 8, 2025, as <quote>National Hispanic-Serving Institutions Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Hispanic-Serving Institutions</quote> are degree-granting institutions that have a full-time equivalent undergraduate enrollment of at least 25 percent Hispanic students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hispanic-Serving Institutions play an important role in educating many low-income and underserved students and creating opportunities and increasing access to higher education for such students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the 2023–2024 academic year, 615 Hispanic-Serving Institutions operated in the United States enrolling more than 5,600,000 students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hispanic-Serving Institutions are engines of economic mobility and a major contributor to the economic prosperity of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hispanic-Serving Institutions represent 20 percent of all institutions of higher education, yet serve 31.7 percent of all undergraduate students and 66.2 percent of all Hispanic undergraduate students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hispanic-Serving Institutions are located in 30 States, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the number of <quote>Emerging Hispanic-Serving Institutions</quote>, defined as institutions that do not yet meet the threshold of 25 percent Hispanic full-time equivalent enrollment but serve a Hispanic student population of between 15 and 24.9 percent, stands at 425 institutions operating in 43 States and the District of Columbia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hispanic-Serving Institutions are actively involved in empowering and improving the communities in which the institutions are located;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Hispanic-Serving Institutions are leading efforts to increase Hispanic participation in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (commonly known as <quote>STEM</quote>);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 8 of the top 10 institutions of higher education ranked by the social mobility index were Hispanic-Serving Institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas celebrating the vast contributions of Hispanic-Serving Institutions strengthens the culture of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the achievements and goals of Hispanic-Serving Institutions deserve national recognition: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFCFF74CA3F2047B0A36B378048466B87"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H82080B1A9B2C4CE6891BA00872014CAC"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H6A85BAFBB18E4665B8F3894F441F23E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the achievements and goals of Hispanic-Serving Institutions across the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE77C32EDC86048C389C0AF23C3C44302"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for the designation of <quote>National Hispanic-Serving Institutions Week</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92BE396500874B4D811ABA125F728025"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States and interested groups to observe the week with appropriate ceremonies, activities, and programs to demonstrate support for Hispanic-Serving Institutions in honor of Hispanic Heritage Month.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

