<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5953EF7623FD4D2EBFE25299EE70900C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6851 IH: Lowering American Energy Costs Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6851</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to ban the export of natural gas produced in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6079EB9BE6F4D159FCC688FA0202FA8" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H53D4A395F62446FCBBE9C641CB2D34AF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lowering American Energy Costs Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5A7D098CFD054E9B8C7FE978B6239F90"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H482DF1DD7A454B44862F15444DD50902"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Government has repeatedly found that natural gas exports lead to increased domestic gas and electricity prices, as evidenced by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H910DFC84A997428F95B6BDD39133F17C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a November 2025 analysis by the Energy Information Administration, which predicts that natural gas prices in 2026 will be 16 percent higher than in 2025 due to increased liquefied natural gas (referred to in this section as <quote>LNG</quote>) exports;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F75A4157B7340EA8D4C47FCE5B9E8A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a December 2024 study by the Department of Energy, which determined that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F659614B21C4A15A45323F927F51941"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unconstrained exports of United States LNG are projected to increase wholesale domestic natural gas prices by 31 percent by 2050, not accounting for the additional price impact of LNG exports on natural gas price volatility;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H608B8AC96AD74273998503D26666E216"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>volatility in the global natural gas market will further increase costs on domestic consumers and industry as United States natural gas exports increase;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C89B065B9474CF696BE0E7D54141754"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>United States households will pay up to an additional $122 per year on average in higher natural gas and electricity costs by 2050; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CA03847DF80459882E336CEE891530D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States industrial sector will pay an additional $125,000,000,000 in higher energy costs by 2050 as a result of rising United States LNG exports;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA710DD144FD44062917ADCF3E9283C76"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a January 2024 report from the Energy Information Administration, which found that, in the United States, the price of natural gas is the most important driver of wholesale electricity prices because natural gas is often the highest-cost fuel for electricity generation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82323DAD769541A3AA83B5C42B84AE93"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a 2018 study by the Department of Energy, which found that <quote>producing incremental natural gas volumes to support natural gas exports will increase the marginal cost of supplying natural gas and therefore raise domestic natural gas prices.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6296D43A8A44549BEF79B057DDDC8E0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a 2012 study by the Energy Information Administration, which found that <quote>increased natural gas exports lead to increased natural gas prices.</quote> and that <quote>larger export levels lead to larger domestic price increases, while rapid increases in export levels lead to large initial price increases.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAE45778AB89433AB9E35D8495A352F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>according to research by Public Citizen, from January 2025 through September 2025, households in the United States paid $12,000,000,000 more for natural gas than from the same period in 2024, a 22 percent price increase that translates to a roughly $124 price hike for the average household;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A76CA8423294025A6C6356F1D7DA941"><enum>(3)</enum><text>according to the Institute for Energy Economics and Financial Analysis, surging United States LNG exports from September 2021 to December 2022 led to the sharpest rise of wholesale gas prices in over a decade, costing domestic consumers $111,000,000,000 in higher energy bills;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DED18B538564BAD93597886C0515D19"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States is already the largest producer of natural gas and largest exporter of LNG in the world, and continues to set records for LNG exports, including that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3ECE1A8746F4447F8FB7C54D1FD2B7DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in 2025, the United States had multiple record-setting months for LNG exports; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17CBDBD077634FB18C250417FF83831E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in October 2025, the United States became the first country in the world to surpass 10,000,000 metric tons worth of LNG exports in a single month;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45ABDA1C712840D5B3A3732E6A25ECF6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>natural gas is primarily composed of methane, which is a dangerous greenhouse gas and the second-largest contributor to atmospheric warming; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE87B7EAA15FA462E962F7DBE0C7B1006"><enum>(6)</enum><text>natural gas infrastructure, including pipelines and LNG terminals, lead to significant negative health outcomes for communities surrounding the pipelines and terminals, which is compounded by the fact that new natural gas infrastructure is disproportionately sited in communities that already have polluting infrastructure.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H2770E2E34592452B971E73C48C4F9C95"><enum>3.</enum><header>Domestic use of energy supplies and related materials and equipment</header><subsection id="H636323AAEEA5485983D559DF1C066358"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6201">42 U.S.C. 6201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 101 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8E86238541F4392BBAAFBAFDF9028BE"><section id="H6DCBDF3832B44DB199C55E39322E897C"><enum>102.</enum><header>Domestic use of energy supplies and related materials and equipment</header><subsection id="HA7015DCF96414F5E8F7524E16C414CF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Export restrictions</header><text>The President, by rule, under such terms and conditions as the President determines to be appropriate and necessary to carry out the purposes of this Act, shall restrict exports of natural gas for the purpose of keeping domestic energy costs low.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5D038C13B5744200BE1A5FB6CE7C0A1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition of export of natural gas</header><paragraph id="H5DB7FA070D6D44469D21EFBEF8EA3CE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rule</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the President shall exercise the authority provided under subsection (a) to promulgate a rule prohibiting the export of natural gas produced in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85F09C175E1142BA886FBC29A72A3E61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><subparagraph id="H6808FF2598EC4C9AA62CC95CA6309F20"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with subparagraph (A), the President may exempt from a prohibition on the export of natural gas under paragraph (1) any natural gas exports that the President determines—</text><clause id="H9A095FBE4DB74816B423627BDC4E501D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to be consistent with the national interest and will not unreasonably raise costs for residential consumers; or</text></clause><clause id="HDF3AC9ACFCD34E678E7116DEC52F17AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to be critical for the national security of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1D82E10B10846E787795B6FC7419BFC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFE037A595A846D29C2CABF64EDDAD0E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a country that is a strategic international partner or ally of the United States.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H228A83D76667445CB2339497E090329B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Congressional approval</header><text>Before any exemption issued by the President may go into effect, the exemption must be approved by a joint resolution of Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6050E6A847C744EA81F67EC05F88A4DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HA5C4EC8F9B24482DAC082C2FC4ACEC8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (42 U.S.C. prec. 6201) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 101 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2320F8969A14C07A37B3C73D67B1F0C"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">102. Domestic use of energy supplies and related materials and equipment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H463C59DEA85E4033B4AB49275A5681B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 101 of division O of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6212a">42 U.S.C. 6212a</external-xref>), is amended by striking subsections (b) through (d).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

