<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H786AFA77AE2B45DC9FE571C503DF6663" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5897 IH: Public Access to Defibrillation in Transportation Facilities Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5897</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 23, United States Code, to improve access to automated external defibrillators at interstate transportation facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H48A7FAD793824E30A17FA2CFD407522B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDCB489CF2B1C462AAB8D042CC45AF467" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Access to Defibrillation in Transportation Facilities Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H4454510782EA47EC924F3D0679DA077B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H104B169259994498A27B55C9A1BC72EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA0E6A832A4F84A34896D593B4A46C933"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Sudden cardiac arrest (in this section referred to as <quote>SCA</quote>) is a leading cause of death in the United States, with an estimated 356,000 out-of-hospital cardiac arrests occurring annually.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD028EE52CBF4490A5D95D84B0A98810"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Automated external defibrillators (in this section referred to as <quote>AEDs</quote>) are a vital tool in responding to SCA, as they are capable of delivering a life-saving shock to restore the heart’s natural rhythm.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1C1F49013744E35955AD77822D535B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>There is a need for quick response times in cases of SCA, as every minute that passes without defibrillation decreases the likelihood of survival by 7 to 10 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3805E377518A49F2979B9C1E3A94ADCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that Federal agencies, States, and municipalities should accelerate efforts to deploy AEDs in locations that are frequented by large crowds.</text> </subsection></section> 
<section id="HF4DB43F495EF44C9BD7058C1F68B9662"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expansion of surface transportation block grant program to fund AED deployment</header> 
<subsection id="HB3E301134DF0421389C910CEDB7A7FAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 133(b) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC23ACE6C8FBE4151AA6386507684372B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H4F484E7B627D47FEB4F67194D24CC645"><enum>(25)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Projects to purchase and deploy automated external defibrillators for use at transportation facilities otherwise eligible for assistance under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27750CCBB85B4E22B5F588F7AD9CB6AA"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Projects to develop and implement written emergency action plans for responding to medical emergencies at transportation facilities otherwise eligible for assistance under this section, including the use of automated external defibrillators.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="H344853B909CF4FF09572E01DE532ED7A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall provide technical assistance to States and local officials in developing the written emergency action plans referred to in section 133(b)(26) of title 23, United States Code (as added by subsection (a) of this section).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H438EB76068C04AF6BE0448CDF69926D1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Deployment of AEDS in interstate transportation facilities</header> 
<subsection id="HCF717A515F0B42CCAA23B0F8511D2B6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall issue—</text> <paragraph id="H47229A906F424BD4ADAEF72377C458D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations for the deployment of automated external defibrillators (in this section referred to as <quote>AEDs</quote>) at interstate transportation facilities based on best practices for the placement and maintenance of AEDs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10BA1FB406DE4647884CD799F25B5D4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>guidelines to assist any owner or operator of an interstate transportation facility in developing and implementing for such facility a written emergency action plan for responding to medical emergencies, including the use of AEDs.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA81B2430572545C1935F75DE11B8874A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall provide technical assistance to owners and operators of interstate transportation facilities in complying with the recommendations and guidelines issued under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H17177CAC447C4E70B6ECC37240FEAF69"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out financial assistance programs of the Department of Transportation, including its components, the Secretary of Transportation may impose such additional terms and conditions as the Secretary determines necessary to provide for adoption of the recommendations and guidelines issued under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEFF439B0B5814A1BAB74738184E7B97A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC6387B71496B4356A0D867F54F5D5F20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interstate System</header><text>The term <term>Interstate System</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20B9771CE0764E268DAC07897D23FF8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interstate transportation facility</header><text>The term <term>interstate transportation facility</term> includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF2B845DFE4E8429EAC3C77AC86D9E7F3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a bus terminal, a ferry terminal, and a rail passenger transportation terminal;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50448AAA3A05404F8BC3E00FD8CE9935"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a highway rest area on the Interstate System;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H426A686787F44661956514E0B1715216"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a vehicle used to provide rail passenger transportation, other than a vehicle used exclusively to provide transportation between station stops located within 15 minutes of each other (as determined using times established in public timetables); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6250280AE1434C56B3E451290AA42F5E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other facilities as the Secretary of Transportation determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4810C3E9830E465F8A6B1D93644CA97D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rail passenger transportation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rail passenger transportation</term> includes transportation provided by a rail fixed guideway public transportation system, an intercity passenger rail system, or a commuter rail passenger transportation system that receives Federal assistance, as identified by the Secretary of Transportation.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE72D0A64A2E04D14B681F43B6457DB50"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall apply beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

