<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B7446646BBB4EB0B4A7A6D68C9FBAF5" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1168 IH: Recognizing U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for their work in protecting communities from violent criminals and illegal aliens.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1168</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260414">April 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for their work in protecting communities from violent criminals and illegal aliens.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Biden administration failed to identify and prosecute individuals illegally entering our country through the southern border;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement’s (ICE) work disrupts foreign criminal and drug networks, making all United States citizens safer;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas some State and local law enforcement agencies have stopped sharing data with Federal law enforcement officers, preventing swift identification of dangerous criminals;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas ICE agents have received an 8,000 percent increase in death threats against them and their families, even as they arrest murderers, assailants, and drug traffickers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas agitators, including elected politicians, are encouraging violence against Department of Homeland Security (DHS) personnel, leading to a significant increase in assaults against them;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas law enforcement officers protecting United States citizens from violent criminals should not be the subject of physical violence; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas ICE officers have taken on additional roles during the DHS shutdown, assisting Transportation Security Administration employees in checking identification and providing additional security: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HBAF1E8765CDC45F997647BD1666CC28D"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H14EE1D90A0864A2A8221EEB3DDF5F63C"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA1CA241B95B7434ABAE2E9CA5D8D6144"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms its support for U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) agents and staff performing their duties while facing threats and harassment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77BB9BF4D167467B97BDC9527E121337"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on State and local law enforcement officers to stand with their Federal partners in investigating threats made against all Federal law enforcement officers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA6BB411346E4414B9F4023D8D8F36AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>condemns all forms of political violence, especially against officers carrying out their sworn duty to protect United States citizens from violent criminals; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF7A2B57C9AA47F6903AE2C0E385D541"><enum>(4)</enum><text>thanks ICE agents for their expanded role at airports amid the partial government shutdown.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

