<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA04B95848782471A9FA1083B030A2DC0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7408 IH: Water Project Navigators Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7408</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260205">February 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of a Water Project Navigators Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBD71D72C1CEA4BFF926D632C427E9F8C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB5C4B36B4AAB482790EDBC17B241FE97" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Project Navigators Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2DA81E1FD3354A21A43E9CA5E92A8631"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H7D02AA74818B4B5EA0B5E9ABE7F1C082"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disadvantaged community</header><text>Except as otherwise defined by the Secretary of the Interior based on current methodologies, the term <term>disadvantaged community</term> means a community (including a city, town, county, or reasonably isolated and divisible segment of a larger municipality) with an annual median income that is less than the statewide annual median income for the State in which the community is located, according to the most recent decennial census.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DFEF3D083024B5B87DEDC95F46EEF7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HACCC0AC3DCC8488B88F5AFBA7F01767D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC09D2DEBA87648D5BEABEAEFE5E5F357"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFCFA89F5EA7B46D3827F275E8CEFE9C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any acequia, land grant-merced, local government, water supplier, special district, conservation district, or municipal water district located in an eligible State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD139276281F64E1DB2674F7FB7111665"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any State, regional, or local authority located in an eligible State, the members of which include 1 or more organizations with water or power delivery authority;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H686840D352AC4FCB8AEB75D9FDC6E2F4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a nonprofit conservation organization with a demonstrated history of working in partnership with 1 or more entities described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (D); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D125A559ACA49F08B0CD0DD40B0068B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a combination of entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H84A5337B4F6D4E58A9F39530112A2D71"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible state</header><text>The term <term>eligible State</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H4251EB4CA4DB465181DA8823914E8DDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State or territory described in the first section of the Act of June 17, 1902 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/391">43 U.S.C. 391</external-xref>; 32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H02F8BC8AE0FE462DAEEC00FEFB23E601"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State of Alaska;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2BEB31B462F24CCA80619A274D96A225"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the State of Hawaii; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA961EBC63DF447E1895E2C590D969F68"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H026125AD79494BC7821418EB92DA1814"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H988343EF6C354149840D0F4C377EB500"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Multi-benefit water project</header><text>The term <term>multi-benefit water project</term> means any project in an eligible State that—</text> <subparagraph id="H9A3C0054F0B4463FB5DB7E58D8A6ED9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhances the overall resilience of a community or region to climate-related impacts on water supplies, including through activities—</text>
<clause id="HD76FCC2C9B044F368C3E3223E563F180"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to increase water use efficiency;</text></clause> <clause id="HFC293F21129C4DE29571526DA4332170"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to reduce consumptive use of water;</text></clause>
<clause id="H17F3421D991541F488648D8271C6FDC9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to promote system conservation;</text></clause> <clause id="H85919605721C4AEFB7FB9E16248F9425"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to reduce water supply-demand imbalances;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF831ED72C8A64674A0AFE6F73C2B5F3C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to promote water recycling and other advanced water treatments to augment water supplies;</text></clause> <clause id="HEFE1D7DAB6C946DF886FB2D1E87EA18A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to improve management or delivery of water resources;</text></clause>
<clause id="H0B20EE7C397B407CA5B02FAF91FF21C6"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>to address risks to water infrastructure from weather-related events and climate change;</text></clause> <clause id="H1C03CAFBA39040E2B959D8783DE1D62D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>to provide or improve access to safe drinking water in communities that lack reliable access to adequate clean water supplies;</text></clause>
<clause id="H1BC67B72444D40B7B3CC4038DD1EC3F0"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>to promote investment in the economies of rural communities, Tribal communities, or disadvantaged communities through water projects;</text></clause> <clause id="H66C93A181C144A0CA89940E5B5A1265A"><enum>(x)</enum><text>to enhance water-based recreational opportunities for the benefit of community members and the local recreational economy; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HD8BD5CF7E4684AD4868F165F513BA58B"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>to encourage sustainable surface water or groundwater management; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B7ADDF703D4498CBC02FF2E47536B11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides benefits to ecosystems and watersheds, including through activities—</text>
<clause id="H562A64EE907F4B0C91C1DF1008F80B92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to conserve or enhance fish and wildlife habitat;</text></clause> <clause id="H2983AE3E788F46B488FA829DF20F7CD1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to protect or improve water quality;</text></clause>
<clause id="H93DB8FD048964D0289F9C6C452596F4E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to improve watershed health and function;</text></clause> <clause id="HA340DAF3365947B680FAFCD15F8337FB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to protect against invasive species;</text></clause>
<clause id="HA4E9A38FBB6740408E0444954D751CF1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to restore aspects of the natural ecosystem; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA3B79C42EB304684B7F13A9FD1C0E229"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to maintain sustainable groundwater supplies for multiple uses, including for riparian or wetland ecosystems.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5143E77C557F4AF4AC8DFD210EF9BC4C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Natural feature</header><text>The term <term>natural feature</term> means a feature that is created through the action of physical, geological, biological, and chemical processes over time.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A1C501B1B1245BCB22DA79F0C83CBD6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Nature-based feature</header><text>The term <term>nature-based feature</term> means a feature that is created by human design, engineering, and construction to provide a means to reduce water supply and demand imbalances or drought or flood risk by acting in concert with natural processes.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC5DF221B89CF4CA191991A04394CFC93"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Water Project Navigators Program established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D219F847B3F4ED1A83284999C53D45F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Rural community</header><text>The term <term>rural community</term> means a community or group of communities, each of which has a population of not more than 50,000 inhabitants, which may include Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, dispersed homesites, and rural areas.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF09F1D9FCD0B4C00AA41732ED5D0314A"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior (acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H5ECF55010D9A4A57920EC9F772D04837"><enum>3.</enum><header>Water project navigators program</header> <subsection id="HE397B6C0C1EB4D3EB8FC59FEB49CB508"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a program to support the development and implementation of multi-benefit water projects within eligible States, to be known as the <quote>Water Project Navigators Program</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9975DAD9C187471DA805DBA847D8DB54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to support the creation or continuation of multi-benefit water project navigator positions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H928F8FD9D8AD4477A6B2AA08E3A29DB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria and guidelines; priority</header> <paragraph id="H1EA6061508F647DE840D1561BDE0D30C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criteria and guidelines</header> <subparagraph id="HFDB4C4EEC0104F79A2F64080227A4F80"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall develop criteria and guidelines for awarding grants and cooperative agreements under the Program that consider—</text>
<clause id="H6204B80A0BD540959CA5013EFCE2B851"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the potential of the eligible entity to accelerate development and implementation of multi-benefit water projects within—</text> <subclause id="H735981AFC3B84ED69C1F1408C2C389CB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the jurisdiction or service area of the eligible entity; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HAECA5AA6F29941FA9075953FF875CA02"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity that is a nongovernmental applicant, an area in which the eligible entity has a demonstrated history of productive engagement with the community and stakeholders;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H900A9289741A4868BD0432701FE4C337"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any history of development of multi-benefit water projects by the eligible entity; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H6332FCA541CA48D9BA9D44FD4045899C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any potential multi-benefit water projects identified to meet needs in the area to be served by the multi-benefit water project navigator that the eligible entity has not yet implemented due to lack of capacity.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H581FCFF0226F48309E33673DA8FC366E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>Before finalizing the criteria and guidelines developed under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall make the criteria and guidelines available for public comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H06CAF433912A49CB8B83C62805C67C3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants or cooperative agreements under the Program, the Secretary shall prioritize applications from eligible entities that would directly serve Indian Tribes, disadvantaged communities, rural communities, and other eligible entities with limited resources and capacity to develop multi-benefit water projects, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H5A6F8ED8368945589D81261431EC2931"><enum>(A)</enum><text>applications from eligible entities—</text>
<clause id="HBC8550E40DA842DA98493707EA378DCD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with a demonstrated intent and ability to incorporate improvements to the condition of a natural feature or nature-based feature in multi-benefit water projects designed under the Program;</text></clause> <clause id="H0F8DF0E5F34E484195FCDA33E78C3178"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with demonstrated support from multiple stakeholders, including Indian Tribes, representatives of irrigated agricultural production, hydroelectric production, municipal and industrial water users, local governments, community-based organizations, and nonprofit conservation organizations;</text></clause>
<clause id="H9292A9CE26D94812A8741619A5F0A877"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that may promote job creation and retention in Tribal communities, disadvantaged communities, and rural communities; and</text></clause> <clause id="H954D16A0D75647AA9DFBE9BF9EC36BFF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>with the capability to work in coordination with other projects that have been funded under, or help advance the objectives of, other Department of the Interior programs, including programs focused on drought resilience and watershed health; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB4BB9B3384CE44E5BC2BB69746B4517F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>applications that address any other priorities that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23019010A9AC487DB0F9D008EB4C1A6B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Secretary may not award a grant or cooperative agreement under the Program that would fund activities to meet existing environmental mitigation or compliance obligations under Federal or State law.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA004682A80A34E588A59305BE9799485"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties of navigators</header><text>A multi-benefit water project navigator funded under the Program shall assist the eligible entity in planning, developing, and implementing multi-benefit water projects, including—</text> <paragraph id="H6917D6A37DDE4B7EA8077095CF8DE989"><enum>(1)</enum><text>grant writing;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2991E77CF2C148228C0827D0D490678F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>project management;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF93AA096BE445CEB73F2A7A8B9095B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>technical assistance, such as feasibility, design, preliminary environmental review, and engineering; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF611C55E2E584A32B2742A2E4E706281"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other necessary activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD91633230ED542569A930BB607995069"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duration of grants and cooperative agreements</header> <paragraph id="H8354F80FADE7430B96AC2D07143DA56F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a grant or cooperative agreement under the Program shall be limited to a period of not more than 3 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5D95A975AFF34B39846C6007913D389F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuation and extension</header><text>At the discretion of the Secretary, the Secretary may issue a continuation grant or extend a cooperative agreement awarded under the Program for not more than 2 additional years, with additional funding to be awarded, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary, if the recipient of the grant or cooperative agreement has demonstrated satisfactory performance with implementation of the proposal under the initial grant or cooperative agreement, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8984EC41ABE1447EA1B33D68E8DAFFCF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Continuous enrollment</header><text>The Secretary shall make funding opportunities for the Program available on a regular basis.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB61C73A14C5C42FD913FEA3FDB456DCE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Cost share</header>
<paragraph id="H9661B09C984B4B369A26948CA84E6086"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Federal share of the cost of any activity awarded a grant or cooperative agreement under the Program shall not exceed 75 percent of the cost of the activity carried out under the grant or cooperative agreement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87C4C3D713FF43AAB7FA8A2C975F5099"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of non-federal cost share</header><text>The non-Federal share of the cost of an activity awarded a grant or cooperative agreement under the Program may be in the form of cash or in-kind contributions.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF76433989AFF4BA5BBC2765F5A52D350"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reduction; waiver</header><text>With respect to a grant or cooperative agreement awarded to an Indian Tribe, acequia, land grant-merced, disadvantaged community, or any other eligible entity working in partnership with or on behalf of those entities, the Secretary may reduce or waive the non-Federal share of the cost of any activity that is the subject of the grant or cooperative agreement if the Secretary determines that contribution of the non-Federal share would result in a financial hardship for the entity.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6EDA491ED620463F9DD38CDCAD379475"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In administering the Program, the Secretary shall coordinate, to the maximum extent practicable, with other Federal, Tribal, State, and local government technical assistance programs to enhance multi-benefit water project development.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9AA3F238DB81474988C1133D8E1C1EED"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>A multi-benefit water project navigator funded under the Program shall comply with all applicable Federal and State laws in carrying out the duties of the multi-benefit water project navigator under the Program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4F90D67E1B104651BFEB64BDF50E76F4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</text>
<paragraph id="H3C315A729CA6466290B12DA3D3859BD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the ways in which the Program assists the Secretary in—</text> <subparagraph id="HFA411C28505A48BF99A3A6EB90FA53A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reducing basin-wide water supply-demand imbalances;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE68428746E4B498FA76778F768861E0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhancing drought and ecosystem resilience; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A12FF2044654031B283B3F05DA2DE78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting multi-benefit water project development and capacity building by disadvantaged communities, Indian Tribes, rural communities, and other eligible entities; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8B6730384DA74B66AAB7C894A6AA8AE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the benefits that the Program provides, including, to the maximum extent practicable, a quantitative analysis of the multiple benefits advanced under the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H769F0B66F62E48838E0EB71E1A271D14"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2032, to remain available until expended.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

