<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR26477-GYJ-2F-9C6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4241 IS: Boosting Housing Supply through Small Businesses Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4241</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require interagency coordination to support housing industry businesses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Boosting Housing Supply through Small Businesses Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4c3d116db0a423885a774b58140028c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><subsection id="id18c2f5abd1b64440a14295b31b2b05fc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id4862a140681e41eba8b71b991bd62569"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration; Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administration</term> and <term>Administrator</term> mean the Small Business Administration and the Administrator thereof, respectively.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5fee700fb9b94f5bb97b7a2ac90e56f1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id2f373c525310417c9c8e9eca5e8ab72d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1aa452d8cf145d196e563320655ce8b" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Small Business and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4cd37b8b77d34226839dcbd61a6e9a5c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0abf77736db4aa28d4828c6c0f26d25"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Housing industry small business</header><text>The term <term>housing industry small business</term> means a small business concern in the housing industry that contributes to housing supply and affordability, including residential and multifamily homebuilders, developers, general and specialty contractors, property managers and owners, housing startups, and home improvement and repair businesses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id20559779929840a9b1ab358733702395"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d2e22439b004542b3b14b0761c26962" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Small business concern; small business development center</header><text>The terms <term>small business concern</term> and <term>small business development center</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28b9889ee2eb4e31878c64eb69a9e7f1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="idc8c056d1a0dc4d5da2b93f6435d6060e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Administration and the Department share a mutual interest in supporting housing industry small businesses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9854eb1f5d044d51aec3b8ddbe35f68d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>there is a severe shortage of affordable and quality housing in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7d460bd5fc04f41a00e8ab1ac203a3e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the majority of American homebuilders and specialty contractors are small business concerns; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbc2041facbb74a68937c471387f1fd4d" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>homebuilders, contractors, and other housing industry small businesses play a significant role in increasing housing supply.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ida0f3d20bd9b24c8999f6d22dd2efdc31"><enum>4.</enum><header>Interagency coordination to support housing industry businesses</header><subsection id="id5fc1956968474773b3a8eb3979945de4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text>The Administrator shall coordinate with the Secretary to—</text><paragraph id="idaf96f9d11e454a6b81d09a2547efb77f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expand access to capital for housing industry small businesses, including rural and underserved businesses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id68d7e7025bfc485798b5d854abd7b79a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>streamline existing technical assistance, resources, and counseling services provided by the Administration and the Department that benefit housing industry small businesses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f26a03a93f1447aa0e14ebb849f853e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increase awareness and improve access for housing industry small businesses to Administration and Department financial and technical assistance programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id021a1043a3f440218c89f8c676dde455"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reduce barriers to starting and growing a housing industry small business.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idba0eb7be9c6048f2923f64b9295d0bea"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency plan</header><paragraph id="id692d64799891427ba9460b0480e228ac"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall work in coordination with the Secretary to develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees, and make publicly available on a website of the Administration, an interagency plan that includes—</text><subparagraph id="idf58d2d919ce24130b5fc0ee9d577df17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an examination of current gaps in financial and technical assistance for housing industry small businesses at the Administration and the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id354fdf83c7704e32b90d4fe2a499eb74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reforms to expand access to Administration loans to housing industry small businesses, including the loan programs under subsections (a) and (m) of section 7 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636</external-xref>) and section 502 of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/696">15 U.S.C. 696</external-xref>), or creating new loan products for housing industry small businesses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfaecbb3a64b24ee683c79a64be997834"><enum>(C)</enum><text>new programming or resources to be offered by the Administration or the Department that are specifically tailored to the needs of housing industry small businesses, including opportunities to host joint trainings or workshops;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10bb44858a474b73881257b9b5c6592e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>processes for information sharing and discussion of best practices between the Administration and the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1dc79c6a9e094615b1c38c4411015d9d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>opportunities for coordinated support between resource partners, including small business development centers, women's business centers described in section 29 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>), Veteran Outreach Business Centers described in section 32 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b</external-xref>), and chapters of the Service Corps of Retired Executives described in section 8(b)(1)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e73b910fc684aa08cd03fe0b37b3e37"><enum>(F)</enum><text>opportunities to support startups developing innovative products related to the housing industry, including by reducing barriers to access the Small Business Innovation Research and Small Business Technology Transfer programs under section 9 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638</external-xref>) or creating new innovation initiatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idadd7e3b267d94e46bffedc2edfa49640"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community engagement</header><text>The Administrator and the Secretary shall work in partnership with State and local governments, housing industry small businesses, resource partners described in paragraph (1)(F), and community and nonprofit organizations to develop the interagency plan required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

