<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-CAN25B43-WR0-J5-1N8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>94 SJ 100 IS: To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities against vessels operating in the Caribbean Sea or the Eastern Pacific Ocean that have not been authorized by Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 100</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities against vessels operating in the Caribbean Sea or the Eastern Pacific Ocean that have not been authorized by Congress.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section id="id3280566dd6094ae58a1b9da605b1b8d8" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idb0e7eb58b3174af4b3547c4a71372fb9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress has the sole power to declare war under article I, section 8, clause 11 of the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id418d161b5e1b43caa38b7253bc6322d6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress has not declared war or authorized the use of military force with respect to any of the vessels in the Caribbean Sea or the Eastern Pacific Ocean attacked by the United States Armed Forces since September 2, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35df695167c24c89abce57d61ba51d4d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>These maritime strikes beginning on September 2, 2025, within the meaning of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541 et seq.</external-xref>), are hostilities into which United States Armed Forces have been introduced.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c7862d9b044412c8ed791820ff8b864"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Pursuant to section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1544">50 U.S.C. 1544(b)</external-xref>), <quote>Within sixty calendar days after a report is submitted or is required to be submitted pursuant to section 4(a)(1) [of such Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1543">50 U.S.C. 1543(a)(1)</external-xref>)], whichever is earlier, the President shall terminate any use of United States Armed Forces with respect to which such report was submitted (or required to be submitted), unless the Congress (1) has declared war or has enacted a specific authorization for such use of United States Armed Forces, (2) has extended by law such sixty-day period, or (3) is physically unable to meet as a result of an armed attack upon the United States.</quote> Sixty days have passed since the President notified Congress of the actions described in paragraph (2), and no such authorization or extension has been enacted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id661fcb55111249e7883e17ff7678c7f6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>) provides that any joint resolution or bill to require the removal of United States Armed Forces engaged in hostilities without a declaration of war or specific statutory authorization shall be considered in accordance with the expedited procedures of section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/329">Public Law 94–329</external-xref>; 90 Stat. 765).</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc9b2119232204fad9c956f7c357c1d65"><enum>2.</enum><header>Termination of the use of United States Armed Forces for hostilities against vessels operating in the Caribbean Sea or the Eastern Pacific Ocean</header><subsection id="id9498faaa43a04b14844a3564810d8c54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Pursuant to section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>) and in accordance with the provisions of section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/329">Public Law 94–329</external-xref>; 90 Stat. 765), Congress hereby directs the President to terminate the use of United States Armed Forces for hostilities against vessels operating in the Caribbean Sea or the Eastern Pacific Ocean, unless explicitly authorized by a declaration of war or specific authorization for use of military force.</text></subsection><subsection id="idcfad2865f45540e1a21fe6e74ab62a38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the United States from defending itself from an armed attack or threat of an imminent armed attack.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution>

