<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7747CD03C1C048139EE40397E68D2C02" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1002 IH: Recognizing the value of the Older Americans Act of 1965 nutrition program in addressing hunger, malnutrition, and isolation, and improving the health and quality of life for millions of our Nations seniors each year.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1002</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the value of the Older Americans Act of 1965 nutrition program in addressing hunger, malnutrition, and isolation, and improving the health and quality of life for millions of our Nations seniors each year.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on March 22, 1972, President Richard Nixon signed into law <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/92/258">Public Law 92–258</external-xref>, which amended the Older Americans Act of 1965 (OAA) and established a national nutrition program for individuals 60 years and older;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas thousands of local senior nutrition programs, both congregate and home-delivered, are funded through the OAA nutrition program;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas these programs provide a vital lifeline to millions of older adults and individuals with disabilities in communities across the United States who may be homebound and isolated, struggling with hunger and malnutrition;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas local OAA nutrition programs provide nutritious meals, socialization, friendly visits, and wellness and safety checks through volunteers and staff to individuals who suffer from long-term chronic conditions, as well as to those who may need short-term assistance;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the official purposes of the OAA nutrition program are to—</text> <paragraph id="H9C3FEE0254C84C62A0596A957AA6BE6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduce hunger, food insecurity, and malnutrition;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E092E9FA2CA467E9825A23D4B70F8D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote socialization of older individuals; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE3C99A12077426FAA4F33CE1C5A5CF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote the health and well-being of older individuals by assisting such individuals to gain access to nutrition and other disease prevention and health promotion services that can delay the onset of adverse health conditions resulting from poor nutritional health or sedentary behavior;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the OAA nutrition program reduces other costs to taxpayers, primarily lowering Medicare and Medicaid expenditures by helping to—</text> <paragraph id="HC8069805499D49A28A167DA8CA9DA91B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevent falls;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB00EF4595EFB4DC5A690C82C083A4EF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>avoid unnecessary hospital transports, admissions, and readmissions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H870274CDD562447E8380C764E0D013DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expedite recovery from illness; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA28572F2C5DD4A1492152582361A39E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>delay or prevent institutionalization;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas local OAA nutrition programs are proven, valuable, and effective public-private partnerships that leverage private, corporate, and individual donations and other non-Federal funding sources to operate their services efficiently and successfully; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the over-60 population of the United States is rapidly growing and projected to increase significantly every year for the next several decades, causing a similar increase in the need and demand for local OAA nutrition program services: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas> </preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD643BA5751794B5DBF318D8FDB9F4C8B"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HED9333FDFB0449E59B9BF0EEDCF0F0E0"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H598324CA9E7849128F36EEE60355F7FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes and values the important work of local Older Americans Act of 1965 (OAA) nutrition programs nationwide in giving voice to millions of our Nation’s seniors each year, improving their quality of life and addressing senior hunger, malnutrition, and isolation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H292315C104D941A1813BC4BBB1D5A99E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes and values the important role that local OAA nutrition programs and national organizations play in increasing awareness of the growing unmet need for these programs and in raising additional non-Federal funds and soliciting volunteers to support and assist the important missions of these programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1704EFE1AE4A406F822D2FE6282717EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes and values volunteers as the backbone of the OAA nutrition program, noting that they deliver nutritious meals to seniors and individuals with disabilities who are at significant risk of hunger, malnutrition, and isolation, and provide caring concern and attention to the welfare of program participants; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H271547DD5DE1405E89C074AAA8A2979E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages Members of Congress to support their local OAA nutrition programs by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H54E59E87735F4B0AB847046937ED99DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>delivering meals to homebound seniors or serving them in a congregate setting with a program in their district or State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C845637C8F344E5B9278635A82DB9E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>working to secure sustained Federal funding for the OAA nutrition program that will allow local providers to keep pace with increased program costs and demand.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

