<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25M35-4NR-4J-S00"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3574 IS: Ending Chinese Lawfare Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3574</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit United States courts from recognizing, enforcing, or giving effect to any judgment, order, decree, or provisional measure issued by a court of the People’s Republic of China in a proceeding motivated by retaliation for lawful acts, including political speech.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Chinese Lawfare Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id03dd3da0fcdd42e58158b9141f00f58b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idd928223c5c51466caa04f5b1fda7ccfb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The judicial system of the People’s Republic of China is constitutionally subordinate to the Chinese Communist Party, which exercises ultimate authority over judicial outcomes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf70e6f1e9e5e49f0a0ad173cf03c6f77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Courts of the People’s Republic of China have been used as instruments of state policy, including by retaliating against foreign officials, governments, businesses, and individuals for protected political speech and lawful sovereign acts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0952573b215424285aa45b8ec2d5ff9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States has a compelling interest in protecting the First Amendment rights of its officials and citizens, preserving national sovereignty, and preventing foreign governments from weaponizing judicial processes to chill lawful conduct.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f39ee664d2b4b25ae4ba94aa2189c77"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recognition and enforcement of foreign judgments in the United States is a matter of comity, not obligation, and Congress has authority to regulate or prohibit such recognition whenever it conflicts with the Constitution, laws, or public policy of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6d01b62476104ca9ac86735d91376817"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>Politically motivated foreign judgments pose a direct threat to democratic governance and judicial integrity whenever foreign courts are used to punish speech or official action protected under United States law.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id4d96cea7c95f46819821076920b87d70"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on recognition or enforcement of politically-motivated judgments</header><subsection id="id25ab7bf250774eb1a5c8fbfc0a2d8234"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>No court of the United States, or of any State, territory, or possession of the United States, may recognize, enforce, or give effect to any judgment, order, decree, or provisional measure issued by a court of the People’s Republic of China if the United States court determines that the proceeding at which such issuance occurred—</text><paragraph id="id9b4efa8a15754424bbd8f755cb34d85a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>was initiated, directed, controlled, or materially supported by the Chinese Communist Party, the Government of the People’s Republic of China, or any instrumentality of either such entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id266e084b3fbd401a8a1d16164ca7d5e7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>was substantially motivated by retaliation for—</text><subparagraph id="idf5e5bb4d36ef403d925f38528d512c59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protected political speech;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c651d6b4c3f4babbefa9e25fb51d1db"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the lawful exercise of governmental authority; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1df297b6d86b451f85ae4ef54363c0a4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the exercise of rights secured by the Constitution or laws of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id50c61fb8c3a54e7bb5bfc1903eec27a3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evidentiary standard</header><text>A United States court may make a determination described in subsection (a) based on the totality of the circumstances, including—</text><paragraph id="id34e33471a3d24803820a917c5384fe11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the lack of judicial independence in the originating forum;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfdde4ac65cc34192b0116ad09e8e15cd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the identity of the plaintiff or its affiliation with the Chinese Communist Party or state entities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8001858f320546438739d16a14b931c7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>public statements by Chinese officials relating to the proceeding;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc12d31b7d5634b5ba49cb8d6eab0cf37"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the nature of the claims asserted and their relationship to protected speech or sovereign acts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2459e4b459474f0987cb2c12111c3c0e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the absence of due process or neutral adjudication.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5efe855fdc544015904216d38e88a20d"><enum>4.</enum><header>Fee-shifting and deterrence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If a party seeks recognition or enforcement of a judgment, order, decree, or provisional measure barred under section 3, the prevailing party opposing enforcement shall be awarded reasonable attorneys’ fees, costs, and expenses, including expert fees.</text></section><section id="idfe6e8517e8d74ee5b6262db1535e9f8a"><enum>5.</enum><header>Federal jurisdiction and removal</header><subsection id="idc33e65ddbe734a0b874fd3a21abd9063"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Original jurisdiction</header><text>The district courts of the United States shall have original jurisdiction over any action seeking recognition or enforcement of a judgment, order, decree, or provisional measure described in section 3(a).</text></subsection><subsection id="ida5535632d85d4b9b873c408cb6537213"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>Any action described in subsection (a) that is commenced in a State court may be removed to the appropriate United States district court by any party.</text></subsection></section><section id="idf151f95957d44ce7b21f5eab758488ce"><enum>6.</enum><header>Department of Justice intervention</header><subsection id="idc0f4112a88d34b29b9ab68dc4745af6a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Right To intervene</header><text>The Attorney General may intervene, as of right, in any proceeding involving the recognition or enforcement of a judgment, order, decree, or provisional measure described in section 3(a).</text></subsection><subsection id="id45ace38fc4934e1ba2e2c5ff7d4caef8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of interest</header><text>The Attorney General may submit a statement of interest regarding the political nature of the foreign proceeding, the lack of judicial independence, or the foreign policy interests of the United States, which the United States court shall give substantial weight.</text></subsection></section><section id="idcf1a7f84d2a74b9da899dd35f9910e3b"><enum>7.</enum><header>First Amendment and Sovereignty Protection Clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No judgment described in section 3(a) may be recognized or enforced if such recognition or enforcement would—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea612093e7d84536a89478c2aa8b1e7b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">penalize, burden, or chill speech or conduct protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ea69d26daa24066b34ab5fe723c57d7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interfere with the lawful exercise of United States sovereign authority.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id54c59e80fa9949deade6f17a8e08024d"><enum>8.</enum><header>Declaratory and injunctive relief</header><subsection id="id61915ccb29d04d25be9175554a494eda"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil action authorized</header><text>Any person, State, or governmental entity that is a party to, the subject of, or the target of a proceeding in a court of the People’s Republic of China described in section 3(a), and that has incurred or is incurring concrete costs, burdens, or restraints as a result of such proceeding, may bring a civil action in a United States district court for declaratory and injunctive relief.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb70258d4394f49a78a005ba51e9d66b0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Injury in fact</header><text>For purposes of article III of the Constitution of the United States, an injury in fact shall be deemed to exist if the plaintiff demonstrates, to the satisfaction of the court—</text><paragraph id="id411a9a2bb9654aafbc16cfa44215b71c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>participation in, or exposure to, a foreign judicial proceeding described in section 3; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76b0dddfcfad40769727e092b396202d"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ide95a3a5abdc248bf9d3f4c5cfb917d8f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>legal expenses or compliance costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29b53d092f5e4a2faf8d483db36287e7" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reputational injury;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id35ebedee297149848713a8230e740ef7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a credible chilling effect on constitutionally protected speech or conduct;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idcca451cce51c452b8d48224a0a6c07a0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impairment of property, contractual, or financial interests; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id972f6fde357b4f8397972b8cc6180095"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a substantial risk of enforcement efforts affecting United States-based interests.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide713945ed98c41b58147e4735c0a2d20"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In any action under this section, the court may—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e4ee6acf75842568fe7c3c8ef1d128a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">declare the foreign judgment or proceeding is not recognizable or enforceable in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id799aa187030447979d22ee5739848e08"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grant appropriate injunctive relief to prevent any attempt to seek recognition or enforcement of such judgment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id602728b5ee7f47309c2c3ab9d8f1443f"><enum>9.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to require a United States court to recognize or enforce any foreign judgment. This Act establishes a minimum standard of nonrecognition and does not limit other grounds for refusing enforcement under Federal or State law.</text></section><section id="id1851e8ad05b048148adb4d080832ec41"><enum>10.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision, is held invalid, the remainder of this Act and other applications of this Act shall not be affected.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

