<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA91A676675374D029928D27EF5B54E62" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8673 IH: To exempt stinger-steered combinations from a requirement to include warning flags on projecting loads.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8673</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To exempt stinger-steered combinations from a requirement to include warning flags on projecting loads.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H893B7B2CD2D044198FD1DEBAFB3991ED" style="OLC"><section id="H47B7FFF614654FB9A0BDD2A21C7387B0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Exemption of certain automobile transporters from requirement to include warning flags on projecting loads</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD981BE0684ED46CAABABF83A538319ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, section 393.87 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), shall not apply to a stinger-steered combination (as defined in section 658.5 of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)), that is transporting assembled highway vehicles.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD56CBC6F3191437682C88925295BB60D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revision</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8812716F1F1646D99052608EBF206C37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall revise section 393.87 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to exempt from the requirements of that regulation stinger-steered combinations (as defined in section 658.5 of title 23, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)), that are transporting assembled highway vehicles.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9040D307540249F4A07703F74A1896A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Transportation shall carry out paragraph (1) without engaging in notice and comment or any other formal rulemaking process.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

