<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H65F2C3F05A344E058FA934EDDCA7F375" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8960 IH: Local Beef Marketing Incentive Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8960</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a subsidy program to make payments to eligible producers for certain revenue losses associated with direct-to-market sales of beef, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2AB2A0E27CF0430EB4548E3BA2468EB5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H678697563F0245639F32492E60B7C974" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Beef Marketing Incentive Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H398D06E9CEAE47BB8A0C10E84B2381CD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of local beef marketing subsidy program</header> <subsection id="H71089229C0F04EC095F20D181FA101A0"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Farm Service Agency, (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall, with respect to each year determined to be a subsidy year under subsection (b), make payments to eligible producers for revenue losses associated with direct-to-market sales of beef.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H05EC73CB59044B22B31D7178D8007DF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of subsidy year</header> 
<paragraph id="HC2C8AC83E8ED4DC4B9932F50A959EC81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than March 1 of each calendar year, the Secretary shall determine the percent decrease, if any, in direct-to-market sales of beef for the preceding calendar year compared to the average direct-to-market sales of beef for the 5-year period preceding such calendar year, excluding the year with the highest and the year with the lowest direct-to-market sales of beef.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5AC2C7049F2541B2BB36B36130F75CCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualification for subsidy year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the percent determined under paragraph (1) with respect to a calendar year is greater than or equal to 25 percent for a calendar year, such calendar year shall be a subsidy year.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDA902893A90246D0A0A61BD9F427D502" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a payment under this section for a subsidy year, an eligible producer shall, not later than 1 year after the last date of such subsidy year, submit to the Secretary an application, including—</text> <paragraph id="H49E07F6885A0457DBA0A03B2454DD544" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">documentation demonstrating that such producer used a local processor during the subsidy year, including receipts or invoices;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58C517F472584D66AFC1B0F933E2E169" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>documentation of any direct-to-market sale completed by such producer during the subsidy year, including sale records, invoices, or such other documentation as the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB62AD25236F64D12A6C551961DAECC7B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a certification by the producer that such producer meets each requirement required pursuant to subsection (g)(3).</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H30BF1E0C4B36433FA3026559F4B526C5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payment amounts</header> 
<paragraph id="H30B2E7AA8990443DB3E3E3F4A6BF3D01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), not later than 90 days after receiving an application from an eligible producer with respect to a subsidy year under subsection (c), the Secretary shall, with respect to each head of cattle that such producer slaughters using a local processor and sells through direct-to-market sales in the subsidy year, make a payment to such producer in an amount that is equal to—</text> <subparagraph id="HBECE2A3E2DAF41999B0E49B691734780"><enum>(A)</enum><text>20 percent of the amount equal to—</text> 
<clause id="H645D8999A0A945BBAB4330F11FAFF320"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the average of the beef cattle price for the 5 years preceding the subsidy year, excluding the year with the highest and the year with the lowest average beef cattle price; minus</text> </clause> <clause id="H8D3F6CEAF2DC41F5B73D347E3A471EC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the beef cattle price for the subsidy year; multiplied by</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E9C6F1D51624AE89254B1577F7D268F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average of the live weight (in hundredweight) for all such cattle.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD07ECA510514818A93721901BF8E728"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header> <subparagraph id="H0B9A076254DD447895E24E2C16C6468A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Maximum payment amount with respect to head of cattle</header><text>The payment amount to a producer with respect to a head of cattle shall not exceed $500.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9174003CC4DD4E189E136DF39C76BED8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum total payment amount</header><text>The total amount of payments received under paragraph (1) by a producer for a subsidy year shall not exceed $100,000.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H78CA485EB3F54B1782BDD513BFD8A618"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issues such rules as may be necessary to carry out this section, including establishing procedures for verifying eligibility of a producer and preventing fraud.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H99A0722E25D94406AABAC2E66317C88B" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as necessary to carry out this section for fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H383F6AEBBEF34C45B0C38D6DFDDFC4BC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAE4D51BAF7DD4D33B4B7FBFD1CE959A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Beef cattle price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>beef cattle price</term> means the annual average price received by producers for all beef cattle (in dollars per hundredweight), as determined by the Secretary using data reported by the National Agricultural Statistics Service of the Department of Agriculture.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CA01EDC56044777AD0B49959D572BF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Direct-to-market sale</header><text>The term <term>direct-to-market sale</term> means the sale of beef products—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H993C3D99EF3E49BAB3F186C40600E116"><enum>(A)</enum><text>directly to consumers, restaurants, or retail stores;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC071D5F05E1D45DFB38E34F805192FC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through farmers’ markets, on-farm sales, community-supported agriculture programs, or similar channels; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E4133B9B9E348198D5D56B9E7234EDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>without using an intermediary, including a large-scale packer or distributor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C5D495E961347FBAA648C6D59FC0F97"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible producer</header><text>The term <term>eligible producer</term> means a farmer or rancher that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCF109522E6F54156A3CA27E119AE7F1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>raises and finishes steers or heifers for slaughter;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H58D3185BC2954E6CB039F6D58699A4B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>uses a local processor for such slaughter; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H09846AE3CE114587A217A0F51655E539"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engages in direct-to-market sales for at least 50 percent of their beef production in the subsidy year.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1546603B0AEE453C9E8C40B1F99DD4E2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Head of cattle</header><text>The term <term>head of cattle</term> means an individual steer or heifer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC872DF8DCF84FBF9287A146CD6AE65C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Local processor</header><text>The term <term>local processor</term> means a slaughter facility that is—</text> <subparagraph id="HC832F31F1A7347C887FA1C2E3A81B049"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inspected by the Food Safety and Inspection Service of the Department of Agriculture, or an equivalent State inspection program; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H825B1AE481E4464A86F5D53AD301384E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>located—</text> <clause id="HE5BD0E92502D4DE8B1BCD620C347A31E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the same State as the eligible producer using the services of such facility; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA1AC42EC9A894F99A1DCD2BB91AB8EA3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>within 200-miles of such producer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

