<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H70D57FFA0344400294BDC8F52656FA44" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8708 IH: Main Street Business Resource Integration and Development for Growth and Equity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8708</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and the National Director of the Minority Business Development Agency to direct small business development centers and MBDA Business Centers to collaborate to better serve small business concerns, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1C93971DD69047FC9683192796BA8708" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB45CBAD8475F4836A036EF254E912558" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Main Street Business Resource Integration and Development for Growth and Equity Act</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>Main Street BRIDGE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H5A6F4AFDDD144FF18D618F62E7682010"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collaboration between small business development centers and MBDA Business Centers</header> 
<subsection id="H6529ACF43473498FB7CDF178DBA4F490"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Collaboration required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator and the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall direct small business development centers and MBDA Business Centers, respectively, to collaborate to better serve small business concerns. </text> </subsection> <subsection id="H2B530D2354F94B5DB2F18CBCA9948D4D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator and the Director shall jointly submit to Congress a report that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5F3BB09187E74206BFA14F550AB47143"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A summary of the results of the collaboration required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6E967AFB9CB464988A75DDD0BE60C5D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the challenges faced by small business development centers and MBDA Business Centers in carrying out the collaboration required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H40C83670ABE347BE8CC143672D409501"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of consultations, educational activities, and outreach activities performed by small business development centers and MBDA Business Centers in connection with the collaboration required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8BC870A2AB244E9AB0AA14C51B7481C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of small business concerns served as a result of the collaboration required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H193EBA26664E4B2DA62A8DCBB0DE62BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of new small business concerns started as a result of the collaboration required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FF67F1EA8584366914EEC93782401BD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The number of new jobs created and existing jobs supported, in small business concerns, as a result of the collaboration required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF256EEE8EF14E62B75E544A926F846F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The dollar amount of financial assistance provided to small business concerns as a result of assistance received from small business development centers and MBDA Business Centers in connection with the collaboration required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD1BA4170D81490990A15461798CF52C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any recommendations for enhancing collaboration between small business development centers and MBDA Business Centers. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD248E696A4DF4314ADA939815BFC45B7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H0E5702C878C9414E9A3AD4ED037DC2F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CC99ACD164E4EC7BC4AC98B70661405"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the National Director of the Minority Business Development Agency. </text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H50CA57B1C3D24E67ADBFF25DCBBAACF5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>MBDA Business Center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>MBDA Business Center</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 100002(7) of the Minority Business Development Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9501">15 U.S.C. 9501(7)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F3810332D7C4B78B501657F3597302A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Commerce. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA520750C5048408891829DAACD7C599A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <quote>small business concern</quote> has the meaning given the term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3260A6D18A4B4078AADAF6B9AACA0367"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Small business development center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>small business development center</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 3(t) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(t)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> </section> </legis-body></bill>

