<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8645EB44362B41CF96F49B470353BAC4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9457 IH: Diversity Visa Protection and Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9457</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001246">Ms. Mejia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001245">Mr. Menefee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect the integrity of the Diversity Immigrant Visa Program, prevent unauthorized program-wide suspension, ensure transparency and congressional oversight of executive action, and reaffirm congressional intent.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H790E8C32E59F4BD580B192E0B88B84E4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4FBE8042AFF64DF39F380AEDBA12F82F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Diversity Visa Protection and Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HAC50086B353642E0AA9F3D056CD67346"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="HC9B2717A01B740D993B5AF37BF8BC5A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9228300EFFC14ADCBA54694E037D491F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Diversity Immigrant Visa Program is a congressionally authorized program established under section 203(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to promote diversity in lawful permanent immigration to the United States of America.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD9FCA01396140A4A6B2EC79E3F948FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress has delegated to the executive branch authority to administer immigration programs, including conducting security screening and imposing targeted restrictions where justified by national security or foreign policy concerns.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCB40A1A5A244CE2895CB11199785B4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such authority has historically included country-specific, regional, or case-by-case limitations, including restrictions related to armed conflict, sanctions, diplomatic breakdowns, or individualized security risks.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8E053AA556A4BB7997EA07757D4A095"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Program-wide or indefinite suspension of the Diversity Immigrant Visa Program, including halting issuance across all eligible countries, exceeds routine administrative discretion absent explicit statutory authorization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE193231BA5DD4DA09FAF8315263183E6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">National security screening of Diversity Immigrant Visa applicants occurs prior to visa issuance and can be strengthened or tailored without suspending the program as a whole.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEEDEDBF9093848A595A02B65AE743B8A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Indefinite or opaque administrative pauses undermine congressional intent, due process, and the lawful expectations of Diversity Immigrant Visa selectees.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD57F877E5EE74D688B7B60EDB7490144"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to—</text> <paragraph id="HF435B4FD70904C4CA553624013A20BA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirm the authority of Congress over the continuation of the Diversity Immigrant Visa Program as a whole;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32EFC496B8D94488A13CD365F6CB4E1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>distinguish between permissible targeted restrictions and impermissible wholesale suspension of the program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F0D863C1268465C8AEDBAA26AD86923"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure transparency, accountability, and congressional oversight when the executive branch limits Diversity Immigrant Visa processing; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8835AB832F0D46B0AEF5ED549CD3256A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protect eligible Diversity Immigrant Visa selectees from losing lawful immigration opportunities due to broad, non-specific administrative pauses (or Executive action).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H32A3D4FB2EB44DC78B28C901C06FD8F2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on program-wide suspension of the diversity immigrant visa program</header> <subsection id="HF1C7C9E1B4934C439C9E23F1A9B19208"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on program-wide suspension</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as applicable, may not suspend, pause, or stop the issuance of visas pursuant to section 203(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(c)</external-xref>). </text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H779138C252524191BB3937F9839458A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limited exceptions</header><text>The Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as applicable, may—</text> <paragraph id="H90ED055D1FBA499ABE774C5E323237FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement a country-specific or regional suspension or limitation on the issuance of visas pursuant to section 203(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(c)</external-xref>) following notification to Congress in accordance with subsection (c); </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98C1E85D4CBD45A8B99C23ABDC010EF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>undertake a case-by-case delay, denial, or request for enhanced screening based on an individualized security, criminal, or eligibility determinations; or </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10FA2DDE2EAD4518A3FBF76E8BF5E497"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">suspend the issuance of visas pursuant to section 203(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(c)</external-xref>) for a limited period not exceeding 60 days with issuance automatically resuming on the date that is 60 days after the date of such suspension following notification to Congress in accordance with subsection (c). </text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5D8463CF8B348358C7EED1E9D2D1023"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional notice and transparency requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HCAEA1DDF58DE40C8B3590B9009B112EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice to congress</header><text>Not later than 7 days before initiating a suspension or limitation described under subsection (b)(1), the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as applicable, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees notice of such suspension or limitation, including —</text> <subparagraph id="HFED4017F275F49BA93DCC34B1A07D209"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the scope, geographic reach, and duration of the suspension or limitation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF68ACCD150944C67800600C59E2BC15C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification of the specific and extraordinary threat that necessitates the issuance of visas pursuant to section 203(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(c)</external-xref>) and explanation why a narrower, targeted, or country-specific measure would not sufficiently address the identified threat, if applicable; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H304F94DD8873470796DC90A088CBC20D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the specific national security or foreign policy rationale for the suspension or limitation; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H62A11791B09A4FDE8B22B764B6A0CC6A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the legal authority relied upon for such suspension; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3BE753AD8EE24C218DD7B8309F032BC9"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the steps being taken to resume normal issuance of visas pursuant to section 203(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(c)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB16CED6A2B4546F8BC35D10D20B99731"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public disclosure</header><text>The notice described under paragraph (1) shall be published in the Federal Register, except for classified annexes provided to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE16E4D164A854832B47E11C376437109"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Protection for diversity immigrant visa selectees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No individual issued a visa pursuant to section 203(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(c)</external-xref>) shall lose eligibility for such visa as a result of a suspension described under subsection (b)(3). </text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCAF0925D8FD84F00A3C2FB30533851E0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committee defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committee</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="HC8E49B3D8585406FB0431E9873EDBF73"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H49A8A19516B5468AA6CDC6840C44B82C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B777ACD363A4886B43A02176FD575FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations on the Senate. </text> </paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

