<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25B98-FJS-KS-PPS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3268 IS: Broadband and Telecommunications RAIL Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3268</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to streamline the deployment of telecommunications or broadband service facilities in public rights-of-way and the rights-of-way of railroad carriers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Broadband and Telecommunications RAIL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id5b1eea1e45ee4c778e7e4b06adbc11c0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Deployment of telecommunications or broadband service facilities in public rights-of-way and railroad rights-of-way</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VII of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/601">47 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71d28fab5f864d5e9449a90c634becab"><section id="id1c2408c5b5624269b9854562f34b281d"><enum>723.</enum><header>Deployment of telecommunications or broadband service facilities in public rights-of-way and railroad rights-of- way</header><subsection id="ida64934f5e4c54738a0fe2f3e22f76785"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id11b1b894770e4df1b64eadee2ff96089"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadband service</header><text>The term <term>broadband service</term> has the meaning given the term <term>broadband internet access service</term> in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id24384242fc294a59b1dd44a7970441b4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provider</header><text>The term <term>provider</term> means a provider of telecommunications service or broadband service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31f83aae7d894110a1aa3f270fe32b49"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public right-of-way</header><text>The term <term>public right-of-way</term> means a public street, highway, route, or road (as designated by the Federal Government or a State or local government), including—</text><subparagraph id="id4af5f09c0453480590eb6d63d4022773"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any railroad installation listed in the National Highway-Rail Crossing Inventory of the Department of Transportation as an over (at grade), under (subgrade), longitudinal (parallel), or transverse (crossing) installation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb12d7da5a9ec48869038a4aafc61d6d7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a private crossing with public access listed in the National Highway-Rail Crossing Inventory of the Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b6727e6be4041428c9a5dc7da0137da"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Railroad carrier</header><text>The term <term>railroad carrier</term> has the meaning given the term in section 20102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id80b8b40a7cc74888821f578fd773fd83"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Telecommunications or broadband service facility</header><text>The term <term>telecommunications or broadband service facility</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id02230f333820445fa062889844465da2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a facility used to provide or support the provision of any telecommunications service or broadband service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58db588e0af947009e3aaf444568c871"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a facility described in subparagraph (A) that is used to provide, or support the provision of, other services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3b59b4f564bd4f158e0a79a62acbd249"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification of work by providers in public rights-of-Way</header><paragraph id="idbf166672cb3b4974bc50ddb337ee38a6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a State or local government has authorized a provider to place or modify a telecommunications or broadband service facility in a public right-of-way, and the telecommunications or broadband service facility will be placed or modified in an area where the public right-of-way intersects with a railroad corridor, the provider—</text><subparagraph id="id735f17614bf142b38fe4e50c023fc051"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall submit to the applicable railroad carrier a written notification that the placement or modification has been authorized by the State or local government; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id272607ced2e04185ae0af1e5197fceca"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not be required to submit an application to the railroad carrier under subsection (c) with respect to the placement or modification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b1808d6fb504f738db10ae2e733bc80"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A notification submitted under paragraph (1) shall contain the following information with respect to a placement or modification described in that paragraph:</text><subparagraph id="idb3bf6b549b3e4834a858a07bc96b2770"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The location of the placement or modification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05b67b882d274af9bd6a37817fb13c51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The proposed date of commencement of work with respect to the placement or modification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id055372adaef54181b94055e446462cb2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The anticipated duration of the work described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59c95a191e5b4a2d84353db7387d0431"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The entry and exit points that will be used with respect to the performance of the work described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09307d0048e447178da95227ab10b994"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The contact information of the provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fd5e0af5e344ba2867aaf20e94276f5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Scheduling</header><text>Following the submission of a complete notification under paragraph (1) by a provider—</text><subparagraph id="idb0a4b0835d21466b89b87c6168ada31e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the provider shall schedule a date in coordination with the applicable railroad carrier for the placement or modification of the telecommunications or broadband service facility to which the notification applies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ff9861b24e94f78adb41faf074a2d4f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the placement or modification described in subparagraph (A) shall commence—</text><clause id="ided86720d47d947b9a0e0f0abdf9f5b24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not earlier than the date that is 15 days after the date on which the notification is submitted; and</text></clause><clause id="idb6c784bc09d84ed7bb471abafe9efde0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than—</text><subclause id="id443de8ac59554b3aaea95b33dbb9822e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date that is 30 days after the date on which the notification is submitted; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id047320c4fca641fba20f85ae92c47c58"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such other date as mutually agreed upon by the provider and the applicable railroad carrier.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6aa75a50c49442e96d4c2027d0750fb"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Payment not required</header><subparagraph id="id50492e49a3de4b998d2743dbb93b8336"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A provider shall not be required to pay a railroad carrier with respect to the placement or modification of a telecommunications or broadband service facility in a public right-of-way, as authorized by a State or local government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id80fb1c45439b49dda0b3320bf4457b7b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) may be construed to affect any requirement, pursuant to an authorization by a State or local government for a provider to place or modify a telecommunications or broadband service facility in a public right-of- way, for the provider to make any payment to any entity with respect to the placement or modification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id490dcde25c89470a82a43d733f1a5add"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application To place or modify telecommunications or broadband service facilities in railroad rights-of-Way</header><paragraph id="idd8ee70d29a0544c4b1a467eab7242800"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to place or modify a telecommunications or broadband service facility in the right-of-way of a railroad carrier, a provider shall submit to the railroad carrier a written application that contains the following information:</text><subparagraph id="idda5358d6685b4bc682373d5d6a12e0bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Engineering design plans, construction plans, and (if applicable) bore plans with respect to the placement or modification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id654a690cd27b4048ac8439618f7e89d7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The location of the placement or modification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95859f48d50b4c898c06c1fe16d92174"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The proposed date of commencement of work with respect to the placement or modification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75174b404ac24287981a1a099fb7c326"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The anticipated duration of the work described in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfcaf14ae48cc459294aadd0749b3871c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The entry and exit points that will be used with respect to the performance of the work described in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f90b141939d45a3932a9c41c1b174c9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The contact information of the provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8948583b6dd64140a11eca3911ef4c67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Decision</header><subparagraph id="ided8e7822347941049d7b82d285c76e81"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which a railroad carrier receives a complete application that contains the information required under paragraph (1), the railroad carrier shall—</text><clause id="id35511c623b684f119c2ddc5e6fd5ac60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approve or deny the application; and</text></clause><clause id="idcd984ac4941c43b78b47905f2a9c977e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transmit to the provider that submitted the application a notification of the approval or denial under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e82dc41d89c424cb5ce929199c08620"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusive reasons for denial</header><text>A railroad carrier may only deny an application under subparagraph (A) if the placement or modification of a telecommunications or broadband service facility proposed in the application would—</text><clause id="id32a9ce863b174db5a760f535a5f2c94f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>substantially interfere with or damage the infrastructure or permanent operations of the railroad carrier; or</text></clause><clause id="idee157d19dc0f4e7697d7d09be1ac8b5b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>jeopardize the safety of passengers or employees of the railroad carrier.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4598bff86ca34b28bdb6d4f8f13fab76"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Explanation</header><text>If a railroad carrier denies an application under subparagraph (A), the railroad carrier shall include in the notification required under clause (ii) of that subparagraph an identification of each reason under subparagraph (B) for which the railroad carrier denied the application and an explanation of how that reason for denial applies to the application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf35dfdca3d743b1924616c23e8a06cc"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Scheduling</header><text>Following approval of an application under this subsection, the applicable provider shall schedule a date in coordination with the railroad carrier for the placement or modification of the applicable telecommunications or broadband service facility, which shall commence not later than—</text><subparagraph id="id4b999a536e154c859d0c0dcf28de5445"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that is 30 days after the date of the approval; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde1d966f99a347f6a751e7ab260ae861"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such other date as indicated in the application or mutually agreed upon by the provider and the railroad carrier.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ff0fb1246bc4c4abb65df2218e761b0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>A provider that submits to a railroad carrier an application under this subsection shall pay the railroad carrier compensation in an amount that is equal to the actual costs reasonably and directly incurred by the railroad carrier with respect to the application.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id06050079bb6e4a4f844f0a7646a42efd"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Petition for relief</header><paragraph id="id00ce3c089de44ea59891ab93b926530d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="idd8a335a4e6d249eaa576badb3a93216c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Railroad carrier</header><text>A railroad carrier may petition the Commission for relief regarding the placement or modification by a provider of a telecommunications or broadband service facility in an area where a public right-of-way intersects with a railroad corridor, or in the right-of-way of the railroad carrier, if the railroad carrier asserts that—</text><clause id="idfa9f7eaad7eb486797d57aec0a248d5e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a placement or modification with respect to which the provider has submitted an application to the railroad carrier under subsection (c), the amount of compensation that the provider proposes to pay under paragraph (4) of that subsection is not actual costs reasonably and directly incurred by the railroad carrier, as required by that paragraph; or</text></clause><clause id="id53506d41e43a44e184be3364c690a273"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the provider has otherwise failed to comply with this section or a regulation promulgated under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ffe5d1da29e4151a118c0dec222a17c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Provider</header><clause id="id2a7695abec3d4ed9914bd4dc22e77ce5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A provider may petition the Commission for relief regarding the placement or modification by the provider of a telecommunications or broadband service facility in an area where a public right-of-way intersects with a railroad corridor, or in the right-of-way of a railroad carrier, if the provider asserts that the relevant railroad carrier has—</text><subclause id="ida091cb95c14e413d81235a66f0a39e8c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>wrongfully obstructed or delayed the placement or modification;</text></subclause><subclause id="id3a3d92465ff44b38b69cfea62414c58a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>requested payment in an amount in excess of the actual costs required under subsection (c)(4); or</text></subclause><subclause id="idb85b5996ffaf40bbaea9ec337185fabb"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise failed to comply with this section or a regulation promulgated under this section.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3294316aae7a44e49f643612d1f0a61e"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>In the case of a placement or modification with respect to which a provider has submitted an application to a railroad carrier under subsection (c), the provider may not file a petition for relief under clause (i) with respect to the placement or modification before the earlier of—</text><subclause id="id577370d4e1aa4462898df9d27ada9a7f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date on which the railroad carrier notifies the provider of the approval or denial of the application; and</text></subclause><subclause id="iddf85ee594fb24dd2865040a14270bdc1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the day after the date that is 60 days after the date on which the railroad carrier receives the application.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id64f65be7b2b0431e92dea35412d8d6a6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjudication</header><subparagraph id="id25b235d4a1034a04a86a7e7615655a06"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>The Commission shall be the sole Federal agency with jurisdiction to hear and resolve a petition filed under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida971881d8c26423e8e282184128fe53a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>In adjudicating a petition filed under paragraph (1), the Commission may make any necessary findings of fact or determinations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id777d17add8824bc8a78e54ddc69184d8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use of experts</header><clause id="id5e1f9a75991745499838c034079bd2b9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In adjudicating a petition filed under paragraph (1), the Commission may employ experts to advise the Commission with respect to—</text><subclause id="idb6d358749b6d4c2eb75099835f63c907"><enum>(I)</enum><text>examining locations, plans, specifications, and descriptions of equipment and methods proposed to be employed;</text></subclause><subclause id="id3e12ea674c7d4b74bdffd8e9c453aeb4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>hearing any objections and considering any modifications that the applicable railroad carrier or provider submits;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd5b477829d69484e8f2835ada6f6838e"><enum>(III)</enum><text>rejecting, approving, or modifying proposed plans and specifications; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id6fbce42f828a493eaea12aad8185e4e0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>technical, economic, and other matters concerning the applicable placement or modification.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id62de7d9a2acb4c7f97f61f4f87216b46"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>The party against which the Commission rules on an issue with respect to which an expert employed by the Commission under clause (i) renders services under that clause shall reimburse the Commission for the cost of those services.</text></clause><clause id="id2687fbaeba694de6b9b9b3e2d825e62f"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Deposit of collections</header><text>Amounts received to reimburse the Commission for the cost of services rendered by an expert employed under clause (i) shall be deposited in, and credited to, the account through which funds were made available to pay that cost.</text></clause><clause id="id668675dabc1d41fb94959c011acde4d6"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Commission may employ experts under clause (i) pursuant to section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd141280e73fc4067a33a9bc5fb4273b6"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Coordination with Federal agencies</header><text>In adjudicating a petition filed under paragraph (1), the Commission shall coordinate with the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration regarding any finding of fact or determination relating to railroad safety.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8c7fa12c3fa4e469a42dab42a29b0fd"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Final order</header><clause id="id9af0aa7af3d74240afe4f73c29109000"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a petition is filed under paragraph (1), the Commission shall issue a final order regarding the petition in which the Commission may grant such relief as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></clause><clause id="idb2a3494c89c545f9a22086647ba601ea"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Extension of deadline</header><subclause id="id967ffd6f0fc349109455acd84b91459d"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subclause (II), the Commission may extend the deadline with respect to a petition under clause (i), as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></subclause><subclause id="id971d3f2337164c3c9bd42b4f4c55ed97"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Commission may not extend the deadline with respect to a petition under clause (i) on the basis of the coordination required under subparagraph (D).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id210c8578890845f1afcb4184a617ddc2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Responsibilities of parties</header><paragraph id="id841160fc547c4a25839b0e2910bac7f2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Railroad carriers</header><text>With respect to the placement or modification by a provider of a telecommunications or broadband service facility in an area where a public right-of-way intersects with a railroad corridor, or in the right-of-way of a railroad carrier, the relevant railroad carrier shall—</text><subparagraph id="id085fb266ef794f998a7bb93e8c3fa06c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take such protective measures as the railroad carrier determines necessary and appropriate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c6a2d51f7494379bbc6885c593c5867"><enum>(B)</enum><text>perform any work necessary to implement the placement or modification that the provider is prohibited from performing because of the limitations under subsection (f)(2)(D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5d27cdff5384bb181762de0a19bc282"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Providers</header><text>With respect to the placement or modification by a provider of a telecommunications or broadband service facility in an area where a public right-of-way intersects with a railroad corridor, or in the right-of-way of a railroad carrier, the provider—</text><subparagraph id="id95f18fb3b6054c1388ada9da63fba84e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be required to obtain additional insurance for the placement or modification; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e1f188dd11a45eea47a0160b0e4730f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall—</text><clause id="id2bd5e309efd34a20a0fc89295f95e350"><enum>(i)</enum><text>carry out all aspects of the implementation of the placement or modification (other than any work necessary to implement the placement or modification that the provider is prohibited from performing because of the limitations under subsection (f)(2)(D)); and</text></clause><clause id="id07828f488521494fa4c4dea48e49d599"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that the placement or modification is carried out, and that the telecommunications or broadband service facility is operated, in accordance with—</text><subclause id="idcab5840217f045299e9f2b345bd7224b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all applicable Federal laws and regulations, including those relating to railroad safety; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idc70777c638114f1fb8aecd1922f5f67f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any accepted industry standards specified by the Commission.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id542c97d0e078443da21ec00ea20eb978"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><paragraph id="idf19fe61d3fac49a6bfdd7e83bcf30670"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Commission shall promulgate regulations (which may include regulations applicable to railroad carriers) to implement this section in a manner that—</text><subparagraph id="id28ac5aa75b884652a002197bcaa95c03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensures railroad safety, including by ensuring compliance with all applicable Federal laws and regulations, including those relating to railroad safety;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc903964744ab4d4390a0b72909681ab5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides a process for more the timely placement or modification of a telecommunications or broadband service facility in an emergency situation than would otherwise be provided for under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f747d8c941a4102acb3917dcf9c4a0e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prevents substantial interference with the infrastructure or operations of railroad carriers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb96e4706103421c96a1b7342e8e24bd"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allows for the timely and efficient placement and modification of telecommunications or broadband service facilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbc257e0d61e044d29e11642f5ca786e9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provides a process for the more timely placement or modification of a telecommunications or broadband service facility in a railroad carrier crossing that is discontinued or abandoned than would otherwise be provided for under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id48d713acf9174b0eb21c466fb5edca08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>In the regulations promulgated under paragraph (1), the Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="id3ede7a56f0b54ed1bfd46d76a05d4c18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish standards and procedures for determining whether the reasons for denial under clauses (i) and (ii) of subsection (c)(2)(B) are satisfied;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3afc73924ece498a923cba71b22c2af4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish standards and procedures for determining actual costs under subsection (c)(4);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e27e77684a143c9b283932dbae43374"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish standards and procedures for adjudicating petitions for relief under subsection (d), including with respect to reimbursement of the Commission for the cost of services rendered by experts employed under subsection (d)(2)(C);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida63ffa134551480fa6f7dc3afd041113"><enum>(D)</enum><text>specify any limitations on the locations within an area where a public right-of-way intersects with a railroad corridor, or within the right-of-way of a railroad carrier, where a provider may perform work relating to the placement or modification of a telecommunications or broadband service facility, or on the types of such work that a provider may perform within such an area or right-of-way, in order to ensure railroad safety and to prevent substantial interference with the infrastructure or operations of railroad carriers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5d01b3cf8ac4bb3869f85f0360b895f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>otherwise establish standards and procedures and define terms as necessary to implement this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4413c8e8125248f1952b5b7129b71892"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with Federal agencies</header><text>In promulgating regulations under paragraph (1), the Commission shall coordinate with the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration regarding any matter relating to railroad safety.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id671be6d83e5e4956b43ebc90c7c0397d"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Commission and the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration shall confer and enter into a memorandum of understanding to work cooperatively to ensure that safety concerns of railroad carriers and users of public rights-of-way are addressed in any coordination that occurs pursuant to subsection (d)(2)(D) or (f)(3).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d0d9f5f76594ab6bbdcb4cc997e2185"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section, including in any regulation promulgated under subsection (f), may be construed as establishing, eliminating, or modifying an agreement between a railroad carrier and a labor organization representing a class or craft of employees of that railroad carrier that is covered by the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

