<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0A3DE9AAD7454BA8A1CF657DAA2A6EF4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9314 IH: DHS Surveillance Technology Moratorium Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9314</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enact a moratorium on certain Department of Homeland Security contracts relating to the use and implementation of surveillance and data analytics technologies pending public audits and reporting requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8C90A590BF2D41EEB8874AA6C13103B4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8F776CA7D67C497D88D36F65ECE428AD" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Surveillance Technology Moratorium Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H567C824EEE384F6283E63B77AE8822A8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HDCE4666FB95F484DAEE76BC008DDE676"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered contract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered contract</term> means any contract or agreement relating to a covered surveillance technology and its use by the Department of Homeland Security to identify, locate, or otherwise track individuals or support or inform immigration enforcement operations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D71A901ADD14840B27B336611B3197A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered surveillance technology</header><text>The term <term>covered surveillance technology</term> means any technology, software, platform, application, or service used by the Department of Homeland Security that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF10147C18AD147879C86A06AA5AC2250"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collects, aggregates, analyzes, retains, maps, predicts, or operationalizes personal information; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF0D6473E17F4458A8E65F525293498F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is used to identify, locate, track, or otherwise support or inform immigration enforcement operations, whether civil or criminal in nature, conducted by the Department, including technologies involving facial recognition technologies, social media monitoring, cellphone location tracking, geolocation analytics, predictive analytics, artificial Intelligence-assisted targeting, or integrated data aggregation platforms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E10F40F42F54F03A1B6087A9E121CDF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H73245CF230AE4C73BE8457732530AE7A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Moratorium of covered contracts</header> 
<subsection id="HA018A3900C34422494BCD5C8479C812F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (d), no funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Homeland Security may be obligated or expended for—</text> <paragraph id="H169E35147A264986A3EF0322E62BF169"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the award of a new covered contract,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25B7CB0B988E44B0A9E49E702F76F625"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the renewal or extension of an existing covered contract,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H878EBC941F8A42BBBD49A82D220EAF97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the exercise of an option under a covered contract, or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE664FC78B1C4D928A4F7B20A253E4B0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the expansion or modification of a covered contract,</text></paragraph> <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">until the requirements under section 4 are fulfilled.</continuation-text></subsection> <subsection id="HDC0492D4836F4DE68CF18360F1938363"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply to all covered contracts entered into by—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDA14A63871DB4EECB04C965E7FFF8F27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CABC690E9174EB593664A6A3FE77609"><enum>(2)</enum><text>U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDDB5BD1F99564080AEF2E42759FAF449"><enum>(3)</enum><text>United States Citizenship and Immigration Services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H472463987E6447DABC732A128320ADD5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Office of Intelligence and Analysis; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23C1D5ECB718408EAE661494D5CCCDA8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other Department of Homeland Security component determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEA92F4B4598246AA8F1427F30296B35F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Existing operations</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to require the immediate termination of an existing covered contract in effect, or the use by the Department of Homeland Security of a covered surveillance technology, as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H14EFC89D688B4574A875E4A542EC9DCE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception</header> 
<paragraph id="HEBD481E0A4A34A9480CFEC2467588F9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may waive subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis if the Secretary certifies to Congress that the covered contract at issue is necessary to address—</text> <subparagraph id="HF9EFD36CE4E845919B8FB9620DED18AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an imminent act of violence or specific, articulable threat to life or public safety; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25FBC7733282443EAF5591EFED6D21F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a specific national security threat.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9579EB51D934E6C8FC143ECE7FC7EA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>Any such waiver shall include a detailed written justification submitted to Congress not later than seven days after the issuance of such waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3444B093D11C4CAD927C0582CDC6F19C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Required audit and review</header> 
<subsection id="HA5D546F7927D461BB4560E674B2451BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Department of Homeland Security Privacy Office and the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties, shall conduct an audit and review of all covered surveillance technologies used by the Department.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H44A06FDE3B9D4BB8AA0363A26FD9B32B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required contents</header><text>The audit and review required under subsection (a) shall examine—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCEED75F8FCAC462DB658F9575E9952B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the categories and sources of data collected, compiled, or aggregated;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B19E2E875F44604B550FF5B90C1F068"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether data relating to United States citizens is collected, retained, or analyzed;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33E05319D06C40F8A929C3C6949C8F71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use of facial recognition technologies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5AAE934709A845D2AE1248497A856644"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the use of commercial data brokers or telemetry data;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD40DC287D6F14A5AB2003D5298953213"><enum>(5)</enum><text>data retention and deletion practices;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4DF5C0065194F6EB6D9E6D4E6657C04"><enum>(6)</enum><text>contractor access to Federal Government data;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3397FD14CC654C17958E75CA3CB82E7C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>privacy and civil liberties impacts;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD952F05EFD2741329C316A9338EAB3CB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the use of technologies and information collected in connection with lawful protest, assembly, or protected speech;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B6094D672A543A4B0B54DA30A7E21AE"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of technologies and information collected in connection with immigration enforcement operations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C8FB5E25965451D9365DE215E2AC04D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the accuracy and reliability of predictive or probabilistic systems; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E2A635DFA0147C4A42DB6DF4C836682">
          <enum>(11)</enum>
 <text>compliance with applicable Federal privacy and civil liberties laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE4CDC7E9E8E4488B9C5D3F77F6D38BC0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Public reporting requirements</header> <subsection id="HA94D5479674B46258C506BC0BB744F45" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after completion of the audit and review required under section 4, the Secretary shall publish an unclassified and publicly available report containing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7C6E2E992F4149DC9633BCAB2D131252" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of all covered surveillance technologies currently used by Department of Homeland Security;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6910569B4E54D8C955E6F958EAF82B5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the names of all contractors providing such technologies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93614524BB644493A03F54E25D9AB57C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the capabilities and purposes of each such technology;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8B1DAB663984BCEBEC119E076C8FA10" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all privacy and civil liberties impact assessments relating to the use of such technologies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE93B6DA0E0F04955A68BC10ECAA4627E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the impacts of the use of such technology on civil immigration enforcement operations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70829F2A8F7F44BCA2FCB45472C31C2E" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>all data sources used by such technologies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37F1376D8CC1422D870277C6B492983F" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>all policies governing the retention, sharing, and deletion of collected information; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA788A531E1A8433082CDCFFB2E1CFC04"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any agreements, policies, or practices that govern the sharing of information utilized by covered surveillance technologies between the Department of Homeland Security and—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H28AF999D959D4B818C9F5694E48A1436"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other Federal agencies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D92B984A601466F82922CE4710580D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any State, local, Tribal, or territorial government; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8CDF0BD9F0B6410693E9F9A852636BD9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any private sector entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8684B18DA63B4C24815565656CFE81A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Redactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any redactions in the report required under subsection (a) shall be limited solely to information the disclosure of which would create a specific and identifiable harm to national security. Any such redaction shall be accompanied by a written justification relating thereto, and shall be reviewed by the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC9856E13420F43E1B796E84B705B9867" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Conditions for end of moratorium</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The moratorium under section 3 shall terminate only after the later of—</text> <paragraph id="H3FC7B25EC61248F5B87F5C29927AFCD3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the audit required under section 4 is completed;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9698D524B0949688F330B29B61A19E3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the public report required under section 5 is published; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00CFF9B22DEB4625899EAA1E4F7EE474" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the elapse of 90 days after the Secretary provides to Congress a report specifying—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6D02EE9AF3104CA986FBD6BBD410BDFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the implementation by the Department of Homeland Security of necessary safeguards to ensure compliance with all applicable constitutional, statutory, and privacy protections;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE32B78DE16BE463984E1842137337A4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the legal authorities relied upon by the Secretary for the procurement, deployment, and use of covered surveillance technologies; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3826B696A0040838713D151555912BA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all internal memoranda, policy directives, or guidance, and other records relied upon by the Department in authorizing or governing the use of covered surveillance technologies.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph></section> <section id="H77F14C8DDB05458F94D9088271DC7F8D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Annual reporting after moratorium</header> <subsection id="H0F04F255503C4F4D9FC8A46A1E3972F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the termination of the moratorium under section 3 and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress and publish on a publicly available website of the Department of Homeland Security an unclassified report on the Department’s use of covered surveillance technologies.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H14CE2813F27144BE8ABCBCECC3703A13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required contents</header><text>Each report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H1864EB1BE6344F57B577E3537F902D3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A current list of all covered surveillance technologies in use, and an identification of the contractors providing from which such technologies have been procured.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC079E95F8D0140C9A71BA6F3354CC78B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information relating to any new covered contracts entered into during the immediately preceding year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H570FDB56CA634E99A7920F9B4EB52D7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of any changes to data retention, sharing, or deletion policies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26B1E14442724F06B4C09D1A23975218"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A summary of privacy and civil liberties incidents or complaints and the resolution of such incidents and complaints.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF726C4AF7EA4EDDB34098585A2D5226"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Information relating to any waivers issued under section 3(d) during the immediately preceding year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1778F025F1E45328C5EE7A4C08D6527"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assessment of continued compliance with applicable constitutional, statutory, and privacy protections.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC3B632B175084E338063EBE58B78E584" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Redactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any redactions in a report required under subsection (a) shall be limited solely to information the disclosure of which would create a specific and identifiable harm to national security. Any such redaction shall be accompanied by a written justification relating thereto, and shall be reviewed by the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

