<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H24473583C6724AE3B1E9864A864B6347" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6192 IH: Fertilizer Research Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6192</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to publish a report on the fertilizer industry, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H19FC3CD9E5404555BC0B555CC6020C79" style="OLC"><section id="HB930421F44394460A85636C48FDC32FA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fertilizer Research Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H58562104A152419285C350E7238C4636"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fertilizer industry report</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB5E57543EAB482BB00CE7AEEA4B6940"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Administrator of the Economic Research Service, shall publish on the website of the Department of Agriculture a report on the United States fertilizer industry, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBDD7EEC8C794D5EA87FD5505DD55B2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the impacts on the fertilizer industry that influence the prices that agricultural producers receive for their agricultural products at the location of the farm;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H591163224D6F44F0A82E7FACE208E5A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the current size and value, and the size and value over the previous 25 years, of the United States fertilizer market, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4471FECFA0894CB0A8B19C48DFAF32E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any trends over the previous 25 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAACB831EFC4F4DF49E4ABEE81DE684AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such sizes and values by each type of fertilizer;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A1B50E88683498A834BC9FA4E0C52B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any patterns in pricing of fertilizer over the previous 25 years;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE9B20E03B414F04B99F6F29EEEC641B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the importation of fertilizer into the United States, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95FB362E00E244D696B16C39E3AEC78D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of types of fertilizer that are imported into the United States, including the quantity of each type of fertilizer imported;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E3EF8F47AF646839D46B7805B3A45C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of foreign companies and domestic companies that import into the United States fertilizer, including the quantity of fertilizer imported by each company;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BB80BAD223E47FA8CBAAE5222879B25"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of the countries from which fertilizer is imported into the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CC2F6D25BB144F383857AD5E6175025"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the impacts that antidumping duties and countervailing duties have on prices of fertilizer paid at the retail level;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA6DB24110444571AD5F028EE03C43FF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an overview of the manufacturing level, distribution channels, and retail level of the fertilizer supply chain, including transportation, logistics, and supply chain disruptions from natural disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03C0FEC0D805434091647F9F500442F4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a study of the concentration of the United States fertilizer industry in United States fertilizer companies, including an evaluation of the extent to which concentration has had any anticompetitive impacts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5355866BA2F64B518E33AA11E39720D6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of the prices, crop-use efficiencies, and crop yields of emerging fertilizers and fertilizer technologies, including biological fertilizers and other recently developed tools, compared to conventional fertilizers and fertilizer technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H294A54C334254017B1DAA4009039B864"><enum>(8)</enum><text>an assessment of the regulatory environment governing fertilizer production, distribution, and usage, including a description of areas in which regulatory burden is hampering domestic production, distribution, and usage of fertilizer;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E72C8B62D874EBBB74A4E8232707E09"><enum>(9)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which current public price reporting of fertilizer is transparent for market participants and the extent to which further public price reporting is needed to achieve transparency for market participants, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF040897A0714544854C642EFC297C8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the potential for the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a fertilizer reporting mechanism in which the fertilizer industry is required to report fertilizer prices at multiple levels of the supply chain on a daily, weekly, or monthly basis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7483367FB4A3497F8447E9C4E12E385D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a recommendation to Congress on whether a reporting mechanism described in subparagraph (A) should be established; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89C52084DA1F43C09B3816FCF3C2694F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>a description of the projected growth of the United States fertilizer market and the anticipated economic and political risks to fertilizer production as a result of that growth.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H371481DE63E94F2B8FFA1433E62E3AA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Confidential information</header><text>The report published under subsection (a) shall not include any confidential business information.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

