<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E3B6064385744189AEAA885E9679687" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 934 IH: Supporting the recognition of November 2025 as “Carbon Monoxide Action and Awareness Month” and promoting nationwide education, prevention, and detection efforts to protect United States families from carbon monoxide poisoning.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 934</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251205">December 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000622">Mr. Patronis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the recognition of November 2025 as <quote>Carbon Monoxide Action and Awareness Month</quote> and promoting nationwide education, prevention, and detection efforts to protect United States families from carbon monoxide poisoning.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas carbon monoxide is an invisible, odorless, and tasteless gas that can cause serious poisoning incidents resulting in hundreds of deaths, over 100,000 emergency medical care visits, and approximately 14,000 hospitalizations each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 400 United States citizens die annually from unintentional carbon monoxide poisoning and as many as 30 to 40 percent of victims die before reaching the hospital;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an estimated 76 percent of carbon monoxide poisoning cases occur in residential settings, demonstrating that the greatest risk exists in everyday home environments;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 86,200,000 United States citizens, or 36 percent of adults, have no carbon monoxide detection or alarm system in their homes, leaving millions of families unprotected from a preventable danger;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas environmental exposures in the home, including toxic gases, such as carbon monoxide, are known drivers of chronic disease, particularly among children, the elderly, and immunocompromised populations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is important to use carbon monoxide detectors that have been tested and certified by a Nationally Recognized Testing Laboratory in order to verify compliance with UL standards;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas certification is critical to help United States citizens recognize that these devices meet the standard safety and performance requirements;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas national health initiatives have identified healthy homes as a critical component of preventive healthcare, calling for improved public awareness, strengthened safety standards, and greater coordination between public agencies and private partners to address indoor environmental risks;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas carbon monoxide poisoning poses a significant risk after hurricanes due to improper use of gasoline powered generators and those poisonings could be prevented by carbon monoxide alarms and by placing gas generators more than 20 feet from indoor structures;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas carbon monoxide poisoning imposes a significant economic burden, costing the United States more than $1,300,000,000 annually in hospital expenses, emergency response, and lost productivity; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public education, routine appliance maintenance, and the widespread installation of certified carbon monoxide alarms are proven, cost-effective methods for preventing carbon monoxide injuries and deaths: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD86253D3AB144E1F8722A654199669FA"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6705E94CC16A4778920F87F4F3E54E19"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H76B569A3D27548EF8A54019CA05E4FFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the recognition <quote>Carbon Monoxide Action and Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F74377A7EE444F6AD8EE1A91C404D58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages Federal, State, and local agencies to collaborate with public health organizations, safety advocates, and first responders to expand awareness and prevention efforts nationwide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6C9D54A2C7143DAB210B45C565F6998"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges all United States citizens to install and maintain certified carbon monoxide alarms, to test them regularly, and to learn to recognize the signs and symptoms of carbon monoxide poisoning;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD081611BA60C461FA0800967996983F6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports continued public and private partnerships that raise awareness of carbon monoxide hazards and promote healthy home environments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD99433E8F7014D4D90052EE0C8BA44CF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>commends first responders, medical professionals, and community educators for their ongoing commitment to saving lives through carbon monoxide prevention and education.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

