<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDF0FF52F33EF437F9A65A13449A5D4F2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5812 IH: Correcting Opportunity and Accountability in Collegiate Hiring Act (COACH Act)</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5812</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251024">October 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to cap certain intercollegiate athletics compensation and buyouts as a condition of institutional participation in Federal student aid programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5E6EAC8524EA44858E36D64114C1C293" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE669E21778824725920A74E45885C33C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Correcting Opportunity and Accountability in Collegiate Hiring Act (COACH Act)</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD7FD64C4DE87474491F7D8B67F9ACB50"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<subsection id="H3989D195F1CF4EDFAEFEAB568DC54C6C"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Intercollegiate athletics, when properly governed, promote student development and broad-based participation aligned with educational missions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB08537F025704C84BD038EE9FFA1F1A4"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Institutions participating in programs under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) receive substantial Federal support and tax advantages, creating a heightened obligation to manage athletics in service of educational priorities and equal opportunity.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4FEDC01A5C044305B300283C82261415"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Escalating compensation and buyouts for athletics personnel can divert resources from academic priorities and broad-based opportunities, including women’s and Olympic sports, and warrant reasonable, uniform guardrails as a condition of title IV participation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBBF2D73EE7AE447FA196F35118068C23"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Federal courts have held that the National Collegiate Athletic Association’s caps on coaches’ pay violate antitrust laws—e.g., Law v. NCAA (10th Cir. 1998) permanently enjoining the NCAA’s <quote>restricted-earnings coach</quote> salary cap rule—and have continued to scrutinize coach-compensation restraints (including rules setting compensation to zero); therefore, any statutory cap must be accompanied by a targeted antitrust safe harbor to permit collective implementation and enforcement.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H27AAFE571A9947B184327AED46B3235F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Program participation agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H0B88C7279DD6436189CE949947EB8075" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H82B5DCAC9F884CBA8EAC22DCBDDCDC1E"><enum>(30)</enum><header>Limitations on intercollegiate athletics compensation and buyouts</header> <subparagraph id="H5112BEA595884C8CB35F6096C6321A03"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Compensation cap</header><text>As a condition of eligibility under this title, the institution shall ensure that the total annual compensation paid, promised, or provided to any athletics department employee does not exceed 10 times the institution’s tuition and required fees for a first-time, full-time undergraduate for the most recent academic year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B73929F98794F1E8EF1612543297865"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Buyouts and separation payments</header><text>Any payment to terminate, buy out, or settle an employment agreement with an athletics department employee shall be treated as compensation for purposes of subparagraph (A) in the year paid, and may not cause the cap in subparagraph (A) to be exceeded.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H247CB281C67B4502AB6E7FFD6E8402C1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Conference and affiliate coverage</header><text>The institution shall ensure compliance with this paragraph for any agreement entered by an athletics conference, media-rights consortium, collective, foundation, or other affiliate that allocates, assigns, or provides compensation or buyouts to the institution’s athletics department employees.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C33C557992E4BF088556E0776B517C2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Certification and disclosure</header><text>The Secretary shall require annual program participation agreement certification that the institution and its affiliates are in compliance with this paragraph and shall require public disclosure of the cap amount for the year and the tuition and required fees figure used to calculate it and the number of covered employees whose total annual compensation is within 10 percent of the cap.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A3BC61430B64D818774760CB66AF68B"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Transition</header> <clause id="H73E55728C8DB447AAD005ABB5D1815EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Written employment agreements executed before the date of this Act may continue for their remaining original term (excluding extensions or renewals), provided that the agreement and scheduled payments are disclosed under subparagraph (D); and no amendment increases compensation above amounts stated in the agreement as of the date of this Act.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H85F25EFE333A4385BC71E4B405A1F894"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prospective compliance</header><text>Agreements executed on or after the date of this Act shall comply with this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13E92CF4CE1A4237872798135FF99FE0"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph, the term:</text> 
<clause id="H417D00028E9043D59C32033C01DC9ACA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Athletics department employee—means any employee of the institution (or of a related organization acting for the institution) whose primary duties relate to intercollegiate athletics, including head and assistant coaches, the director of athletics, associate or assistant athletic directors, and senior athletics administrators.</text></clause> <clause id="HA46D2C106876480389337F013283512F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Tuition and required fees—means the published undergraduate tuition and required fees for a first-time, full-time undergraduate student at the institution, as reported to the Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System pursuant to section 487(a)(17) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)(17)</external-xref>). For public institutions with differential resident and nonresident rates, the in-state figure applies.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H54D528EDAFE14CA3955A58E762662C82">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Athletics conference—means a voluntary association of institutions of higher education formed to organize, regulate, or commercialize intercollegiate varsity athletics competition, including any media-rights or data-rights affiliate.</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H0E2BF8F41E1A4FB48719CE96DB570B73"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>Total annual compensation</quote>—means wages, salaries, stipends, allowances, incentive or performance bonuses, signing or retention bonuses, deferred compensation, employer retirement contributions above standard plan matches, severance, buyouts, cancellation or mitigation payments, in-kind compensation, appearance fees, debt servicing, debt relief, and any other compensation paid by or through a related organization (including a foundation, booster organization, media arm, or affiliate) or a third party under an arrangement to perform services for the institution.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H960022FAF9554589AFDBAAA24400D208"><enum>4.</enum><header>Liability limitation</header> <subsection id="HF01E11AA79FB4794ABAA777335398764"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Adoption of, agreement to, compliance with, or enforcement of any rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision established pursuant to, or in compliance with, section 3 of this Act shall be treated as lawful under the antitrust laws and any similar State provision having the force and effect of law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H79B813B655DB47C0B14378E37D597FA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Antitrust laws</header><text>The term <quote>antitrust laws</quote> in sub-paragraph (a) has the meaning given such term in the 1st section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>) and includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent that such section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

