<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9509230983A64E17A97E4442B4C7C575" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6051 IH: To Inform Families First Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6051</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251117">November 17, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To promote the voluntary inclusion of emergency contact information in State driver’s license and identification systems and to provide support to States for implementation of such systems, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HFCAA9EF428C24DC8A7FD1F07C5D2F4E6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAEC1F6C99885441E940B9F6A107ABC57" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>To Inform Families First Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H029A63A6AD874521B6EC0EA685320E3D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Highway Traffic Safety Administration grant program for emergency contact information system</header> <subsection id="H9FE6768219D64D649278F22157A86114"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, shall establish a program (in this section referred to as <quote>the program</quote>) to provide assistance to States to develop and implement systems to collect emergency contact information for inclusion in the driver’s license and identification records of such States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD9D78EEB38E541638E1F1B866012A6D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Forms of assistance</header><text>Assistance provided under the program section may be in the form of a grant or technical assistance.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCBCD7232D60748A5A2FD12ACB258E02F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>As a condition of receiving assistance under the program, a State shall use such assistance to develop an emergency contact information system described in subsection (a) and such State shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H02A0E8608B2344F4BF07FCEE52B022EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that the provision of emergency contact information by an individual under such system is voluntary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9C473E963AD4D44BA32C1D5D25AC985"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include robust data security protections in such system;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA04BB9C874F438A9DBB9315263A29C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>restrict access to information provided under such system to authorized emergency personnel for use only during an emergency; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDEC87E8993248CE94F108093C31E194"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that there is no requirement to display such emergency contact information on a physical driver’s license or identification card.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAF06A4D63A8E4290B71F27F9D3A444AD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report on the implementation of this section and include in such report information on any technical assistance provided under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HED6C8E6A1E41473E857C77850C1303D5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>State defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>State</quote> means any of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


