<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA731EB9402D6448483FE33B3BC50C510" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8036 IH: Interagency Coordination in Export Controls Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8036</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260324">March 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to permit the Secretary of State, Defense, or Energy to submit proposed rules to the Export Administration Review Board, to require the Secretary of State to evaluate the military civil fusion strategy of the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H86D0B36466E3451CB6A9666E610CDAB0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H238B91AD2AA647F687D6B9231B7414E3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Interagency Coordination in Export Controls Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H3C99164A439848C28D7C308698A35C47"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency rulemaking proposals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1754 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1073075A379A4714AFD527E2D40B37C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>consultation</quote> and inserting <quote>coordination</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8386CF1B09547E6BB3F905262C78D93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end, the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC182ADE4E4AD4C669AD78B12542A48D7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HFD35499D4CB64E649946A98D552C0616"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Interagency rulemaking proposals</header> 
<paragraph id="HCC168E7798194CD68C7F47D2C05F94F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission of proposals</header><text>The Secretary of State, Defense, or Energy may submit to the Export Administration Review Board (or its successor) (hereinafter the <quote>Board</quote>) a proposal for a new rule, or an amendment to an existing rule, under the Export Administration Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H313D7E9116E34D2BBACA5FE592B73DB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval of proposals</header> <subparagraph id="H30EBB373FF064F61940A6930DF1FB19F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided under subparagraph (B), not later than days 30 days after a proposal is submitted under paragraph (1), the Board shall vote to accept or reject the proposal. The Secretary shall initiate the rulemaking process for each proposal accepted by a simple majority vote of the Board.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF17FE157E5164101A21A2D88108D83E6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Board member may extend the deadline described in subparagraph (A) by an additional 30 days if—</text> <clause id="HE4D196615BDA4FBAA37751A203C3A9EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Board member requires additional information regarding the proposal with respect to which such extension is sought; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H842225896A234EA7898B8175FE1EAB0E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Board member that issued such proposal agrees to such extension.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section> <section id="HE16F204908264431AB66C84AD5AF2FB0"><enum>3.</enum><header>State Department evaluation of China’s military-civil fusion strategy</header> <subsection id="HABFA62C182D848F9B016175740BDEECC" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall, in consultation with each agency that is represented by a member of the Operating Committee for Export Policy, complete a review of the implications of the military-civil fusion strategy of the People’s Republic of China (in this Act referred to as the <quote>PRC</quote>) for the export control policy of the United States and for the national security of the United States, including a review of the following topics:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6BFC2D9EFF1644F7B92277C052AA048D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exploitation of United States and allied technology and talent by the PRC to modernize the PRC’s military.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC6356AFE9D54A739EE912F96CC6E9C3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether any entity in the PRC can be considered, in the context of United States national security and export control policy, a purely civilian entity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA46124FDD24848ACB7841F47D556DF46"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reliability of end-use checks and end-use conditions for exports, reexports, and in-country transfers to entities that are located or headquartered in, or the ultimate parent company of which is headquartered in, the PRC.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA788F9E6F2EF4D8A9D17F9431FF55B12" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The relationship between the PRC’s strategic technology sectors (such as artificial intelligence, semiconductor, quantum, robotics, biotechnology) and the PRC’s military.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8AD7B46064F4253A6413310D1D885D4" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the addition of any entity to the Military End-User List would address to any extent the national security risks posed by the military-civil fusion strategy of the PRC.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1917E3375A924B0D9605184C9B924F01" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Due diligence required by exporters to prevent the PRC’s military from accessing United States technology.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H314D2290702C4C188BC4B7A1A62BE728" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether any change to United States export control policy would address to any extent the national security risks posed by the military-civil fusion strategy of the PRC.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA00B96E5B4404DD9BCF026587FF83582" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any other topic the Secretary determines is relevant for this review.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC9ACCA8ECA00445FB74F5E1270D35CB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proposed changes to policy</header> 
<paragraph id="H01F46B014A4B4D0CAD79E9E3EB519A9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall consider proposing to the Export Administration Review Board (or any successor entity) any change to United States export control policy identified pursuant to the review required by <internal-xref idref="HABFA62C182D848F9B016175740BDEECC" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C7F69C8407E41C0A815B61D634B59E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>additions to the Military End-User List;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7CCAD115EA784EE9B4363199D0C7C21F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>changes to export control restrictions on certain military end uses;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D3D1BAAE46E4C9AB16BA272DF9AD3A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>new rules or amendments to the Export Administration Regulations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC88918D395A546989D903B0BDF12B34B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a final rule pursuant to the proposed rule published in the Federal Register entitled <quote>End-Use and End-User Based Export Controls, Including U.S. Persons Activities Controls: Military and Intelligence End Uses and End Users</quote> (89 Fed. Reg. 60985 (July 29, 2024)); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H851FF4645F1347F8BAA030E8E5C37EB5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other policy the Secretary determines would address the national security risks posed by the military-civil fusion strategy of the PRC.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC381132328A543E984268BA63F36B1A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interagency vote</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall vote on the adoption of each change proposed pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H01F46B014A4B4D0CAD79E9E3EB519A9F" legis-path="3.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> in the manner described in subsection (g)(2) of section 1754 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813</external-xref>), as added by <internal-xref idref="H3C99164A439848C28D7C308698A35C47" legis-path="2.">section 2</internal-xref>.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H76E03ABF01E842FD88921091BE48AA44"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 150 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBF479D3E620045119FFD0C33EC73145F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The review required by <internal-xref idref="HABFA62C182D848F9B016175740BDEECC" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14B295C16CE843BEA5C44E43F73123A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any proposed rule required by <internal-xref idref="HC9ACCA8ECA00445FB74F5E1270D35CB0" legis-path="3.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63A00AD7C6B3418B88C536DDA5A6E54B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any change in United States policy approved by the Export Administration Review Board.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4DF62B6F0A644AD85F3752F359477BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any recommended change to United States law that would help address the national security risks posed by the military-civil fusion strategy of the PRC.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H769BF9840E664F88852812B8F6D856C1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H9651F9F7FFB94449AE2170D2786B1946"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8E25FABAB3644DC68B68712F4BCA7ED4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBFF71CDD7B24FF6A4BF25D8B212FE91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97B29776644546F590E860416487C420"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Military End-User List</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Military End-User List</term> means the list maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 7 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93F1E621D5A54972A898C31BF215F03F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Operating Committee for Export Policy</header><text>The term <term>Operating Committee for Export Policy</term> means the Operating Committee for Export Policy referred to in section 1763(c) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4822">50 U.S.C. 4822(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7AF003C5B5754D6EA1615CC7B30EFD26"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

