<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA26230-2JS-9J-K6T"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4069 IS: AI-Ready Bio-Data Standards Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4069</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to establish definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks to ensure certain biological datasets are ready for use in artificial intelligence models, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HE653564F736C4768B149ED1BF73A0C39"><section id="id7ad4d4ca3e1047d688c432d65da76d58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AI-Ready Bio-Data Standards Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H332EAD0A4B2A4D089A57BE778C61916A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks by the National Institute of Standards and Technology for certain biological datasets</header><subsection commented="no" id="HF90FD50881234F15826923C12EC1E0FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="HCE0F3FE2519B494C9F1C0E4795038D27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>), pursuant to recommendations from the advisory group under subsection (f) and taking into account any feedback received under subsection (e), shall establish definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks to ensure each biological dataset generated as a result of qualified federally funded research is artificial intelligence-ready.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8f17c635fe64dee9951c9bd13ca3409"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD83A4262C6EE41D49FE1A3B96E94353F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31d3b025ce7948e4b01ba127472b1def"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Director shall establish definitions for the following terms:</text><subclause id="H3F04C745B61E48F388AF75D12353D4CD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Artificial intelligence-ready.</text></subclause><subclause id="HA72F395D3E6744368D7F5DC2C17421BA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Biomanufacturing.</text></subclause><subclause id="H058A10FBB93F4F19A3ADB219664D4246"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Biotechnology.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HF4A52C047393443082984E6C81FEAD5D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Qualified federally funded research.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE90AE4E4808B48D0BB7C8515CFF6490D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements for definition of artificial intelligence-ready</header><subclause id="HB791324582B54579A40FB357F6E693B0"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In defining <quote>artificial intelligence-ready</quote> under clause (i)(I), the Director shall develop a definition that, when applied to a biological dataset, requires that the dataset is generated and formatted in a manner that—</text><item id="H4F3065B8136C4F22B94278B2C531577D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>enables the effective use of the dataset for training artificial intelligence models; and</text></item><item id="HF625517618A14E6A9812AE64ED815F49"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>supports advancements in research relating to artificial intelligence and biotechnology.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HE2E70A985D214916824511EC4179E5BD"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Discretion</header><text>With respect to a biological dataset that otherwise meets the definition of <quote>artificial intelligence-ready</quote> established under clause (i)(I), the Director may, in consultation with the Chief Data Officer of the Federal agency that is responsible for such biological dataset, determine that such dataset is not artificial intelligence-ready.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2DDCBD64C2AD4ADCAFFAD0ED27C22F38"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Requirements for definition of qualified federally funded
 research</header><text>In defining <quote>qualified federally funded research</quote> under clause (i)(IV), the Director shall include certain conditions that, if satisfied, will result in certain federally funded research being qualified federally funded research. Such conditions shall include the following:</text><subclause commented="no" id="H5DB2885BF97C4B9ABCFF062BA48A10E2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of Federal funding awarded to a recipient.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H64B12C6096ED4D27B8E501B57D7949C1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The capability of the recipient to generate a biological dataset, which may include negative data, that is artificial intelligence-ready, regardless of the ability of the recipient to publish such dataset.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H862E5C6A952743E989B7C936F021E90B"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expertise of the recipient in generating a biological dataset that is artificial intelligence-ready.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H6026DA56A8164F6394B278CD31412D13"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The size of the biological dataset generated by the recipient.</text></subclause><subclause id="H593643B811D54ADB8D22F41A2030BF84"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Any other condition the Director considers appropriate.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb51c4d816f3f418da8e8cc35d8c2e894"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Director shall establish standards relating to making biological datasets artificial intelligence-ready, in accordance with the definition of artificial intelligence-ready established under subparagraph (A)(i)(I) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H01C1324488544B90B3904646D0A933F3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Resources and frameworks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Director shall establish data management resources and cybersecurity frameworks for the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="H7B4FE0574DF441888C89AF34CC9C5E97"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal departments and agencies that provide either full or partial Federal funding for research that generates biological datasets.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H4FC6C41C4EF34FBEA7DCF60D4ADC15CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federally funded researchers who are collecting, cleaning, curating, or generating biological datasets to make the datasets artificial intelligence-ready.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFD049E5D16734C5086F4CFED63EA6F5B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall ensure that the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks established under paragraph (1)—</text><clause commented="no" id="HE2A54527CCDF4E2AB5EEEBE2E5CC7F1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are not overly burdensome on recipients of funding for qualified federally funded research, such that the act of generating biological datasets that are artificial intelligence-ready requires resources and expertise beyond those available to the recipients; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HE7428A97AE31459F97239A6C44EFF951"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are tested and evaluated in accordance with subsection (c) and in consultation with—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H984546DA447F490DB0A53E15ED1AAA56"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the head of any Federal agency the Director considers appropriate;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HAE4A68E1CBBC4D079B4520FC62824C90"><enum>(II)</enum><text>representatives from any private sector entity the Director considers appropriate; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB88EE4C17F834588B477F28AD3C7A79C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any biotechnology researcher the Director considers appropriate.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a67da5b7a9f46bb993a234a4e1db00a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual updates</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the establishment of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks under paragraph (1), and annually thereafter, the Director shall review the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks and, if the Director considers it appropriate, shall update the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks in accordance with the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H87DC95943F7B4B2B94020EE400D6CAFD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To facilitate the establishment of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks under paragraph (1), and any update under paragraph (3), the Director shall consult with the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7A1A514B42674C58BAF370FFF6E1FE14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Private sector entities from the biotechnology industry.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42f49f27ac244753b35d2d3bd6b6cf5c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Private sector entities from the frontier artificial intelligence model industry.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE500636764A64D6A952916AA57D0CE33"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of academia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H30F88449F1CD42ABB235DAE9A5B9C2BA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The following heads of Federal agencies that provide funding for qualified federally funded research relating to the generation of biological datasets:</text><clause commented="no" id="HF0156B37146C449FA7983572D342BAB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H80E55F4C644A406384DC29FD82C8A443"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA2830E53385C49ACA1F346758DEA88BB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HF67A9D8A785142A7B7165AB45DAC4E62"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA3DB1131FE6A4D6F8FA3647BB9969F1E"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA39632CD1960438B88A099BDFA415E79"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Administrator of the National Science Foundation.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H7522AE0A247742BB8A92C80597C6F62B"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The head of any other Federal agency the Director considers appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA2F41F3FAB84F278CCAA4090F93364C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To facilitate the establishment of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks under paragraph (1), and any update under paragraph (3), the Director shall hire staff as the Director determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCC0F3D52FD13452C9A036438E61139B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information gathering</header><paragraph id="HE63A21136F18468894A4A58960A64777"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall inventory the following:</text><subparagraph id="H41923F7FDD7B4A1CB55755DBA881CE6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Existing biotechnology standards utilized by recipients of Federal funding for biotechnology research to generate biological datasets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA148FBD3EACC404796788FADC598CFD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Existing biological datasets generated by recipients of Federal funding for biotechnology research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9507B3DF811444A7B7A87B4267D5C244" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the Director completes the inventory requirement under paragraph (1), the Director shall make any information inventoried under that paragraph available to the public through a website of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC0BC8A6666104BB188012272F75085CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Test and evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than every 2 years thereafter, the Director shall coordinate with the Administrator of the National Science Foundation to conduct a test and evaluation of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks established pursuant to subsection (a)(1) on a sample of biological datasets generated as a result of qualified federally funded research to determine the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HA11B4FB36B104A1A8E4D5934EF2C5D77"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks are clearly written, easy to follow, and easily applicable for the generation of biological datasets that are artificial intelligence-ready.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H07042B453110401582F44E315416C8FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether compliance with the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks established under subsection (a)(1) when generating or curating biological datasets results in an undue burden on the recipients of such qualified federally funded research, and if so, how to modify the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks, as the case may be, so as to reduce the burden.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC1A01573E2034520AB5025B85DBDD116"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agency-Specific data management policies</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H75A092456EF14C2198778BBD10B26D6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act and in accordance with requirements under subsection (e), the Director shall establish or, if already established, review and revise agency-specific data management policies for each Federal agency that provides funding for qualified federally funded research to ensure implementation of policies that require that any biological dataset generated by a recipient of qualified federally funded research is artificial intelligence-ready.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec1ca1235bbb4949a4aa9557834bae66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The data management policies described in paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H58B8B381B696448EA397495E694A9421"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A mechanism to ensure sufficient Federal funding to a recipient to satisfy the requirements of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks established under subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H72202801AC37418AA02A6357F5428B2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A process for the Chief Data Officer of each Federal agency to designate an individual of such agency to ensure compliance with the policies established or revised under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H43993BBB69064D379027973CC2D2CE17"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Oversight mechanisms</header><text>As part of the agency-specific data management policies under paragraph (1), the Director shall establish the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H282558DC78404564A3DFB47D8D4BE4DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A regularly updated central repository of the policies established at each Federal agency, made available to the public as the Director determines appropriate, for the purpose of tracking available policies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA1AB3E9488064B3BB929349A39081C60"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A publicly available database to serve as a single point of access, updated as the Director determines necessary, on which the head of any Federal agency may publish artificial intelligence-ready biological datasets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAEC334BE38134EF3B27DF753382503F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A reporting mechanism available to each Federal agency to report to the Director how the agency is complying with the policies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC6F83933548E4962AAA7B3D825D60AE1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A mechanism available to each Federal agency to request assistance from the Director regarding compliance with the policies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAB3FB22E367C47829222318C42042CF6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public input and feedback; consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks under subsection (a)(1) and the agency-specific data management policies under subsection (d)(1), the Director shall carry out the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H9D5EE80B66A04ECAAE387CF1C106F6F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solicit input and feedback from the public regarding the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks and the agency-specific data management policies.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H715810982DD6481588C458BBC2B4986D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consult with the following heads of Federal agencies that provide funding for qualified federally funded research to ensure such agencies are able to comply with the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks and the agency-specific data management policies:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5D31F26FAB9941049CBC228A1E823534"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF04BFCC362F148209FDDCE6E9004EB5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCE01D4B4718C4DABB50135249715358F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5FE44D3DEE374777A41806812DE63B8E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7B92523F00F741CE87283C0956A8922E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H119DD2833031421683538BF1CFC57F87"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Administrator of the National Science Foundation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA84C043289114942992C2ADDFEB58379"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The head of any other Federal agency as determined by the Director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F4388132AF64970A223F344FD43FCA4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Advisory group</header><paragraph id="H94662D87059345EF90BD9ACEC2F5787B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish an advisory group to carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2E9C7827D96A412C897AA9C323010955"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide recommendations relating to the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks established under subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75521ED8896348E28EC0D332BBAF8D04"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To review and provide feedback on the agency-specific data management policies established or revised under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFA03A431F97C4332816FBFBA5E1002AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To provide recommendations to academic journals for guidelines relating to artificial intelligence-ready biological datasets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H879C04D3A1D74ACA8C97E1F5FC4001C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To solicit recommendations from the academic community regarding implementation of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H129C873AF8854EFF850688AAD999843C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>To provide any other guidance the Director may request.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46C4F6B0EF924728AA1E7137FA8358FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9107172fa3304d218c9ad33631a8c763"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory group established under paragraph (1) shall be composed of not fewer than 12 members to include—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19881fdf11784165b5ae34e33aa1d48e"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of Federal agencies that award funds to recipients to carry out qualified federally funded research; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a5237120ea04d78b895aa2619996428"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of academia, private sector entities, and academic publishers.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AA4C40DA5A44D0E8826CD71FE239792"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms</header><clause id="H026FFB083ACE4CCD95BFC3BBFA38FE3B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member shall serve for a term of 2 years.</text></clause><clause id="H45EFDE8A5E62462A875A3011440A053E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the discretion of the Director, the term of each member may be renewed for an additional 2-year term.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AE33A0CDDEB41399BA16572E69CC258"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><subparagraph id="H7228CE4B29144EBFA1BF8428F3AF6B4C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Chairperson of the advisory group shall be designated by the Director from among the members.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5FB3907F4294AFAB7340862DDB2EBC6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The term of the Chairperson shall be 1 year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73160AB5E94942B0AC2BD8F9CCEEBCE3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>Subject to the discretion of the Director, the term of a Chairperson may be renewed for an additional 1-year term.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09609D4068B04AF8BB03011995ED3493"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48828c53a21a49e7837be2a0d1d6ab84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the advisory group shall submit to the Director a interim report that contains advice and guidance with respect to the matters described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f0ba3220a304457bcef412e67a32d8e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the advisory group or the Director determines appropriate, the advisory group shall submit to the Director subsequent reports relating to the matters described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7AC06E1C92DB414F825F4B52F20B3378"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal Acquisition Regulation revisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall revised the Federal Acquisition Regulation as necessary to implement the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks established under subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="H5BA5A0DDC63D4BF9935944C8E355CD11"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph id="H7A3834C61D5649E3A55C01C5268D5258"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to Congress and the Comptroller General of the United States an interim report that includes information relating to the progress of establishing the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks under subsection (a)(1) and the agency-specific data management policies under subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE4FCB6AD98445A99FC28E78C1DAEFDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to Congress and the Comptroller General of the United States a report that includes information relating to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H3CE4F809E6BE4C3CBC6A26F3D954E837"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment, implementation, and, if applicable, revision, of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks established under subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAA307B43B0314867B17843DD2056A0E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment, implementation, and, if applicable, revision of the agency-specific data management policies established or revised under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CE5DA94F8124FC3B6C0D59B23B01935"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional requirement for first subsequent report</header><text>With respect to the first subsequent report under paragraph (2), the Director shall include a summary of the testing and evaluation under subsection (c) that includes information relating to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H6863D0BBE49D4BBCB7AB8E73AEE7A345"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The findings of the testing and evaluation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4A1B73EA04D4CDA934BD8B60731A6F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The manner by which the Director addressed any concern identified as a result of the testing and evaluation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2DBFFCEE04254157B3429032664CE66E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of any burden on recipients of funding for qualified federally funded research regarding ensuring that biological datasets are artificial intelligence-ready.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8C4192809EBC452C9485859DD6692ED3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A cost-benefit analysis of the value of ensuring that biological datasets are artificial intelligence-ready in relation to any such burden.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31CA80745FF74D528809A0FBF01B927B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the impact of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks established under subsection (a)(1), including the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HD85866C77D19418FA0A2A06096B40EEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the effectiveness of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks in ensuring each biological dataset generated by a recipient of funding for qualified federally funded research is artificial intelligence-ready.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8FFA16DF92C14BA891E2585DE8E200F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of whether the implementation of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks, as the case may be, has resulted in an undue burden on any recipient of Federal funding.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2AD0A04E95BB41DC908D04999BDC073D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any recommendations with respect to the implementation of the definitions, standards, resources, and frameworks.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1095596758FA4620B973A6C39B7640C3"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA776002954D249719C2B0E532239A526"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H29F6A515285F4B6DA7EFA2BB120CC7D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biological data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>biological data</term> means information that is measured, collected, or aggregated for analysis, including associated descriptors, derived from the structure, function, or process of a biological system.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF7F6D559F99E4E91B4B4CF970B278B22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biological dataset</header><text>The term <term>biological dataset</term> means a discreet collection of biological data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FC5EDBB58974606A7640EEEB6BC61EA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Biological data repository</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>biological data repository</term> means any centralized data storage capacity meant for managing or storing biological data.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddce139b5505f4f099065162629bc7e09"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Negative data</header><text>The term <term>negative data</term> means data that disproves, fails to support, or explains through previously unknown or contradictory means a research hypothesis but that otherwise still advances scientific knowledge or understanding.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

