<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9CA7AE00E3214BCABDE323F0D6771962" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9323 IH: Department of Advanced Technology and Artificial Intelligence Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9323</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Department of Advanced Technology and Artificial Intelligence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8F991827D6B54D1387C7E8533C88ADF9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H494CDADAE47145799CA3F15A80A0C58A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Advanced Technology and Artificial Intelligence Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H253908253FE4476CA95C67D4922508AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Advanced Technology and Artificial Intelligence</header> 
<subsection id="HAA9BAA4E22044BF3BD275B7B32AF6F7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a Department of Advanced Technology and Artificial Intelligence (in this section referred to as the <quote>Department</quote>), as an Executive department of the United States within the meaning of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF43E17D1ED884234ADDE1B6874AB33A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary</header> <paragraph id="H3233A314104A4ABC87B2F17873E62EFD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is a Secretary of Advanced Technology and Artificial Intelligence appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H639F6CABB82E4D749E109B30FDD34ECD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Head of Department</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Advanced Technology and Artificial Intelligence is the head of the Department and shall have direction, authority, and control over it.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CA6CED41BBA43BCA6665C1D9E9C2246"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Functions vested in Secretary</header><text>All functions of all officers, employees, and organizational units of the Department are vested in the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0C988B40E858424BB15F1179F6DDBD07"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mission</header><text>The primary mission of the Department is to carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="H0E91196AA4F049D0A2DC45055687B0DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop a Federal technology and artificial intelligence framework to update relevant Federal statutes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF3EEA3B6F3F4047A1137E3F5E5DCCE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Develop a Federal strategy across all Federal departments and agencies to ensure such departments and agencies are in a consistent manner developing and implementing standards and policies relating to the utilization of artificial intelligence by such departments and agencies.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H328B7AE899A5441BBF906DCBB2FC559E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>To carry out the mission of the Department under subsection (c), the Secretary shall carry out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD9987C11AA9B44DDB846B242605E5FFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Fund and carry out research and infrastructure management related to the utilization of artificial intelligence by Federal departments and agencies, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCFD6F422510468A8AF8A33DD5E8DB2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Develop standards for safety and oversight guidance with respect to such utilization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6877ECE523754893A0CE56E2A437AF62"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Establish artificial intelligence incident reporting systems for cybersecurity risks and breach prevention related to such utilization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F5B1CDF9F2D45B99B57FAE256A0B23E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop regulatory frameworks for the Department to promulgate regulations related to such utilization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9822B06390CD4AE9AEDDF6D2F94D3C11" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Provide a strategies related to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H72D6CC18020545908EF9E98F5A1D13A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>How to promote the following:</text> 
<clause id="H4F30905F07F847E6B76C40EFA515A6CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Literacy related to artificial intelligence in schools.</text></clause> <clause id="H491B322FEAF147509DAE81923A067F19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Workforce programs related to artificial intelligence utilization.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H141CAC3302AE4107944C8EA0B8BA6162"><enum>(B)</enum><text>How to address labor displacement to coordinate worker protections.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBAFB5DD116E343E8AAF453664D4232B2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0580596F66F945B18A449CE6381C1231"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Information related to any regulation issued by, or Federal program established within, a Federal department or agency relating to utilizing artificial intelligence, including whether there is any duplication of such regulation or program across such departments or agencies.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C3B24C5DDBD49E6AF4DF82266ABEA9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information related to any efforts between such departments or agencies to coordinate, in a consistent manner, standards and policies relating to utilization of artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA4F1C9947453446796A5A117AE4017E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations with respect to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H449C2245C05E4777BDFDB7FCF3CBD3A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Restructuring or eliminating any such duplication, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61C782591B9C4E369F7322C4455633BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Improving any such efforts.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD763C6CBDAE74EC68FD5E80E69219063" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>How the Department approaches national and international priorities relating to artificial intelligence and innovation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H756AC9626825475FA8F268B26EBAD67E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The functions of the Department.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6DE229CD2464F09A5A8C6BE201003B6" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The leadership structure of the Department, including with respect to the Secretary and any under secretaries of the Department, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3E088CECE9DA46EA9E4B952D72A979A2" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The organizational structure of the Department.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9FA1EE3F74C430BB07CFACD76BF8E33" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any funding, resource, and staffing needs of the Department.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5600A81259474C1BAC959E6315E41B8D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Legislative actions to carry out the following:</text> <clause id="H377848BBB3D847BBB47815EF03465C80"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Update relevant Federal statutes to carry out the following:</text> 
<subclause id="H16013C1639FA453AA6403574EA93EBF2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Include references to the Department.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAB0B859D5E4E4FB085CF23E622FF519A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establish consumer, workforce, and privacy protections, safety requirements, and regulations, including protections, requirements and regulations related to deepfakes or misinformation.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H90A37D9B74384296B0764067A83B6EE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Establish safeguards relating to the utilization of artificial intelligence by such departments or agencies, including with respect to data privacy and cybersecurity.</text></clause> <clause id="H8537D5B52CB24D1CB0E83AEC66A7C88A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Establish mechanisms for reporting incidents of cybersecurity risks and breach prevention relating to such utilization.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD36558A8903A4F6BB42C85EBC4A34715"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of relevant Federal statutes and executive orders related to the regulation of artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA915671B135A4432AB0694CDD18CF99B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>artificial intelligence</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 238(g) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; 10 U.S.C. note prec. 4061).</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

