<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H71CE612A9EA840DFB5D09E893DEC9746" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 923 IH: A resolution honoring the service and sacrifice of United States Army Specialist Sarah Beckstrom and United States Air Force Staff Sergeant Andrew Wolfe, who were tragically shot in Washington, D.C., in a targeted assault against United States service members on November 26, 2025.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 923</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution honoring the service and sacrifice of United States Army Specialist Sarah Beckstrom and United States Air Force Staff Sergeant Andrew Wolfe, who were tragically shot in Washington, D.C., in a targeted assault against United States service members on November 26, 2025.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on the afternoon of November 26, 2025, members of the National Guard on patrol in Washington, D.C. as part of the D.C. Safe and Beautiful Task Force were violently assaulted with gunfire in a vicious, targeted attack;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas United States Army Specialist Sarah Beckstrom and United States Air Force Staff Sergeant Andrew Wolfe, both members of the West Virginia National Guard, sustained severe gunshot wounds during the attack;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Specialist Beckstrom succumbed to her injuries and passed away surrounded by her loved ones on November 27, 2025, making the ultimate sacrifice in service to her country;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Staff Sergeant Wolfe remains hospitalized in critical condition;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas United States Army Specialist Sarah Beckstrom, who was 20 years old at the time of her passing, was from Summersville, West Virginia, enlisted on June 6, 2023, weeks after graduating with honors from Webster County High School, and was assigned to the 863rd Military Police Company, 111th Engineer Brigade of the West Virginia Army National Guard;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Specialist Beckstrom worked a civilian job as a community engagement specialist at a Certified Community Behavioral Health Clinic in Summersville, West Virginia that provides mental health and substance use disorder treatment;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas United States Air Force Staff Sergeant Andrew Wolfe, age 24, of Martinsburg, West Virginia, a graduate of Musselman High School in Inwood, West Virginia, enlisted on February 5, 2019, while still in high school, and was assigned to the Force Support Squadron, 167th Airlift Wing of the West Virginia Air National Guard;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in his civilian job, Staff Sergeant Wolfe has worked as a lineman with Frontier Communications since 2023, which has benefitted his community by bringing connectivity to more homes and businesses in West Virginia;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Specialist Beckstrom and Staff Sergeant Wolfe have both received an outpouring of support and praise from their communities and from around the country as individuals who served with distinction, earned the admiration and respect of their communities, and acted selflessly and courageously on behalf of others; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Specialist Beckstrom and Staff Sergeant Wolfe had both recently volunteered to extend their deployments in Washington, D.C. and continue their service to help keep the Capital of the United States safe: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H20BC297D58244B2F9E54D4F67465BAF9"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF694B236E610461284557A270F938D17"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H5D04F83647854E89B1476E1D3040C5BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the memory, service and sacrifice of United States Army Specialist Sarah Beckstrom for her dedicated service to her State and to her country as a member of the West Virginia National Guard;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EF1F751AB1A450D87B2B9BEC63F9686"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the service and sacrifice of United States Air Force Staff Sergeant Andrew Wolfe for his dedicated service to his State and to his country as a member of the West Virginia National Guard;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDD7ED4ECE894E1D8F975B6AD2449FD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>extends its sympathies, gratitude, and support for the Beckstrom and Wolfe families for all they have endured and will face because of this attack, as their love and support have been the foundation of the service of Specialist Beckstrom and Staff Sergeant Wolfe to their State and the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC5B128570E848C5891C6C3BC04F4574"><enum>(4)</enum><text>honors the bravery of National Guard members on the scene who displayed courage and strength while under attack;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20A6B36198B243CB91D1B0BCD8EF1819"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expresses gratitude for the swift action of first responders on the scene who responded to the attack and apprehended the attacker;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AA0971C444342BF8A7E15CF502DE347"><enum>(6)</enum><text>condemns in the strongest terms the horrific, violent assault on United States service members in the Capital of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E2B6DD415C34F9582A508661E8DDA5A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recognizes that the men and women who volunteer to serve their communities and their country as members of the National Guard represent the very best of the United States of America.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

