<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F3D8DE78E394059B27068BB365E6F06" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8529 IH: Fair Air Standards Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8529</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Clean Air Act to establish a procedure under which an ozone nonattainment area may be redesignated as an attainment area if certain requirements are met, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA4E14CBBB209460FAF00D2EB01E9BF37" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE37281447108455F8C68152D2A8507EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Air Standards Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1446CDBFC76B4897BD9BF49A0679321E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Redesignation of ozone nonattainment area as attainment area if certain requirements are met</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 107(d)(4)(A) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7407">42 U.S.C. 7407(d)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5CB5CF2A92A3447599EAC837696C54E9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="H748704CDF77649B2BBA0CB0A39D2C16A" indent="up1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding clause (iii), an area designated as an ozone nonattainment area shall be redesignated as an ozone attainment area if the State finds and demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Administrator, and the Administrator concurs in such finding, that the area would have attained the national ambient air quality standard for ozone by the applicable attainment date, but for ozone or ozone precursors emanating from outside the State. The Governor of the State may submit the finding and demonstration to the Administrator at any time and on the Governor’s own motion. Not later than 180 days after the submission date of the finding and demonstration, the Administrator shall concur or nonconcur in the finding and, if the Administrator concurs, shall promulgate the redesignation. In making such finding, the Governor and the Administrator shall consider, among other factors, modeling or monitoring evidence of emissions from other States and foreign countries.</text></clause> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

