<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC2B711E7DE3841D5843615B203288E33" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7091 IH: Expanding Veterans’ Access to Emerging Treatments Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7091</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish an investigational research and extended access treatment program utilizing innovative treatments and emerging therapies to address conditions with unmet medical needs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3BCE004E00E44529833D59317FF965BE" style="OLC"><section id="H43267C67C972425F8D068C316734A8C6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Veterans’ Access to Emerging Treatments Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2650412D55BD4ADAACFD42B147F3ED6D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H49DA57434A744996AC0B121238B97E66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Many conditions, such as chronic pain, post-traumatic stress disorder, and substance use disorders, continue to challenge the veteran community amid a lack of new innovative treatments and emerging therapies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D62C180E7B3413BB7170E155D2A61C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These and other conditions represent an urgent unmet medical need among veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD67D427FCAD04E78892C2F5DA75E8A32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs should continue to advance research and facilitate timely access to innovative treatments and emerging therapies, including psychedelic- and entactogenic-assisted therapies, for veterans with such unmet treatment needs.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7A145A6C68F74A2799D3DA88EA32344C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Research program of the Department of Veterans Affairs on innovative treatments and emerging therapies for certain covered conditions</header><subsection id="H05A7690E71264B1AB948D223D2476052"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall develop an investigational research program for the treatment of veterans diagnosed with a covered condition using innovative treatments and emerging therapies, consistent with applicable Federal law, including laws governing investigational medical products and controlled substances. Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall designate a lead administrator to carry out the research and treatment program under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC59A1F99C33F4BF28F4DD249DCF841F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investigational research program</header><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs may—</text><paragraph id="H9C1E2C2B54AE408BBA37DB2E30A5872D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct one or more clinical trials for the treatment of a covered condition that include veterans as participants in the clinical trial using innovative treatments and emerging therapies, which may be selected following a review of their efficacy, safety, and ease of administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9DF0B64FC04474381380B0F7B012EDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop a compassionate or extended access protocol that facilitates consideration of, and as appropriate access to, innovative treatments and emerging therapies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H176635F147A042C1B054C0FBF1069020"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Participation in clinical trials or extended access</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process under which a veteran diagnosed with a covered condition may—</text><paragraph id="HCA33ACAD65E948B9AFC9E1AAAA103D29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>participate in a clinical trial conducted under this section; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53931291040E4A509207BD7F100CA8CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be considered for access to an innovative treatment or emerging therapy under a compassionate or extended access protocol, as clinically appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF409BFBD44E24BDC8F0A6C4FB797B9CA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional authority</header><text>In addition to carrying out the activities under this section, the Secretary may, using amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated and otherwise available to the Department of Veterans Affairs, support one or more clinical research trials using innovative treatments and emerging therapies described in subsection (g).</text></subsection><subsection id="HED23D4B1186C43E4A4C4B75D194CFF63"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report, including the following:</text><paragraph id="HEB4FEE34F10D41519098B4130A572C92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identification of clinics designated to host activities under such a protocol under this section and the number of veterans expected to participate in a clinical trial conducted in subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BAB73DA00134805993FE7F2CC23EB30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information on the findings and outcomes of such clinical trials, including preliminary outcomes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36191B64AE7B4B4EA7C589B051D0A5B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A review of all innovative treatments and emerging therapies utilized for the treatment of covered conditions, including safety and efficacy studies, cost, regulatory, and logistical considerations associated with each.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8CD6A38667C4980BA8461A83F1E1E47"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, the investigational program shall be reviewed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, who may then choose to extend or terminate the program at their discretion.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3B67F746E1954E88B308BF076B5C394B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H170A5439889B44D5B42E33470087424D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>innovative treatment</term> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HDBB4C53F1B3243C28710F9ADC8E36251"><enum>(A)</enum><text>3,4-Methylenedioxy-methamphetamine;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82D725502DEE45FCAB53DABEF693D5F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5-Methoxy-N,N-dimethyltryptamine;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B55F3917A094CCFBF67DBB324FCF7DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>5-Methoxy-2-aminoindane;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F595FB67ADD4FA2A262E78ED18137A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Ibogaine;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13CF98850E0A4B97981EDA46D9019E10"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Ketamine;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D56630F8DFB40C88391CC8A897594D6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Psilocybin; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF011AFAD932474ABDD632F451DF7B23"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Such other treatments as may be designated by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1329A08AF5134041AD82DA25D754445B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>emerging therapies</term> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H5F5FF01485614E189CA2653DC9B22EB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Investigational pharmaceutical candidates that meet the Government’s Definition of Recovery;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H060D0D051ECC473EA4253C9A8AF4A164"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Investigational medical devices, such as deep brain neurostimulation or hyperbaric oxygen therapy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31E2E4E12CEC4F5FADDDBBC8B2B974AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such other therapeutic interventions as may be designated by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8385EDC0006144BEB03363E429B3A72C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>covered condition</term> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB8F429EB37174F1DA2BF31166D6AF3D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Anxiety;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78861BA10847462293A5F85D0E48A8D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Chronic pain;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE46C4671C6E4755BC5CBE7FB9A3582E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Depression;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF47556DDC6114CAEA8E6252A47C5205A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Post-traumatic stress disorder;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98F3821773A5406A8F7CBA5A54BA1AF4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Substance use disorders, including but not limited to alcohol use and cocaine use disorders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8E40A7606A84B9F9C578DCCFEF6BF4F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Traumatic brain injury; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01076BDE770642C0A6E942F26A396CD6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Such other conditions as may be designated by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EBBB05138444DBC8776E17FAAEEC8CB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require or direct the Secretary to act in a manner inconsistent with applicable Federal law, including laws governing investigational medical products and controlled substances.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

