<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H33F374BF762241398C94E3473BF1143E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7785 IH: Protecting Our Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7785</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve accountability and training for Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC3316154906D4069BAAAC8544D628059" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEF287BD2A69B4163A3E2DEF47348C68A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H6D280E0249B2437EA85801FF704C5D50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Our Communities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H02BCFF465B994F6FBBC88161DB8B973A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HEF287BD2A69B4163A3E2DEF47348C68A" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD7B8494DB16A4328B290A4CD844B3B70" level="section">Sec. 2. Body cameras.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H94AB09F533D1443DBEB46C361A4BAE3C" level="section">Sec. 3. Insignia and identification required for law enforcement officers and agents engaged in border security or immigration enforcement.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7711B41B6ECB4FE9A24B7E0EBDBE71EB" level="section">Sec. 4. Deescalation traning.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8882F0B9E1D246DE8D3816F8C3DF48DC" level="section">Sec. 5. Requiring notification for local law enforcement.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H16769A833A98451B9DEF6E20F3C422F9" level="section">Sec. 6. Reporting Requirements.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD7B8494DB16A4328B290A4CD844B3B70"><enum>2.</enum><header>Body cameras</header> 
<subsection id="HE7B8FE0C15174C83BF32F393A316F7BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Body and vehicle camera requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="H452A7BBFEC4D4928A245ADCB49AC445B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop and disseminate a Department-wide directive requiring the use of—</text> <subparagraph id="H559D96E7A899432CB944BCB1F6954E38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>body-worn cameras by all Federal immigration enforcement personnel; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFF004925F93041FA8973D32EB4F1CECA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>dashboard cameras for all vehicles being used in Federal immigration enforcement operations and associated recording protocols.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC63DD6647D9541A1A0F79D2299D2B76C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement for body camera</header><text>A body camera required under paragraph (1) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H980131E4C8424DF394F2B9D3BB525E06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have a field of view at least as broad as the officer’s vision; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD96BE3E205EF4151942EE6F249C0ECDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be worn in a manner that maximizes the camera’s ability to capture video footage of the officer’s activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC1C22F901A34D278F15006D188D55ED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement to activate</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8EB0C18B5B3E40FE82AC3502C3E9B5CC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Both the video and audio recording functions of the body camera shall be activated whenever a Federal immigration enforcement personnel is participating in a Federal immigration enforcement operation, except that when an immediate threat to the person’s life or safety makes activating the camera impossible or dangerous the Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall activate the camera at the first reasonable opportunity to do so.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA22763A69CEB424F8726C9ACD527C384"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allowable deactivation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The body camera shall not be deactivated until the Federal immigration enforcement operation ceases and the Federal immigration enforcement personnel leaves the scene.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46C6F944E7F44959ABFC752CDCB77F42"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitations on use of body camera</header><text>Body cameras shall not be used to gather intelligence information based on First Amendment protected speech, associations, or religion, or to record activity that is unrelated to a Federal immigration enforcement operation, and shall not be equipped with or employ any facial recognition technologies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9A1D5BDD454409C8C829242369396E4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Retention of footage</header> <subparagraph id="H9FDF76D5AF114106AD9130A8EDCF7288" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Body camera and dashboard camera video footage shall be retained by the Department of Homeland Security for one year after the date on which it was recorded, after which time such footage shall be permanently deleted.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H365427E616544E1FB8162503B603FD9C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Right to inspect</header><text>During the one year retention period described in paragraph (1), the following persons shall have the right to inspect the body camera footage:</text> <clause id="H776AB531D73F436CBE5F559C36381C17"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who is a subject of body camera video footage, and their designated legal counsel.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H35ED1AB17D034AB1841AB230D6283541"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A parent or legal guardian of a minor subject of body camera video footage, and their designated legal counsel.</text></clause> <clause id="H40F3A146E7614838B49E3392B8E936EB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The spouse, next of kin, or legally authorized designee of a deceased subject of body camera video footage, and their designated legal counsel.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBABCE9FEB66E41339E1E52C42C560EE9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A Federal immigration enforcement personnel whose body camera recorded the video footage, and their designated legal counsel, subject to the limitations and restrictions in this Act.</text></clause> <clause id="H8F4E5D31717D4154B970D9111D221C68"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The superior officer of a Federal immigration enforcement personnel whose body camera recorded the video footage, subject to the limitations and restrictions in this Act.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5722B516A85E48CFA596A734733C2A17"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Any defense counsel who claims, pursuant to a written affidavit, to have a reasonable basis for believing a video may contain evidence that exculpates a client.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17CE088962BA4B5B9E2E10A598BCE710"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Principles</header><text>In preparing the directive required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H222065F76BE14FB886CF958287712593"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Benchmarks for implementation of the use of body-worn cameras by Federal immigration enforcement personnel and dashboard cameras for vehicles being used for Federal immigration enforcement to conform with a standard that cameras are on by default and may only be turned off in certain circumstances.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA39B27ADE79044C48540EF17A8BF58C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Training requirements, procedures, and best practices for the use of body-worn cameras and dashboard cameras.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3094A4E1A389424FBE14EF8BFB68F232"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Plans to publicize the directive and the requirements set forth in this section to ensure Federal immigration enforcement personnel and other impacted individuals are notified of new policies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H94AB09F533D1443DBEB46C361A4BAE3C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Insignia and identification required for law enforcement officers and agents engaged in border security or immigration enforcement</header> <subsection id="H8BA64B4A54734ED78B8ACF58D76C4AFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title VII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/341">6 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HE62035FA687D4405AA44BEB2D26468D9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8DC283501DEE44B2B4A0D2B37BEB9F04"><enum>714.</enum><header>Insignia and identification required for law enforcement officers and agents engaged in border security or immigration enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="H90CA858120B34B1A8A28D1F3F2FB313C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HDE8FB479141143B3944F98C490E64D62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a law enforcement officer or agent of the Department detains or arrests an individual in connection with a border security or immigration enforcement function of such officer or agent, during such detention or arrest, as the case may be, such officer or agent—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE0697EB2BB64625BD1A7C1D5D8304BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall—</text> 
<clause id="H95C13316171F419581BADFDF395BEEA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide such individual with an identification of the component of the Department that employs such officer or agent; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8FED38134D9E4362B56E8F6F4790AF29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>display or wear the official insignia or uniform of such officer or agent in a manner that is visible to individuals other than such officer or agent; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA5F373CC61546D9A3BED30A729F3937"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not wear a face covering or any other item that conceals the face of such officer or agent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E5541EA209A4F91ACA73EA019E9226E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit or prohibit the use of tactical gear by law enforcement officers and agents consistent with the policies and procedures of the Department.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEBA79F4356546989C5CAD6564E67BE5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC9E41D3FFB0245F7A807A11F1A7595A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the policies and procedures of the Department regarding the use of tactical gear by law enforcement officers and agents of the Department.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DDD770E4AF04B6C9F6D0951DE1908EE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>If the Secretary modifies the policies or procedures of the Department regarding the use of tactical gear by law enforcement officers or agents of the Department, not later than 30 days after any such modification, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report relating thereto.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H86920F70D56D4D489228476B34275515"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research and development</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, and in coordination with the heads of components of the Department that employ law enforcement officers or agents, shall carry out research and development of technology to maximize the visibility of the official insignia or uniform of such an officer or agent to be utilized during detentions or arrests, including technology to maximize such visibility in response to certain factors in connection with such detentions or arrests, including the following:</text> <paragraph id="HAA73EC25B2654D16806F3D20B420FF78"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Location.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0B3A0C0765B42CD8049C57BF5925E79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Time of day.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28C599542AD54E01880A849D93EFB7F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Weather.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8C9D355CC434D37A825B24205925761"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HA6E80F2DE3BF414485ED0C3A9B375EDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Law enforcement officer or agent</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement officer or agent</term> means a law enforcement officer or agent of the Department, including U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62744A2FA40F4177ADED8105A0530AEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Official insignia or uniform</header><text>The term <term>official insignia or uniform</term> has the meaning given such term in section 716 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H53DB0DABDF8D4E31A50C447ACB1829D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for such Act is amended by inserting after the item pertaining to section 713 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD8CE9F6F86F34F3C8A13206F13CF37AF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">714. Insignia and identification required for law enforcement officers and agents engaged in border security or immigration enforcement.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7711B41B6ECB4FE9A24B7E0EBDBE71EB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Deescalation traning</header> 
<subsection id="H1F8BD7017F6A4FE4B6715DF9523D5350"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop training curricula or identify effective existing training curricula for Federal immigration enforcement personnel regarding—</text> <paragraph id="HB657324DFCE7408CB9DA87C8B757CDE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deescalation tactics; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B2597267A7D4C1B87426BAA0132AE9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>alternatives to use of force.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA54A89797EC64669B35BB14971971E2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Particular inclusions</header><text>The training curricula developed or identified under subsection (a) shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5512E40C89414D4F8B5772C26F124095"><enum>(1)</enum><text>scenario-based exercises;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H209558C9ACE94648B63CBB88043BB1F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pretraining and posttraining tests to assess relevant knowledge and skills covered in the training curricula; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0297F5F48DC040BF8669541A67E1E036"><enum>(3)</enum><text>followup evaluative assessments to determine the degree to which participants in the training apply, in their jobs, the knowledge and skills gained in the training.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H95423B6771E24F698AABB3702E8544AE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop and identify training curricula under this section in consultation with relevant law enforcement agencies of States and units of local government, immigrant organizations, associations that represent individuals with mental or behavioral health diagnoses or individuals with disabilities, labor organizations, professional law enforcement organizations, local law enforcement labor and representative organizations, law enforcement trade associations, mental health and suicide prevention organizations, family advocacy organizations, and civil rights and civil liberties groups.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8882F0B9E1D246DE8D3816F8C3DF48DC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requiring notification for local law enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement shall notify local law enforcement of impending operations in their jurisdiction.</text></section> <section id="H16769A833A98451B9DEF6E20F3C422F9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reporting Requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Beginning not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress the following reports on the criteria Federal immigration enforcement personnel use to determine whether an immigrant poses a public safety or national security threat:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD62BBA2179C442BF9000FB5B9B5F5EC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a report every 6 months detailing—</text> <subparagraph id="HB4E7AF7BA60E4585B5BDEBF2738DD8AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>instances where nondeadly force was used;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1DF38FE9B8FA43B3933EB3663240C4F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the level of public safety or national security threat the target posed;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13E3E9B7BBA04EC9A42FA8A18489C3CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for what reason nondeadly force was administered;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H10348D0D864F4D7BA8341805B2B1F029"><enum>(D)</enum><text>specific instances where nondeadly force was improperly administered; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31AFA32CED99439EB33E2C9975B28CAE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the measures the Department took to ensure accountability for improper use of force.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7141A7AEA7A40D097542D7065423FE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a report every 6 months detailing instances of assaults against Federal immigration enforcement personnel. The report shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H299870CD56FF4EFFBA609DF007154716"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of personnel involved in immigration enforcement operations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC2398CDF08FE4091BB68A26BEF22FCA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of assaults against Federal immigration enforcement personnel; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C7F76C41D9B49908D693FA5583300D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>details on the severity of those instances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF1D63371F7F45AFB85C96D027D83794"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall send a report to Congress every 6 months detailing all instances in which Federal immigration enforcement personnel operated without displaying or wearing the official insignia or uniform.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

