<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H77F2D2363D55452FACB30696A75565EC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7282 IH: Freeing Residential Affordable Markets from Excess Regulation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7282</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260130">January 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001137">Mr. Crank</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To incentivize States not to enact costly, burdensome, and unreasonable energy code housing policies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H17494D1CDC0945FC8B6F8D39454A93DE" style="OLC"><section id="H78E8DC9D21EF419CA27A5D01CDBF6114" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Freeing Residential Affordable Markets from Excess Regulation Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FRAMER Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEA39E093F10743D1B4B4CBEB091B9E8C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Energy Codes in Opportunity Zones</header><subsection id="HED7C17AFDB5C45068A65EEA101F20534"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 104 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5304">42 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6B415AFB0BDB4D0A8FABB16CE0FFA470" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H3F99D3126A2E4806B33EE44D0927B093"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Energy Codes in Opportunity Zones</header><paragraph id="HA551E27D305B4EAE9BC99706A63F9E2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive amounts under this title on or after the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, a State shall provide to each person who built a covered dwelling unit in an opportunity zone that is located in the jurisdiction of such entity, not later than 30 days after such dwelling unit has been inspected and certified for occupancy, a payment in the amount equal to the difference, determined by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, between—</text><subparagraph id="HA2931955B9D7499C960C53C9AEFE5813"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cost of implementing the energy housing code of the State with respect to such covered dwelling unit, including costs associated with labor, supplies, wages of employees, inspection costs, or any other cost realized by the person who built a covered dwelling unit; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF41F7FE0CAD487493E78C841CEC340E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of implementing the Department of Housing and Urban Development’s Minimum Energy Standard with respect to such covered dwelling unit, regardless of whether such covered dwelling is subject to such standard.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAC23CA239A545BA870E8AF2E1C16259"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply if the energy housing code of the State has a lower cost than the Department of Housing and Urban Development’s Minimum Energy Standard.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AEBAA568EB046A9A281D7E2C464A243"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Disclosure requirement</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who built a covered dwelling unit in an opportunity zone and who has received or may in the future receive a reimbursement for building costs incurred shall provide to the person who first buys the covered dwelling unit, using a procedure and form established by the Secretary, a disclosure document that, based on information reasonably available at the time such disclosure is made,—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="H024F9AB46A514420A768FA015A192668" commented="no">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies the difference between the cost of implementing the energy housing code of the State with respect to such covered dwelling unit and the cost of implementing the Department of Housing and Urban Development’s Minimum Energy Standard with respect to such covered dwelling unit;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="HBC27D23159434ECFA6BFAD01530A7ACD">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies any amount that such person who built a covered dwelling unit has received or expects to receive from the a State under this section and any portion of such amount that was used by such person to reduce the price of the covered dwelling unit.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H578D0F33CE6B4465BDE82D3100C5F0D2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H77D444A006FD415484721E89226B32D2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered dwelling unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered dwelling unit</quote> means a <quote>residential building</quote> such as term is defined in section 6832 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H994432A99A7B480388A4D411F6A28A38"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Opportunity zone</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>opportunity zone</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 1400Z–2 of title 26, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HEDE9C2ECB41A4EBEBB459AA4AFC24C2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall, each year until the date described in subsection (c), submit a report to the Congress that, to the degree practicable—</text><paragraph id="HCC4D895051FA433882CCB511197D679B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lists the States that were required under Section 104(n) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to provide payments to persons who built dwelling units;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF09939FC15274D649E9DE73D611B0C50"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of each such payment, broken out by metropolitan city, urban county, State, unit of general local government, and insular area;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A52F12CF81545D8A2B6D554063BECD3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the total amount of all such payments, broken out by metropolitan city, urban county, State, unit of general local government, and insular area; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69757ADE8AFA47F0BBBBC44D9611E838"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of the difference between the State codes and Department of Housing and Urban Development’s Minimum Energy Standard by metropolitan city, urban county, State, unit of general local government, and insular area.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9B6DA32D7064853BD1F8BAB54EE0029"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 104(n) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974, as added by this section, shall be repealed on the date that is 7 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

