<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HACB92EC403144BCAAB42BD8197DD9EB6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6100 IH: Health Accelerating Consumer’s Care by Expediting Self-Scheduling Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6100</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to lower barriers to increase patient access to health care.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H33D72B6F2EE8472EBA9FC5C6D019C274" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H67D0B561E2C445CA8AC5D79AD2006F46" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Accelerating Consumer’s Care by Expediting Self-Scheduling Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Health ACCESS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H70F518E047304986A4369F89AB083BAA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to section 1128B</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1128B(b) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7b(b)) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H842177197C1645669EA128EA65A58692"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF176257DCA2C46CD980AB095B7125723"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by moving the margin of subparagraphs (J) and (K) 2 ems to the left;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H398376BA334D4A05A5E8BC184B6CDF91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (K), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F3EE24111BC4C62B7649682EE75D8CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (L), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC15CCDCC00724911AB7F1FDC8137C49B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H481C9E64B5514A61801C53998A15B4CB"> <subparagraph id="HAF79FE633906423AB9B64815213368A5" indent="up1"><enum>(M)</enum><text>any remuneration paid by a provider of services (as defined in section 1861(u)) or a supplier (as defined in section 1861(d)) to an information service provider (as defined in paragraph (5)) for participation in an information service (as so defined), if—</text> 
<clause id="H38C8787E84A040AAAEB6D294E9569EE9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such information service provider does not—</text> <subclause id="HB99D7C07B4F549AF921A14A3F7551CB6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>steer or lead a consumer to select a particular provider of services or supplier based on the amount a provider of services or supplier pays or may pay the information service provider;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H83C2798299AD40FC862A9BBE558C784D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide, or represent itself as providing, any medical items or services, diagnostic or counseling services, or assessments of illness or injury, or make any promises of cure or guarantees of treatment;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H705C334C91894076A356D5C402F07EF6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide contact information regarding a consumer (as defined in paragraph (5)) to providers of services or suppliers, except to the specific provider of services or supplier selected by the consumer;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H151C8AB396AA422699795A2FE13A8071"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>provide or arrange for transportation of an individual to, or from, the location of a provider of services or supplier;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H82710FCA45864C26BC37BADB9172F96B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>provide or arrange for the provision of any other remuneration to a Federal health care program beneficiary other than the inherent convenience of the information service; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6AA20B844BE1467BB5059AAEF3B0D8C2"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>engage in targeted marketing of a particular provider of services or supplier through phone calls or text messages, with respect to consumers or potential consumers who have not previously interacted with the information service provider or who have opted out;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HC884160A4D84417CB995D1C03F8EE8F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the methodology for determining compensation paid to the information service provider by a provider of services or supplier is set in advance in writing, and the compensation—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H017DCCB49EC444E495CA61FDB515D2CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not exceed fair market value;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBD3F26CDEDC440E86DB98FE490AB609"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is for services, specified in writing; and </text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADE250E6667447FABD7E01FC35A3B691"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not take into account the value of any items or services payable in whole or in part by a Federal health care program provided to consumers by providers or suppliers who participate in the information services;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H49309E4EBFED4BFA8EC319A99F6B1B8B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such information service provider clearly discloses the financial arrangement between it and the providers of services or suppliers participating in such service to consumers;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF000CBDB0505489DB9B832671B9D91FA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such information service provider furnishes provider- and supplier-specific information to consumers based only on objective, consumer-centric criteria;</text></clause> <clause id="H205EDEA029544F849C73828B86D18F48"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such information service provider develops objective criteria for participation in such information service and does not exclude any providers of services or suppliers who meet such criteria from participating therein; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA014CEA0DC5B44DF95DC12481B5E767C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>such information service provider meets other conditions that may be determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABFD0EB13A97439F9DB1EC522F14AAA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H131983078D4F4F7BA648BB86F1F5F5BC"> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23F6C7EB4C5048B0A0ABDD0C6B8029C4" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (3)(M):</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7FBB217815C4B0590477B509FA42419"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consumer</header><text>The term <term>consumer</term> means an individual who uses a platform provided by an information service provider for the purpose of searching providers of services or suppliers.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FE0AC38B72D48B0862E747C5CD55690"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>information service</quote> means a web-based platform that has the primary purpose of providing consumers a bookable directory to search for providers of services or suppliers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC00E09CCB8504E82AB6F097BEA49D705"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Information service provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>information service provider</term> means any individual or entity operating a web-based platform that makes information regarding providers of services or suppliers available to consumers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

