<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H10D371B651B74CBA9EE5C20CF618299C">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7902 IH: Safeguarding Women from Chemical Abortion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7902</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide that the approved application under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act for the drug mifepristone for the purpose of the termination of intrauterine pregnancy is deemed to have been withdrawn, to establish a Federal tort for harm to women caused by chemical abortion drugs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H3A197B6F849443B290F6D6A797DDA2C8">
<section section-type="section-one" id="H0B98B99B256A413594601610907FB992"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding Women from Chemical Abortion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD95B40E10F924B8A98FA8BBDC733B435"><enum>2.</enum><header>Withdrawal of approval of the drug mifepristone for termination of pregnancy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective upon the expiration of 14 days after the date of the enactment of this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H05104A1361BB42A38CC0E0F43DE4E481"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Approval of an application submitted under subsection (b) of section 505 of the <act-name parsable-cite="FFDCA">Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) for the drug mifepristone (marketed as Mifeprex, and also known as RU–486) with an indication for the termination of intrauterine pregnancy, and of any application submitted under subsection (j) of such section for a drug with the same indication and for which mifepristone is the reference drug, is deemed to have been withdrawn under subsection (e) of such section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13650764AEB74C14B31725B424A07AD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of sections 301(d) and 304 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331(d)</external-xref>; 334), the introduction or delivery for introduction of a drug, the approval of which has been withdrawn as described in paragraph (1), into interstate commerce shall be considered a violation of section 505 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H64DE7DEA2FF146DD9DF9D86E4917F961"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The drug mifepristone shall be considered misbranded for purposes of sections 301 and 304 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331</external-xref>; 334) if the drug bears labeling providing that the drug may be used for the termination of intrauterine pregnancy or that the drug may be used in conjunction with another drug for the termination of intrauterine pregnancy.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HBA49FE846AC747C8BBB8CF920815669D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal tort for harm to women caused by chemical abortion drugs</header> <subsection id="H97B3CFC0482A4A64839EB6484392E91C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HF8894F7576A942C3AD00492488EA7071"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means a person that manufactures a covered medication for introduction into interstate commerce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9C8EF7464504D599C1F6B0B13C965DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered medication</header><text>The term <term>covered medication</term> means the drug mifepristone (marketed as Mifeprex, and also known as RU–486), with an indication for the termination of intrauterine pregnancy, approved pursuant to an application submitted under subsection (b) or (j) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD72334139ACE42489F8113AFF5524088"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>A covered entity shall be liable in accordance with this section to any individual who suffers bodily injury or harm to mental health (including any physical, psychological, emotional, or physiological harm) that is attributable, in whole or in part, to the individual’s use of a covered medication manufactured by a covered entity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF89F0339E1A74D8DB337310A19BF46F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text>An individual who suffers bodily injury or harm to mental health that is attributable, in whole or in part, to the individual’s use of a covered medication as described in subsection (b) may bring a civil action against the covered entity in an appropriate district court of the United States or a State court of competent jurisdiction for—</text>
<paragraph id="HFE5241C4BF3745BC918339D5B44FCF7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>compensatory damages;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10F81BED51AE4E9AA44CD14E1CF27D55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>punitive damages; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0351FAE7453B42FA9CC73CACF758F37B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>attorney’s fees and costs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H045ED4392FAD4A1780291A2036ED1D5E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt any State law that makes available any other remedy to an individual described in subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9B3F56B56A2347578DBA7C6B34227052" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6715E71ECD224139B377B0117FCE7EA0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect any provision of section 1461 of title 18, United States Code.</text></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>

