<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8E2CE5FD27E94EBEAF872C269A4798BE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7239 IH: Next-Gen Collision Avoidance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7239</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to submit to Congress an action plan for advancing the deployment of the Airborne Collision Avoidance System-X, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H31714A7216C4478FB2AC68BB23BE19B1" style="OLC"><section id="H62A13759A9984FCABC531CC4EAF5A8BE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Next-Gen Collision Avoidance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H14CE0D9958444738B11BD2F91EBC05FA"><enum>2.</enum><header>ACAS–X action plan</header><subsection id="H3790BDC6171244A6AD48F0F0AA102422"><enum>(a)</enum><header>ACAS–X action plan</header><paragraph id="HBBF148C1F732470A8A9D5F5C8264EF1F"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an action plan for advancing the deployment of the Airborne Collision Avoidance System-X (in this section referred to as <quote>ACAS–X</quote>), ACAS–Xa, ACAS–Xr, ACAS–Xo, ACAS–Xu, ACAS–sXu, ACAS–Xp, or any variant or successor technology, in the national airspace system. The Administrator shall publish the action plan in a publicly available format not later than 10 days after submitting such action plan to Congress.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C1420B2CE9545FE83C41BC765B5179E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In developing the action plan under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HEBF4FD66767E401991A1892BA6E855BC"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a strategic roadmap for the deployment of ACAS–X technology, including steps required for widespread adoption among aircraft operators;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H652E45A14D764E97B27D163E6C964083"><enum>(B)</enum><text>actions and funding necessary to complete any applicable research, development, testing, evaluation, and standards development needed to support the certification of such technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H831A3D68DEB64A558848C7BC6DABB436"><enum>(C)</enum><text>plans for engagement with appropriate stakeholders, including—</text><clause id="H149B920ACBFD4BDD881F60A371AB9971"><enum>(i)</enum><text>aircraft operators;</text></clause><clause id="H5033AF886B704FC5B372897FB9B9F17B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>aviation safety experts outside the FAA;</text></clause><clause id="H38465D606A3A4BF79F5F932092738F18"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>avionics manufacturers;</text></clause><clause id="HED739232E1584F2BA415ABE2E70D5ACE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>aircraft manufacturers;</text></clause><clause id="H1156FDDDF9634D48ACD102C2D79C984A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>general aviation organizations;</text></clause><clause id="HFD747B5095ED454BBB748B8F1B6B8724"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">organizations representing certified collective bargaining representatives of airline pilots;</text></clause><clause id="H9E769F95280E4EBFB888F00B924BF26C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>labor organizations representing air carrier pilots, including the principal organization representing the largest certified collective bargaining representative of airline pilots; and</text></clause><clause id="HBA5DE3A3855D4A12995EB0AF68DBE22D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any other stakeholders determined appropriate by the Administrator;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF9130FEE019449580EEB86A47C7607C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>engagement with foreign civil aviation authorities to harmonize international standards for certification of such technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0949340C96F64297AA575ACBED27FEA3"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>ACAS–X interoperability considerations for aircraft operators (including rotorcraft operators) equipped with ADS–B Out and ADS–B In equipment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D04D681929646E8BB6631BDCF1EA992"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an assessment of safety benefits for aircraft operators equipping with such technology, including civil operators; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D77B1498F554D08B3E43FBC0FB9DDC8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any recommendations for administrative or legislative action, as determined appropriate by the Administrator, to advance such technology deployment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H175F5183E83B41E19977D7BB1C0AA56E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Administrator may take actions, as appropriate, to implement the action plan developed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EF26BD176B448D58324F05923E6347B"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Briefing</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Administrator submits the action plan under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress on the contents of such action plan and any prospective actions to implement such plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H407250E8A2B245F4B1D64D3E476D432C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B40DAAD0305423DB51F8675558D8EC3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ADS–B In</header><text>The term <term>ADS–B In</term> means onboard avionics equipment that receives and processes Automatic Dependent Surveillance-Broadcast transmissions that are broadcast in accordance with sections 91.225 and 91.227 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), and other aviation advisory information from ground stations, that provides the aircraft with awareness to the location of other aircraft and traffic advisories.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H784AB538A7BA4D169A73DB88A876142E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ADS–B Out</header><text>The term <term>ADS–B Out</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26C509D39C92439D904D06CF495B5548"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given such term in section 91.227 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81E8D55FDD89448BA21B6AC61804312A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">broadcasts information from the aircraft in accordance with sections 91.225 and 91.227 of such title 14 (or any successor regulations).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74C19359AB164F0EBE77377F72F416A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11A056965AE4478DAC51CF012246DA3C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>FAA</header><text>The term <term>FAA</term> means the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86EC9426E5D34BA5A319A18B12A1B0E6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rotorcraft</header><text>The term <term>rotorcraft</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1.1 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

