<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RYA26686-WWP-9J-VG7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4860 IS: Cultivating Horticultural Innovation in Local Economies Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4860</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 to establish a specialty crop emergency assistance framework, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id5ff8fa1d76b8431481517320cf03ce55" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cultivating Horticultural Innovation in Local Economies Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CHILE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id45c0a8cbb10f4b5a9727605618da14fe" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Specialty crop emergency assistance framework</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided31611bfd5b419faccb520931af6939"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 is amended by inserting after section 196 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7333">7 U.S.C. 7333</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a467d935b144065957499034db8ba01"><section id="id1b2e891dd9d84949b5770ecac245cf36"><enum>197.</enum><header>Specialty crop emergency assistance framework</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97fecc850ea7437283e219ae24076dbd"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition of specialty crop</header><text>In this section, the term <term>specialty crop</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Specialty Crops Competitiveness Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1621">7 U.S.C. 1621</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/465">Public Law 108–465</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="idc1fe990f4b0b426295d7eeea19cb94d7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Framework</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a framework to provide direct assistance to producers of specialty crops the production of which is impacted by an adverse event (including an economic crisis or market disruption), as determined by the Secretary, in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="idfa2fdb5b0a224717931ddfc8eda09903"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payment calculation</header><text>In determining a payment calculation for purposes of direct assistance to a producer of specialty crops under subsection (b), the Secretary shall calculate payments based on the product obtained by multiplying—</text><paragraph id="id1d77e71b1da64097b21d1bfb707d38ed"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the producer’s sales of specialty crops for a calendar year that precedes the year in which the adverse event described in that subsection occurred or the average of those sales over a set of consecutive calendar years that precedes the year in which that adverse event occurred, as determined by the Secretary; by</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id2d134d0964114971a593554dbfebd3c9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a payment factor the Secretary determines, subject to the availability of funds, to address losses of those specialty crops from that adverse event.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1733a0f801bc4e17a0c6a457af924b87"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>Subject to subsection (e), in providing direct assistance pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall consider—</text><paragraph id="id6bac215bd0bf43698b16350d550fca68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the higher value of specialty crops relative to other crops;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id723d05e9aa724989bfce32eb47625159"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the greater input costs required to grow specialty crops relative to other crops; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98efe65a1ec94e31bcb1f24014f482a9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the diverse types of legal entities and business structures used by specialty crop producers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2751652cf8824203b463c17fd8c1c665"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph id="id04f10d96ade04a0ea22232474e4c0382"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Total amount</header><subparagraph id="idf0a49dd0e3794644af78c2b60824c6c9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the total amount of payments received, directly or indirectly, by a person or legal entity (except a qualified pass through entity) (as those terms are defined in section 1001(a) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1308">7 U.S.C. 1308(a)</external-xref>)) for any crop year under this section may not exceed the amount specified in subsection (b) of section 1001 of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1308">7 U.S.C. 1308</external-xref>), as adjusted pursuant to subsection (i) of that section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7263047ffd3948b5beec7e76fdad0f58"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>In the case of a person or legal entity with an average gross income (as calculated under subparagraph (B) of section 1001D(b)(4) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (7 U.S.C. 1308–3a(b)(4))) for which greater than or equal to 75 percent of the average derives from farming, ranching, or silviculture activities (as defined in subparagraph (A) of that section)—</text><clause id="id8a2ae11474854f4b8c4209c7dc3b4124"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not apply; and</text></clause><clause id="id8dd9f1bab37d45798893ba69f088769b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total maximum amount of payments received, directly or indirectly, by that person or legal entity for any crop year under this section shall be set by the Secretary, except that amount may not be less than $900,000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id56d328d9aff84dccabda161085ff0a5b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification of interests; eligibility; denials</header><text>Sections 1001A(a), 1001B, and 1001C of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1308-1">7 U.S.C. 1308–1(a)</external-xref>, 1308–2, 1308–3) shall apply to a producer of a specialty crop under this section in the same manner as those sections apply to a person or legal entity with respect to a covered commodity, except to the extent those sections relate to the application of subsections (b) through (d) of section 1001A of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1308-1">7 U.S.C. 1308–1</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id53b9cb3654cd434e82551a168b9957bf"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Default structure</header><text>The Secretary shall administer any program to deliver direct assistance to producers of specialty crops described in subsection (b), including any direct assistance administered under the authority of section 5 of the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/714c">15 U.S.C. 714c</external-xref>), through the framework established under subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1067a53bd101428eb21f2f02f092bee0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>There is appropriated to the Secretary of Agriculture, out of any amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $5,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2027, to remain available until expended, to provide direct assistance to producers of specialty crops pursuant to section 197 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (as added by subsection (a)).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

