<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KIN25579-XPC-R6-MJP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3234 IS: Convenient Care for Caregivers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3234</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to establish a pilot program for family caregivers for individuals with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="ide9f5168d449c47f1a10b2b52c353c89b" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Convenient Care for Caregivers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id52da6e941cdb4eaeae61e6bf5081c650"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for family caregivers for individuals with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the Older Americans Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after section 414 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3032c">42 U.S.C. 3032c</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id314DFEE8ADE348B184B35C10CC392D64"><section id="id41A02B40CDC24A6BA4BB780BCCAF8546" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>415.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pilot program for family caregivers for individuals with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e02b5131e184ffe92b67a9c7c3db1ec"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacbb23e5ff6947d58c4fd5a93f9bdb5c"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Family caregiver for an individual with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction</header><text>The term <term>family caregiver for an individual with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e79e99edc3146678f97e583174cbc85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an adult family member, or another individual, who is an informal provider of in-home and community care to an individual of any age who is an individual with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id382a18c6891843c1934a23ef1ad47739"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an individual, providing care to an individual with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction, whose primary relationship with the indivdual is based on a financial or professional agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id162b7fb4f4e444e3a0a81c65f0d0628d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified entity</header><text>The term <term>qualified entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60857f4396c74b8096bf6abd8ba2aae6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an area agency on aging;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7315e9009f7c487ebb9d322245592ed9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a multipurpose senior center;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf548290852cc4e198f749a476034d2c5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an institution of higher education; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2531464c99fe44a79266c5a5c578024a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a tribal organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id00d01ff6ea5c4faaba6ca3e45bccc6e2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05776939ccb9467da27980ed8f4246a6"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development, shall establish and carry out a pilot program to assist family caregivers for individuals with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction to access health care services and other supports in order to improve the health outcomes of the family caregivers and the individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96cadd92f86641a380dd056fcee61f99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Projects</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d5299b85bb143f5981ec382d8d5a311"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program, the Assistant Secretary shall make grants to qualified entities meeting the requirements under subsection (c) to carry out projects that assist family caregivers for individuals with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction in addressing the health care needs of such caregivers and individuals by offering evidence-informed, or evidence-based, health care services and other supports to such caregivers and individuals at the same time and the same location.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0253161618648e8a0097cb4253e30aa"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each qualified entity receiving a grant under this section shall carry out a project described in subparagraph (A) in an easily accessible space and in accordance with applicable requirements under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id041abe98d73542af823d5c8381312aa4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a qualified entity shall submit an application at such time and in such manner as the Assistant Secretary may require, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4983647eef5c47e1a9f2c1906cdedd7d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on how the entity located an appropriate space described in subsection (b)(2)(B) to carry out a project, including any consideration of a converted retail mall or other accessible space with proximity to public transportation and ample parking, and any collaboration with a State or local economic development organization to identify that appropriate space;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd054155223a646b3961366b500f46516"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assurance that the entity—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa5b6ffb83224e748ed706265da6155a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will cooperate with efforts in which the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services will submit data to the Assistant Secretary on the payment indicators described in subsection (e)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id702c301f9b014b6dbda4aaf21ddb8789"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will submit data to the Assistant Secretary on the health indicators described in subsection (e)(2); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5aff8882ee504df6b28779a0d157822e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how the entity will share information on family caregivers of individuals with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction, and such individuals, among providers in the project.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5a7de3785d9646efacf3b866e3dbc40d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A qualified entity that receives a grant under this section may use the grant funds to provide—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a73825620c44e2aae61a052dc04ce20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>cognitive health screenings;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe7a2029ebf043979170e16bea2c28ad"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">family consultations and other care consultations;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7665df808f82422aa81b3b328de4cc96"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0786bf6df1204c2db79e24f9bc6e7c8b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>family caregiver support groups;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddad01a2ccfb24e34962d7c1586c0f3bd"><enum>(5)</enum><text>conversation groups for individuals with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f84922f5ebd43bf9d14ceaff6aecb67"><enum>(6)</enum><text>specialized bereavement services;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57a1ce77d35547838add4b6789f02cef"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ongoing support by phone or person-to-person conferencing;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3c2f79763f04b09882030281ee8d7ee"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">insurance support; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9144c2f268449c59e3418c196604a66"><enum>(9)</enum><text>social and cultural activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9c54ed791c8143819fce1df991bcce77"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Outcome data</header><text>A qualified entity that receives a grant under this section for a project shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id604b8882b5ef43ca993f5e1cad22c110"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the date of the enrollment of the family caregiver of an individual with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction, and such individual, in the project, notify the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services of the enrollment and request that the Administrator send to the Assistant Secretary—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida5f203ab45d74dc5b11cf4c6b5716533"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an estimated amount on an indicator consisting of the payments made by the Centers, through programs under the jurisdiction of the Centers, on behalf of the caregiver and individual during the last full fiscal year preceding the enrollment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf41bf92657ab4ecfa766ff8337a68dd0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after each fiscal year for which the caregiver and individual are enrolled in the project, a calculated amount on that payment indicator for that fiscal year;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id127eda5f796d49708c6a4ac1a49c21ad"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5585df60f7b64228845a36a636e8ecec"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Assistant Secretary, after the first appointments of the family caregiver of an individual with Alzheimer's disease or a related disorder with neurological and organic brain dysfunction, and the individual, with the project, initial data on health indicators of the caregiver and individual consisting of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id055B238149844AB3841B23CFF12DCFD5" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cholesterol levels;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70B5351194A049759A8B37ED03303B0F" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>body mass index;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2C44648F3D0F4517BF2EE5ACC324E13E" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>weight;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4618EB725BE04902BC55F75CB4DA2078" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>glucose levels;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id53a7872d6e0e4d868c57f366d5fc400c"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">self-reported data, including data on emotional stress, physical strain, loneliness, and feelings of isolation; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD7D6E9762CBA4105B263304ACD6B44B4" indent="up1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>such other health indicators as the Assistant Secretary may establish; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6d779ef3be04b0c841010bbf59c51d5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Assistant Secretary, not later than 60 days after each fiscal year for which the caregiver and individual are so enrolled, subsequent data on the health indicators.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id798af01f7f674113a661eae6e8288e94"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 120 days after each such fiscal year, the Assistant Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate, the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, a report containing information on the outcome data collected under subsection (e), including the differences between the estimated and calculated amounts on the payment indicators reported under subsection (e)(1) and the differences between the initial and subsequent data on the health indicators reported under subsection (e)(2).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe57622603eb44e8915e9f9218ede9f1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall work with the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to develop the indicator described in subsection (e)(1), and means of collecting data on that indicator.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

