<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0B8B9B0DB6EA49A2BC8C517B4ADF2E93" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8820 IH: Prohibit Deactivation of the ECABs Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8820</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001137">Mr. Crank</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the use of certain funds for the deactivation of Expeditionary Combat Aviation Brigades, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H47B6093A4AAE4F8895BCC7AE1F3712E1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H67215293D98E48D89F738DFA3B7F31F9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prohibit Deactivation of the ECABs Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H642F602E60784BFC9DFD21E97CC89526" section-type="subsequent-section"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Limitation on use of funds for deactivation of Expeditionary Combat Aviation Brigades</header> <subsection id="HD992994A24C646C69A0E13973E5E7FE1"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Limitation</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any of fiscal years 2027 through 2031 for the Army may be obligated or expended to retire, deactivate, schedule to deactivate, or proceed with any other action that would reduce the capabilities, resources, aircraft, or personnel available, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, for the Expeditionary Combat Aviation Brigades unless the Secretary of the Army submits to the congressional defense committees—</text>
                <paragraph id="H4F045C56F60E4217B6FE481462B99B31">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification that the Secretary of the Army plans to recapitalize any such aircraft for the Expeditionary Combat Aviation Brigades and to otherwise restore any such capabilities, resources, or personnel levels reduced; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H8D5F2F2D6A5047E19654BFEC238AA12C">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the plan of the Secretary of the Army for the actions specified in paragraph (1).</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H0AF043DED95A4526897BC8BEBE0A7BFB">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Requirement To restore</header>
                <paragraph id="H9927438BF34E470A90FA0E020198E417">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Requirement</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, for any Expeditionary Combat Aviation Brigade that, prior to such date of enactment, the Secretary of the Army retired or deactivated (or carried out any other activity to reduce the capabilities, resources, aircraft, or personnel thereof), the Secretary of the Army shall reinstate or reactivate such brigade, or otherwise restore such brigade to the levels preceding such reduction, as the case may be.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HD71E181D6E114E3393950EDBED87E66D">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Report</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the implementation of this subsection.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HC01E97306AE74DBE867EBB4695230E2B">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Plan required</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army shall submit to the congressional defense committees a plan to sustain and modernize the aircraft used by the Expeditionary Combat Aviation Brigades.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H13234347EE5441A1A67041B677AD2F25">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of the Army for the operation of aircraft, and training for such operation, by the Expeditionary Combat Aviation Brigades $35,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H6270034D5AE24BDE836FA1AE030E78D8">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Congressional defense committees defined</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>congressional defense committees</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

