<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72A295A5942342E79AB9A366D8FE5201" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1213 IH: Supporting the recognition of April 2026 as “National County Government Month” to honor the county government workforce, educate residents about local programs and services, and celebrate the county government role in the intergovernmental partnership.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1213</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260423">April 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001245">Mr. Menefee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the recognition of April 2026 as <quote>National County Government Month</quote> to honor the county government workforce, educate residents about local programs and services, and celebrate the county government role in the intergovernmental partnership.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas county governments are one of the oldest forms of government in the United States, with roots dating back to 1634, when the first county governments were established in Virginia;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas today’s 3,069 county governments are chartered under State constitutions or laws to serve the diverse needs of local communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas county governments serve as the level of government closest to the people, delivering essential services that impact the daily life of residents of the county, including public safety, infrastructure, health care, economic development, and social services;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Association of Counties has, since 1991, designated the month of April as <quote>National County Government Month</quote> to encourage counties across the United States to raise public awareness about county roles and responsibilities in serving residents;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas America’s 3,069 counties, parishes, and boroughs keep our communities healthy, vibrant, and safe, employing approximately 3,600,000 dedicated public servants who serve residents every day;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas counties are governed by locally elected officials, including more than 19,350 county, elected executives and board members across the country who are directly accountable to the residents they serve;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas county governments are vital partners in the intergovernmental system, working alongside Federal, State, Tribal, and local officials to implement laws, regulations, and services that benefit all Americans;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas counties invest in critical infrastructure, including roads, bridges, and public transit, that connects communities and drives economic prosperity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas counties support approximately 70 percent of all local public health departments in the United States, invest approximately $130,000,000,000 annually in community health and hospitals;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas <quote>National County Government Month</quote> offers an opportunity for counties to tell their stories, celebrate their workforces, and strengthen civic connections between county governments and the residents they serve through activities such as open houses, facility tours, proclamations, media outreach, social media campaigns, and school engagement; and</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas the National Association of Counties commends the county officials and employees whose dedication and public service make communities across America better places to live, work, and thrive: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H3821237DCC2D41C1A0D51BDC14E77E42"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H51EE44CFBE5F4FAB8790F5939728A0ED"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HCA07E23670004BEC806953C2AFF317E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports <quote>National County Government Month</quote> and calls on all counties, parishes, and boroughs across the United States to join in this celebration;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F48660050DC4D05977D8AB1B905899E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages all counties, parishes, and boroughs to pass a resolution or proclamation recognizing <quote>National County Government Month</quote> in their respective jurisdictions and to use the month to actively promote the roles and responsibilities of counties in serving residents;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4A1849FAB724748B1C7E78DD056756B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages each county to use <quote>National County Government Month</quote> to tell the story of the county, raising awareness of local programs and services that impact residents every day; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE8FD5601F8148F79B46EB4F9E50DBE0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages Members of Congress to engage with their local communities to raise awareness about <quote>National County Government Month</quote> and to support the goals of the celebration of educating the public about the essential role counties play in daily American life.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

