<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF26573-KKW-7V-GD6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4937 IS: Investor Choice Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4937</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to prohibit mandatory pre-dispute arbitration agreements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="H686AABF1458D461B8318AEB73D969B5A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investor Choice Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H16242A8BE6814F2C8576D3157D64163D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H4DE6ED37D843482BBB3506A0974FEFA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Investor confidence in fair and equitable recourse is essential to the health and stability of the securities markets and to the participation of retail investors in those markets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D2D046B30DE4A33A45346B08F10E135"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Issuers, brokers, dealers, and investment advisers hold powerful advantages over investors, and mandatory arbitration clauses, including contracts that force investors to submit claims to arbitration or to waive the right of investors to participate in a class action lawsuit, leverage those advantages to severely restrict the ability of defrauded investors to seek redress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52E45EB1924E44D69471CB6DE0349FB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Investors should be free to—</text><subparagraph id="idD04E072AC7964BAE9E0A08219BA644E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>choose arbitration to resolve disputes if they judge that arbitration truly offers them the best opportunity to efficiently and fairly settle disputes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCAD529DE4A4D468284363B0BC7AB34CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pursue remedies in court should they view that option as superior to arbitration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HAD0006E1D2A744C293AD62BBE93F45F4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Arbitration agreements in the Securities Exchange Act of 1934</header><subsection id="H0A9EDF3E5639434C9C7B4C5812BA99A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5E2DCDA65A964D1B805AA509A43553B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 6(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78f">15 U.S.C. 78f(b)</external-xref>), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86F8F128B33944BEA19A4ADE8AC39AB5"><paragraph id="H3410CE90A9574277A2E14FF6AF24FA7C"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The rules of the exchange prohibit the listing of any security if the issuer of the security, in the bylaws of the issuer, other governing documents, or any contract with a shareholder relating to the parties as issuer and shareholder, mandates arbitration for any dispute between the issuer and the shareholders of the issuer, without regard to whether such a provision in the bylaws, documents, or contract is otherwise permissible under title 9, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H42539A19B9F147BEB6180A1FB902A983"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 15 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o</external-xref>), by amending subsection (o) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9D8248CABF6B4944BA9342CB781D01CE"><subsection id="H75BA8E7032354FBAAA26334C5D9F89C3"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Limitations on pre-Dispute agreements</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including any provision of title 9, United States Code, it shall be unlawful for any broker, dealer, funding portal, or municipal securities dealer to enter into, modify, or extend an agreement with customers or clients of that entity with respect to a future dispute between the parties that—</text><paragraph id="HB2A6E8BA63A34A5AA6C09AD86BB59FA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>mandates arbitration for that dispute;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FD9480DD37E4D49A8680B0CE16C83F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>restricts, limits, or conditions the ability of a customer or client of that entity to select or designate a forum for resolution of that dispute; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F384AFFA5B64697B42B71F7ABDECA02"><enum>(3)</enum><text>restricts, limits, or conditions the ability of a customer or client of that entity to pursue a claim relating to that dispute in an individual or representative capacity or on a class action or consolidated basis.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A1B554FB168439CB3AFC42752AFFD49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to existing agreements</header><paragraph id="H2533170C0577488F91769EC7653B927E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to an agreement described in section 15(o) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o(o)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a) of this section, that was entered into before the date of enactment of this Act, any provision of that agreement that is prohibited by such section 15(o), as amended by subsection (a) of this section, is void.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0004DF7F5684F9BA792CC51D195313D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ongoing arbitration</header><text>A provision of an agreement prohibited by section 15(o) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o(o)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a) of this section, shall not be void under paragraph (1) if arbitration required by that provision was initiated by any party on or before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H426A59E5CFFD4E0CB870A6A252433FB9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Arbitration agreements in the Securities Act of 1933</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77f">15 U.S.C. 77f</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAED97CFC9D474481BD210FCB0BA1F494"><subsection id="HFA5EB1D49AA64518808DC29F507ED6CD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on arbitration requirements</header><text>A security may not be registered with the Commission if the issuer of the security, in the bylaws of the issuer, other governing documents, or any contract with a shareholder relating to the parties as issuer and shareholder, mandates arbitration for any dispute between the issuer and the shareholders of the issuer, without regard to whether such a provision in the bylaws, documents, or contract is otherwise permissible under title 9, United States Code.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H70EE9111C325435397BD55BDD52D3CAD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Arbitration agreements in the Investment Advisers Act of 1940</header><subsection id="H2EFD6245F81A4A4181148F5E90542466"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 205(f) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-5">15 U.S.C. 80b–5(f)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC06DA1AFCE034ED9805BA0D8FEB75866"><subsection id="H83DE1349FC164D49901578409C58A1ED"><enum>(f)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including any provision of title 9, United States Code, it shall be unlawful for any investment adviser to enter into, modify, or extend an agreement with customers or clients of the investment adviser with respect to a future dispute between the parties to that agreement that—</text><paragraph id="HBA19872BECCE46078BE057C902EF00AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>mandates arbitration for that dispute;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C45B76174F34CBF91982DB75A67AF9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>restricts, limits, or conditions the ability of a customer or client of the investment adviser to select or designate a forum for resolution of that dispute; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B82DD4FDDF84D16A70AD50C18EE803E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>restricts, limits, or conditions the ability of a customer or client of the investment adviser to pursue a claim relating to that dispute in an individual or representative capacity or on a class action or consolidated basis.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6C16A95ABE644156BBF49FA8E0BC7058"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to existing agreements</header><paragraph id="HF398234F07964167A273254E6F6AED3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to an agreement described in section 205(f) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-5">15 U.S.C. 80b–5(f)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a) of this section, that was entered into before the date of enactment of this Act, any provision prohibited by such section 205(f), as amended by subsection (a) of this section, is void.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49A8A65CBBE944BAA5C49C90134EE3FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ongoing arbitration</header><text>A provision of an agreement prohibited by section 205(f) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-5">15 U.S.C. 80b–5(f)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a) of this section, shall not be void under paragraph (1) if arbitration required by that provision was initiated by any party on or before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3E8891E31D8F4077A4C4CE2D318EFACB"><enum>6.</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise stated, the amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to any agreement entered into, modified, or extended after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

