<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H98BA886E4B9D4445A158A9EC5D5F7E8D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7524 IH: Older Workers’ Bureau Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7524</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish in the Department of Labor an Older Workers’ Bureau, to establish a data hub and a technical assistance center at the Department of Labor related to employment of older workers and the effect of older employment on retirement security, to establish grant programs related to the employment of older workers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7E820E5793CC45FF8C7A7E450306A904" style="OLC"> 
<section commented="no" section-type="section-one" id="H88B931928F60416D8F1D3900C83BED23"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Older Workers’ Bureau Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBE7B697C7857443DB29BF58EC210E24C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H671F5511A2384160851CB9394A217AD3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0C146CEEC1B645679ECFA6F19D2A23B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the 5,350,000 workers expected to be added to the United States Workforce over the next 10 years, 2,070,000 will be older than 55, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E25096F9C214F09885A146248C593A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From 2004 to 2024, the share of older workers in the labor force grew from 16 percent to over 23 percent.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27D3EA2A359649C3A59DAFD346F7D2C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Supplemental Poverty Measure (SPM) the older adult poverty rate went up to 15 percent in 2024 from 9.5 percent during the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6ECBB988941487384AC2ABAE5A4DD15"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Older adults in the bottom 20 percent of wealth died on average 9 years earlier than those in the top 20 percent.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E657990690A4A68A579FA3A0BB40532"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Physically and psychologically difficult working conditions are widespread and damaging for older workers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B262E1F573B491B9448D29F915FB893"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Older workers are more likely to be involuntary part time, gig, or temporary workers than prime age workers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2F412134CB545129B2ED5F7B2B14A96"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">More than <fraction>1/3</fraction> or 35.1 percent of women ages 55 and older earned low wages, defined as $17.37 per hour or less.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5E8AAC424674A16BF8B90E425A3346B"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Concern about age discrimination amongst older workers reached a record high during the COVID–19 pandemic and remains consistently and persistently high at 64 percent.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BFBA1CB61164811ACD4CCA938730D45"><enum>(9)</enum><text>More than 1,000,000 older workers were pushed out or voluntarily left the labor force during the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0623549639234174B379F6DEFD006250"><enum>(10)</enum><text>While some older workers have returned to the labor force since the beginning of the COVID–19 pandemic, many have struggled to obtain work and others fear returning to unsafe working conditions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E4212AA3BEF420CBEC6C13C139E7677"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Significant numbers of women between the age of 55 and 64 have unexpected workforce exits due to health and care giving responsibilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA90CE15FEA5B434EBF2F90088A983AFE"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Older workers need specific policy consideration and assistance that could be met by establishing an Older Workers’ Bureau within the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H481C80336345433E8229CFD15E26D92E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to promote productive, inclusive, and welfare-enhancing employment opportunities and workplaces for older workers through research, policy development, outreach, and grant programs.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE11524DABB2940FB9934A8EE8AAF5950"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HEC0D6DDAB0124AE0B6BBF4F6BAC74A8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Bureau</term> means the Older Workers’ Bureau established under section 4(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28B380DBEC1D4EF4AC39FE0924DC1410"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Older Workers’ Bureau.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H797CD0C9A789498C9A4289EEBAE0EC64"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Older worker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>older worker</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3F8068C7DF84FF3838E15BB4FA2909A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not younger than 55 years of age; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H511D51E3A626432C96410165E0F2A90E"><enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H81C49FB81A96476288C949DF141C55A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is employed;</text></clause> <clause id="H6555537E36434A8EA5B8E6D08628D7EC" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is seeking employment; or</text></clause> 
<clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0D88289EDCA48A4ACDD03766FAFDFFD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>wants employment, is available for employment, and has sought employment within the preceding 12 months.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H922D7FD4A17940D28390F69E431A823C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7D3D5406DE944DCF981B2462822B3F4C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Older Worker’s Bureau</header> 
<subsection id="HDCA842A4C06346DF9BA21434D65C5B7C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department of Labor a bureau to be known as the <quote>Older Workers’ Bureau</quote>, which shall be under the direction of the Director of the Older Workers’ Bureau.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HED7F7185AC854F9584F416A297A85804"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personnel</header> <paragraph id="H49B1C70C95974B49B1526FDD27B486E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header> <subparagraph id="H1DE1C8C2EB034606AB53EC5642843486"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall appoint a Director to lead the Bureau.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD6D6408066CB4D079233B5012268C7AD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion in Executive Schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC54444E00D554A098CD2CCBA50478D92"> <paragraph id="HC7EFB9CB72324FA6AA32C189C80BEF03"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Director of the Older Workers’ Bureau, Department of Labor.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE1578C56C6D42EC91AD0FCA1E6C5208"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall employ such staff as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the functions of the Bureau, at such rates of pay as the Secretary may provide, subject to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title, relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates. The Secretary may not reduce staffing levels of the Bureau below that necessary to carry out such functions efficiently.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H996E0E19CCB14C9F92E9315DE499C8F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Director shall promote the welfare and improve the working conditions of older workers, increase the efficiency, capacity, and coordination of programs serving older workers, and advance the employment opportunities of older workers, including by carrying out, with respect to older workers, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H19B5D1362C4043AB8562A94B64A772E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Research relating to—</text> <subparagraph id="H3883A67C3E5942E183C6060D94797747"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public benefits that support—</text> 
<clause id="HB3FFD92EE00547009D0419568ADD0526"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the economic and financial security of such workers; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDFA0F50F0ECC4BB29210E8A0B9DC8A53"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>access and retention of safety net supports for such workers who earn an annual income that is not more than 200 percent of the Federal poverty guidelines;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0E84DD7DC1C947B99E549A24C354C4C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>access for such workers to—</text> <clause id="HA7DA20B76C5D4DC6AFBDAD58DD0B5DCB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>leave under the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2601">29 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA7BE6A0076264E79B717ADD6A95FFB8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>workplace flexibility opportunities to support the needs of such workers with respect to managing personal health and caregiving responsibilities;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76EA16AE3F21474AB4BA5DC2CBCBAEE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>tailored, person-centered approaches to job training and adult education (including on soft skills, financial literacy education, and digital literacy) for such workers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F15DDF1B70146CE89C37192EADEE01C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>access to savings and tax-advantaged opportunities for such workers to provide a path toward a financially secure retirement;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8BCACEC46B14F55AA7F43A2A75B99CD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>age discrimination in the workplace, including how such discrimination is, and could be, addressed and how such discrimination impacts such workers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H63B8A365E03B484E913B3F075BE4DB7A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>wages paid to such workers, including whether such wages are commensurate with experience;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H605F2364BB5043839A6E8625DCBE7F78"><enum>(G)</enum><text>job security for such workers, including—</text> 
<clause id="H04C56C4202544EA3922044E98DA8E235"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the probability of job loss; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF445F040CD014010ABCE28C9D3B3661E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resources available to such workers in the event of job separation;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEBF50E8AAED848938CFEC91D73376D54"><enum>(H)</enum><text>retirement readiness for such workers, including the impact of Federal policies on retirement readiness for such workers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78EF1F353FD94D26BA43014AAB3B81C1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the impact of Federal policies on the equitable treatment (including with respect to race, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, education, ability, and residence) of such workers and their retirement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9190D124529F4BB3AEF66ED9BBCDFFFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Policy development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52679BDCC77748D3AB1218FEB9D84826"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Outreach and education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC37E565CE47448287272DD9F595BDF6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Grant program administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5DA095E386245AE9C54DAD2C55E7369"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Coordinating Federal research relating to such workers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84CE389DF48D45468812BC960B71FEFB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Improving access to data on the economic situation of such workers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3B204E97F9EC4932BF8699C729890A7B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Office quarters</header><text>The Secretary shall furnish sufficient quarters, office furniture, and equipment as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the functions of the Bureau.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H49E8C0169848441D8BD29D34498A53D8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Director—</text> <paragraph id="H723A2E8F63D345BC8AF56C6F4738C412"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall annually submit to the Secretary a report—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5263EDB3CE484CB5B0185AA3C6F5BFBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the activities of the Bureau with respect to older workers, including with respect to the functions described in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CA50106E2AC431F8E2E77647868411D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that catalogs Federal programs that support the employment, economic success, and well-being of such workers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA2A7013F962499E90D08D906BB924C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that identifies issues with respect to such workers that may be improved with Federal support; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F3BC2C3FB9C4B628049B33396D56702"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that makes recommendations to promote the welfare and economic and financial security, improve the working conditions, increase the efficiency, capacity, and coordination of programs serving older workers, and advance the employment opportunities of such workers; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H055269EBF2E846D7A69DB9C3A375902A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may publish such report, as directed by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8E1CACD31223484CBA3F3B216B71F519" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the functions of the Bureau, the Secretary, acting through the Director, may consult with—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8E4096D56A7A45DE86B5EA6AB2C70258" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal agencies that have jurisdiction over matters involving older adults, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HB580F9BDFE9245CAAA2E9AD9303C918A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Social Security Administration, including the Office of Retirement and Disability Policy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H744684DC5D8F49E9B9E7F9899A4A3105" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services, including the Administration for Community Living, the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, and the National Institute on Aging;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73A644B9F684492F808C7D8A19123BDC" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H67DEB38353E8471990824EA5E01A9ED6" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC16315AA544744289DAC4A5CC8753C3A" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury, including the Internal Revenue Service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8A3BB3F022B345559854B202FB1AC2AD" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05EFF4DBC48C464BA6ECD323B400AAFB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other Federal agency that the Secretary determines has relevant expertise.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC22592C2A78A4A98B61AF9500C0D5D94"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The Secretary shall take such actions as are necessary to ensure the Bureau is operational not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0D2D0E283E54499FAF48226D241AAED1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Research grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Bureau is operational, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall carry out a program to award, on a competitive basis, grants to facilitate, with respect to older workers, research—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0752E7842C1447DDAC0FD358E7C55114"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designed to identify areas that could benefit from additional research for the purposes of—</text> <subparagraph id="H329F50BD27234BF0A9A8E449A167388D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying and eliminating barriers to securing employment, job retention, and reemployment for such workers; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB0A5FC563D643DC87EA17D529F5DC3F">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>identifying policies that the Federal Government may implement to assist such workers; and</text>
        </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11C52149EA314C43B50096CD6A20C35B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as determined appropriate by the Secretary, into the areas identified under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HFBFC6DB7E49D4C5BB38DCF7F17EBB840"><enum>6.</enum><header>Grants to combat structural ageism</header> <subsection id="HAB7D5329E213485DA5BDC056EE893523"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Bureau is operational, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall carry out a program to award, on a competitive basis, grants to covered institutions to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5CBA8A927CC848E0A7E6786FD512E5E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitate activities, services, and programs to improve the welfare of older workers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A94F9822195406BA4123BDC3D703665"><enum>(2)</enum><text>combat structural ageism;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3770E0768BE452C89FC518AFA6A5BDB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve employment opportunities for older workers; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1BAA0C32D2A4265961BEFF3377C77D5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>create a more diverse and inclusive workplace.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H07D4DEB48E734799836453EC8F0B9DE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to a covered institution that is located in an area that has no training programs specifically targeted to disadvantaged older workers.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H32C445204C1A4349B3A7DC673DD3708D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered institutions defined</header><text>For the purposes of this section, the term <term>covered institution</term> means any of the following:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H7764E2FCDEE14CCB8241C4332E89FAD4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An employer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H557348966B3D402694CB963BD0E05AD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An employer association.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H22C8F84094BF4E14A6B47696D69485BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A labor organization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3AE9A8A8544B40AEBA195F9C07166A99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A nonprofit with expertise in older workers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H438B2EED4E844FA09848D6C0213C0D54"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A worker organization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HEB1904639FEA421BA6E2D9F8967EA3E7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Another institution determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5FA7E86C92CB4A0C92F7847ECB7868AA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To carry out sections 5 and 6, there is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2027.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

