<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H91F9970CFF7643E99A292A9F73FBCE88" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7664 IH: State Partnerships to Enhance Removal of Criminal Aliens Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7664</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260224">February 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for the performance of certain Department of Homeland Security counsel functions by State officers and employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5418EA6EE9A84E1D8A8BD02E2191FDF6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H553F774F45764311AA8828FDF50F2330" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Partnerships to Enhance Removal of Criminal Aliens Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H759E02BF47A4426588A3E2B11986914F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Performance of certain Department of Homeland Security counsel functions by State officers and employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE99B6DD49FDD42CB9E9AACE128BE916D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (i); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45E89D929D6F4D4E909E126DCDAF7057"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting the following after subsection (g):</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB57F46927B0D4C7295BDC4659E88C204" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HBD64413A7D884295A4483EA66ED72B53"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Performance of certain Department of Homeland Security counsel functions by State officers and employees</header> 
<paragraph id="H80FF4B599A0C47EDB808F1B68E5BDAE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Attorney General, may enter into a written agreement with a State pursuant to which an officer or employee of the State, who is a licensed attorney and who is determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security to be qualified to perform the function of an Office of the Principal Legal Advisor attorney in representing the Department of Homeland Security in removal proceedings described in paragraph (9), may carry out such function at the expense of the State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCFBABD8CEDB40208B9D93D3ECCC863A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An agreement under this subsection shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4DEB93604DDA4F6EB01CBABDA6A9CE34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require that an officer or employee of a State performing a function under the agreement have knowledge of, and adhere to, Federal law relating to the function;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAFD3E8A05AAA4D82A0DFC8B31CF85324"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contain a written certification that the officers or employees of a State performing the function under the agreement have received adequate training regarding the enforcement of relevant Federal immigration laws; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74A7A15EC8474365910B1968DF3FEA35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>state that an officer or employee of a State performing a function under the agreement has no independent prosecutorial or policymaking discretion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FD37992F0654202BD3D50C250CDEAD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In performing a function under this subsection, an officer or employee of a State shall be subject to the direction and supervision of the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H397430D44B624F968BE393006D218C6D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In performing a function under this subsection, an officer or employee of a State may use Federal property or facilities, as provided in a written agreement between the Secretary and the State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FD1C0939A6048BDA5C52D392FD14D7A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>With respect to each officer or employee of a State who is authorized to perform a function under this subsection, the specific powers and duties that may be, or are required to be, exercised or performed by the individual, the duration of the authority of the individual, and the position of the agency of the Secretary of Homeland Security who is required to supervise and direct the individual, shall be set forth in a written agreement between the Secretary of Homeland Security and the State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A3E3577439443ABAAA3BF1EEE62784C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not accept a service under this subsection if the service will be used to displace any Federal employee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H224DF013135F4222819832917EE48CEA"> <enum>(7)</enum> <text>Except as provided in paragraph (8), an officer or employee of a State performing functions under this subsection shall not be treated as a Federal employee for any purpose other than for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5 (relating to compensation for injury) and sections 2671 through 2680 of title 28, United States Code (relating to tort claims).</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4360C143EC0F43E78EDE9FDFF4AA1148"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An officer or employee of a State acting under color of authority under this subsection, or any agreement entered into under this subsection, shall be considered to be acting under color of Federal authority for purposes of determining the liability, and immunity from suit, of the officer or employee in a civil action brought under Federal, State, local, or tribal law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H902D38226E1B40F2AF2643ED2931BC34"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The removal proceedings described in paragraph (1) are proceedings under—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB46998BC70964C05AF0D8C664F06155C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 238 if the alien is located in a Federal, State, or local correctional facility in the State with which the Secretary of Homeland Security has entered into a written agreement described in this section; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H94B5D22C4F85498BBB73D288D98F6F65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 240 if—</text> 
<clause id="H6B6BAA19CFC145078B955CE6E429B6E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the alien is charged with a ground of inadmissibility under section 212(a) or a ground of deportability under section 237(a) that is based on a violation of State law, to the extent the Secretary of Homeland Security has entered into a written agreement described in this section with that State; or</text></clause> <clause id="HA5EBD8A5B29E41BB8A5733F1B7E85899"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the alien’s eligibility for immigration relief may be affected by such a violation of State law, to the extent the Secretary of Homeland Security has entered into a written agreement described in this section with that State.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7A03F7CF5D33417385EADEDC9920C9A7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Aggravated felony</header> 
<subsection id="H2467CA60B11D42C08BF6848E5C43CDDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (43) of section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(43)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H34C741B347564AF2A84B5F7E4B6180B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>minor</quote> and inserting <quote>minor, or an offense involving any of the preceding offenses</quote>;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB6FB303F2A1442E5AE41D8F8D386C3E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1380173565CC428BBCF1A2D7A4ECCB86" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H42F5324D879747CB8136E1186D8D1D85"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an offense involving—</text> 
<clause id="H3ED580693B11490C8AA9260753A72943"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">illicit trafficking in a controlled substance (as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act), including a drug trafficking crime (as defined in section 924(c) of title 18, United States Code); or</text></clause> <clause id="H7B3D17B1C3E446AF8956FCBDB988BA57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other crime classified as a felony in the jurisdiction of conviction, or punishable by a maximum term of imprisonment of more than 1 year in the jurisdiction of conviction, involving—</text> 
<subclause id="H43E35E3C894341A69CF2B87C42939D58"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an offense under State, local, or tribal law, a substance that is classified as a controlled substance under such law, as applicable, regardless of whether the substance is a controlled substance (as defined in section 102 of such Act); or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4BEB5BD989AB4E84B3D02F8A86257F60"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an offense under Federal law or foreign law, a controlled substance (as defined in section 102 of such Act);</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26E5278FABCE40DE9AABF49007EB1A64"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote>an offense involving</quote> before <quote>illicit trafficking in firearms</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E958DD651AB4BEC8FD134C8B775568D" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE853337BB0EB49F7B6EEA025F0CE67B2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CCEBF7B1B62494DA11629DFABD577C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iii) as clause (iv); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56AD46A5306A4B0D8A37103664C8F7B1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (ii) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5438C427E1AF4DAAA39783E902BAA26E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HF4F8D2D587F047658E307A2FA0FE56E5" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sections 932 and 933 of title 18 (relating to straw purchasing of firearms and trafficking in firearms); or</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2B3B6CBF99F4196B049734B10BD9E48"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>or 2252</quote> and inserting <quote>2252, or 2252A</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD65FD014513C443D8A395169B14968BA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (F) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCD5119B35466428C9384DAE48C5A80E3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HE2462F9CDE9A4DD1B4151EF493FE47C5"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an offense that is—</text> <clause id="H9E475A874BDA45C4B4D6D9DE6C0AEA1A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a crime of violence (as defined in section 16 of title 18, United States Code, but not including a purely political offense) for which the term of imprisonment is at least one year;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF9EBB387B70B4260864FF343FDD2587C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any crime, for which the term of imprisonment is at least one year, where evidence establishes the circumstances of the crime as actually committed by the alien involved the use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force against the person or property of another; </text></clause> <clause id="H9EDC9BCB3E0C4E5A89F4FFD8CBCA17CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assault, battery, or robbery, as defined under the jurisdiction of conviction, for which the term of imprisonment is at least one year; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H33CD6C6361C54F8F8A00538791482933"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>described in section 2119 of title 18, United States Code (relating to carjacking);</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCDA0D28EE624E5FAF6A2F837987943D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (G) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H39520C633E2045A19632347A25A5EE4D" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HEFAAE51C51D2428D84DDF97B34E34748" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum> 
<clause id="H2D435CC8971141B1B14D64357E55089F" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an offense involving burglary (regardless of whether a structure was involved) or theft (including theft by deceit, theft by fraud, embezzlement, or receipt, possession, or use of stolen property), regardless of whether any taking was temporary or permanent, for which the term of imprisonment is at least one year; or </text></clause> <clause id="H92CDB5F61F504C1BBDBCCD635EAC4AD8" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any crime, for which the term of imprisonment is at least one year, where evidence establishes the circumstances of the crime as actually committed by the alien was an offense involving burglary (regardless of whether a structure was involved) or theft (including theft by deceit, theft by fraud, embezzlement, or receipt, possession, or use of stolen property), regardless of whether any taking was temporary or permanent;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H204D63696F594450A03708D0B691DD89"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in subparagraph (N)—</text> <subparagraph id="H81DBC4E2BE474681AAA20B81E0427BCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>paragraph (1)(A) or (2) of</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H40F800BC10EA4DCFAB14BB473C4BA989"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting a semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H912829B11DBE4D60A3F3430136CD387B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in subparagraph (O), by striking <quote>section 275(a) or 276 committed by an alien who was previously deported on the basis of a conviction for an offense described in another subparagraph of this paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>section 275 or 276 for which the term of imprisonment is at least 1 year</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C38F2CC62674371873D1F7B21456EAE"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in subparagraph (P)—</text> <subparagraph id="H933F86533DD447FD9193695A401F4B11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(i) which either is falsely making, forging, counterfeiting, mutilating, or altering a passport or instrument in violation of section 1543 of title 18, United States Code, or is described in section 1546(a) of such title (relating to document fraud) and (ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>described in any section of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CD3D2AE974C4E14AAD273E93CEC7861"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, except in the case of a first offense for which the alien has affirmatively shown that the alien committed the offense for the purpose of assisting, abetting, or aiding only the alien’s spouse, child, or parent (and no other individual) to violate a provision of this Act</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H328BDFB318144D67A55C8CCABA14149B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>in subparagraph (T), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FD1A0803B4E4501B5FA0EB7D443FFE9"><enum>(12)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (U); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6DBCAE6B8754742A5629AC35B7ABF71"><enum>(13)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H667771BC74FC4058BDC3855F62EFA4F8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H07C97B8DA1824B9389B5361FD709B1EE"><enum>(U)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an offense described in—</text> <clause id="H330E90197B7B49289A547968C9717200"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 2441 of title 18, United States Code (relating to war crimes);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H40E53F53B51843ECB8831F2B4E597E2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 2340A of title 18, United States Code (relating to torture);</text></clause> <clause id="HEA8426C161364A1491BA607B19A9B475"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1091 of title 18, United States Code (relating to genocide); or </text></clause> 
<clause id="H6AD1FC05DC604A7DA9DF24184F445D40"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 2442 of title 18, United States Code (relating to use and recruitment of child soldiers); </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C49B9EEA5D54C85AC5253EB8334DC92" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any offense not otherwise listed in this paragraph that is—</text> 
<clause id="HAD84F8CE0FB84398BEFC98C7218F56A7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>defined as a felony by the jurisdiction of conviction; or</text></clause> <clause id="H67F927AD4F184A3B90BE1236B6D3ADD3" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>punishable by a maximum term of imprisonment of more than 1 year; and </text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H17C6373874C24AA7B091590F2311EDF4"><enum>(W)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an offense, either classified in the jurisdiction of conviction as or consisting of, a conspiracy, attempt, or solicitation to commit an offense described in this paragraph, or aiding, abetting, counseling, procuring, commanding, or inducing the commission of such an offense. </text></subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HB100A4645B7247ACAFB10495F6614E7A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inadmissibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 212(a)(2)(A)(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H47F2CEBEEE134339B930C0F47C523B8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00C349B53D99477AA591D6E91AE2EE30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECD09AAEED634475BCC5A446E5F5EE0D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subclause (II) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCC3A27BF87B54292823F0D05F2F3CE1B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subclause id="H8B0A624FB550487F87800DBD20D5748C"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an aggravated felony,</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7C6F8C4182E042AEB157ACDBB1F9346A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H900C34AD6FA740C2993291B0FCD8BE48"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 208(b)(2)(B)(i), by adding after the period the following <quote>An alien may be determined to have been convicted of a particularly serious crime even if the alien’s conviction does not constitute an aggravated felony.</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H464A1C7F829543429088B8F41FDF91E6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 238(a)(1), by striking <quote>for aliens convicted of any criminal offense covered in</quote> and all that follows through <quote>otherwise covered by section 241(a)(2)(A)(i)</quote> and inserting <quote>for aliens convicted of any criminal offense covered in section 237(a)(2)</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8B510DBD9A14284BC8C4A99DDD1F9DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 241(b)(3)(B), in the matter following clause (iv), by striking <quote>For purposes of clause (ii), an alien who has been convicted of an aggravated felony (or felonies) for which the alien has been sentenced to an aggregate term of imprisonment of at least 5 years shall be considered to have committed a particularly serious crime. The previous sentence shall not preclude the Attorney General from determining that, notwithstanding the length of sentence imposed, an alien has been convicted of a particularly serious crime.</quote> and inserting <quote>For purposes of clause (ii), an alien who has been convicted of an aggravated felony shall be considered to have been convicted of a particularly serious crime. The Attorney General and Secretary of Homeland Security may jointly designate, by regulation, offenses that will be considered to be a crime described in clause (ii) or (iii). An alien may be determined to have been convicted of a particularly serious crime without regard to whether the offense for which the alien was convicted is an aggravated felony or an offense designated under the previous sentence.</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H413A7F30FA234C888440DF5390758AB9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 242(a)(2)(C), by striking <quote>237(a)(2)(A)(iii)</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>section 237(a)(2)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6DEFE327E11244618896E71D213B9C54"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall apply with respect to the commission of an offense before, on, or after the date of enactment of this section, and with respect to removal proceedings commenced before, on, or after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HFB068E87D2624BE583DA34DE044420B3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or any amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision to any person, entity, government, or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, or any amendment made thereby, or the application of such provision to all other persons, entities, governments, or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

