<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBDABBC507DEE433682D9D2C5E4B29E93" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9534 IH: Wildfire Response Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9534</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260629">June 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Air Force to procure space-based commercial data and end products to support the efforts of the Department of Defense and the wildfire mission of the United States Northern Command.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H83688A9250444D6D861EC92EBF2813A3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H849154BE9E684C01A46A885FDCC3975C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Response Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H54414F14D6E7487EB74D2117B59E8BAB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Procurement of commercial space-based data to support wildfire resilience</header> <subsection id="H09A9C5EEAC154AA2AB4D118941DC47FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Procurement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, the Secretary of the Air Force, acting through the Commercial Space Office and in coordination with the FireGuard program of the National Guard and the Commander of the United States Northern Command, shall procure space-based commercial data and end products to support the efforts of the Department of Defense and the wildfire mission of the United States Northern Command by delivering timely, effective military support to the Federal Government and State, local, and Tribal governments to protect military readiness and installations, provide emergency military support to civil authorities, and conduct proactive wildland fire management.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2E88B6810866443B920AC048D6D4E8D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorized sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may share space-based commercial data and end products procured under subsection (a) with State, local, and Tribal governments to assist with firefighting efforts.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

