<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB8E06A1C24104A29AB1D62D13DBB6A55" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1116 IH: Commemorating the 5-year remembrance of the March 16, 2021, shootings in the Atlanta, Georgia, region and denouncing continuing anti-Asian hate, including the resurgence of xenophobic and anti-immigrant rhetoric.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1116</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260316">March 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the 5-year remembrance of the March 16, 2021, shootings in the Atlanta, Georgia, region and denouncing continuing anti-Asian hate, including the resurgence of xenophobic and anti-immigrant rhetoric.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on March 16, 2021, a shooter murdered 8 people and injured 1 person in the Atlanta, Georgia, region in 3 separate shootings that took place at Asian-owned spas;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the victims included—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1ED5DD4CC0EE4613A5966BD1B85C60DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Xiaojie <quote>Emily</quote> Tan;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08CDCB594479465E98B9401F71651A8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Daoyou Feng;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF07EBFA20F5B47B3AC5D9B7E3468051E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Delaina Ashley Yaun;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8971C2E656964F69B0971BE88C89B315"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Paul Andre Michels;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCFEFA1F70F3B4176BAC2856408A2F31D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Yong Ae Yue;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC974139556AE4CD88BCEB1D9DC1EF69F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Soon Chung <quote>Julie</quote> Park;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AF6417FF31743F8AB424CBF05F641E0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Hyun Jung Grant; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F0C07D7D3F443FBA6C18345F38F495F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Sun Cha Kim;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 2026 marks the fifth year since the loss of these innocent lives, 7 of whom were women, 6 of whom were women of Asian descent, and several of whom were immigrants;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas communities continue to grapple with grief, trauma, and the long-term mental-health impacts of anti-Asian hate, and require access to culturally responsive mental health services, trauma-informed care, and language-accessible support services to heal and rebuild;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas the Atlanta spa shootings occurred amid an alarming surge in anti-Asian hate crimes and incidents nationwide fueled by the use of anti-Asian rhetoric that scapegoated Asian Americans for the COVID–19 pandemic;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas the use of rhetoric that portrays Asian countries, and by extension, Asian nationals or those of Asian descent, as enemies of the United States continues to contribute to the scapegoating of innocent Asian Americans;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas such rhetoric exists in the context of historic and ongoing discriminatory policies, including alien land laws and other measures that have targeted Asian communities, like the so-called China Initiative;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the latest Federal hate crime statistics for 2024 show that anti-Asian hate crimes were nearly 3 times higher than the prepandemic average and anti-Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander hate crimes were at the highest number ever recorded since the Federal Bureau of Investigation began disaggregating this category in 2013, confirming persistent risk, underreporting, and ongoing community harm;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas language access barriers, immigration status concerns, and fear of law enforcement or deportation can contribute to underreporting of hate crimes and limit access to services for survivors;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas 40 percent of Americans believe that Asian Americans are more loyal to their countries of origin than to the United States, a belief that has doubled since 2021, compounding suspicions of dual loyalty that perpetuate the narrative that Asian Americans are foreigners in their own home;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Asian-American women have been historically marginalized and faced specific threats of violence linked to misogynistic narratives and sexual objectification;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas anti-Asian hate remains elevated and increasingly intersects with xenophobic, anti-immigrant, and anti-Asian narratives, particularly in online spaces, and is more frequently directed at South Asian communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas community reports and media accounts underscore that anti-immigrant rhetoric and disinformation portraying Asian immigrants as economic or security threats continue to fuel hostility and can translate into real-world intimidation and violence; and</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander communities have contributed immeasurably to the cultural, civic, scientific, and economic life of the United States, and deserve safety, dignity, and equal protection under the law: Now, therefore, be it</text>
    </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF9DEC75B56B24BDBAE35F40E2B199CAA"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC4417F421A034D548D4113F4BBABE2E2"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H40C54009031B4E75936D09040F782F51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the heinous acts of gun violence on March 16, 2021, and the racism and sexism reflected in the shooter’s deliberate targeting of Asian-owned businesses and the murder of 7 women;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H361FFDEA3B544ECE83DE2B5490670759"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the memory of the victims and offers heartfelt condolences to their families, loved ones, and the communities forever changed by this tragedy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3F617567818489B9CE25C675302182D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the importance of addressing anti-Asian hate at all levels of government and improving hate crime reporting infrastructure that builds upon the implementation of the COVID–19 Hate Crimes Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/13">Public Law 117–13</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7473EA8D79E4AE28D2B69711AD6D746"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls for the restoration and expansion of the Department of Justice’s Bureau of Justice Assistance Programs, COVID–19 Hate Crimes Act programs, Jabara-Heyer NO HATE Act programs, and other community-based approaches to prevent and combat hate crimes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC127BFF2DB67489BA1D3CE5764B2866C"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages efforts to combat online hate and disinformation and to promote education on Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander history and antibias practices in both K–12 and postsecondary educational institutions; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF027E8EEA4CC4970A5BF7A15DA433BC5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>reaffirms the commitment of the Federal Government to protect the civil and human rights of all people in the United States and ensure that communities can live free from fear and violence.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

