<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H44D273DC18AD401CA6D3887E60A84E9B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7625 IH: Marine Transportation System Cybersecurity Budget and Evaluation Report Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7625</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a review of the budget, resources, and capabilities of the Coast Guard as the co-Sector Risk Management Agency for the marine transportation system.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB9DB28C5CC2443BCA53C60DD789E5D8D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2C2768F95601462DA1C183578A893F54" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Marine Transportation System Cybersecurity Budget and Evaluation Report Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MTS CYBER Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H973B489B1F2E4427AC880E81F7D01C79"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAE2876AA74754B0B8E6310A2112465EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Maritime trade is essential to America’s economic stability, supporting $2,100,000,000,000 in economic activity, or 41.5 percent of the global trade value of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3FC1FB631284C748982EB013F4D4FD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The increasing frequency and severity of cyber threats to the marine transportation system (hereinafter referred to as <quote>MTS</quote>) presents economic and national security risks.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE5F45B878F8481DA6DC6EA37E69C14E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Transportation are designated as co-Sector Risk Management Agencies (hereinafter referred to as <quote>SRMAs</quote>) for the MTS under Presidential Policy Directive 21, with further delegation of responsibilities to agencies such as the Coast Guard and the Transportation Security Administration as outlined in implementing documents.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84D42B994B5847CD9B86F10B4E78B066"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Executive Order 14116, issued by President Biden in February 2024, expands the United States Coast Guard’s regulatory authorities to strengthen MTS cybersecurity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC37F1F623B9140438B73BDD1FFA2BB52"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Coast Guard issued a final cybersecurity rule, <quote>Cybersecurity in the Marine Transportation System</quote>, establishing mandatory incident reporting for regulated entities, significantly expanding the Coast Guard’s cybersecurity oversight responsibilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73BD519C0006424189EDCA1643A3F298"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Through the Investing in America Agenda, the Biden administration dedicated $20,000,000,000 for United States port infrastructure, but it fails to specify cybersecurity-specific spending allocations to provide the Coast Guard with adequate resources and funding.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20AE5CAB06744389AFBB4250BA940530"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Coast Guard remains underfunded and understaffed for the purpose of sector risk management.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H679F26FE44F34B22B96B528C54C8292E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The ability of the Coast Guard to fulfill SRMA duties is contingent upon adequate budgetary resources and a healthy workforce.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H187B5CE827604517A1B0BAB7C02A730B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A Government Accountability Office audit is necessary to assess the budget and capabilities of the Coast Guard as an SRMA to ensure it can fulfill responsibilities for protecting the MTS against cyber threats.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H9ABF3E9BF8644F3C8715D05B408F80D7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coast Guard Sector Risk Management Agency budget and capabilities review</header> <subsection id="H59C84506AA574052884443E301CB2EE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>GAO review</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review to assess the funding and resource needs of the Coast Guard to fulfill the SRMA responsibilities of the Coast Guard, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1285A6919C5E427BBB4BF869D21314F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the sufficiency of Coast Guard funding for the sector risk management responsibilities, including funding for cybersecurity personnel, training, and enforcement, in light of statutory requirements under section 9002 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 and additional requirements in Presidential Policy Directive 21;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2809CC4D2B1840FBB37E751F5000D0A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the ability of Coast Guard personnel to evaluate compliance with cybersecurity requirements for regulated entities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81EA826492D6426BB21F8F340968770D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the sufficiency of guidance provided to industry stakeholders on implementing and complying with cyber regulations, assessed against applicable statutory requirements, Federal regulatory benchmarks, and widely recognized industry best practices for maritime cybersecurity.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H85809340844D4F3887D6326EF49E8360"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Comptroller General shall submit the findings and recommendations from the review required under subsection (a) to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7059B4340B3A4EFE8E4EC3BBF129DE57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DEAC85C762543778FEF67AB66CB3D1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HFA5466679B354C9599C8DB876D09B4A6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H20AABD13269049299E0275670B9CE033"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Marine transportation system</header><text>The term <term>marine transportation system</term> means navigable waterways, ports, terminals, intermodal connections, vessels, and related infrastructure that facilitate the movement of goods and people by water.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70E85563E264405396E2B9EACC693385"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sector Risk Management Agency; SRMA</header><text>The term <term>Sector Risk Management Agency</term> or <quote>SRMA</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>Sector Risk Management Agency</quote> in section 2200 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/650">6 U.S.C. 650</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

