<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25M10-1YW-HY-XTG">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3167 IS: No Troops in Our Streets Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3167</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms.
                    Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, and
                    <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill;
                which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To provide for appropriate limitations on military deployments, and for
            other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="S1" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Troops in Our Streets Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="idae71934c13dd460baeb66e50356507c0">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Termination authority for posse comitatus exceptions</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1385 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb96c1ff77327410da5f2562ed0f1d35e">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>Whoever</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">In general</header-in-text>.—Whoever</quote>; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf86fe6743e96439587f41e485b38cfe0">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29f81df777c54df69021688a4af4087e"> <subsection id="id79ea99d828fa44e19ea585af5d51afbb"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Congressional authority To terminate</header> <text>Congress may terminate any exception to subsection (a) at any time by enacting a joint resolution of disapproval as described under subsection (c).</text>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="idc94eec9407a446d99a3b40d68e4761f4" commented="no">
                        <enum>(c)</enum>
                        <header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header>
                        <paragraph id="idf9f93e178b164a2687ca5501dfce7205" commented="no">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>In this subsection, the term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means only a joint resolution of either House of Congress—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="id9f0293975a9343d8992410cc36df54ce" commented="no">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>A joint resolution expressing congressional disapproval of the deployment of Armed Forces in [_____].</quote>, with the blank space being filled with the location prohibited; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id73ba053a4cdb41b698ab9f6acd7036a6" commented="no">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is the following: <quote>Congress prohibits the deployment of Armed Forces under title [___], United States Code, with respect to [_____] in [_____] for [____].</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with the title under which authority to send troops was provided, the second blank space being filled with a short description of the military actions prohibited, the third blank space being filled with the location where the deployment is prohibited, and the fourth blank space being filled with the duration of the prohibition.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id051698458d67485393c633b16bfb20f0" commented="no">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Introduction</header>
 <text>A joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced—</text> <subparagraph id="ide117d42976bc4155a5153748d99c890b" commented="no"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in the Senate, by the majority leader (or the majority leader’s designee) or the minority leader (or the minority leader’s designee); and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idcf04c29f213745c591270de002389f73" commented="no">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in the House of Representatives, by the Speaker of the House or the minority leader.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id421df605f9bb4caa9bb8d8fe8a969d3c" commented="no">
                            <enum>(3)</enum>
                            <header>Consideration in the Senate</header>
                            <subparagraph id="id529c836de4f84567a62c180aca1cd8b5" commented="no">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
                                <header>Committee referral</header>
 <text>A joint resolution of disapproval introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id08fd97ca472e48a3a97783f75390d1ad" commented="no">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
                                <header>Reporting and discharge</header>
 <text>If the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate has not reported a joint resolution of disapproval within 5 calendar days after the date of referral of the joint resolution, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id57af3afc75d54e5b99392b2b790347fc" commented="no">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
                                <header>Proceeding to consideration</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after the Committee on Armed Services reports a joint resolution of disapproval to the Senate or has been discharged from consideration of such a joint resolution (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) are waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id735b9561e66c49d3a8222d66c0bc0ad6" commented="no">
                                <enum>(D)</enum>
                                <header>Rulings of the chair on procedure</header>
 <text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to a joint resolution of disapproval shall be decided without debate.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id05d34402eb1c4d7d894674e4944d0740" commented="no">
                                <enum>(E)</enum>
                                <header>Consideration of veto messages</header>
 <text>Debate in the Senate of any veto message with respect to a joint resolution of disapproval, including all debatable motions and appeals in connection with the joint resolution, shall be limited to 10 hours, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader or their designees.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id6ac3343eadf14091be071ae31ed5d6e2" commented="no">
                                <enum>(F)</enum>
                                <header>Floor consideration in the House of Representatives</header>
 <text>If a committee of the House of Representatives to which a joint resolution of disapproval has been referred has not reported the joint resolution within 5 calendar days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id9606f881e7934f93aae627ca182b947b" commented="no">
                            <enum>(4)</enum>
                            <header>Rules relating to the Senate and the House of
                                Representatives</header>
                            <subparagraph id="id20b4392d67e3493782dca9db2e6a8f8d" commented="no">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
                                <header>Treatment of House of Representatives joint resolution in
                                    Senate</header>
                                <clause id="idc18d6109de1848c9b0667f0e09ed0efb" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                                    <header>Receipt before passage of Senate resolution</header>
 <text>If, before the passage by the Senate of a joint resolution of disapproval, the Senate receives an identical joint resolution from the House of Representatives, the following procedures shall apply:</text>
                                    <subclause id="idac73c3b0c67a45f580cb00e6b65569d4"
                                        commented="no">
                                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>That joint resolution shall not be referred to a committee.</text>
                                    </subclause>
                                    <subclause id="id039e23eaa3534b7a92903d9a27ee8014"
                                        commented="no">
                                        <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>With respect to that joint resolution—</text> <item id="id9ad6f23a419241ee9cbb3adfe22580a2" commented="no"> <enum>(aa)</enum> <text>the procedure in the Senate shall be the same as if no joint resolution had been received from the House of Representatives; but</text>
                                        </item>
                                        <item id="id07eeff93d9fc4272b822c89a2ec8e35b" commented="no">
                                            <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text>the vote on passage shall be on the joint resolution from the House of Representatives.</text>
                                        </item>
                                    </subclause>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id582c04ca50e04dbc8d51fd353f9d1ed8" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                                    <header>Receipt following passage of Senate resolution</header>
 <text>If, following passage of a joint resolution of disapproval in the Senate, the Senate receives an identical joint resolution from the House of Representatives, that joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate Senate calendar.</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id56096af3ac5b4a8e8209c9e476164cf4" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
                                    <header>No companion resolution</header>
 <text>If a joint resolution of disapproval is received from the House of Representatives, and no companion joint resolution has been introduced in the Senate, the Senate procedures under this subparagraph shall apply to the House of Representatives joint resolution.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id5c7d5c7749c844daa6555d03b6dc839f" commented="no">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
                                <header>Treatment of Senate joint resolution in House of
                                    Representatives</header>
 <text>In the House of Representatives, the following procedures shall apply to a joint resolution of disapproval received from the Senate (unless the House of Representatives has already passed a joint resolution relating to the same proposed action):</text>
                                <clause id="idb6829fa5c4944093885756dfdbe3b810" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>The joint resolution shall be referred to the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id64b3df806d7846cdaf9b8af7f1e9f966" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>If the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives has not reported the joint resolution within two calendar days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution.</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id58bc88bcf9fc4e3dbc220bb77526f733" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Beginning on the third legislative day after the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives reports the joint resolution to the House of Representatives or has been discharged from further consideration thereof, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House of Representatives. All points of order against the motion are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House of Representatives has disposed of a motion to proceed on the joint resolution. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id9c50ce5353d24d85bcfdf94d5b43fbd5" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except two hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall not be in order.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="id2ab5195888f047c492a6083869e0f267" commented="no">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
                                <header>Inapplicability to revenue measure in House of
                                    Representatives</header>
 <text>The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply in the House of Representatives to a joint resolution of disapproval that is a revenue measure.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idce18790fc8b44cb09d78ea057c9200ed" commented="no">
                                <enum>(D)</enum>
                                <header>Rules of Senate and House of Representatives</header>
 <text>This paragraph is enacted by Congress—</text> <clause id="iddcff54c08a814bf1804528c7548835ec" commented="no"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="idcb402f8cd6494435b44135a743dade32" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id39b4998de13c4cc59a235f912f8a2042">
                            <enum>(5)</enum>
                            <header>Congressional intent</header>
 <text>If a joint resolution of disapproval with respect to the deployment of the Armed Forces in a particular location is not introduced or enacted, no court or agency may infer any intent of Congress from any action or inaction of Congress with regard to such joint resolution of disapproval.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="idcc126c7888cb49ca9a8c9c76c97bbdd0">
                        <enum>(d)</enum>
                        <header>Severability</header>
 <text>If any provision of this section, or any application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this section and the application of this section to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text>
                    </subsection>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id1769f513042d4460aec5c35644dced23">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Termination authority for section 12406 activations</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12406 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54139b28f57a45caa6e4b18e6d5e1245">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>Whenever—</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">In general</header-in-text>.—Whenever</quote>; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ef56e056eaa465b9fb7c9cf90b2b966">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb82d5d13f2b04c389479c84fae15931d">
                    <subsection id="id6836aa1ff6fa4846b463edf5f587a87f">
                        <enum>(b)</enum>
                        <header>Congressional authority To terminate</header>
 <text>Congress may terminate any activation pursuant to subsection (a) at any time by enacting a joint resolution of disapproval.</text>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="id667c14b4c4ef46aea86f37357dc87932">
                        <enum>(c)</enum>
                        <header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> has the meanings given such term under subsection (c) of section 1385 of title 18.</text>
                    </subsection>
                    <subsection id="id7dc560ebeb024919aa528a4998a7fbdc">
                        <enum>(d)</enum>
                        <header>Severability</header>
 <text>If any provision of this section, or any application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this section and the application of this section to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text>
                    </subsection>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
        <section id="id50f81e73efa54a3b8907f15f00b48f2a">
            <enum>4.</enum>
            <header>Funding for State and local law enforcement</header>
            <subsection id="id3dda68ff10934139a42230165e8fd55a">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>In addition to amounts otherwise appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for fiscal year 2026, for <quote>Department of Justice—State and Local Law Enforcement Activities—Office of Justice Programs—State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance</quote>, there is appropriated—</text>
                <paragraph id="idb0f07b1ddcc14e47a4a6a51b0afe4f82">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>$600,000,000, to remain available until expended, for the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program as authorized by subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>) (except that section 1001(c), and the special rules for Puerto Rico under section 505(g), of title I of that Act shall not apply for purposes of this Act);</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id7523c3d37073490fae5f40fefa290c87">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>$150,000,000, to remain available until expended, for a community violence intervention and prevention initiative; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id716221b0dbcf4f44be5de957a7257b79">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>$50,000,000, to remain available until expended, for emergency law enforcement assistance, as authorized by section 609M of the Justice Assistance Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/50101">34 U.S.C. 50101</external-xref>), to support any of the purposes specified in section 501 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10152">34 U.S.C. 10152</external-xref>), of which the President may direct not greater than $10,000,000 per law enforcement emergency, as defined in section 609N of the Justice Assistance Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/50102">34 U.S.C. 50102</external-xref>), with the approval of the chief executive of the State and locality, to support State and local law enforcement.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idf1daa42a598049c98bd2f5f4240c3ef4">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Community-Oriented policing hiring</header>
 <text>In addition to amounts otherwise appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for fiscal year 2026, there is appropriated $100,000,000, to remain available until expended, for grants for the hiring and rehiring of additional career law enforcement officers under section 1701 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381</external-xref>).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id0af69b1937924192ae604d7462e5d9ce">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Prohibition</header>
 <text>None of the amounts made available under this section may be used to fund the assignment of Federal law enforcement personnel to States and localities.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id24a410e5282c4e9d8ed616bf4b8a4cd5">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Emergency designation</header>
 <text>Amounts appropriated under subsections (a) and (b) are designated by Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 4001(a)(1) of S. Con. Res. 14 (117th Congress), the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2022, and to legislation establishing fiscal year 2026 budget enforcement in the House of Representatives.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

