<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WAL25668-08H-JJ-CYW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3289 IS: Crime Gun Tracing Modernization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3289</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251201">December 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend section 923 of title 18, United States Code, to require an electronic, searchable database of the importation, production, shipment, receipt, sale, or other disposition of firearms.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Crime Gun Tracing Modernization Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb5a74c26bfec404bab4f7fbec26b5460"><enum>2.</enum><header>Electronic, searchable databases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 923(g) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5425101327cf4abe83693553ee6e961d"><paragraph id="HA6BFFCD0148B4EB1A666CC2E1BF8C74E" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H71874DBD6D8D43D98DBCFF015B56BCE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>foreign intelligence information</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E03DBB670CE433B86CE48F399128762" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the National Tracing Center of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>National Tracing Center</quote>) shall establish and maintain electronic, searchable databases of all records within its possession of the importation, production, shipment, receipt, sale, or other disposition of firearms required to be submitted to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives by persons licensed under this chapter.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BB2774CCA6F433E9436EA420601D026" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Each licensee under this chapter may provide the National Tracing Center with electronic access, consistent with the requirements of this paragraph, to all records within the licensee’s possession that are required to be kept under this chapter.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1B7E405DE51411FA37DFAD1014DECCD" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A licensee may voluntarily relinquish possession of any non-electronic record required to be kept under this chapter to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives if—</text><clause id="H3E1BE88D944649CB97527212AA6A9F9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>10 years have elapsed from the date of the firearm transaction; or</text></clause><clause id="HECD385D11AE048519E68C51FBB3C5F99"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of paper acquisition and disposition books, 10 years have elapsed without any open disposition entries and with no dispositions recorded in the record.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9925481EC1B04F9BA9BF914CEC181CDC" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The National Tracing Center—</text><clause id="H1A9D08FB02C64A62AD81D438A20334AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall have remote access to and may query, search, or otherwise access the electronic databases described in this paragraph; and</text></clause><clause id="H0C31F3BBF3AD41C9A811938348AD3C46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may, with the permission of a State, or political subdivision of a State, have remote access to, and may query, search, or otherwise access the databases of the firearms registration system or pawnbroker records system of the State or political subdivision.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC45EE65E84394F53A328A441F6EBCB76" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The National Tracing Center may query, search, or otherwise access the electronic databases described in this paragraph for only the following purposes:</text><clause id="H3178FBFE45C14F1AAA4A48C95C1CF718"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To obtain information related to a bona fide law enforcement investigation by a Federal, State, local, Tribal, or foreign law enforcement agency.</text></clause><clause id="H89D96C1C95364C30A1CC449356A3B606"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>To obtain information that is—</text><subclause id="HDC3CAFFB744B4A70AB0A33243198B1D7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>foreign intelligence information; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HAA2DD3719AED44038CBC7A9C5A909A39"><enum>(II)</enum><text>necessary to understand, or to assess the importance of, foreign intelligence information.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H122F1146E092465D9FFD30F628524E65"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To obtain information necessary during a compliance inspection of an active licensee who has submitted non-electronic records in accordance with subparagraph (D).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBFE566EF5DC44398F157D703E67DF07" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The databases established under this paragraph—</text><clause id="HE013547F0BDD4B5DAE536BB806D9BC1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be electronically searchable by date of acquisition or disposition, license number, and the information identified on each firearm or other firearm descriptor, including the manufacturer, importer, model, serial number, type, and caliber or gauge;</text></clause><clause id="H424B63C3F00F464F8676844F3C9A0ACF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not be electronically searchable by the personally identifiable information of any individual; and</text></clause><clause id="H9054ED9DC6FE43C39BFA2434B244E37D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall include in search results the entire contents of the relevant records kept by the licensee.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H602DA903C1424BDD9DCAD726F54D2334" indent="up1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>This paragraph shall take effect notwithstanding any other provision of law, including any temporary or permanent restrictions placed on funds made available to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, or the Department of Justice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d8cdeb621c6419299de9ce27ce1ef44"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this paragraph, and every 2 years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d4f45268747458483bbdeca60ffe2f3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out an audit on compliance by the National Tracing Center and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives with the requirements of this paragraph; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69dee60bcf2840d88bc2467f5d509f3f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the audit carried out under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

