<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL26543-VJ0-L0-F1P"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 753 IS: Expressing the sense of the Senate to reduce traffic fatalities to zero by 2050.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 753</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate to reduce traffic fatalities to zero by 2050.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas roadway fatalities kill tens of thousands of people in the United States each year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (referred to in this preamble as <quote>NHTSA</quote>), 39,254 lives were lost in motor vehicle crashes in 2024, and all of the deaths were preventable;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, traffic crashes are a leading cause of death for people ages 1 to 54 and kill more than 100 people every day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, alcohol-impaired driving crashes are a leading killer on the roadways of the United States, with 11,904 lives lost to alcohol-impaired driving in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, 3,208 people died in motor vehicle crashes involving distracted drivers in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, 7,080 pedestrians were killed in traffic crashes in the United States in 2024, representing 14 percent of all motor vehicle crash fatalities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, the number of pedestrian fatalities increased by 78 percent since their lowest point in 2009;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, a total of 1,166 bicyclists were killed in crashes with motor vehicles in 2023, representing a 57 percent increase in the last 10 years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, 6,335 motorcyclists were killed in motor vehicle crashes in 2023, representing the deadliest year for motorcyclists since 1975;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, in 2023, 41 percent of motor vehicle traffic fatalities occurred on rural roads, despite only 31 percent of miles traveled occurring on rural roads;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Federal Highway Administration, adequately maintained retroreflective signs, pavement markings, and roadway lighting improve nighttime highway visibility and reduce the risk of crashes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Federal Highway Administration, 850 people died in work zone crashes in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, seatbelts have saved an estimated 374,276 lives from 1975 through 2017;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, in 2024, 48 percent of passenger vehicle occupants who died in a motor vehicle crash were unrestrained;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, 43 percent of crash fatalities initially survived the impact but later died, highlighting the importance of improving post-crash care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Insurance Institute for Highway Safety, increasing speed limits over the 25 year period of 1993 to 2017 led to approximately 36,760 deaths;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, speeding killed 11,775 people in 2023;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to Consumer Reports, existing safety technologies could cut road fatalities in half if such technologies were made standard on all vehicles, saving approximately 20,000 lives annually;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas roadway fatalities and injuries rose during the COVID–19 pandemic and remain a persistent cause of death in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the National Safety Council, medically consulted injuries in motor-vehicle crashes totaled 4,900,000 in 2024;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the National Safety Council, total motor-vehicle injury costs were estimated at $559,300,000,000;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, women sustain 46 percent higher injury risk than men in frontal crashes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to NHTSA, women sustain 55 percent higher injury risk than men in rollover crashes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas advanced vehicle and infrastructure technologies show promise in eliminating motor vehicles crashes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas better roadway fatality data collection could help drive better behavioral safety and infrastructure improvements;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas too many families in the United States have been personally affected by preventable crashes; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a data-driven safe systems approach is proven to be effective at reducing traffic fatalities and injuries, including through taking into account all aspects of the transportation environment and not requiring a single actor to be responsible for traffic safety: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body id="H03F8BFA3D71D44DD96F4BEB98F7BEADA"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id75136bbf23cb41aeaf97de8c24b659a4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commits to advancing policies that will end roadway fatalities by 2050;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4b8c8d6f056b468ea5e4ca43a7f40246"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on Congress and the Department of Transportation to commit to working together to achieve zero roadway fatalities by the year 2050;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ad33f7e226c45bb93d304b65cfea98c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports efforts to address disparities related to transportation safety;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id178a8d7d88194150b95d223a089de8a2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls on the Department of Transportation, and the agencies within the Department of Transportation, to improve data gathering and tracking of traffic crashes and other issues related to transportation safety;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03632dac976a4a8cbee68b03a646af9b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls on the Department of Transportation, and the agencies within the Department of Transportation, to commit to the implementation of proven countermeasures and interventions to prioritize transportation safety;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd93d6c63c07408c86e0313142891a1e"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recognizes the need for a safe system approach to transportation in the United States to improve access, safety, and mobility; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id25a70e9c76bf4213a3aa89fe2f18a91e"><enum>(7)</enum><text>supports the use of the term <term>crash</term>, instead of <term>accident</term>, when describing traffic incidents and encourages all agencies of the Federal Government to use this term.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

