<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E4C6C3294DA48EAB3ED95A028528180" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8813 IH: Supporting Survivors from Faith-based Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8813</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a grant program to support the establishment and operation of a national faith-based resource center on domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H429CF3B244F445AF9DB1324BCC6B0EDE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H600AFABF235249968D9740A51A140E5A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Survivors from Faith-based Communities Act</short-title></quote></text></section> <section id="H24CC4438635F4A3EAA4B3E84778612CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC19A4F55FBB24E72B1E21E449C9A3E89"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">41 percent of American women and 26.3 percent of American men experience, over their lifetimes, physical violence, sexual assault, or stalking by an intimate partner with associated impacts such as injury, post-traumatic stress disorder, the need for medical care, or law enforcement involvement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF52918FA67545EE863EAF9BE368BCBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Faith and faith communities often play a central role in the lives of individuals experiencing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, particularly in underserved or culturally specific populations. Faith and faith communities can be a source of strength and support for victims and survivors, and can improve survivors’ outcomes and resilience.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H607FDB810894446A9D92A0DFE5AF6F3B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Many survivors of domestic or sexual violence want to be able to talk about the faith or spiritual dimensions of their healing journey with advocates, yet it is rare for advocacy programs to take into account religious or spiritual concerns raised by survivors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H642C35CDCDF14A22B46FBACEB02583BE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Studies have found that spiritual and religious sources of resilience are common among survivors of domestic violence, sexual assault, and child abuse.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H799C3C3C16454E8BA53C361334B58926"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Clergy respondents have often reported that they have been approached by victims of domestic abuse and were often the first professional the survivor approached.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H777B11C6BD194328BB3688FBFD913A4A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Religious involvement can promote greater psychological well-being for domestic violence survivors, including a greater quality of life, and decreased depression.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H31FFB3A83FE145D683C34E1F2CDE8483"><enum>3.</enum><header>National resource center on domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking in faith communities</header> 
<subsection id="H5FFF029B74F54E4E808DB6255958275E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<paragraph id="H1AFA5E686C8845538893F79C760B725B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consortium of eligible entities</header><text>The term <term>consortium of eligible entities</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H87270068B4194877A86FC371B13C0898"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an agreement among three or more eligible entities to collaborate in carrying out the purposes of this section, including at least two faith-based organizations representing different underserved faith communities and one culturally specific organization; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H208B4931EAB8491DAD8838D3D0BD5753"><enum>(B)</enum><text>wherein at least one of the eligible entities of the consortium described in subparagraph (A) has previously completed not fewer than two grants administered by the Office on Violence Against Women as a lead applicant. </text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F428FC54C7A4DA4BE4303D8114AD8E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE3D0C6FE2D7A4E2D90885973AAC115C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> <clause id="H9DADD360E6B64C7EBEA18A00D3CE0CFC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a faith-based nonprofit, non-governmental organization with a demonstrated history of providing trauma-informed, victim-centered training and technical assistance about the needs and experiences of victims with faith, including a population-specific organization, culturally specific organization, or tribal organization; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC2E75160573848D38CC13AF613587160"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a non-faith-based culturally specific organization, including a tribal organization; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1438342DD6AF4936887604F2521BD780"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include any organization or subgrantee or contractor thereof that prioritizes family cohesion, marriage, family or community privacy, opposition to divorce, sexual purity, or other considerations over the safety, autonomy, needs, and preferences of victims.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">A history of providing faith-based marriage counseling shall not, by itself, qualify an organization as an eligible entity.</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9D4D038CA794E798026F9F24EE9BEC4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Faith community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>faith community</term> means a community of individuals who share a common religion or spiritual practice, including a denomination within a religion or culturally-based spiritual practice, a specific congregation, or a culturally-based spiritual community.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10882EDBFF0A4034BD0D7EB579AF7FFF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Faith institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>faith institution</term> means an organized entity within a religious community, such as a house of worship, denominational body, or other official structure of that community.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4239CD4A669740B1929A319EABB41167"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Religious divorce denial</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>religious divorce denial</term> means the refusal to cooperate in a religious divorce process or other religious marriage termination process, thereby preventing the victim from exiting the marriage despite any civil legal proceedings or civil legal judgment of divorce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2A4994B20C44EAE975C5ABF7DB60964"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Spiritual abuse</header><text>The term <term>spiritual abuse</term> means the use or manipulation of religion, religious law, sacred texts, or spiritual beliefs as a means of exerting coercive control or to justify domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8247ACBCE3164E6AB657835DEEE79BAC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Victim with faith</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>victim with faith</term> means a victim of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking who identifies with a faith or spiritual tradition, including identifying culturally with a faith or spiritual tradition, or holds religious or spiritual beliefs, whether or not they are officially affiliated with a faith community or institution or participate in religious observances.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2CF3A9DB737444EC98BF15246860328E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of provisions of VAWA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The definitions and grant conditions set forth in section 40002 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291</external-xref>) apply for purposes of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HEB445F98BDB6407880E28839C5F16B07"><enum>(c)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women, may award grants to a consortium of eligible entities in order to provide for the establishment and operation of a national faith-based resource center on domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. The resource center shall provide education, training, and technical assistance to faith communities, faith institutions, victim service providers, community-based and culturally specific organizations, and Federal, State, Tribal, and local agencies, and criminal and civil legal system stakeholders, and shall engage in other activities to—</text> <paragraph id="H35E35DB74E28418BB49BCBA1F0F3F4FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the response of victim service organizations, legal assistance providers, law enforcement, prosecutors, courts, child protective services, housing providers, and other stakeholders to victims with faith; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A749C250EFF42BDB8EC8086070567FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance the capacity of faith communities and faith institutions to prevent and respond to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE8C3FF2C33BC4B2194D45267CE78D123"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a consortium of eligible entities shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may require, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA25F6840B21C422288A4AD5C45FE7DE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information to demonstrate a collective history of providing training and technical assistance to one or more faith communities about trauma-informed, victim-centered prevention and responses to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA104A3380CDC49DF9D28CDC259605E58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information to demonstrate a collective history of providing training and technical assistance about one or more faith communities and the needs of victims with faith to mainstream victim service providers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3638BD18AA4C4E2E93A92FF7347DCD53"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an attestation that the safety and autonomy of victims with faith and their children are the primary priority of all consortium members, and consortium members, subgrantees, or contractors will not prioritize family cohesion, marriage, family or community privacy, opposition to divorce, sexual purity, or other considerations over the safety, autonomy, needs, and preferences of victims;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BB47377492A4753B7DB0BE4D30AE444"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a plan to engage with experts from faith communities not directly represented by consortium members to provide training and technical assistance to and about those communities; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6D43A26D85A430EAB9A9C6E62491C01"><enum>(5)</enum><text>evidence of longstanding relationships with faith-based organizations and stakeholders representing a variety of other faith communities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H944C57E7B20243FAB424F5BC804D3CAE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a plan to establish and be advised by a victim advisory working group composed of victims with faith, including those who are underserved for reasons in addition to faith, which shall meet periodically throughout the grant period to inform the activities carried out under the grant. Members of the victim advisory working group shall be compensated for their participation.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDFA53D5A3BAB4581B201B1DA0093A0FA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A consortium of eligible entities may use funds under this section to—</text> <paragraph id="H0B534CFAD9F54D959CD4E2CFD8DE1B41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide training and technical assistance to faith communities, faith institutions, seminaries and clergy training programs, faith-based schools and institutes of higher education, faith youth groups, clergy and lay leaders, and other faith stakeholders to equip them to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA6A0B19F70B94B488710DD7350938D5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>understand and recognize domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including the impact on children;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1C864A4815D146D4B4AB07BE38900DAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>draw upon faith values and texts to raise awareness about and address domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06A2B0554D0143F9AFB289424134A081"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop and implement prevention programs that are consistent with faith teachings and trauma-informed, victim-centered practices;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE67D0285740D4B0FAFCBA03EB06426E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>educate community members about religious arbitration agreements, terms of religious marital contracts, and other religious premarital or marital documents intended to prevent or discourage religious divorce denial;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC8F93189D3F4A3B8642BE70201C30E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>support victims with faith within their faith communities in a victim-centered and trauma-informed manner;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C1D807BA72D497589A6A9A19A10D4DF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>refer victims with faith to local victim service providers, including population-specific and culturally specific programs, and other resources;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3986E736777249A2AE07078785A6081F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>hold offenders accountable, including implementing restorative practices in collaboration with entities receiving funding authorized under section 41801 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC727A49F0B95470881A9BF85B31B8F8D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>support offender behavior change;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H099D7694E1AC4326AF84D377F454D914"><enum>(I)</enum><text>enact safety protocols to protect victims with faith;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18EEEA1DA52E4175888F0157D1594F5E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>understand legal issues impacting victims with faith and uphold protection orders and child custody orders;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9360190AECB7452694FEDA2131F6F955"><enum>(K)</enum><text>engage in peer-to-peer learning and teaching, including with other faith communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC48C0C89F97345A4959A17C2C14E008C"><enum>(L)</enum><text>participate in coordinated community responses;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE504C87C0214EDA82BE4827838B62EB"><enum>(M)</enum><text>prevent and respond to forced marriage; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9623F1FA3B5C424F91A0C88FBFCFDDF6"><enum>(N)</enum><text>undertake other activities to prevent, respond to, address, or support victims of faith;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A39F55D0EF1461CA671E2DF0B474C0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide training and technical assistance to victim service providers and State and Tribal coalitions, legal service providers, housing providers, and other nonprofit organizations working with victims with faith, and to criminal and civil justice agencies, including law enforcement, prosecutors, courts, probation and parole staff, and child protective services to empower them to—</text> <subparagraph id="H99753769AF00439CA2375B57FA5C2BB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporate faith communities into coordinated community responses;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB13EC5D6FF124741996CCDB559FDA6EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>address unique needs and experiences of victims with faith, including spiritual abuse;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44DA5E280EB3489BB90C1303ABE4FC14"><enum>(C)</enum><text>understand and address barriers that victims with faith face when seeking safety and services, including unconscious bias;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3CD9389D54745FD809BB78D48B42F60"><enum>(D)</enum><text>implement faith-specific considerations and best practices for working with and supporting victims with faith, including—</text> <clause id="HBFF6D815E9AF49DBB1DDA15BFAABD8D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing religiously-appropriate food and dietary accommodations in shelters and transitional housing;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA90F2493E319446E8BA22C724C488AA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the greatest extent practicable, understanding and taking into account faith-based modesty norms, dress requirements, and related cultural norms, including during interactions involving law enforcement personnel; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9407C175F6E54519AD348D53BB7BF013"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>accommodating daily prayer, rituals, or other faith-based observances, such as prayer timing and pre- and post-meal blessings; </text></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H57F4F263658B4608BDE699076C6EFA89"><enum>(E)</enum><text>implement best practices for interacting with and collaborating with faith communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H57E9FABE8DCE4FA681395298A776632E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in the context of intimate partner homicides, honor faith traditions related to the care and handling of the deceased; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8DA56AAD57E441A98FCCAB6D9C3730D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>undertake other activities to prevent, respond to, address, or support victims of faith;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D0DFE469EAE4B939701D684900A1AC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide appropriate training and technical assistance to other stakeholders, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8DA37F5AA96A4EBFA3BD5490238CDCDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health professionals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H454CBF318BE5473D94F7C901F04C434A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>researchers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53443A74B3A441B1B00D9595770B0A32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disaster response coordinators and organizers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15E5128784064D43A63439384B25D316"><enum>(D)</enum><text>faith-based, secular, and non-sectarian social service agencies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D10903A54DC447BBC4A77353590340E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support the Office on Violence Against Women in convening faith communities, victim service providers, culturally specific programs, population-specific programs, victims, other stakeholders, and federal government personnel to identify areas of strength, ongoing challenges, and emerging issues to guide future training and technical assistance, and grantmaking; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C542E5951644156B1A53D8F415B9622"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the establishment and operation of a victim advisory working group required under subsection (c)(6), including compensation for members. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H64BFEF744FD5451CBAB8DDF0FA4100BF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Establishment Phase</header><text>During the first year of the initial grant cycle, the consortium shall use grant funds solely for the purpose of establishing the basic administrative and operational infrastructure necessary to operate the National Resource Center, including initial staffing, governance structures, and core systems to support its activities, as well as developing partnerships to understand and address the needs of communities that are underserved for reasons other than, or in addition to, faith.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H72F8447411EF4BAE9CF2190F1A59C3BB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE7CAF7552EA54134BB51556447FD6CFB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Availability of grant funds</header><text>Funds appropriated under this section shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7A1E02BC2B9643DFAA4D0FC4A84937CD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> <paragraph id="H2886F82356754A4BA601C887781DC38C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Funds made available under this section shall not be used to proselytize, to promote any religion or religious viewpoint, to promote religiosity or increased religious observance, or for any other purposes related to faith or religion that are prohibited under federal, state, Tribal, or local law or violate the Constitutional separation of religion and state.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F4AEA106BCE4E668960699F767EC2E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Funds made available under this section shall supplement, not supplant, existing Office on Violence Against Women grants focused on specific faith communities.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="H07B712974413430BA7DA29D9173C18B2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Model State Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General shall, in consultation with experts in religious divorce denial, advocates working with victims experiencing religious divorce denial, victims who have experienced religious divorce denial, faith leaders, faith communities, and population-specific victim service providers, develop and publish model State legislative language to address religious divorce denial. This model legislative language shall take into account relevant religious laws and cultural practices, and be designed to be workable within affected faith communities, while remaining consistent with the requirements of the Constitution.</text></section> 
<section id="H068FB80AA60348A7B792A6D0F349CBFC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting and evaluation</header> 
<subsection id="H7ED1C51B7A9A497095900F432065EDFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports to the Attorney General</header><text>On the date that is 1 year after first receiving a grant under this Act, and annually thereafter for the duration of the grant period, each consortium of eligible entities shall submit to the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women, a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HC134A3D5EBF74279ACF979ED984D3E19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of activities conducted under the grant and populations served; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF4D3006061E4884A7AAA33ABA063C26"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the effectiveness of such activities in achieving the purposes of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3B50166022504C9AA821307DBC5BE014"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than November 1 of each even-numbered fiscal year, the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women shall compile and summarize the reports submitted under subsection (a) and submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report on the activities and effectiveness of the program established under this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

