<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H171E41385B41434C89A4F9F23DA95506" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 941 IH: Recognizing May 20 as “National Women in Aerospace Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 941</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="H001099">Mr. Haridopolos</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing May 20 as <quote>National Women in Aerospace Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas National Women in Aerospace Day recognizes and emphasizes the importance of American women in aviation, human spaceflight, and other related aerospace fields, including—</text><paragraph id="H81B4A26B0ABE4338B6F394DD31BCBD3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Harriet Quimby, the first American woman to earn a pilot’s license;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EE82B44E8E043628D1B87CBB3568B9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Bessie Coleman, the first African-American person to earn a pilot’s license;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D5E55A41126414295A177BD880606A5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Amelia Earhart, the first woman to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean, and was instrumental in the formation of The Ninety-Nines, an organization for female pilots;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B6536FD072C4928B277840DF2269BF4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Jacqueline Cochran, the first woman to break the sound barrier;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4F995352E52420E946174FEC3D75D3B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Pearl I. Young, the first female technical employee at the National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics (NACA), and a pioneer in technical writing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D994A03147F43DBA61A30CCBA41F2C5"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Jerrie Cobb, the first woman to undergo and pass the same physical testing developed for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration's (NASA) astronaut selection, and a staunch advocate for women in space flight;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H014B9A0AD9FC4D689852134720084CBE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Katherine Johnson, a mathematician who provided calculations and analyzed data for NACA, and then NASA, including for the Freedom 7 mission and for Apollo missions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8567A4F9FE94DB498418BCB89589981"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Dr. Nancy Grace Roman, NASA’s first Chief of Astronomy and first female executive, a prominent figure in development of the Hubble Space Telescope, and the namesake of the Nancy Grace Roman Space Telescope currently under development at NASA;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF161F7AD8A4A4B8A8DC1624F9C140593"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Eleanor Williams, the first African-American woman to be certified as an air traffic controller;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H910074A47EBA44A3A180C149E547DFA2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Emily Howell Warner, the first woman to become a United States airline captain;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF13212A855954355BFBF5BE1617A2C7F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Dr. Sally Ride, a physicist and the first American woman to travel to space;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB5D4B79298240D684305FB29EFD4B14"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Dr. Kathryn Sullivan, a geologist and the first American woman to perform a spacewalk;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E9FD8B87EF149348DD36F2C1D72678C"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Dr. Mae Jemison, a medical doctor and the first African-American woman to travel to space;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF696724DC2C943658A235987B74C2B71"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Dr. Ellen Ochoa, an engineer and the first Hispanic woman to travel to space and the first Hispanic director of NASA’s Johnson Space Center;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2769B619E7A9437F971301A2463D4D66"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Patrice Clarke-Washington, the first African-American woman to become a United States airline captain;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E442B6B0658491BA3D0A7EF5A896A05"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Colonel Eileen Collins, the first woman to pilot and to command a space shuttle;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H594EDCA148D44BFF8560C719796DCE44"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Dr. Christine Darden, an engineer whose research revolutionized aerodynamics design, particularly to reduce the production of sonic noise, and the first African-American woman at NASA Langley to be promoted to Senior Executive Service, the top rank in the Federal civil service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EAA3CECC4564C5CA416630AF914CBD1"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Dr. Jeanette Epps, an engineer and the African-American astronaut who has spent the most time in space;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H731D2717AF5F4D57B66BF00FA423A95D"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Dr. Jessica U. Meir, a scientist who (along with Christina Koch) conducted the first 3 all-female spacewalks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H088A3C43565F4E28B3623D904DDEF6C2"><enum>(20)</enum><text>Christina Koch, an engineer who (along with Jessica U. Meir) conducted the first 3 all-female spacewalks, is the recordholder for the longest single space flight by a woman, and is set to become the first woman to travel beyond low Earth orbit on the Artemis II mission in 2026; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H554DF1523EDA4B96B880C794FAA96ECC"> <enum>(21)</enum> <text>countless other women whose pioneering achievements and dedication have expanded the frontiers of aerospace;</text>
 </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women’s contributions in the field of aerospace have been critical to its success;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas women currently make up only roughly 20 percent of the aerospace workforce;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas increasing the number of women in the aerospace field will be critical to maintaining a competitive aerospace workforce and programs; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas diversity in any field incorporates different experiences, which can ultimately lead to more creative and pioneering solutions;</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H87F9CF62261A4165860C68400FBBF6E2"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5B16D15BECE84C809AE624F2D13C43BC"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HDF3CBC90E1134451B293A46BFA0512A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the celebration of <quote>National Women in Aerospace Day</quote> as a time to reflect on the many notable contributions that women have made to the field of aerospace in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1F33C7DDF1F4B29ABDB5C65B87BD796"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the people of the United States to observe National Women in Aerospace Day with appropriate programs and activities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A8D277E5C644099A63F3FF5EF987CA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms the commitment of the House of Representatives to ensuring that all women have equal access to opportunity in the aerospace field.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

