<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MDM25M29-6S1-6T-0K7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 573 IS: Expressing the need for the United States continued leadership on matters of religious freedom.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 573</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the need for the United States continued leadership on
 matters of religious freedom.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the freedom of religion is the United States first right that launched a revolution to enshrine freedom for all;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States clearly states, <quote>Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press; or the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress of grievances</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States founding fathers believed all persons had <quote>inalienable rights</quote>, as endowed by our Creator and further protected by the Government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these inalienable rights also belong to those around the world, as they are inherent and the foundation of individual dignity and freedom;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States is the global leader in the fight to protect and expand the inalienable right to freedom of religion;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has consistently reaffirmed its commitment to the freedom of religion, including through the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/292">Public Law 105–292</external-xref>) and the Frank R. Wolf International Religious Freedom Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/281">Public Law 114–281</external-xref>);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress has reaffirmed its commitment to the promotion of religious freedom abroad by creating and confirming Ambassadors-at-Large for International Religious Freedom and the Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Antisemitism;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas other Western countries have not taken similar steps to enshrine the inalienable right of religious freedom in their founding documents or in a consistent pattern of domestic policies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the rise of religious intolerance in Europe has created an environment that—</text><paragraph id="id4f7d0139a9d4460b93ee3312543a191c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>criminalizes certain religious practices that target Jews; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e1a7a3ff434434b9450e5804cb5afe6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creates subtly inhospitable environments for Christians;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas countries around the world continue to engage in gross violations of internationally recognized human rights, including violations of the inalienable right to freedom of religion;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas governments in Afghanistan, Algeria, Azerbaijan, Burma, China, Cuba, Egypt, Eritrea, India, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kazakhstan, Malaysia, Nicaragua, Nigeria, North Korea, Pakistan, Russia, Saudi Arabia, Sri Lanka, Syria, Tajikistan, Turkey, Turkmenistan, Uzbekistan, Venezuela, and Vietnam, and have all engaged in patterns of violations of varying degrees of religious freedom;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Chinese Communist Party arrested dozens of Zion House Church members and leaders in October 2025, which was the greatest attack on Christianity in China in decades in their continued campaign to Sinicize religion;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom 2025 Annual Report revealed that the Government of Nicaragua continues to ruthlessly suppress religious freedom for Christians, including through intimidation tactics;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Vatican leaders are mourning the ongoing killings of Christians for their faith, which are occurring in increasing numbers in some places;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas according to the pontifical foundation Aid to the Church in Need, more than 360,000,000 Christians live in areas where they face high levels of persecution;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas such patterns of violating religious freedom will continue in these countries unless the United States sends clear, concise, and strong messages to cease such behavior; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as the global leader for centuries on religious freedom, only the United States can proclaim without reservation that these countries must reverse course and protect and defend the inalienable rights of all people, particularly those who are seeking to exercise the most provocative right, which is the natural and inalienable right to freedom of religion: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id08cc24177d1745eea9517f91ddef92c9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirms the United States leadership around the world to promote, protect, and expand the inalienable and internationally recognized right to freedom of religion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8bacb5e605904ee2bfcc407e61a8f37d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the Secretary of State—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37a8ef82b47648e090c7ccac085fb563"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to continue to engage on matters of religious freedom;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b4cc4f6877747e09af571714f7c22ac"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to use all available tools and resources to discourage foreign governments from continuing patterns of violations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4bdce8549d8c4a5f90894f08fa7a4db2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to continue to engage on matters of religious freedom with friendly nations to prevent further erosion of religious freedom;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id59b97605b48e4038965d25fec0953108"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the importance of the offices of the Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom and the Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Antisemitism;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00c5ca636e2d4d19a215290bb928c9eb"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports the offices of the Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom and the Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Antisemitism to work together to ensure that no faith or believer is left behind; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0562481a950b4cb58426d86545bdd9a9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>commits the United States to always support those seeking freedom from authoritarian repression against our shared and inalienable rights.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

