<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7AA0B8FCC3394FF2A7FC34E5062F4169" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6676 IH: State Industrial Competitiveness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6676</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide financial assistance to States and Indian Tribes for the development, implementation, improvement, or expansion of a flex-tech energy program to enhance manufacturing competitiveness, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2FD95747E1694E52845B544DA4CD9318" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H94933F3C54CC4777AF2DBCAEE76BED8D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Industrial Competitiveness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6B7E74286A6B41468935D1BD927FD770"><enum>2.</enum><header>State flex-tech energy program</header> <subsection id="HAC07AB2BB0E54153A59E52F0A00A2F6A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part D of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6321">42 U.S.C. 6321 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H161B74F7769442019D6EB46105A5AFA4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H17C688AECAF8493FA70E165198801B52" commented="no"><enum>367.</enum><header>Flex-tech energy program to enhance manufacturing competitiveness</header> 
<subsection id="H8B29A96663004050917ACAEB7F5A49E4" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Financial assistance</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, upon request from the State energy agency of a State that has in effect an approved State energy conservation plan under this part, or an Indian Tribe, the Secretary shall provide financial assistance to such State energy agency or Indian Tribe to be used for the development, implementation, improvement, or expansion of a flex-tech energy program described in subsection (b) to enhance manufacturing competitiveness.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE497B239802040CEAB90D1355E069916" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Flex-Tech energy program elements</header> <paragraph id="H9D40E674EF6F4973BA1FC3F8AB309479" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A flex-tech energy program may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H30741BC71C6D48AF997779B5CB349A8B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provision of technical and administrative assistance to manufacturers through qualified engineering firms, as determined by the State energy agency or Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAEB26B88BFD54013BF49422F82528F2D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provision of financial assistance to manufacturers—</text> 
<clause id="HA63A489A95A9429BAD1342ACAAFB47B5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for energy studies of manufacturing facilities that are conducted by qualified engineering firms; and</text></clause> <clause id="H54BAB57E534A4096B8DBA6DB2B6FF71A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support the implementation of the measures and recommendations identified in energy studies conducted pursuant to clause (i), including the design, acquisition, installation, testing, operation, maintenance, and repair of energy- and water-using systems, resiliency-related measures, emissions reduction-related measures, utility cost savings measures, and measures related to advanced manufacturing technologies and artificial intelligence; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB7F02FDBAD5B448986668E40FCF2D5AF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reporting on monitoring, tracking, and success metrics of the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F46C083DC304786BBE69973392315FE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Studies</header><text>An energy study of a manufacturing facility conducted pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA8F66AB5537F41A7A026751EDA4510AF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the energy-using systems of the facility, including evaluation of the performance of such systems relative to design intent, operational needs of the facility and its occupants, and operation and maintenance procedures;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0875AE0E8DD4DC69DC87F20C72D8FC5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of emissions related to the facility, including greenhouse gas emissions, and recommendations on sustainability planning and practices;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78612D51E790455DA8BB9BD27444F2C8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an evaluation of potential energy efficiency, water efficiency, greenhouse gas emissions mitigation, and load reduction measures for the facility;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88100ACA624C4241BCFBA006FA9D830D" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of potential on-site energy measures, including grid-interactive efficiency systems, combined heat and power, industrial heat pumps, efficient compressed air systems, energy storage, energy management systems, renewable thermal systems, and electrification or other forms of fuel switching;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82E36D425D09499E8441BD07C29D6F2D" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommendations on the use of new technologies by the applicable manufacturer; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F9448FB4D894E4697D022000F8EC243" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>detailed estimates of potential implementation costs, operating cost savings, energy savings, emissions reductions, and simple payback periods, for measures and recommendations identified in such study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H556C7B5A47A248E5AEDB6E7B5A23FF64" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified engineering firms</header><text>A State energy agency or Indian Tribe administering a flex-tech energy program shall maintain and regularly update a publicly available list of qualified engineering firms that are approved by the State energy agency or Indian Tribe to provide assistance to manufacturers pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF0969EA0D91243C5A0AAB9FD586CA59E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="H9DB5E6C55BF24F489372A5825CA0F34B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), to the extent practicable, the Secretary shall allocate funding made available to carry out this section in accordance with the formula used for distribution of Federal financial assistance provided pursuant to this part to States that have in effect an approved State energy conservation plan under this part.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H471C8BD2D1FF4FF692F1364B6D56D329" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall set aside and distribute not less than 5 percent of amounts made available for each fiscal year to carry out this section to provide financial assistance—</text> <subparagraph id="H8F8D20D69FB84811B36BF03A6CB267CB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to Indian Tribes; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9029DA690B054EC59216A6497E2C3CD7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly to manufacturers located in Indian Country or, in the case of Alaska, an Alaska Native Village Statistical Area, as identified by the U.S. Census Bureau, for energy studies and implementation of the measures and recommendations identified in such energy studies, as described in subsection (b)(1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD059E60A986344649698AB329286C8E9" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <subparagraph id="HB39CC42360C349A097F9B45648B7149E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Energy studies; administrative expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State energy agency or Indian Tribe that receives financial assistance pursuant to this section for a fiscal year may not—</text> 
<clause id="H962CC84CF1634F4798614A1962DEE7D2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use more than 50 percent of such financial assistance for energy studies;</text></clause> <clause id="H576C81B351AF488BA034CE0CB60B3FA5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use more than 50 percent of such financial assistance to support the implementation of recommendations from such energy studies; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1B81B29FAE2243E7B2FF6B5439FE0F27" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>use more than 10 percent of such financial assistance for administrative expenses, including for outreach and technical assistance.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0D2A6E9DE6B4C229958457686BA682B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Individual manufacturing facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State energy agency that receives financial assistance pursuant to this section for a fiscal year may not use more than the greater of $100,000 or 5 percent of such financial assistance with respect to an individual manufacturing facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6CEA7B6B8CD44579397F51704DAB18B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Supplement</header><text>Financial assistance provided to a State energy agency or Indian Tribe pursuant to this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, any Federal, State, or other funds otherwise made available to such State under this part.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36075CB140E34D0AA339CD5DD54E4DEE" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Financing</header><text>To the extent practicable, a State energy agency or Indian Tribe shall implement a flex-tech energy program described in subsection (b) using funding provided under this Act, public financing, private financing, or any other sources of funds.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF189281864F14E7C89DD3C2667674D2D" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header> 
<paragraph id="H182F262BDF4344F9AB675FCE4D656E56" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon request of a State energy agency or Indian Tribe, the Secretary shall provide information and technical assistance in the development, implementation, improvement, or expansion of a flex-tech energy program described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H67286EC275A049BB9A5111DA96FF588F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>Technical assistance provided pursuant to paragraph (1) may include program design options to, with respect to manufacturers that employ fewer than 500 full-time equivalent employees at a manufacturing facility—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H214039BD8D8F425A8D30B6221BB48D96" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meet the needs of such manufacturers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2DE1E8754C484584A20C7233D1A6F5F4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage the use of advanced manufacturing processes by such manufacturers, including use of additive manufacturing, advanced sensors and controls, techniques to reduce embedded emissions, and advanced composite materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77B7F13BB51B49EDA130E9A581CD9854" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4522BF6643F94012BD3968C8A2A65B1F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian Country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Country</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H833CF56F2E25443F9F20B0D838038F47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all land within the limits of any Indian reservation under the jurisdiction of the United States Government, notwithstanding the issuance of any patent, and, including rights-of-way running through the reservation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59D52AD2B8CE47649B45B934A70F6DA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all dependent Indian communities within the borders of the United States whether within the original or subsequently acquired territory thereof, and whether within or without the limits of a State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA62E20289664BF8893680C3D3BE9A4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all Indian allotments, the Indian titles to which have not been extinguished, including rights-of-way running through the same.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DF6A65079E746089BBE2AE277AB397D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5B038ED13CF44388CE08586B4EB3168" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State energy agency</header><text>The term <term>State energy agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 391(10).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC4CCA0F33DBF48DF828586BDD2D0D9A6" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Energy Policy and Conservation Act is amended by adding after the item related to section 366 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H3CE3F21F0E084FAC82F7689B14121777" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 367. Flex-tech energy program to enhance manufacturing competitiveness.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H010454B4EF6245A0BF1AEEB3674C3D61" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Section 365(f) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6325">42 U.S.C. 6325(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAC879098178F4FC6BE41016B70B5CC06" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H1BD7F2D523A64D6F9695146FD409256A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Flex-tech energy program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the authorization of appropriations under paragraph (1), for the purposes of carrying out section 367, there are authorized to be appropriated $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

