<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HB7FED6F5765C4241B3AA39C0254055CE"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5645 IH: Pray Safe Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5645</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To establish a Federal Clearinghouse on Safety and Best Practices for Nonprofit Organizations, Faith-based Organizations, and Houses of Worship within the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H59224065E62349528F8EED0014F0F74E">
<section section-type="section-one" id="H25EE1FB98D5945558DE6D1CEB5365AFD" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pray Safe Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9739CA9B899E42C0872D06A62506FDC8" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8F9278E79454B74B11F4AC50E3B2570" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clearinghouse</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Clearinghouse</term> means the Federal Clearinghouse on Safety and Security Best Practices for Nonprofit Organizations, Faith-based Organizations, and Houses of Worship established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA44915343CBD40AAB928277C571C3FD4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H20B45EB1194B4082822D33167EBC3E3F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Faith-based organization</header><text>The term <term>faith-based organization</term> means a group, center, or nongovernmental organization with a religious, ideological, or spiritual motivation, character, affiliation, or purpose that meets the definition of nonprofit organization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H85D0ED32B84D465A991883DF4B1912EB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>House of worship</header><text>The term <term>house of worship</term> means a place or building, including a synagogue, mosque, temple, and church, in which congregants practice their religious or spiritual beliefs.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1B164A14BEAE4A2F9C9E407FE198656D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95F01C22C7104722B06C2D18258FD9A8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the type described in subsection (c)(3) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under subsection (a) of such section; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H794D2F3001484FA38A062E3CAA75D461" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determined to be at risk of a terrorist attack or other threat by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H597297C63731413DBDE76048E4D25C6B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Safety and security</header><text>The term <term>safety and security</term> means prevention of, protection against, or recovery from threats and incidents, including natural disasters, manmade disasters, or terrorist attacks.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD030E728C7D464CA852C96245738181" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A70D1B6773A411FB2530BB71D02923C" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Clearinghouse on Safety and Security Best Practices for Nonprofit Organizations, Faith-based Organizations, and Houses of Worship</header> <subsection id="H2CA4EC602CFF4B56AB4685BFB1B698F0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal Clearinghouse</header> <paragraph id="H213DBD8D9F724AA9ACB5838DBAC5866A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <subparagraph id="HF675CF570B0D48FD8157FFCDA4A90FD2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Executive Director of the White House Office of Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships, and the head of any other agency the Secretary determines appropriate, shall establish within the Department a Federal Clearinghouse on Safety and Security Best Practices for Nonprofit Organizations, Faith-based Organizations, and Houses of Worship.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC7E480EC253E4663A9C1ECFE4516A9FC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Clearinghouse shall be the primary resource of the Federal Government to—</text> <clause id="H490D4BC26F4C4D11B8B3577184269D24" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">educate and publish online best practices and recommendations for safety and security for nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HA9E54D2908BA42A599756F44840CC3F1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide information relating to Federal grant programs available to nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE707C24A932448DCB767D12B232007C0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Personnel</header> <clause id="H97741EC32B52426F81B1E2D395563161" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Assignments</header><text>The Clearinghouse shall be assigned such personnel and resources as the Secretary considers appropriate to carry out this subsection.</text></clause>
<clause id="H352DC29970DA43C7B271888D7BBFC418" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>The Secretary may coordinate detailees on a reimbursable or a nonreimbursable basis as required for the Clearinghouse.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H3045C758E0E54B65BC0D1534065C54F4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Designated point of contact</header> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6096734796104D73B0D8624B1E23CB63" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be not fewer than 1 employee assigned or detailed to the Clearinghouse who shall be the designated point of contact to provide information and assistance to nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship, including assistance relating to the grant program established under subsection (c).</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46776F1B1E1345F1A40BF64E92002EF8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Contact information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The contact information of the designated point of contact under subclause (I) shall be made available on the website of the Clearinghouse.</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H09C2E1CB51D14C5F9FF17DAC2E79B7EB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Qualification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent possible, any personnel assigned or detailed to the Clearinghouse under this subparagraph should be familiar with nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship and with physical and online security measures to identify and prevent safety and security risks.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6A071790CB53418AA12051077BE6449D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clearinghouse contents</header>
<subparagraph id="HEE3211CE5D7C450C8DB40045AA7A87D8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Evidence-based tiers</header>
<clause commented="no" id="H223C4D22FED646E38E14C66FB9E0E3BA" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Executive Director of the White House Office of Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships, and the head of any other agency the Secretary determines appropriate, shall develop tiers for determining evidence-based best practices and recommendations that demonstrate a significant effect on improving safety and security of nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship.</text></clause> <clause id="HD27432D788814114A57738DFB772E006" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The tiers required to be developed under clause (i) shall—</text>
<subclause id="H63E2DE567F3348748BB804601625B6C6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>prioritize—</text> <item id="H7081F2D8FF6E4297AD1ADB93B09E67EE" changed="not-changed"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>strong evidence from not fewer than 1 well-designed and well-implemented experimental study; and</text></item>
<item id="HA25B0BE4027545BC830670247E0E4978" changed="not-changed"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>moderate evidence from not fewer than 1 well-designed and well-implemented quasi-experimental study; and</text></item></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H22AC4AEB1B3E46F28CC734020290398A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider promising evidence that demonstrates a rationale based on high-quality research findings or positive evaluations that the activity, strategy, or intervention is likely to improve and promote safety and security of nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD262CF5A5DA9410CB9CE9D2AC0EC4926" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria for best practices and recommendations</header><text>The best practices and recommendations referred to in paragraph (1)(B)(i) of the Clearinghouse shall, at a minimum—</text> <clause id="HAD9ED5DF3B3541E09F448E9EB491F6A8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify areas of concern for nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship, including event planning recommendations, checklists, facility hardening, tabletop exercise resources, and other resilience measures;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H3D32E7A2E35B4658B6E113DAC98DDFAD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">involve comprehensive safety and security measures, including threat prevention, preparedness, protection, mitigation, incident response, and recovery to improve the safety and security posture of nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship upon implementation;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HBFFA3B81491B4FEE964277AA7803EA16" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">involve comprehensive safety and security measures, including preparedness, protection, mitigation, incident response, and recovery to improve the resiliency of nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship from threats and incidents, including natural disasters, manmade disasters, or terrorist attacks or other threats;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H64AACC9369994F0D800334F99FE80908" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include any evidence or research rationale supporting the determination of the Clearinghouse that the comprehensive safety and security measures under clauses (ii) and (iii) have been shown to have a significant effect on improving the safety and security of individuals who, at the time of any such threat or incident, are physically located in the place or building of a nonprofit organization, including a faith-based organization, or a house of worship, including—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H4A371923DF51402DBEB8492227597336" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">findings and data from previous Federal, State, local, Tribal, territorial, private sector, and nongovernmental organization research centers relating to the safety and security of nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship, including from targeted violence; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" id="HE04DFE465AF047D29E70FCD8C901FEA6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other supportive evidence or findings relied upon by the Clearinghouse in determining best practices and recommendations to improve the safety and security posture of nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship upon implementation; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE02A9A94E7364BF6B128F99465F78890" changed="not-changed"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include an overview of the available resources the Clearinghouse can provide to nonprofit organizations and houses of worship.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C9FA610CD1946BF92564BFAC19C407F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clearinghouse shall maintain and make available a comprehensive index of all Federal grant programs for which nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship are eligible, which shall include the performance metrics the recipient will be required to provide for each grant.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2DBF4EDED3834E7C9EC87735F4259693" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Past recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the greatest extent practicable, the Clearinghouse shall identify and present, as appropriate, best practices and recommendations issued by Federal, State, local, Tribal, territorial, private sector, and nongovernmental organizations relevant to the safety and security of nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H29D71C96DF2A45F294EC0DE8D53F979D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Existing platform</header><text>The Secretary may establish and maintain the Clearinghouse on an online platform or a website that is in existence as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B2B20B6FAB14418BE8622AA5F9DD582" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assistance and training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may produce and publish materials on the Clearinghouse to assist and train nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship regarding the implementation of the best practices and recommendations under this subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9EEBEBF7FAFC46E6BD159C1152DA4547" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Continuous improvement</header>
<subparagraph id="H95478B2231AE4C6E970EBF633A613DDA" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HD9D600DBE4E14161AF96D2478A4B193C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collect for the purpose of continuous improvement of the Clearinghouse—</text>
<subclause id="H38A4E105606F49AD8F938302041B3E73" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Clearinghouse data analytics;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE26CA82D758241868E229B22EDD22143" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>user feedback on the implementation of resources, best practices, and recommendations identified by the Clearinghouse; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H9B7FED7A40544C4CA7D8804063810DEF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any evaluations conducted regarding implementation of such best practices and recommendations;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA5C94EA554274C11AA315024A912BA41" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in coordination with the Faith-Based Security Advisory Council of the Department, the Department of Justice, the Executive Director of the White House Office of Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships, and any other agency the Secretary determines appropriate—</text>
<subclause id="H2C13CF973D4D4CF280FF65B27135EA7C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>assess and identify Clearinghouse best practices and recommendations for which there are no resources available through Federal Government programs for implementation;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H10F49C19FDF9423293D980A61FFE93A5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide feedback on the implementation of such best practices and recommendations; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HF9E31A3FCEBF4BA689967DDDC072CA5E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(III)</enum><text>propose additional best practices and recommendations for inclusion in the Clearinghouse; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H2CE8A54BF2804894827B919F95CE63DD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not less frequently than annually, examine and update the Clearinghouse in accordance with—</text>
<subclause id="H1AEB8164EE1E48178CB515E62C35BE12" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the information collected under clause (i); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H33863BE8FBCD448BB59B51E634333BC9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the best practices and recommendations proposed under clause (ii)(III).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H9F6A281E1FC747A0955FD62804E9276A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 3 years thereafter during the period in which the Clearinghouse is in existence, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the updates under subparagraph (A)(iii) made to the Clearinghouse during the preceding 3-year period, which shall include a description of any changes made pursuant thereto to the Clearinghouse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFDBEA24531C44C988A305DB6F8D378FD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification of the Clearinghouse</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3D8626BCFD2B44AEA9A0682612597A99" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide to the individuals, Federal agencies, and committees specified in paragraph (2) written notification of the establishment of the Clearinghouse, including updates pertaining to grant programs identified under subsection (a)(2)(C).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H89CDBFC14A06413791F6496874384A04" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals, Federal agencies, and committees specified</header><text>The individuals, Federal entities, and committees specified in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H6D78EB53A7774AAC8797DB9635F37BE9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Every State homeland security advisor.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7D749B21BB70424BB9F86E2965305D81" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Every State department of homeland security.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H298C4CFFF3DD41A39CDDA9DAAEB5A463" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Other Federal agencies with grant programs or initiatives that aid in the safety and security of nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA9F290331C8945719C91134E9A3875F3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Every Cyber Security Advisor.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7028376AB36E478FB2BDB9F33D91B346" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Every Protective Security Advisor.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2565315C830E47CF9DCB387C13E0A0AC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Every Federal Bureau of Investigation Joint Terrorism Task Force.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80FE819D5F29417FAEE94A712ACB8108" changed="not-changed"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Every Homeland Security Fusion Center.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5EAD4974087C4906B5020C713B2C2BF3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Every State or territorial Governor or other chief executive.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H699CB5928A054556BCAFBB4D1A69435D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4B6AD44B2B9947A883382221601611FB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDBFB97240B0446FB89865F0769CCB90B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal grants and resources overview</header> <paragraph id="H27A03CD274F343B8B2F242D7F4892BC0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Secretary, when carrying out subsection (a)(2)(C), shall include a grants program overview on the website of the Clearinghouse that shall—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC49EC600E32B46CFA5A05C0C9394FF56" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be a location for all information regarding Federal grant programs that are open to nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship for the purposes of safety and security;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC29ADFFF722C4877BAA35BA9FFDA7AD2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>directly link to each grant application and any applicable user guides;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9CF2DD9E10D849098A7213C7C1DF8DE1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify all safety and security homeland security assistance programs managed by the Department that may be used to implement best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C78AD0242934D479DA082C1C12F8D60" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">concurrent with the application period for any grant identified under subsection (a)(2)(C), provide information related to the required elements of grant applications to aid nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship in meeting the eligibility criteria for Federal grants; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4B9BD7DC698C4EAFBEFDFA39670F294D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide answers to frequently asked questions regarding the implementation of best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse and best practices for applying for a grant identified under subsection (a)(2)(C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H85B7F545D6E74E1A8E745491F1061797" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provision of information relating to Federal grants and resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal agency notified under subsection (b) shall provide to the Secretary or other appropriate point of contact for the Clearinghouse for inclusion in the Clearinghouse necessary information regarding any Federal grant programs or resources of the Federal agency that are available for nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1E045B46D03D44CF81D3873340E3C987" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State grants and resources</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H142AD321B0C242E9AFC2B21BE7B6A696" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any State notified under subsection (b) may provide to the Secretary or other appropriate point of contact for the Clearinghouse for inclusion in the Clearinghouse necessary information regarding any grant programs or resources of the State available for nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship for the purposes of safety and security.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87AAA72329AD464CA14290DE63885F97" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Identification of resources</header><text>The Clearinghouse shall, to the extent practicable, identify for each State the following:</text>
<clause commented="no" id="HF9D1168D5B614FF08A9B7C44DBA6240D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State agency responsible for safety and security of nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship in the State, or any State that does not have such an agency designated.</text></clause> <clause id="HD386B8AF64494B6CA8C81ABCCC2282E2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any grant program that may be used for the purposes of implementing best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse.</text></clause>
<clause id="HDE142D979135445492DB9E1083F6E03A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any resources or programs, including community prevention or intervention efforts, that may be used to assist in targeted violence and terrorism prevention.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H9F955F18EB464C8094F843E2A5BFFB78" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, on the website of the Clearinghouse, include a separate section for other resources that shall provide a centralized list of all available points of contact from which a nonprofit organization, including a faith-based organization, or a house of worship may seek assistance in grant applications and in carrying out the best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse, including the following:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H04A92A653AF049E49876F4811D7E2F42" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of contact information to reach Department personnel to assist with grant-related questions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB3F4186D55C249A4B6ECB0C66A83B218" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The applicable Agency contact information to connect houses of worship with Protective Security Advisors.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0F620B2B3A49470A910267C128943A07" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Contact information for all Department Fusion Centers, listed by State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H2DE53F11BAB64E2387B6141D1E6D6C00" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Information on the <quote>If you See Something Say Something Campaign</quote> of the Department.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0B33F9399C5E4B8188CC93559FCFEAFB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any other appropriate contacts.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7C686C2065DD41F3BB0182E43E421F13" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to create, satisfy, or waive any requirement under Federal civil rights laws, including—</text>
<paragraph id="H1B2F9DAA2C914461AACA6298839FD526" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>title II of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12131">42 U.S.C. 12131 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82B5B9EFAE6E458C93BC337862BF3721" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EB5B7403495429EAA75ECB9CB30D804" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This Act shall cease to be effective on the date that is 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HBE1B06DF26CC4D5FBE64B5E713B25FB3" changed="not-changed"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the state of Federal grants devoted to safety and security for nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship, and an evaluation of the relevant programs and resources devoted to the safety and security of nonprofit organizations, including faith-based organizations, and houses of worship as of the date of the report.</text></section>
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


