<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD438C5C3B19C4D588F3B8C3F4140ED93" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7311 IH: Lebanon Election Integrity and Diaspora Voting Protection Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7311</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260202">February 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the President to impose sanctions with respect to any foreign person or entity that hinders, obstructs or delays Lebanon&#8217;s electoral process, including efforts to restrict or prevent Lebanese citizens abroad from voting in parliamentary elections, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE51E308791C04290A9A725AD26FBEA6A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H26AE34D241CE46F4862941EDEB33DC1E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lebanon Election Integrity and Diaspora Voting Protection Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H63974138ED9F48B7BA963E092F92C193"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H27C6631D5F6A409294F679B6EDE9767F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Free, fair, and timely elections are essential to Lebanon’s sovereignty, political stability, and democratic governance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8252C9957BC47DB8696734B5CC2FA3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Lebanon’s constitution and electoral laws provide for participation by Lebanese citizens residing abroad in parliamentary elections.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38407B9121A6468580356F6B21746A7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Lebanon’s diaspora population – estimated in the millions – plays a critical role in the country’s civic, political, and economic life.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDEA35EB4126248F4853CF8BF94EE7A64"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Hezbollah and other armed groups, corrupt political elites, and foreign actors have historically exerted undue influence over Lebanon’s political processes, including voter intimidation, manipulation of electoral administration, and obstruction of reforms enabling diaspora voting.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC97AE15771884DCB90FDB0C5AA3F9586"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Protecting the rights of Lebanese voters, including those abroad, is in the national security interest of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HCCC127A2D1644923AB30798D1786697C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of sanctions</header> <subsection id="H3F16F1C1D9EC41B9BABAA6294A41476C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President is authorized, in consultation as appropriate with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Director of National Intelligence, to impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person that the President determines—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB4AEDA2FA83F40A49F5714FEE4833489"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has engaged in, sponsored, or provided material support for actions that—</text> <subparagraph id="HAF93AAA19D534D23BE4E3122398A0033"><enum>(A)</enum><text>constitute diaspora voting obstruction; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C6682D14A694655B09345C9A2D36942"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise obstruct Lebanon’s parliamentary elections;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H390CE5D3103543839937F5822FDCAE85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has obstructed the ability of Lebanese citizens abroad to vote according to Lebanese law;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD80A61385EB422EA7E5462F409185E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has acted on behalf of, or at the direction of, any entity engaged in such activities; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CDFBC9D7721488BBC1E678B0A4B5609"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has financially, materially, or operationally assisted in any activity described in paragraphs (1) through (3).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H24C2CB5E20F14E2B913CAB9A3215C038"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text> The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H7955E593DC7D4396982220AE3A31A559"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>), the President may exercise of all powers granted to the President by that Act to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E8580A41CD34601BABDC328A66D580B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header> 
<subparagraph id="HAEA1278168E94C09AD5C0F9145EA1439"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>A foreign person that is an alien shall be—</text> <clause id="HC873B40B00CE439BA7B5335ADCD9504B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDCF1D765D5F04F22B2E804DAA5D8EBCB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDD114B4725224F4FA4DDAD91A909C911"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE14940A1D5EB4080BBE23781031B4C94"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><text>The foreign person shall be subject to the following:</text> <clause id="H1CF14423D91B4F469EF36A2605CA5C1B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB5AA5DC0320B40B9945A7C70ADE6BF0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall take effect immediately and automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the foreign person’s possession.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H891C267965FB4E3BA01806EC66985307"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other measures</header><text>Any other sanction imposed using any of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB9AF7DB456034508BEB4F081511773F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (d)(2)(A) or any regulation, license, or order issued under that subsection shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HFD8CAC05949447A690BE3DE65DD5B672"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header> <subsection id="HA733404843C446E285D10C815AB80D5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H90EECEEE22A54C599C8FCA9FC62939CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an identification of each foreign person the President determines has engaged in the actions described in <internal-xref idref="H3F16F1C1D9EC41B9BABAA6294A41476C" legis-path="3.(a)">section 3(a)</internal-xref>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0381E094E2344317BFC12AE29C13F362"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of efforts undermining diaspora voting among Lebanese citizens residing abroad; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE61ABAC70A2D4DF7BC6B188AB08C7EB8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of foreign government or proxy involvement, including Iran-backed entities, with respect to the upcoming Lebanese parliamentary elections in May 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD8E5AE7482834913965C9913BC882C15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the submission of the report required by subsection (a), and semi-annually thereafter, the President shall submit to such committees an updated report on—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE1828547514C4FE29812D0BFFC96A75C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">new individuals or entities identified as having engaged in the actions described in <internal-xref idref="H3F16F1C1D9EC41B9BABAA6294A41476C" legis-path="3.(a)">section 3(a)</internal-xref>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E199D5C0B2945AF9918A2E2C588CE6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any sanctions imposed in the preceding 180-day period with respect to such newly identified individuals;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H73E973073BD8440E952A5C7E01AFBAA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>progress or setbacks in Lebanon’s election administration; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC963744E9E142DBA27226B6C99FD915"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for strengthening election integrity and diaspora participation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE2712C91735545BEA9065B1B732E4A1F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H509A5E17C3C04D078ED40246D92D1370"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>admission</term>, <term>admitted</term>, and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7A6DF5EE4A14FADBD5137FCD16C22C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means any individual or entity that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3A6F883787D4123B389937E57979595"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>diaspora voting obstruction</term> means any action that directly or indirectly—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA2D2FE38BC154F1E84B76600B02426E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevents, limits, delays, or manipulates the ability of Lebanese citizens residing abroad to vote in Lebanon’s parliamentary elections;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87A31A44DFE0452B9C82ACD79418413C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>undermines voter registration, ballot distribution, ballot collection, or vote tabulation for overseas voters;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5CF457F32E241EC92C8923F45F48575"><enum>(C)</enum><text>intimidates, threatens, coerces, or retaliates against diaspora voters; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H90D96827443248A0ACB494D860E3C0C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>otherwise interferes with election administration in ways inconsistent with Lebanese law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD717FA3145424B2AA0638D6F968A9B47"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>obstruct</term>, with respect to Lebanon’s parliamentary elections, includes any action that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7BA252E9F9F04A62B8071DFBD4E8EC80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>undermines the timely conduct of parliamentary elections;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC003D05646C84AD990952F188BE32B0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>corrupts or manipulates electoral institutions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC48D0D5FD144B83A32163DB1ABD9B09"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engages in political violence or coercion to influence outcomes; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF6E5085DFB542D2B132B7FEF7C6A5B5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>materially supports such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC611E4DA073147A0914D6E43AF6B7BE4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H585C97725ED64D72964EF1F08FAC4FD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a citizen, national, or alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60AA79D75D7C4ED4A27C7D4B67535C3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including any foreign subsidiaries of such an entity; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB45FBBC25C6465BBC775E71EC7B589C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person located in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HAC17F078D784404C8C8D6106036DA19B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> The authority to impose sanctions under this Act shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

