<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72B62D4560E541FABB8FBD1CE934F18D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1366 IH: Commending Taiwan on the 30th anniversary of its first direct presidential election in 1996, and expressing support for Taiwan in the preservation of its democratic institutions.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1366</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending Taiwan on the 30th anniversary of its first direct presidential election in 1996, and expressing support for Taiwan in the preservation of its democratic institutions.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Taiwan, which officially calls itself the Republic of China, began transitioning to a liberal democracy in the late 1980s, lifted martial law in 1987, and held its first direct legislative election in 1992;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on March 23, 1996, the people of Taiwan held their first direct presidential election, marking a historic milestone in Taiwan’s democratic development;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Taiwan has now held 8 presidential and multiple legislative and local elections since its democratic transition, all of which were free, fair, and representative of the will of the people of Taiwan;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Taiwan has demonstrated the strength of its democratic system through multiple peaceful transfers of political power, which is a bedrock of a free, stable, and representative political system;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the democratic institutions of Taiwan codify the freedoms of speech, press, assembly, and religion into law, and the citizens of Taiwan have exercised these freedoms in practice to build a vibrant civil society, a strong journalistic and media sector, and an advanced business community;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Taiwan has continued to strengthen and safeguard its democracy in the face of growing military, economic, and political pressure from the People’s Republic of China (PRC);</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the people of Taiwan have shown resilience and steadfast commitment to democratic values despite persistent PRC coercion and intimidation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Taiwan’s democracy and respect for the rule of law contribute to peace, stability, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>), the Three Joint Communiqués, and the Six Assurances remain fundamental elements of United States policy toward Taiwan; and</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the people of the United States and the people of Taiwan continue to stand as partners against coercion, and threats to regional peace and stability: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H9D3701A2F5F4402D8B680075F5E69AF5"> 
<section id="H6A03861C8EFC461EBEE345D117FB6475" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Commemoration statement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The House of Representatives of the United States—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2253C009F364FA89BDA003500F17E62"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commemorates the significance of Taiwan’s first direct presidential election, which was held on March 23, 1996;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H94F4E34ACCB5425F84AF5496FD0CB8CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends Taiwan for building and sustaining a robust democratic system;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC180D519CE4F442CA3A397B6F60305DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>regards Taiwan’s vibrant democracy as a great example for the free world and a key component of strong and enduring United States-Taiwan relations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF3BD2EE85A94D8E8AF4737225983E2B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is committed to supporting Taiwan’s self-defense and the liberty of its people; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8BB16B850B64635A65AC8D8D085FF5A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>remains committed to the United States policy toward Taiwan that has been established by the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/8">Public Law 96–8</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>), the Three Communiqués, and the Six Assurances towards Taiwan.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE9AACCACC7954A759753C7E70AA8602B" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this resolution may be construed as authorizing the use of military force.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

