<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25J65-R3N-RC-TY2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3291 IS: Enhanced COVID-19 Transparency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3291</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251201">December 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a declassification review for intelligence relating to the COVID–19 pandemic, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id2ba612da875c44aabb600059561a8934" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhanced COVID-19 Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id49cacd589059407e8562dad17ce26084"><enum>2.</enum><header>Declassification of intelligence and additional transparency measures relating to the COVID–19 pandemic</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f652fcbfebf4343a6deb80890ab2ef1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>congressional intelligence committees</term> and <term>intelligence community</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc90aa752653947b1860760ae99093f2d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence and each head of an element of the intelligence community shall jointly—</text><paragraph id="idd2306f7155da4637bf3ec2349410274f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>perform a declassification review of intelligence products relating to the origins of the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID–19), including—</text><subparagraph id="id472421370bbb478a906d616ca3609652"><enum>(A)</enum><text>research conducted at the Wuhan Institute of Virology or any other medical or scientific research center within the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide10c0248966041a3b186def459c61f45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information relating to Gain of Function research and the intention of this research; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idabd5a2b0cd124b298df1ee7ebf21ef90"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information relating to sources of funding or direction for research on coronaviruses, including both sources within the People’s Republic of China and foreign sources;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id490abe82ad7144e090a8b114b8b55c93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>perform a declassification review of intelligence products relating to efforts by government officials of entities of the People’s Republic of China—</text><subparagraph id="idb33465782aba40c78e7580e21a50ace7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to disrupt or obstruct information sharing or investigations into the origins of the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID–19) pandemic;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddbd7df5c8f674d869e0561710784b013"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to disrupt the sharing of medically significant information relating to the transmissibility and potential harm of SARS–CoV–2 to humans, including—</text><clause id="id422e9280bab24956b349311b52e60709"><enum>(i)</enum><text>efforts to limit the sharing of information with the United States Government;</text></clause><clause id="id252aea2d32c748089c5cda4feda6d0b6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>efforts to limit the sharing of information with the governments of allies and partners of the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="idfcd2d4efc9b9480c906dfe0c0205aaba"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>efforts to limit the sharing of information with the United Nations and World Health Organization;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfcdf5a5c4944f33809f8c9b2b0a5180"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to obstruct or otherwise limit the sharing of information between national, provincial, and city governments within the People’s Republic of China and between subnational entities within the People's Republic of China and external researchers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2decb94118c6416ea94adb25828d9a6c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to deny the sharing of information with the United States, allies and partners of the United States, or multilateral organizations, including the United Nations and the World Health Organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57bd3006624a407baad1ec40237ccabf"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to pressure or lobby foreign governments, journalists, medical researchers, officials of the United States Government, or officials of multilateral organizations (including the United Nations and the World Health Organization) with respect to the source, scientific origins, transmissibility, or other attributes of the SARS–CoV–2 virus or the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae33432f38524b2b96a87b2d00e52805"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to disrupt government or private-sector efforts to conduct research and development of medical interventions or countermeasures for the COVID–19 pandemic, including vaccines; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide4b57fbb7df84a5786f563fd1c0362f7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to promote alternative narratives regarding the origins of COVID–19 as well as the domestic Chinese and international response to the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7fab573dd9946488beff01a6c83c348"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make available to the public appropriately declassified intelligence products described under paragraphs (1) and (2), including such redactions as the Director, with the concurrence of the head of the originating element of the intelligence community, determines necessary to protect sources and methods and information concerning United States persons; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idabe72decad3d4304866d594ce6654a19"><enum>(4)</enum><text>submit to the congressional intelligence committees an unredacted version of the declassified intelligence products described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

