<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7CE812592409449AA15C7911332ED352" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8859 IH: Creating Early Childhood Leaders Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8859</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260515">May 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to increase the knowledge and skills of principals and school leaders regarding early childhood education.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF8ABA9AD49864508AC586E0AD4067DCA" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H4D01846CFCB4452DB17BB46B7F26F105"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Creating Early Childhood Leaders Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H29C70BD6D43646B79D6C3CF2ADDA4199"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H1646BF6205444E0E9103AA42EC5940ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H51A1BA18A9C64C5C830AE87192677C8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Since principals and school leaders have the second largest in-school impact on student achievement (after teachers), a principal or school leader's knowledge has a substantial impact on the teachers and students under the principal or school leader's supervision.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE662BBAA6BBE4BEB812E867A97CB92BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Principals and school leaders are increasingly being asked to supervise teachers and children in pre-kindergarten programs, yet school leaders often do not have training in early childhood education.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H185A778D43314F6FB7EB683F68147203"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Given the critical development that occurs in a child’s early life and the impacts of this developmental period on later life outcomes, understanding the standards of early childhood education is particularly important.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8EE23488336D4A1F81C50187271DEEB2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to ensure that principals and school leaders are able to effectively support teachers in providing pre-kindergarten students with developmentally appropriate instruction.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H6786A5BC8E624BD5AB0A0642BB4BE9CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>School leader training regarding early childhood education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202(f)(1)(B) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1022a">20 U.S.C. 1022a(f)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA3287750EF2548598CC138A2C99170F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking clause (v) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E3586486A59408A87776A3D43337BA8">
<clause id="H4773E6BCE2484D5784D7DECB2CB8E294"><enum>(v)</enum><text>engage and involve parents, community members, the local educational agency, businesses, providers of early childhood education programs, and other community leaders, to leverage additional resources to improve student academic achievement;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0D18892EB234886B65F76DBF127E9F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (vi), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA9BA243ACDC74A79B37EB298E5EA1C35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE17518753BF45BCA9BDAE0448ABCBBB"> <clause id="H577E896B7FC24CDB9566A75AE18C2ED4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>understand child development, social and emotional development, developmentally appropriate behavioral interventions and supports, and effective instructional leadership skills for children from birth through age 8, in order to effectively manage and support developmentally appropriate early childhood education programs.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>


