<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB65A43CDA6BF457A906F24AA1E806EC4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8520 IH: Human-Services Emergency Logistics Program Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8520</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To facilitate nationwide accessibility and coordination of 211 services in order to provide information and referral to all individuals in the United States for health and human services needs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H95230DCDB1384CA3A14336A71D373A50" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAD514963C1174DE9881907A00AD2E7A0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Human-Services Emergency Logistics Program Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HELP Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HD61287B49DDF47FF8B2F99CDFDFC806E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strengthening nationwide accessibility and coordination of 211 services for information and referral for health and human services</header> 
<subsection id="H8B082918920E493DBF07F646EB5DF486"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish a program for the following purposes:</text> <paragraph id="H8F98F331878A4C3390F1FB33982405BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To increase the capacity of 211 services in the States, to ensure 211 services are directly accessible to all individuals in each State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7D4F046AF3E40E0919C2BA538892C9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To increase coordination between 211, 988, and 911 service providers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE7FF8C51E25465BBFDA913A075D1DDF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To increase awareness and use of 211 services by the public.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2848809B517045FDA1D15F905E2146A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall select one administering agency to assist the Secretary in implementing such program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H97A966C611624EDF958BD7BC6C2F1395"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allotments</header> <paragraph id="H262171C26F4E40E9BD080D441743A812"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purpose specified in subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall, using funds made available under section 6 and in consultation with the administering agency, determine the amount to be made available for grants to qualified 211 service entities in each State.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H899D20C0BC744DFD98E919BA0F107453"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Formula</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a formula for determining the total amount to be allotted for each State for the grants referred to in paragraph (1). Such formula shall be based on population, population density, poverty rate, and other evidence-based predictive data related to the needs in the State for, and access to, health and human services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HF4165D8AA945471F810856E2892A6CC5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Administering agency</header> <subsection id="H06C794E564384722ADE383E15C707823"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>An entity is eligible to be selected as the administering agency under this section if such entity is an organization that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H079AE2D6BC9744E399EC6704BF3BA50B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E7CB42323114472A6CF05D518BC1B59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has experience working with, and providing technical assistance to, 211 service providers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H961CCA7522854857BCF53E9F36BB4ACF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has established relationships with local, community-based organizations in each State; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EFAF4F11513441082BAF71BE49C2B74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has experience in disaster response and Federal grants management (and the infrastructure required to manage such grants).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H05506D39F8F44420AABC5D39F664B02B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of administering agency</header><text>The duties of the administering agency shall be—</text> <paragraph id="HEAE725E705844DB5AA6215EC69D1E711"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to the purpose specified in section 2(a)(1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H249CB656311B4827ADAF1600ADCFE41D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to advise the Secretary on, and make recommendations to, the Secretary with respect to State allotments from amounts made available under section 6, including the amount of each State allotment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE53F524A420C4ED083AA386228B45574"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to determine the amount of funding, on a State-by-State basis, using the amount of each such State allotment, to be made available to each of the qualified 211 service entities in such State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0521E7EA28944C44AE1444244B0FC943"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to award grants to such qualified 211 service entities in each State under section 4;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4E14546AF5D445AA219679A410FE009"><enum>(2)</enum><text>beginning with calendar year 2026 and not less frequently than once every 5 calendar years thereafter, to submit to the Secretary an evaluation of the network of 211 service providers throughout the United States that is conducted in accordance with subsection (d);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5187CB27E7504DCAAE88816052E6D1DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>beginning with calendar year 2026 and each calendar year thereafter, to submit to the Secretary the report under subsection (d);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBFF69A9C8DF47048AE51FCAE8DCA58C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>with respect to the purpose specified in section 2(a)(2), to increase coordination among 211 service providers, 911 service providers, 988 service providers, and other entities providing similar services; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFC363B199F74261B113D8D54890F42D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>with respect to the purpose specified in section 2(a)(3), to develop and implement a public awareness campaign that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7CC8BCBCFE0349858A9BA593D4FC3C66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educates the public with respect to the purpose, function, and use of 211 services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H79C82118C5BA480F9D8D2510FD961A27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensures consistent messaging and branding across 211 service providers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF0D82CAC5A5843EDBED646642652F75E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Shared data platforms</header><text>The administering agency may use funds reserved under section 6 to support shared data platforms, including with respect to the integration or sharing of 211 resource and service-level data.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0DF5D56C4164811B57CDF828544F586">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Application</header>
 <text>An eligible entity seeking to be selected as the administering agency under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application not less frequently than once every 10 years, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="HAB72F86C7DCF4487AEEE40DFD38AC78E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>How the eligible entity intends to—</text> <subparagraph id="H99070CB670A04B3FB520401B43216D3E"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>meet the goal of ensuring that every individual in the United States with phone or internet service can connect to 211 services at no charge; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H30ED379ECC4E4E04A4F72BDDB5E1DF26">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>meet the goal of ensuring availability, throughout each State, of 211 information and referral services with respect to health and human services.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H3518A2634E2447F5B558C3C465E9AB58">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Information about the manner in which the entity will—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA533F93F52342F3BDB2028043EE772E"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>select qualified 211 service entities to receive a grant (or subgrant) under this Act;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB686A23F2D45454E9470C5A91C420EC1">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>develop, sustain, and evaluate the 211 services provided in the United States and work to ensure sufficient 211 service provider capacity for answering and responding to calls to 211;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HFD5969C95FAD481799296F9016D90EC1">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>provide for increased coordination between 211, 911, and 988 systems and other entities providing similar services to divert calls to mental health and human services responders who can assist individuals and link individuals with voluntary, community-based services, as appropriate; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H639C89D8FF1E442FB73E08D84C3AD550">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>use annual 211 operational data to inform the eligible entity’s approach to assessing the program and establishing oversight metrics.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAFCBBFFEF43041168ACAEA116BFE2122">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>A certification that the entity will take all steps necessary to ensure that all activities and information provided by the qualified 211 service entities receiving grants (or eligible 211 service provider receiving a subgrant) pursuant to this Act will be directly accessible for purposes of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794d">29 U.S.C. 794d</external-xref>), and part 1194 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations).</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HAE9B236871D848CBB6295158D5259F06"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation and reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H136A21319E0645E296FBD7A7AB4767E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H727B8EA6CACA4B4F9411FD8D37B89EDB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The administering agency shall award a contract to an independent entity to conduct the evaluation specified in subsection (b)(2).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAD80970C516442D81D1A69D81ECCA40"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The evaluation under subsection (b)(2) shall address—</text> 
<clause id="H2DDA7D7216EA4816BA0F7BE80674FF0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>barriers to access to 211 services;</text></clause> <clause id="HE9121471E69D4CBC9E4FA6153BB6802A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>effectiveness of 211 services at connecting individuals to needed health and human services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H88C526974EA94C0FA5C4AE7016B5BF6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of collaborations among 211, 988, and 911 systems, and other entities providing similar services;</text></clause> <clause id="H42E3D97D1B464E7C959880E47BF4179E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the comprehensiveness of the information in the 211 databases;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H61006261764B424F86C241975A3EAE0D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>public awareness of 211 services; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7F3E9C60A3EC4931980D85B903350925"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>user satisfaction with 211 services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67D637F91D924F81B3F3287594D4E970"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The administering agency shall submit to the Secretary a report on the program carried out under this section, with information disaggregated by State and by each eligible 211 service provider, which shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HD0672B61886E4C18801A1A0458612541"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe the activities or services funded through a grant by each qualified 211 service entity receiving such a grant (or each eligible 211 service provider receiving a subgrant);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D44D5265BC54DD4AEB44ADF9447C4F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess the effectiveness of such activities and services in making available, to all residents of the State, 211 services for information and referrals with respect to health and human services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8B6025A901843659EFBDAF11A2AB94C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assess the effectiveness of collaboration with resource and referral entities and service providers; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0D9C344AB8044872ABFD083EE52DBF4D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>describe the services to which individuals were referred by eligible 211 service providers receiving funding under this Act and any efforts to track the effectiveness of such referrals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H3796E7C1A6E14C6282CA58E9D08808D9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants to 211 service entities to increase capacity</header> <subsection id="HF35069B9880F448AAC74E8774E1C77AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The administering agency shall make grants to qualified 211 service entities in a State to expand the availability and accessibility of 211 services in the State.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA773CB9D3BB484387E3547473B47BA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The administering agency shall, as a condition on the receipt of funding under this Act, ensure that any qualified 211 service entity selected by the administering agency to receive a grant using such funds, only use such grant for—</text> <paragraph id="HD26EE00903C24597BD70A839F8B3E9E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the provision of 211 services via voice, short message service, or other messaging, internet, or other communication methods, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H03DCCF8212E34492958D384247345CEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the operation and maintenance of 211 contact centers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8D9B297491AE4F73AD3185BD02E7B7F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing public awareness of 211 services in the State in collaboration with 911 and 988 services and other entities providing similar services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D4FEECEA1AF4A40906595F2C8D637FA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordination of the State’s 211 services, including the collection, accessibility, and display of information through information and referral databases;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1A82F27787714F85828760A1A77E206B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the conduct of statewide and regional planning for the provision of 211 services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94B4AC948CB2429C99507471C2D1D3C5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any activities necessary to ensure that 211 services are directly accessible, consistent with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794d">29 U.S.C. 794d</external-xref>), and part 1194 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96A7288E6AF4482AA8138557F3FA43FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the start-up costs of extending 211 services to unserved areas, including costs of software and hardware upgrades and telecommunications and internet costs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22DCEE9CC70C4035994131227CB247E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>administrative costs, such as staffing, training, and activities related to accreditation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB118FC9344D74E74874A8C89877A26EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>infrastructure costs, including internet hosting and site development and maintenance for an information and referral database and the development and maintenance of cloud-based data and messaging capacity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE4DB7F242484C64AB135FD5016CA2A9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the evaluation of 211 service provider activities and capacity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC7140CFCC4B400CAB639ACFAE2AEF96"><enum>(6)</enum><text>increasing coordination and collaboration—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE639A4522640471282D639EAC7B7BD98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>among 211 services within the State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6C7F3135CFF4B298837E6F903A6A2CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with local 911 and 988 service providers; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FC8951DA3974768ADED1419BA15CF43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with shared data platforms, including with respect to the integration or sharing of resource and service-level data;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72ACCB8320E248D59CC781B7331C3DB6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the preparation and submission of reports under State reporting requirements and to the administering agency for purposes of section 3(b)(4);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6882D14FEC1945DC95E7A7FF3B28491E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>innovations that support service delivery; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D68AF338B6F4001A9936D077D554063"><enum>(9)</enum><text>carrying out such other activities determined to be appropriate by the administering agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H106034273F1C49BDB4ADDC73290CC781"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection</header> 
<paragraph id="HEE0432BEFBA04B0DBFD762580CC82869"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5353110EA93E41229FFEE9B72059E450"><enum>(A)</enum><header>State 211 networks</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the administering agency shall award the State allocation determined under section 3(b)(1) to the eligible State 211 network in each State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16E66231521C4E57899EE74F25CEEDF6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If the administering agency determines there is no eligible State 211 network in a State, the administering agency shall award grants from the State allotment determined under section 3(b)(1) directly to all eligible 211 service providers in such State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06C613EEB009471E9BBA4B15F6BD626E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In awarding grants to all eligible 211 service providers in a State under paragraph (1)(B), the administering agency shall consider—</text> <subparagraph id="H4618CE0D6F164A3DA3031D2971D02560"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ability of the 211 service provider seeking the grant to carry out activities in furtherance of the provision of 211 services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56F56C611E664F419EFE67BEC3BEAC22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which the award of the grant will facilitate equitable geographic distribution of grants to ensure that rural communities have access to 211 services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF0EAF565A8BA4AAEA0DDFA7757A777FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which the award of the grant will further the goals of—</text> 
<clause id="H754A5946C8DB4CD7B220C652AEAA8E33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>making available 211 services to all individuals in a State via voice, short message service, or other messaging, internet, or other communication methods; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB4AC04728C8D4C7CB6E2DE3374438858"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increasing the provision of community information and referral with respect to health and human services, among individuals, families, agencies seeking such services and the providers of such services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H257911426FF442D796E541246BA8157C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The administering agency shall ensure that each qualified 211 service entity submits an application and agrees, as a condition on the receipt of funds under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H3EF7DF76442147E9AA25CCAAA7C55CF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in making 211 services available, to the maximum extent practicable, to—</text> 
<clause id="HBCCEC914FC2B43318294B003169D4D6C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>abide by the most recently issued version of the Inform USA Standards and Quality Indicators for Professional Information and Referral or a comparable set of standards;</text></clause> <clause id="H9B752FBDA7DB425DA1F8F911C60A0A0F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>collaborate with public and private organizations that provide health and human services and existing national, regional, and local information and referral systems to provide an exhaustive and comprehensive database of services that is maintained and updated on a consistent basis from which to provide information or referrals to individuals using 211 services; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H29CA3ECDD534477EAB4D723B8DF66D0C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensure State-level coordination across all 211 service providers in such State; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2698FB90497E4E29A6031960ABE0DF60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide matching funds, in the form of cash or in-kind contributions, from non-Federal sources in an amount equal to not less than 25 percent of the amount of funds received by the entity under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCDECCB1F5F8046AA8A703A5199845DAE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative costs for certain states</header><text>In the case of a State described in subsection (c)(1)(B), the administering agency may use, of the amount of the allocation determined for such State under section 2(c), an amount determined by the administering agency necessary to cover additional administrative expenses incurred by the administering agency resulting from the lack of an eligible State 211 network in such State.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC124F108E5BE4364ADDF354A5CB9E84F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF5A21BAD1B16424FA9F25153BEF48B8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>211 service</header><text>The term <quote>211 service</quote> means providing individuals with information and referrals, via voice telephone, text telephone, short message service, text, internet phone, or other communication methods, with respect to health and human services and referrals to agencies providing health and human services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1C24CD496F5486EB0C4966B5EAA9371"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible 211 service provider</header><text>The term <quote>eligible 211 service provider</quote> means a provider of 211 services that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3B1C87FE90F44255B8500A2A7E2D4376"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a nonprofit or governmental entity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A780EF8117846DFA31D6BEC06B194D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the capability (directly or through contract with another entity) to provide such services via phone at no charge to the consumer; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE21E3131818A490086843D090F12ED89">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>has access to the applicable State or local 211 dialing code.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBC13A9F50054740B6C1311082035AEE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified 211 service entity</header><text>The term <quote>qualified 211 service entity</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB3F89BAC1A134A00BD888D8CC0AF892C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an eligible State 211 network; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C671FEFA4BB49669F7A9CE613642017"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a State described in section 4(c)(1)(B), an eligible 211 service provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9169C7E9C094636A56E30AD5EF77536"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible state 211 network</header><text>The term <quote>eligible State 211 network</quote> means a nonprofit entity that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD44A320A0F81421D88E3C48EE7099C65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>represents all eligible 211 service providers in a State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H786AD74FC4F44D30AFA53CC7723E6F47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides coordination or infrastructure for providers of 211 services, including—</text> <clause id="HB7FF70F1217C46BFB28848E24B1028E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>acting as a fiscal agent for State 211 funding; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF1861379B8BC426A9F28065B91F4DA86">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>supporting information and referral databases, phone systems, dashboards, web access, or text and website chat tools.</text>
          </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDB422C98BE84767AAAB4E2F5ADD4F00"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Health and human services</header><text>The term <quote>health and human services</quote> means services provided with respect to homelessness and housing supports, veterans resources, food assistance, disaster response and recovery resources, workforce development, community health resources, mental health resources, caregiving resources, domestic violence resources, and other health and human service needs, that—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A216C151DDB4F4FB306D50D41A7E75A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assist individuals in becoming more self-sufficient, in preventing dependency, and in strengthening family relationships;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4652C9813A0243B49256FD6CA77CCCB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>address social determinants of health;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H422137E4113B418CBB7791ED10E08B74"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support personal and social development; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H672EB2FD95AF416D93D1097826ADF346"><enum>(D)</enum><text>help ensure the health and well-being of individuals, families, and communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5FFA99AD3E7407CB91BB3CBAA101E6C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian Tribe; Tribal organization</header><text>The terms <quote>Indian Tribe</quote> and <quote>Tribal organization</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D0C159970104AC7B679F326E33A76DC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD07389136BC04DBA9028268A372F91EC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Funding</header> <subsection id="HB8A6B73375D04FFFB62E5BE741791FD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $250,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2032, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5038AEA9419D43F48F8CC8938E67FBE9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>Of the amount made available under paragraph (1) to carry out this Act for a fiscal year, the Secretary may reserve not more than 10 percent for administrative and coordinating activities by the administering agency (including the expenditures referred to in section 4(d)).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

