<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-stage="proposed" amend-type="engrossed-amendment" amend-degree="first" key="H"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1383 EAH: SAVE America Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<distribution-code display="no"><?xm-replace_text {distribution code}?></distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date> 
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">AMENDMENT:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form> 
<engrossed-amendment-body> 
<section section-type="resolved" id="H483024832"> <text>That the bill from the Senate (S. 1383) entitled <quote>An Act to establish the Veterans Advisory Committee on Equal Access, and for other purposes.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment> <amendment-instruction line-numbers="off"><text>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert:</text></amendment-instruction>
<amendment-block id="HA980652A08B941369B57B15844682222" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic">
<section id="HE71B1D31E3EC4779A317A2D743361A70" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguard American Voter Eligibility Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>SAVE America Act</quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEC16C82F940242E48C6752F1640C95B2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring only citizens are registered to vote in elections for Federal office</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEDB30544DB547D3A728609AD2FC1FE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of documentary proof of United States citizenship</header><text>Section 3 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20502">52 U.S.C. 20502</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H04D4476EA001488F83666B9C2308C035"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>As used</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—As used</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DC03197457B4BFE835326830ADF0C3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H688DCC7B94364713BD80CFDA1B624482">
<subsection id="H73F87BA884034BE8837CD4FEBA5EB7DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Documentary proof of United States citizenship</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As used in this Act, the term <term>documentary proof of United States citizenship</term> means, with respect to an applicant for voter registration, any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2281D0D5C2404D40BB7F368C0DA12E10"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A form of identification issued consistent with the requirements of the REAL ID Act of 2005 that indicates the applicant is a citizen of the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5ECE133304244C51ADF8891B5A97F456"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A valid United States passport.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AF7DEC3D0FC4026AE5BE90470E03CBF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicant's official United States military identification card, together with a United States military record of service showing that the applicant's place of birth was in the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H36DFE22F0A4F4C8BA949715CAB298BD1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A valid government-issued photo identification card issued by a Federal, State or Tribal government showing that the applicant’s place of birth was in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H704CC9D148E248EBB87A96421701221B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A valid government-issued photo identification card issued by a Federal, State or Tribal government other than an identification described in paragraphs (1) through (4), but only if presented together with one or more of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HE903DBEAB6404E61B7CB8B5CCBB4EDCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A certified birth certificate issued by a State, a unit of local government in a State, or a Tribal government which—</text> <clause id="HC838054273024A89AEE13504F64E38AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was issued by the State, unit of local government, or Tribal government in which the applicant was born;</text></clause>
<clause id="H81A24FF9A99F4D8BABB3E51F75033749"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was filed with the office responsible for keeping vital records in the State;</text></clause> <clause id="H9A0AD3650A104DA8A756F8E39BE16A8B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>includes the full name, date of birth, and place of birth of the applicant;</text></clause>
<clause id="HD17CC7C71E7B4ECEA7778AB6B74849F9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>lists the full names of one or both of the parents of the applicant;</text></clause> <clause id="H2ABA3AA2C29B4972A6F5B49172A828C8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>has the signature of an individual who is authorized to sign birth certificates on behalf of the State, unit of local government, or Tribal government in which the applicant was born;</text></clause>
<clause id="HDFCE6D1A865243E99D5797C8AB2DFA95"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes the date that the certificate was filed with the office responsible for keeping vital records in the State; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF1AF481CEB6841098AFDE8DD9F418D05"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the seal of the State, unit of local government, or Tribal government that issued the birth certificate.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H798A8D2F0F5E4115AD03FF3DF0B803FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An extract from a United States hospital Record of Birth created at the time of the applicant's birth which indicates that the applicant’s place of birth was in the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2BFBE3A0029475BAC45277EFCE814D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A final adoption decree showing the applicant’s name and that the applicant’s place of birth was in the United States.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBF8024F580E2427483DBA8717FFDAD2B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Consular Report of Birth Abroad of a citizen of the United States or a certification of the applicant’s Report of Birth of a United States citizen issued by the Secretary of State.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EEE846C32DC4820BDAE143C937D50AE"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Naturalization Certificate or Certificate of Citizenship issued by the Secretary of Homeland Security or any other document or method of proof of United States citizenship issued by the Federal government pursuant to the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H859FAF03CCBE4CBAB57827CF0CD07CCF"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An American Indian Card issued by the Department of Homeland Security with the classification ‘KIC’.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H850B99460A674E338AA9ED298C17CC2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of requirements</header><text>Section 4 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20503">52 U.S.C. 20503</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C444627DDB54C26900554568FBA8B1C">
<subsection id="HF9457293D165455C8CFD43F327B32A34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requiring applicants To present documentary proof of United States citizenship</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under any method of voter registration in a State, the State shall not accept and process an application to register to vote in an election for Federal office unless the applicant presents documentary proof of United States citizenship with the application.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HA758C7F260B24E59BC3AD350C0571350"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Registration with application for motor vehicle driver’s license</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20504">52 U.S.C. 20504</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H139A45947ED64343A38ADDF0F6115E56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>Each State motor vehicle driver's license application</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to the requirements under section 8(j), each State motor vehicle driver's license application</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75CC75AA4AC144A19704CD8A6A0868E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by striking <quote>Each State shall include</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to the requirements under section 8(j), each State shall include</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H63390E56247A4ACA807B647F9A58DA2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)(B)—</text> <subparagraph id="H1EFC547B41D845479A0AA61146D4C36A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE72DC150A4A840A0B11B8635F94BB534"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92EEAEC8B4DC411CB03606CB20A3F326"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB26FBD35F3C74B47A876D0E3080897EC">
<clause id="H2A974BCE510841728C5CCD4B02A66E59" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">verify that the applicant is a citizen of the United States;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25C9741B66D0431FA69AA09C3B93C967"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(2)(C)(i), by striking <quote>(including citizenship)</quote> and inserting <quote>, including the requirement that the applicant provides documentary proof of United States citizenship</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F30F7EA63BC46D9B99199856391C768"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(2)(D)(iii), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>, other than as evidence in a criminal proceeding or immigration proceeding brought against an applicant who knowingly attempts to register to vote and knowingly makes a false declaration under penalty of perjury that the applicant meets the eligibility requirements to register to vote in an election for Federal office; and</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC7FBCFC9E9324256A402C556A716C35A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requiring documentary proof of United States citizenship with national mail voter registration form</header><text>Section 6 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20505">52 U.S.C. 20505</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HD0B0FD2A57344FB6969D054122D9CABB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF293E8D9F6284CEC8AB74E93CD9B3079"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Each State shall accept and use</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to the requirements under section 8(j), each State shall accept and use</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0AFDE57D76EA446ABABCB90E126157B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Federal Election Commission</quote> and inserting <quote>Election Assistance Commission</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5079E04C232F4CA6B8F6A9BD9D414E9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following: <quote>The chief State election official of a State shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that residents of the State are aware of the requirement to provide documentary proof of United States citizenship to register to vote in elections for Federal office in the State.</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA8B760DE2F5042CAA2F1200FF025E4DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0E18E774A20844F6B6AF0A6B7350016E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFDCDC2477D7C46DBA853352EA4B6E2D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E15B968B7114931B723E63CC5D772BB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE7061441FB494269AC35D080E64215E9">
<subparagraph id="H7A17A307A0EB4383998D5A4799B60B92"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the person did not provide documentary proof of United States citizenship when registering to vote.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCF6385425654162BB7B0F56CE32F380"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EE829C829594418B81AE74E09A82BBC">
<subsection id="H91C83635B684445494566C878C22720C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Ensuring proof of United States citizenship</header>
<paragraph id="H31E852A388EB461E8245BF707B93CCD4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Presenting proof of United States citizenship to election official</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An applicant who submits the mail voter registration application form prescribed by the Election Assistance Commission pursuant to section 9(a)(2) or a form described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) shall not be registered to vote in an election for Federal office unless—</text> <subparagraph id="H7BFDF3D0E2D8465999BEC55FCE098983"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant presents documentary proof of United States citizenship in person to the office of the appropriate election official not later than the deadline provided by State law for the receipt of a completed voter registration application for the election; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2F47AB341AD849199B063E994383E5AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a State which permits an individual to register to vote in an election for Federal office at a polling place on the day of the election and on any day when voting, including early voting, is permitted for the election, the applicant presents documentary proof of United States citizenship to the appropriate election official at the polling place not later than the date of the election.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9971DB2AFC174D9DB25EA129E2D8E1DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification of requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receiving an otherwise completed mail voter registration application form prescribed by the Election Assistance Commission pursuant to section 9(a)(2) or a form described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a), the appropriate election official shall transmit a notice to the applicant of the requirement to present documentary proof of United States citizenship under this subsection, and shall include in the notice instructions to enable the applicant to meet the requirement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCB4CDDEC8F6040989A17E1FEA2D1B2E7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall, in consultation with the Election Assistance Commission, ensure that reasonable accommodations are made to allow an individual with a disability who submits the mail voter registration application form prescribed by the Election Assistance Commission pursuant to section 9(a)(2) or a form described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) to present documentary proof of United States citizenship to the appropriate election official.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2537948BDF7A4A2B9FFB67C798E381B4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirements for voter registration agencies</header><text>Section 7 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20506">52 U.S.C. 20506</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HB7880A8852F349D29A7CB8C342C709CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC364F41C941A47B4B6E2F88F8658E2C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A), by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6DBE5D24D2304FF19E0669EC7E6A7058">
<clause id="HE38479BFE3464355BC5ACE7C3116DBE5" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Receipt of documentary proof of United States citizenship of each applicant to register to vote in elections for Federal office in the State.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30EFBB2D978C4C429BBC6DC03F511156"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text>
<clause id="HF9646193567643F7B7B6E50B8A09C4DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i)(I), by striking <quote>(including citizenship)</quote> and inserting <quote>, including the requirement that the applicant provides documentary proof of United States citizenship</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H1986E36C253041A986DA940AB82AC3FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) and (C) as subparagraphs (C) and (D), respectively; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HA866F8272880419AA0E925153A06DF6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2EA43E965ED641C3B0392FD4896FD536"> <subparagraph id="H0912AAAB79B141BCB1CC82882796F0DE" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ask the applicant the question, <quote>Are you a citizen of the United States?</quote> and if the applicant answers in the affirmative require documentary proof of United States citizenship prior to providing the form under subparagraph (C);</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE9CCA8994C2B4204AD3FBAA112A3A357"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by inserting <quote>who are citizens of the United States</quote> after <quote>for persons</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H797B3334820B4BF08974C17074603076"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Requirements with respect to administration of voter registration</header><text>Section 8 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20507">52 U.S.C. 20507</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HBAF6EA18D65C4947B5817057469C9661"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H6AD513C0D37D45A88A5B2069B2083E2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In the administration of voter registration</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to the requirements of subsection (j), in the administration of voter registration</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBD4C1B9115AC4E8192F6D6212B9C6A4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <clause id="H07503F067DA945828EAD09491F3EE7A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HB494A9CADB6941FBB3317897D1DCCC8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAAB8A5EDD7564649BB7995E037552A27"> <subparagraph id="H5F306EBE03344A86B91C2D232C51FD71"><enum>(D)</enum><text>based on documentary proof or verified information that the registrant is not a United States citizen; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0C7CF70334684C81B7AC24C1CB7A2A57"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the registration otherwise fails to comply with applicable State law;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4626D1DDA9B4254BE9B06A4C21864F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (j) as subsection (l); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H83880454E02B4966AA9256B53B6888E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (i) the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC819ACBD146C487AA276187E10031300"> <subsection id="HEA67C3EE0E9F4F01B7951575A5593287"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Ensuring only citizens are registered to vote</header> <paragraph id="H7998B98A987F423C9EA79FE648669063"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, a State may not register an individual to vote in elections for Federal office held in the State unless, at the time the individual applies to register to vote, the individual provides documentary proof of United States citizenship.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31792441B71F4B44805283172FE818C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement in cases of name discrepancies in documentation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a State shall accept and process an application to register to vote in an election for Federal office if the applicant—</text> <subparagraph id="HA217C51D77A94DEFA05A39CC6E21E5CF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>presents with the application documentation that would constitute documentary proof of United States citizenship, except that the name on the documentation is not the name of the applicant; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4FA78C7FC1004696A3B68761492C4402" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides, through a process established by the State (which shall be subject to any relevant guidance adopted by the Election Assistance Commission)—</text> <clause id="H4BFBEB456C7C4309AB9D8654C90FEC20" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>additional documentation as necessary to establish that the name on the documentation is a previous name of the applicant; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H977C8EFCABCE42DBBA133B82BC30D303" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an affidavit signed by the applicant attesting that the name on the documentation is a previous name of the applicant.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D396242576A437E90F339AF9DB396A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional processes in certain cases</header> <subparagraph id="HEB5D890A136E4E2F9C447941018EDA5F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Process for those without documentary proof</header> <clause id="H39D0FBA89D7A48D79ADAA64596A3AA5A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to any relevant guidance adopted by the Election Assistance Commission, each State shall establish a process under which an applicant who cannot provide documentary proof of United States citizenship under paragraph (1) may, if the applicant signs an attestation under penalty of perjury that the applicant is a citizen of the United States and eligible to vote in elections for Federal office, submit such other evidence to the appropriate State or local official demonstrating that the applicant is a citizen of the United States and such official shall make a determination as to whether the applicant has sufficiently established United States citizenship for purposes of registering to vote in elections for Federal office in the State.</text></clause>
<clause id="HE255E369123B447CABA09CC35D2A64A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Affidavit requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a State or local official makes a determination under clause (i) that an applicant has sufficiently established United States citizenship for purposes of registering to vote in elections for Federal office in the State, such determination shall be accompanied by an affidavit developed under clause (iii) signed by the official swearing or affirming the applicant sufficiently established United States citizenship for purposes of registering to vote.</text></clause> <clause id="HE43674B02B554853A810813296572114"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Development of affidavit by the Election Assistance Commission</header><text>The Election Assistance Commission shall develop a uniform affidavit for use by State and local officials under clause (ii), which shall—</text>
<subclause id="HDB6101BEFFE444F2969A5FF533F26ED4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>include an explanation of the minimum standards required for a State or local official to register an applicant who cannot provide documentary proof of United States citizenship to vote in elections for Federal office in the State; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA5E75FC0524C49D8B3167C77C052F0F3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>require the official to explain the basis for registering such applicant to vote in such elections.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF38F47361F6F4C7A86ACB08585E17CC2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Process in case of certain discrepancies in documentation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to any relevant guidance adopted by the Election Assistance Commission, each State shall establish a process under which an applicant can provide such additional documentation to the appropriate election official of the State as may be necessary to establish that the applicant is a citizen of the United States in the event of a discrepancy with respect to the applicant’s documentary proof of United States citizenship.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EC2404A04854414812A26E8F5C35446"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State requirements</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection:</text>
<subparagraph id="HAFD8F14E0ADC412D9A5B164ECAAD15B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each State shall take affirmative steps, on an ongoing basis, to ensure that only United States citizens are registered to vote under the provisions of this Act, and such affirmative steps shall include the establishment of a program described in subparagraphs (B) and (C).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD99DEFF6F0A34B279314E12BC1805F56"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall submit the complete, official list of individuals registered as eligible voters for Federal office in the State to the Department of Homeland Security for comparison through the Systematic Alien Verification for Entitlements (<quote>SAVE</quote>) system for the purposes of identifying individuals who are not citizens of the United States and taking the necessary steps to remove such individuals who are not citizens from the official list, after notice is given to such individuals and such individuals are given the opportunity to provide documentary proof of United States citizenship, but a State with a memorandum of agreement for such purposes with the Department of Homeland Security on the date of the enactment of this subsection may comply with this subparagraph by carrying out such purposes under the memorandum.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3BDFEA76313C41AE8C728A7E2A7977BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Each State may utilize such other sources of data available to the State for the purposes of identifying individuals who are not citizens of the United States and removing such individuals from the official list of eligible voters for Federal office in the State, including (but not limited to) the following:</text> <clause id="H0D1D9EADC0B043A6AF2A086DF9D51524"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State agencies that supply State identification cards or driver’s licenses where the agency confirms the United States citizenship status of applicants.</text></clause>
<clause id="H0698F4EBBE9240EF95D212A3AD9C3729"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other sources, including databases and information provided pursuant to an agreement with the Commissioner of Social Security under section 205(r)(9) of the Social Security Act, which can be used to confirm United States citizenship status, except that any such information provided by the Commissioner may not be the sole grounds for the removal of an individual from the official list of eligible voters for elections for Federal office in a State.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1945C2E6589B4BE697270999E3D7D090"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Availability of information</header> <subparagraph id="H62AB8179497A4BC6B62032F6FAE12286"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of a State election official (including a request related to a process established by a State under paragraph (3)(A) or (3)(B)), any head of a Federal department or agency possessing information relevant to determining the eligibility of an individual to vote in elections for Federal office shall, not later than 24 hours after receipt of such request, provide the official with such information as may be necessary to enable the official to verify that an applicant for voter registration in elections for Federal office held in the State or a registrant on the official list of eligible voters in elections for Federal office held in the State is a citizen of the United States, which shall include providing the official with such batched information as may be requested by the official.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9D3F3FC959E04C94A0116835121BC508"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of SAVE system</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may respond to a request received under paragraph (1) by using the system for the verification of immigration status under the applicable provisions of section 1137 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-7">42 U.S.C. 1320b–7</external-xref>), as established pursuant to section 121(c) of the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/99/603">Public Law 99–603</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87EBEAF29B684E30BD09CF32A4B95874"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Sharing of information</header><text>The heads of Federal departments and agencies shall share information with each other with respect to an individual who is the subject of a request received under paragraph (A) in order to enable them to respond to the request.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE009098EAD674DF0A753362035706222"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Investigation for purposes of removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall conduct an investigation to determine whether to initiate removal proceedings under section 239 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1229">8 U.S.C. 1229</external-xref>) if it is determined pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (B) that an alien (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)) is unlawfully registered to vote in elections for Federal office.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C2073C0BDDB4009928D7E1C6E9B1201"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Prohibiting fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of a Federal department or agency may not charge a fee for responding to a State’s request under paragraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE01BF88043249F29374969BDA7CF395"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Removal of noncitizens from registration rolls</header><text>A State shall remove an individual who is not a citizen of the United States from the official list of eligible voters for elections for Federal office held in the State at any time upon receipt of documentation or verified information that a registrant is not a United States citizen.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72EBACA652CA4BEFACDF93669C06487C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Clarification of authority of State To remove noncitizens from official list of eligible voters</header> <paragraph id="HE24E63FFF78E48559F7B91493143FCBE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8(a)(4) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20507">52 U.S.C. 20507(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="H49B96FC994474F57AE0171F7578C656E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0381DF4D51C84452A3DB8D5AEA7E3CEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H596F5EE40FA742A0B6CC21709D9C99B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FA487C7DD48453D9E8DCC71C1515D29"> <subparagraph id="H0C0D3D4A3CF04B319E1E374CBBDAD75C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">documentary proof or verified information that the registrant is not a United States citizen;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0E071CB26B50453ABAD69712325EF8C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 8(c)(2)(B)(i) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20507">52 U.S.C. 20507(c)(2)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>(4)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>(4)(A) or (C)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7BA995E4045B4430A6919C19A2D92E47"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Requirements with respect to Federal mail voter registration form</header> <paragraph id="HF58DE6895A1F40F5A7AF2B6E6797563A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contents of mail voter registration form</header><text>Section 9(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20508">52 U.S.C. 20508(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1AFE9069302E49D186E2C0760B83BCD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>(including citizenship)</quote> and inserting <quote>(including an explanation of what is required to present documentary proof of United States citizenship)</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C9502EB25634492BEE86518B189200F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBCE0B42D6AAD45948B76BD45725ED975"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDF715719D844DF8A386AEEB996AB1F6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C7BF8C6B00A40D5B30C8B821DD26C2D">
<paragraph id="HE701754CA03541D8B329A620CC87B3F7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include a section, for use only by a State or local election official, to record the type of document the applicant presented as documentary proof of United States citizenship, including the date of issuance, the date of expiration (if any), the office which issued the document, and any unique identification number associated with the document.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H378A344E13CE4F9CA82F847EEA4EC767"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information on mail voter registration form</header><text>Section 9(b)(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20508">52 U.S.C. 20508(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="H148625AB1C894271AF4E333CCE38DA01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) through (iii) as subparagraphs (A) through (C), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1B1121675F0439E88BA4B8594D28B69"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C) (as so redesignated and as amended by paragraph (1)(C)), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>, other than as evidence in a criminal proceeding or immigration proceeding brought against an applicant who attempts to register to vote and makes a false declaration under penalty of perjury that the applicant meets the eligibility requirements to register to vote in an election for Federal office; and</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H83EFE2327BBA4D4593F6EBBAE4384DD7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11(b)(1) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20510">52 U.S.C. 20510(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>a violation of this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>a violation of this Act, including the act of an election official who registers an applicant to vote in an election for Federal office who fails to present documentary proof of United States citizenship,</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA0BC337DC9D4EF3A891B67754FE86DE"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Criminal penalties</header><text>Section 12(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20511">52 U.S.C. 20511(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H50C5D389623547AE8DC7A0725470F2CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8951BD5DAFBB48BBB2CDCD333EF2B479"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (D); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBC898D7C64564B769D7D1BA16A7B3C24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7329209C6C04848BD76520BB3D8179A"> <subparagraph id="HCCEFAF6C7CD64378A51F2CF59384291F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an officer or employee of the executive branch, providing material assistance to a noncitizen in attempting to register to vote or vote in an election for Federal office;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD356F966A8CB491A9957074417678308"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">registering an applicant to vote in an election for Federal office who fails to present documentary proof of United States citizenship; or</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H554D6365996D4038ACACED311C158F2E"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Special rule for States not requiring voter registration</header><text>Section 4 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20503">52 U.S.C. 20503</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA63661E2A9A949CD9667175D56C41E2C" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="H97D5DDE481BA442D9D2E3A074ED442D2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rule for States not requiring voter registration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State or jurisdiction that does not require voter registration as a requirement to vote in an election for Federal office on or after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the State or jurisdiction shall be deemed to meet the requirements of this Act if the State or jurisdiction establishes a system for confirming the citizenship of individuals voting in an election for Federal office prior to the first day for voting with respect to such election and provides such confirmation of citizenship status for each eligible voter to election officials at the polling places during the voting period.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HAEB23E5EFC414D20AF4EA9B1E14F5D63"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Election Assistance Commission guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Election Assistance Commission shall adopt and transmit to the chief State election official of each State guidance with respect to the implementation of the requirements under the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20501">52 U.S.C. 20501 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC5D70438F2F941579F87C75480284756"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Inapplicability of Paperwork Reduction Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>) shall not apply with respect to the development or modification of voter registration materials under the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20501">52 U.S.C. 20501 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by this section, including the development or modification of any voter registration application forms.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2513C4829E0046F097A805BF5EB80AEB"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Duty of Secretary of Homeland Security To notify election officials of naturalization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receiving information that an individual has become a naturalized citizen of the United States, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall promptly provide notice of such information to the appropriate chief election official of the State in which such individual is domiciled.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF97BFD12194D4D4CA8AB043E002DCE22"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Rule of construction regarding provisional ballots</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section or in any amendment made by this section may be construed to supercede, restrict, or otherwise affect the ability of an individual to cast a provisional ballot in an election for Federal office or to have the ballot counted in the election if the individual is verified as a citizen of the United States pursuant to section 8(j) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (as added by subsection (f)).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3745A8E3AE1D44AEBE785E76AFBBE30B"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Rule of construction regarding effect on State exemptions from other Federal laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section or in any amendment made by this section may be construed to affect the exemption of a State from any requirement of any Federal law other than the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20501">52 U.S.C. 20501 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HAE5CD98BE469405DAEEF7CD79DB541AC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Exception for absent uniformed services voters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements in this section shall not apply with respect to an applicant who is an absent uniformed services voter, as defined in section 107(1) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20310">52 U.S.C. 20310(1)</external-xref>). </text></subsection> <subsection id="H4514C00BCD044DA0A2F0373153C5CA26"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section and the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this section, and shall apply with respect to applications for voter registration which are submitted on or after such date.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H8A06FCD3A7D74BF89E0E66338D0D2234" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requiring voters to provide photo identification</header>
<subsection id="H755142B1E8CB4D2793453551AEA5869D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement to provide photo identification as condition of casting ballot</header>
<paragraph id="H1307BFF7D9764BE3A804E0ADFC985473"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 303 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8AD5A7DC3814172965A3AD19E620FA2"> <section id="HDC0AF51FD8B94D96834B66003ED1EF6C"><enum>303A.</enum><header>Photo identification requirements</header> <subsection id="HB9865B205F6A4905BEC4A4A3F63C3154"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of identification required as condition of casting ballot</header> <paragraph id="H3DB9FDA6C15A442486D7000720EF9A77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individuals voting in person</header> <subparagraph id="H845737F5C8034393A347A1FFABDB0A77"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement to provide identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subparagraph (B), the appropriate State or local election official may not provide a ballot for an election for Federal office to an individual who desires to vote in person unless the individual presents to the official a valid physical photo identification.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H805B3210254F48028CFC94896505C42C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability of provisional ballot</header>
<clause id="H5323C670AA4547059762EA5E80F33920"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual does not present the identification required under subparagraph (A), the individual shall be permitted to cast a provisional ballot with respect to the election under section 302(a), except that the appropriate State or local election official may not make a determination under section 302(a)(4) that the individual is eligible under State law to vote in the election unless, not later than 3 days after casting the provisional ballot, the individual presents to the official—</text> <subclause id="H8840DD611CA64D0B8D2514ADC2DCDA16"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the identification required under subparagraph (A); or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H8CE50ABB5A42479A8CF7D8BC1C8185FF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an affidavit developed and made available to the individual by the State attesting that the individual does not possess the identification required under subparagraph (A) because the individual has a religious objection to being photographed.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H65C310A48DF94F18B612EFB7CFE2B92D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No effect on other provisional balloting rules</header><text>Nothing in clause (i) may be construed to apply to the casting of a provisional ballot pursuant to section 302(a) or any State law for reasons other than the failure to present the identification required under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCBBE081A1D6F4DC4829460288F788094"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals voting other than in person</header>
<subparagraph id="H6B8A6C9ADFC64DB6BDBC679355169B3D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subparagraph (B), the appropriate State or local election official may not accept any ballot for an election for Federal office provided by an individual who votes other than in person unless the individual submits with the ballot—</text> <clause id="H98EE2C0DC237472D9A9383938B484828"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a copy of a valid photo identification; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H5FF25648171547AFABB86DCDA6870E5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the last four digits of the individual’s Social Security number and an affidavit developed and made available to the individual by the State attesting that the individual is unable to obtain a copy of a valid photo identification after making reasonable efforts to obtain such a copy.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC9DFC11CE4034D799F81B935DB607AE5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) does not apply with respect to a ballot provided by—</text> 
<clause id="H32592AF4750E46D8AF602177AE0388A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an absent uniformed services voter, as defined in section 107(1) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20310">52 U.S.C. 20310(1)</external-xref>); or</text></clause> <clause id="H5CE842E361B842C2A4F0098CCE47BE94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual provided the right to vote otherwise than in person under section 3(b)(2)(B)(ii) of the Voting Accessibility for the Elderly and Handicapped Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20102">52 U.S.C. 20102(b)(2)(B)(ii)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEE4263E5A267400F8940D6BBB146A68C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Providing public access to digital imaging devices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each State, the appropriate State or local government official of the State shall ensure, to the extent practicable, public access to a digital imaging device, which shall include a printer, copier, image scanner, or multifunction machine, at State and local government buildings in the State, including courts, libraries, and police stations, for the purpose of allowing individuals to use such a device at no cost to the individual to make a copy of a valid photo identification. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HD1A0DF357E9240669938338E532C9509"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Valid photo identifications described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, a <quote>valid photo identification</quote> means, with respect to an individual who seeks to vote in a State, any of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H501CF80A445343D595B0F0F3B21AD8B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A valid State-issued motor vehicle driver’s license that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9528509BA9D45B4AF843CD4C463A4A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A valid State-issued identification card that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date issued by a State motor vehicle authority.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE35666603ABE4028A95B09C1FF984992"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A valid United States passport for the individual.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6444493A32D040B7B2A80F55EE970965"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A valid military identification for the individual.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H933ADA1DE503464698A777333162A961"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A valid identification document issued by a Tribal government that includes a photo of the individual and an expiration date. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD7C24E77D6F24DC780BED3913F31CF5D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification of identification requirement to applicants for voter registration</header> <paragraph id="HDDE81AC248BD450ABD4C519081344405"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State shall ensure that, at the time an individual applies to register to vote in elections for Federal office in the State, the appropriate State or local election official notifies the individual of the photo identification requirements of this section.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8D7AC095DEF94BB7815004276D5C2055"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for individuals applying to register to vote online</header><text>Each State shall ensure that, in the case of an individual who applies to register to vote in elections for Federal office in the State online, the online voter registration system notifies the individual of the photo identification requirements of this section before the individual completes the online registration process.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDE2F48BAB4A7480DB75DC6EAF87E8084"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this section, and shall apply with respect to elections for Federal office held on or after such date.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB76D28D29A3F4D34B91B03936E184045"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 303 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB58C866733A04B2E878239BC08C1D75D"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 303A. Photo identification requirements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE886730D1C9C473A9B70CA4E1A1177B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to voluntary guidance by Election Assistance Commission</header><text>Section 311(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21101">52 U.S.C. 21101(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H61C41951A2B44C92A6AA5FBF6AF65D4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (2);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71489D878B084B138649058074395B75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (3) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6913B46BAC7242CAB4DE1D9B1F659165"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8870C8DA19764EE8B2BE2516B2B05173"> <paragraph id="H792BA25C1A814F5EA4C4788C76A7D0A7" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the recommendations with respect to section 303A, October 1, 2025.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H14F206DA3D234769A84AAFB1A13D437A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>sections 301, 302, 303, and 304</quote> and inserting <quote>subtitle A of title III</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H648FF1D2A4724BF19BA6111AC0D1F8FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section and the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this section, and shall apply with respect to elections for Federal office held on or after such date. </text></subsection></section>
</amendment-block> </amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc> 


