<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H382924D92863473A911478446C2755D3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6482 IH: To rename the community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Michigan Center, Michigan, as the “Captain Herbert Elfring VA Clinic”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6482</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To rename the community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Michigan Center, Michigan, as the <quote>Captain Herbert Elfring VA Clinic</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5A48D186A2964F988EA9B240CC785360" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE99AA08BCA3A4939AE62398CA65FA3BE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Designation of Captain Herbert Elfring VA Clinic</header>
<subsection id="H71FE6EDDAC884C29818D4231FD02B49A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs located at 4328 Page Avenue in Michigan Center, Michigan, shall, after the date of the enactment of this Act, be known and designated as the <quote>Captain Herbert Elfring Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</quote> or the <quote>Captain Herbert Elfring VA Clinic</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H545AE542938F421C94C97EF2040B5050"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the community-based outpatient clinic referred to in subsection (a) shall be considered to be a reference to the Captain Herbert Elfring VA Clinic.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

