<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H089075DFA6934C5C9F5313FE5E340C65" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6505 IH: Next Generation 9–1–1 Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6505</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to provide for further deployment and coordination of Next Generation 9–1–1, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5980551EA7B04F7087F063AF13DDA205" style="OLC"><section id="H15E48AEE662C4EA88112D8112FAB95E1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Next Generation 9–1–1 Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDDEC0A439F024EF492F3EC8E5727C7BF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Further deployment and coordination of Next Generation 9–1–1</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H4A58CCB9AED04B90A56A4E473F530429" style="OLC"><section id="H0A6575E45FB14BC592924B4E879333B6"><enum>159.</enum><header>Coordination of Next Generation 9–1–1 implementation</header><subsection id="H8950F28A361C418F9738372585ED9467"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties of Assistant Secretary with respect to Next Generation 9–1–1</header><paragraph id="HA3188E2C1A564F24802F6CB1039844F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary, after consulting with the Administrator, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H8E9A60E7BA714335B8AF5E9483833BFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take actions, in coordination with State points of contact described under subsection (c)(3)(A)(ii) as applicable, to improve coordination and communication with respect to the implementation of Next Generation 9–1–1;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB42241C02034E1DA2F57911032122E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop, collect, and disseminate information concerning the practices, procedures, and technology used in the implementation of Next Generation 9–1–1;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF537EAA3B7EA4E75B92F9B21BB96956C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advise and assist eligible entities in the preparation of implementation plans required under subsection (c)(3)(A)(iii);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECF0C6B7FA5947999F0E8A18BF6E8A05"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to eligible entities provided a grant under subsection (c) in support of efforts to explore efficiencies related to Next Generation 9–1–1;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4ACC7DB2A55E4178AC13B639991643A3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>review and approve or disapprove applications for grants under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H918DC85D68514CB086E837734AAFF602"><enum>(F)</enum><text>oversee the use of funds provided by such grants in fulfilling such implementation plans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H76F6DDCDE662465EBE0D6002C3EA96CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2026, and each year thereafter until funds made available to make grants under subsection (c) are no longer available to be expended, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the activities conducted by the Assistant Secretary under paragraph (1) in the year preceding the submission of the report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95CE9F42990A498BA345CB0449FF637A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary may seek the assistance of the Administrator in carrying out the duties described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1) as the Assistant Secretary determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2BCEFEB25D4D445AAC6208A13415E045"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional duties</header><paragraph id="H2D0612826ABE42DEB555164CB17DEBAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Management plan</header><subparagraph id="H37ADAB57A6FE4861A5A9FC403E48290B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary, after consulting with the Administrator, shall develop a management plan for the grant program established under this section, including by developing—</text><clause id="HBEC76D536FF7472CAE543E1309EA024B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>plans related to the organizational structure of such program; and</text></clause><clause id="H718321B36AF846A2946B8C90AF959F1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>funding profiles for each fiscal year of the duration of such program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43A4F6740D9E4212A550B6CA2D342D2F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Assistant Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H027832A8F59948018F24ED2F08213989"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit the management plan developed under subparagraph (A) to—</text><subclause id="HC8B27BC062D8456190AAD5705764C070"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6D66E7B2609E4CA091625FD337AB29D7"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Appropriations of the Senate;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H16D8B9101BB249A78D159ED4335B78ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>publish the management plan on the website of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration; and</text></clause><clause id="HDF38637C730F4DE18C6BFD7B4D99FEDD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide the management plan to the Administrator for the purpose of publishing the management plan on the website of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0763918FE3524750867029BE1E6733AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modification of plan</header><subparagraph id="H6847548728C94E808901A45C989D198D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Modification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary, after consulting with the Administrator, may modify the management plan developed under paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEB0C096D1B748EBA6F2327AD6D009B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the plan is modified under subparagraph (A), the Assistant Secretary shall—</text><clause id="HFE3C1C2934914739A47779F27ECF93ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit the modified plan to—</text><subclause id="HE10F6B8104EB4056A0B2B90315236F7B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H113CE66501584245AAA785A33F1388A9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Appropriations of the Senate;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2C43B52FACE04856AB33B32F18BCF099"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>publish the modified plan on the website of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration; and</text></clause><clause id="H128E3676E78A4FBDA8E445BF97898E7D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide the modified plan to the Administrator for the purpose of publishing the modified plan on the website of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H314887F272D44251B5F6E3451529ECAB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Next generation 9–1–1 implementation grants</header><paragraph id="HA415214652B346258A6E6C72A98DB3FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall provide grants to eligible entities for—</text><subparagraph id="H2B6AC8A423604F26A900F866F9DFC7EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implementing Next Generation 9–1–1;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2B1CB99677C46D2B459CC189DB85F1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintaining Next Generation 9–1–1;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C7F974D1AE24FC290CC8F6E9EFD2AA2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training directly related to implementing, maintaining, and operating Next Generation 9–1–1 if the cost related to the training does not exceed—</text><clause id="HA39D9F8388054A388C34A7E9CAE24C05" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>3 percent of the total grant award for eligible entities that are not Tribes; and</text></clause><clause id="H8AF8E860E84B45B68321BC9973959AF7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>5 percent of the total grant award for eligible entities that are Tribes;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FB5298770BF4A59A3CC5CAB9DC49224"><enum>(D)</enum><text>public outreach and education on how the public can best use Next Generation 9–1–1 and the capabilities and usefulness of Next Generation 9–1–1;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE594F1CABD634CD4A511EA5815F43C9D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>administrative costs associated with planning of Next Generation 9–1–1, including any cost related to planning for and preparing an application and related materials as required by this subsection, if—</text><clause id="H5F0D7DDD7D4D4B9C9AD31BC18E303723"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost is fully documented in materials submitted to the Assistant Secretary; and</text></clause><clause id="HAB6AF8BA863A4A88BE088102C89BB607"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost is reasonable, necessary, and does not exceed—</text><subclause id="HD87CDE4B831D4076B3F883F7C0D70FB9" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 percent of the total grant award for eligible entities that are not Tribes; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HDE4EA2E8B47C48E6B1A357DD946427AE" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>2 percent of the total grant award for eligible entities that are Tribes; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3644A770D3E45C1B3B56373ED17E1F5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>costs associated with implementing cybersecurity measures at emergency communications centers or with respect to Next Generation 9–1–1.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB96E4D55869240CBB589B5596671AA44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing grants under paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary, after consulting with the Administrator, shall require an eligible entity to submit to the Assistant Secretary an application, at the time and in the manner determined by the Assistant Secretary, and containing the certification required by paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB88FBC865B4D47D8996D57A2FFB226F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination required</header><text>Each eligible entity shall include in the application required by paragraph (2) a certification that—</text><subparagraph id="H074A4B10C7904609BA4583D445756828"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity that is a State, the entity—</text><clause id="H9AD86B2FE1174FD4A653D040111AA48A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has coordinated the application with the emergency communications centers located within the jurisdiction of the entity;</text></clause><clause id="H492EA99DDD4E482DA4B319B67F0E291E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has designated a single officer or governmental body to serve as the State point of contact to coordinate the implementation of Next Generation 9–1–1 for that State, except that such designation need not vest such officer or governmental body with direct legal authority to implement Next Generation 9–1–1 or to manage emergency communications operations; and</text></clause><clause id="H2D4FDD6FBEE742F697C6CB371C2816C1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has developed and submitted a plan for the coordination and implementation of Next Generation 9–1–1 that—</text><subclause id="H08A20BA892EF45958F7A0EEB4545E051"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ensures interoperability by requiring the use of commonly accepted standards;</text></subclause><subclause id="H275D8C39AD414BB3B63951BF5C2ABEFA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ensures reliability;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE9CE94782F3C46B287A2EB23BA87173D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>enables emergency communications centers to process, analyze, and store multimedia, data, and other information;</text></subclause><subclause id="H4C3759E896754C6DA69534020600C0D9"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>incorporates cybersecurity tools, including intrusion detection and prevention measures;</text></subclause><subclause id="H36DB67172D4641779173A5FDACBB65DD"><enum>(V)</enum><text>includes strategies for coordinating cybersecurity information sharing between Federal, State, Tribal, and local government partners;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7C23DA484D5C4467B6AB91FCB4F046A1"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>uses open and competitive request for proposal processes, including through shared government procurement vehicles, for deployment of Next Generation 9–1–1;</text></subclause><subclause id="H97E027A63E5C4000AE47DD7728FC9105"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>documents how input was received and accounted for from relevant rural and urban emergency communications centers, regional authorities, local authorities, and Tribal authorities;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA7730BC604FA444583493CD821712D81"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>includes a governance body or bodies, either by creation of new, or use of existing, body or bodies, for the development and deployment of Next Generation 9–1–1 that—</text><item id="H4AB281659E634DA5ADC789B50B5A1A1F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>ensures full notice and opportunity for participation by relevant stakeholders; and</text></item><item id="HBF2C9B35C5294A828FA66591AF65CE96"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>consults and coordinates with the State point of contact required by clause (ii);</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H8A1457B8E6BF4DA995DA5CEFA89AD759"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>creates efficiencies related to Next Generation 9–1–1 functions, including cybersecurity and the virtualization and sharing of infrastructure, equipment, and services; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H962E198D31BB41F2828908C9AF2195EB"><enum>(X)</enum><text>utilizes an effective, competitive approach to establishing authentication, credentialing, secure connections, and access in deploying Next Generation 9–1–1, including by—</text><item id="HC11CC2F9B7E7449BA852E0544521D8B7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>requiring certificate authorities to be capable of cross-certification with other authorities;</text></item><item id="H3CDD84007B69495DB8AD968DE20A1DD7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>avoiding risk of a single point of failure or vulnerability; and</text></item><item id="H9C58716995DC4114AAA8613E4D8E34AB"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>adhering to Federal agency best practices such as those promulgated by the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67F1FF5D1AEA4B5B90F2407E704B5E38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity that is a Tribe, the Tribe has complied with clauses (i) and (iii) of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2969446D77F14950A75CF59827A606E4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Criteria</header><subparagraph id="HAF99CA9180444F45A8F151344FFEDD46"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Assistant Secretary, after consulting with the Administrator, shall issue rules, after providing the public with notice and an opportunity to comment, prescribing the criteria for selecting eligible entities for grants under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H426AFBE8B1314505B32CF946AE4E3238"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The criteria shall—</text><clause id="HF27314801E0546C2B7DC2BCB2EA74A2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include performance requirements and a schedule for completion of any project to be financed by a grant under this subsection; and</text></clause><clause id="H2802E47EBAB7438D8D70799AD0EFD8C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specifically permit regional or multi-State applications for funds.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B5FBC4CE740488285BC58CFC9ACD31E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall update such rules as necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0CDC927BF164B468CCBBBC47B1585B6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grant certifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity shall certify to the Assistant Secretary at the time of application for a grant under this subsection, and each eligible entity that receives such a grant shall certify to the Assistant Secretary annually thereafter during any period of time the funds from the grant are available to the eligible entity, that—</text><subparagraph id="H1A9B7123D24B4DB6A4B7A6A5A14F4F90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning on the date that is 180 days before the date on which the application is filed, no portion of any 9–1–1 fee or charge imposed by the eligible entity (or in the case that the eligible entity is not a State or Tribe, any State or taxing jurisdiction within which the eligible entity will carry out, or is carrying out, activities using grant funds) are obligated or expended for a purpose or function not designated under the rules issued pursuant to section 6(f)(3) of the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/615a-1">47 U.S.C. 615a–1(f)(3)</external-xref>) (as such rules are in effect on the date on which the eligible entity makes the certification) as acceptable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5D43A1EFEC94BEC8A35C29B6B29B014"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any funds received by the eligible entity will be used, consistent with paragraph (1), to support the deployment of Next Generation 9–1–1 that ensures reliability and interoperability, by requiring the use of commonly accepted standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D21F047F86D49D59C822F475F3F2223"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the eligible entity (or in the case that the eligible entity is not a State or Tribe, any State or taxing jurisdiction within which the eligible entity will carry out or is carrying out activities using grant funds) has established, or has committed to establish not later than 3 years following the date on which the grant funds are distributed to the eligible entity—</text><clause id="H650B6CDB69854A40BF4BA1D5224A96CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a sustainable funding mechanism for Next Generation 9–1–1; and</text></clause><clause id="H79CE20719CDA4781A0367DCB6B4CDE84"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>effective cybersecurity resources for Next Generation 9–1–1;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE560332B35DB460AAD6736890B66C30B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the eligible entity will promote interoperability between emergency communications centers deploying Next Generation 9–1–1 and emergency response providers, including users of the nationwide public safety broadband network;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85E997509E0A4CA9B9B4CF864AEEA35D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the eligible entity has or will take steps to coordinate with adjoining States and Tribes to establish and maintain Next Generation 9–1–1; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49FD1E8CEA8F4DE29A40679EE1FDBED0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the eligible entity has developed a plan for public outreach and education on how the public can best use Next Generation 9–1–1 and on the capabilities and usefulness of Next Generation 9–1–1.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H036A4C0D2F1B49FDA35D7A8F6BA55780"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Condition of grant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity shall agree, as a condition of receipt of a grant under this subsection, that if any State or taxing jurisdiction within which the eligible entity will carry out activities using grant funds fails to comply with a certification required under paragraph (5), during any period of time during which the funds from the grant are available to the eligible entity, all of the funds from such grant shall be returned to the Assistant Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD62FCA691FBB44A09805642DB44A4031"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Penalty for providing false information</header><text>Any eligible entity that provides a certification under paragraph (5) knowing that the information provided in the certification was false shall—</text><subparagraph id="H18A8DDCA6BAE4DA79D37D5656D62AEC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not be eligible to receive the grant under this subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EDCD66F2F364E818254B9ED77DDA0DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>return any grant awarded under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H151650D2199E44429BAD837EA07849A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not be eligible to receive any subsequent grants under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H29415A162DA64D509A9581895236D269"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Grant funds provided under this subsection may not be used—</text><subparagraph id="HDB9E6209A3F7456788A684BA332EC7B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to support any activity of the First Responder Network Authority; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD31BA1166C894DCB908204C1BCC54E2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to make any payments to a person who has been, for reasons of national security, prohibited by any entity of the Federal Government from bidding on a contract, participating in an auction, or receiving a grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EF176F447ED47B198FBF4CC547671E0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section and sections 160 and 161:</text><paragraph id="HD114AC6717F94005B5D2AA1019926B8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>9–1–1 fee or charge</header><text>The term <term>9–1–1 fee or charge</term> has the meaning given such term in section 6(f)(3)(D) of the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/615a-1">47 U.S.C. 615a–1(f)(3)(D)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2108A5DFF0D45858E2744653B3F2E95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>9–1–1 request for emergency assistance</header><text>The term <term>9–1–1 request for emergency assistance</term> means a communication, such as voice, text, picture, multimedia, or any other type of data that is sent to an emergency communications center for the purpose of requesting emergency assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FD81DF422DE4E4FAE416A7C82F4E8F4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC48FE7EDB384369A991BF8BC46861E2"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Commonly accepted standards</header> <text>The term <term>commonly accepted standards</term> means the technical standards followed by the communications industry for network, device, and Internet Protocol connectivity that—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H24468D4558504851B941597E757BCDF0">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>enable interoperability; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE229A300E51846209EC78478D971707D"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>are—</text>
                <clause id="H2A324AD541D341049FDFB09EA8EA4A49">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>developed and approved by a standards development organization that is accredited by an American standards body (such as the American National Standards Institute) or an equivalent international standards body in a process—</text>
                  <subclause id="H40A76B2E619C44EA96057A6521CDEE4A">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>that is open to the public, including open for participation by any person; and</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="H0ED4FE3C02F24F7B95BB7349F80BC611">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>provides for a conflict resolution process;</text> </subclause> </clause> <clause id="H899F27620A7E40DEBC61D3E3BFD73851"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>subject to an open comment and input process before being finalized by the standards development organization;</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="H9DC26603C69F4171972B12966FE63E99">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>consensus-based; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HE2D6431B55BC4485BEF806C349688815"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>made publicly available once approved.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE786529DA904F9C9E1F86A0156E9F05"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cost related to the training</header><text>The term <term>cost related to the training</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HC3EFC0D88DA349D0B36FED922D644C94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>actual wages incurred for travel and attendance, including any necessary overtime pay and backfill wage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H076BEA085E7C4AC487EE7A32D3E516D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>travel expenses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BFA73E34F044E7C9E154EA4F977AF7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>instructor expenses; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1832DE7710045F5ADCDA4066E80FDA7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facility costs and training materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6411CD3CEFF4B4794231B213C12E499"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H5199EAB2F0354176888FF484CF4133FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text><clause id="H121FAEF32A604786A9BC457FD899E045"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State or a Tribe; or</text></clause><clause id="H00BDA5A52EF3433084447D63339CE946"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity, including a public authority, board, or commission, established by one or more entities described in clause (i); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DFC286224C54805A2FCB249C1EA0B14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any entity that has failed to submit the certifications required under subsection (c)(5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFC118CE13054048BE85B3EFC9890CA6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Emergency communications center</header><subparagraph id="H20084E8CE5DC43918214119028A01C46"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>emergency communications center</term> means—</text><clause id="HF0BC8D84B9A84A569E849E0016F1F749"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a facility that—</text><subclause id="H4BFBD9B756AE4D2796A23558E6AC6B72"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is designated to receive a 9–1–1 request for emergency assistance; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD1F25023AF3D43309F03B9B5D4D3B61A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>performs one or more of the functions described in subparagraph (B); or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4031AC3F77204DC8BA916C7B5E1E513F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a public safety answering point, as defined in section 222 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/222">47 U.S.C. 222</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A7774F11B1249C9A8F91C3905A0556F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Functions described</header><text>The functions described in this subparagraph are the following:</text><clause id="H245BCA652CC944F5A81FE2813C258DC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Processing and analyzing 9–1–1 requests for emergency assistance and information and data related to such requests.</text></clause><clause id="H8B504D12F53343EF96CA54400F89ECAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Dispatching appropriate emergency response providers.</text></clause><clause id="HCE8220A206E14AA0915C13DA9262EBCD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Transferring or exchanging 9–1–1 requests for emergency assistance and information and data related to such requests with one or more other emergency communications centers and emergency response providers.</text></clause><clause id="H94BEA941B3874495A1600E4B42613688"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Analyzing any communications received from emergency response providers.</text></clause><clause id="HFA04661792794DF9B426C88834666373"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Supporting incident command functions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1056357810CB4AD88F5D22C132D6FE37"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Emergency response provider</header><text>The term <term>emergency response provider</term> has the meaning given that term under section 2 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49203D66A1EF472584418770AA77FE46"><enum>(9)</enum><header>First Responder Network Authority</header><text>The term <term>First Responder Network Authority</term> means the authority established under section 6204 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1424">47 U.S.C. 1424</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD69309AEF881463ABCD3325512A61C12"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Interoperability</header><text>The term <term>interoperability</term> means the capability of emergency communications centers to receive 9–1–1 requests for emergency assistance and information and data related to such requests, such as location information and callback numbers from a person initiating the request, then process and share the 9–1–1 requests for emergency assistance and information and data related to such requests with other emergency communications centers and emergency response providers without the need for proprietary interfaces and regardless of jurisdiction, equipment, device, software, service provider, or other relevant factors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H582A74DB79A84351A89820AFFAFD653C"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Nationwide public safety broadband network</header><text>The term <term>nationwide public safety broadband network</term> has the meaning given the term in section 6001 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1401">47 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2758C7EC4E6545898895285665BB546A"> <enum>(12)</enum> <header>Next Generation 9–1–1</header> <text>The term <term>Next Generation 9–1–1</term> means an Internet Protocol-based system that—</text>
              <subparagraph id="H0046347C89D74348ABFE14062C4DE56E">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>ensures interoperability;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABC28E2C96C84A34A63287B7B575C990"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>is secure;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="H5622FA9776374511951739F55DBA566A">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>employs commonly accepted standards;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B7B09F3BD8849EF868CD27BE46B8AA6"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>enables emergency communications centers to receive, process, and analyze all types of 9–1–1 requests for emergency assistance;</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HC82C668368A94722A080F4E50FB0F162">
                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>acquires and integrates additional information useful to handling 9–1–1 requests for emergency assistance; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HA609CD97BB964CDC86977537D33026BB">
                <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>supports sharing information related to 9–1–1 requests for emergency assistance among emergency communications centers and emergency response providers.</text>
              </subparagraph>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8874E6D57E8043BAAE24D2903B32556D"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Reliability</header><text>The term <term>reliability</term> means the employment of sufficient measures to ensure the ongoing operation of Next Generation 9–1–1 including through the use of geo-diverse, device- and network-agnostic elements that provide more than one route between end points with no common points where a single failure at that point would cause all to fail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D3A1524F20144C399C6942555E78D4B"><enum>(14)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H614FB4E738884F3C8F7A9785273B1A6E"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Sustainable funding mechanism</header><text>The term <term>sustainable funding mechanism</term> means a funding mechanism that provides adequate revenues to cover ongoing expenses, including operations, maintenance, and upgrades.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FB0132893434E9D9EB4A496A7D916EC" commented="no"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribe</term> has the meaning given to the term <quote>Indian Tribe</quote> in section 4(e) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF9F4DA51455B4C4E8C0B7220008E6431"><enum>160.</enum><header>Establishment of nationwide next generation 9–1–1 cybersecurity center</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary, after consulting with the Administrator and the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security, shall establish a Next Generation 9–1–1 Cybersecurity Center to coordinate with State, local, and regional governments on the sharing of cybersecurity information about, the analysis of cybersecurity threats to, and guidelines for strategies to detect and prevent cybersecurity intrusions relating to Next Generation 9–1–1.</text></section><section id="H41ED8AF008C14FB7977634B407F683E1"><enum>161.</enum><header>Next generation 9–1–1 advisory board</header><subsection id="H657B9080593B489D9FCAC6C1097DE3E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Next generation 9–1–1 advisory board</header><paragraph id="HA1BC8CA7394E416480A497906B051DE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall establish a <quote>Public Safety Next Generation 9–1–1 Advisory Board</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Board</quote>) to provide recommendations to the Assistant Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H27D31D15564A484692C818B0FB39169F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to carrying out the duties and responsibilities of the Assistant Secretary in issuing the regulations required under section 159(c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0846D6A441F48C393F9094A3FB929D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as required by paragraph (7); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21AB8EE650E44BDA9804724EFA711C3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>upon request under paragraph (8).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA1536C643F2486BA4FCEB78263BFEC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><subparagraph id="H7E0161F9A5B74E5185EDB681A279E216"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Voting members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 150 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Assistant Secretary shall appoint 16 public safety members to the Board, of which—</text><clause id="H5BA07353F25941AB9C8FCC6294EFB530"><enum>(i)</enum><text>4 members shall represent local law enforcement officials;</text></clause><clause id="H3D7EC9617F8146FDA9860B9E51E40BA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>4 members shall represent fire and rescue officials;</text></clause><clause id="HCC60AD6E66444567BAA231EF781C75E8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>4 members shall represent emergency medical service officials; and</text></clause><clause id="H9DC8C161B6314E76998BEDC7895B2AAD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>4 members shall represent 9–1–1 professionals.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7336B61DAE3A4925A2F349F70D00E9C9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Diversity of membership</header><text>Members shall be representatives of States or Tribes and local governments, chosen to reflect geographic and population density differences as well as public safety organizations at the national level across the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB611393051AF4713BDAB7D03AC09E3D6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Expertise</header><text>All members shall have specific expertise necessary for developing technical requirements under this section, such as technical expertise, and expertise related to public safety communications and 9–1–1 services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C99D18AE6F144CEA82EE9F9122DBCAB"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rank and file members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making the appointments required by subparagraph (A), the Assistant Secretary shall appoint a rank and file member from each of the public safety disciplines listed in clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (A) as a member of the Board and shall select such member from an organization that represents its public safety discipline at the national level.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDB8D8A51BC945A28C5803CFC7F3F72E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Period of Appointment</header><subparagraph id="HE6D8C68A5E6E4856AD0932F7968F496F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), members of the Board shall serve for a 3-year term.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD642CB02793C412099FF144A9C0DF7AE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal for cause</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Board may be removed for cause upon the determination of the Assistant Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02508C6951B741AB9835BB8E68902686"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the Board shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E53E701035C4957845B512DBECF34B9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37B5CDC047A0453A8863BE791E483B0A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Chairperson and vice chairperson</header><text>The Board shall select a Chairperson and Vice Chairperson from among the voting members of the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9CAC6B5AB3A4DC7B7F7568A9F9EAAEC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Duty of board to submit recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after all members of the Board are appointed under paragraph (2), the Board shall submit to the Assistant Secretary recommendations for—</text><subparagraph id="HC90214A6245E42FAA443EE1C959D7DD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deploying Next Generation 9–1–1 in rural and urban areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B67EF88C68D49BF9FC89D5D805F93CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring flexibility in guidance, rules, and grant funding to allow for technology improvements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5460C963155B4A98985295BB99A546AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>creating efficiencies related to Next Generation 9–1–1, including cybersecurity and the virtualization and sharing of core infrastructure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6062D71CD8304E87894CEB82B0AE3E44"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enabling effective coordination among State, local, Tribal, and territorial government entities to ensure that the needs of emergency communications centers in both rural and urban areas are taken into account in each implementation plan required under section 159(c)(3)(A)(iii); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA43BD89C8FE45EA94C55E6933194D12"><enum>(E)</enum><text>incorporating existing cybersecurity resources into Next Generation 9–1–1 procurement and deployment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9091BA1CCD9E4CC9BCB67C9D04CA06E4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Authority to provide additional recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraphs (1) and (7), the Board may provide recommendations to the Assistant Secretary only upon request of the Assistant Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F3C0081C7C54B6CA65655B41BE6EF42"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Duration of authority</header><text>The Board shall terminate on the date on which funds made available to make grants under section 159(c) are no longer available to be expended.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58FC84CE83A74A22859722AE17F82FD9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed as limiting the authority of the Assistant Secretary to seek comment from stakeholders and the public.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE41A98D5633A4CAA98C88A64E5BB9E8D"><enum>162.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="HC7F5E9485B66496FB9CA080AE0D64E93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Assistant Secretary to carry out sections 159, 160, and 161 such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2026 through 2030, and such amounts are authorized to remain available until expended.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB425773DFD3B4CA6879BC228A904DE41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Not more than 4 percent of any amounts appropriated under subsection (a) may be used for administrative purposes (including carrying out sections 160 and 161).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

