<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF2D3BAF1034D4D1D934D622A98E5E820" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6042 IH: Law Against Nefarious Drones, Enforcement, Deconfliction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6042</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251112">November 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create mechanisms by which State law enforcement can coordinate with the Federal Government to detect and stop drones involved in unlawful activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAC8C81572FB84716B9CA5223A1825D89" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD449EFD913B448D9A44EC377378528EA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
<subsection id="H7F1DBD1B4B244772BFB5123697A4546F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Law Against Nefarious Drones, Enforcement, Deconfliction Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LANDED Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD96F9C1274494BF996130F2A2BC0D50A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded">
<toc-entry idref="HD449EFD913B448D9A44EC377378528EA" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H04C177AB848841B4A793DDDAD6C3E99E" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HED286EC90229479EA939A2734168206C" level="section">Sec. 3. Counter-UAS mitigation law enforcement cooperation.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H28172BBEC2854A2D8F391983866CD6B4" level="section">Sec. 4 Mandatory drone deconfliction reporting.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H59E44375099A4977AFEDE18008422B8E" level="section">Sec. 5 Counter-UAS security grant program.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HE64766A4AC054F648AF54D6B38AFB6BB" level="section">Sec. 6. Review and report on UAS activity.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<section id="H04C177AB848841B4A793DDDAD6C3E99E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header>
<subsection id="HA807FB5AA34844B4B01305A4380BCD87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application of terms</header><text>The terms in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code, shall apply to this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8967BD36B12D4F0884738311B8DCA69F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H3CBB9ECAB20C43288F1BE96CFA43E328"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Approved counter-UAS detection system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>approved counter-UAS detection system</term> means a system or device capable of lawfully and safely disabling, disrupting, or seizing control of an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3015B7EA130A426EA3EE1572356795A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Threats posed by an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The term <term>threats posed by an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft system</term> means an unauthorized activity of an unmanned aircraft or unmanned aircraft system that is reasonably believed to—</text>
<subparagraph id="HEF4A39AEE8B14B99AD3FCE4AB1536C2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>create the potential for bodily harm to, or loss of, human life; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F63AD5FF89246BBAC9AFA86BD856811"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pose a threat to law enforcement, public safety, national security installations, or critical infrastructure; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6404B90A4A304739AE5295920A2C7413"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have the potential to cause severe economic damage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA848DF596E844BF78E80D277AC2297C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unmanned aircraft system</term> means an unmanned aircraft and associated elements (including communication links and the components that control the unmanned aircraft) that are required for the operator to operate safely and efficiently in the national airspace system.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HED286EC90229479EA939A2734168206C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Counter-UAS mitigation law enforcement cooperation</header>
<subsection id="H7181AF5173014F79B381AC9862A0CBE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Attorney General and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall establish appropriate policies, procedures, and protocols necessary to allow the State law enforcement agency in each State (in coordination with the Secretary, Attorney General, and Administrator) to acquire, deploy, operate, and train with approved counter-UAS mitigation systems and mitigate unauthorized UAS operations. Each authority may be delegated to local law enforcement as deemed appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7D7F71D2FC254F47B19CF6CD16D8F4FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Attorney General. the Administrator and the Commissioner, shall establish an application process to authorize the acquisition, deployment, and operation of an approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology by State law enforcement agencies.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HFB561BAF33904C9CABF40E0864D8181E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>Upon approval of an application required under subsection (b) by the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the applicable State law enforcement agency to authorize the acquisition, deployment, and operation of an approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology, that shall specify, at a minimum—</text> <paragraph id="HACA4E331E18D46EAAA3A13693D6F8CFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology to be operated;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H721F8C7CA5BF4BD9911FE123B3B48F05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the authority to respond to threats posed by an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft system;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29CC0FF0CD1F4A81B3A3B833CA907850"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the time periods, dates, and circumstances during which the counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology may be operated;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5D572872310749078620C6DE1B64C5AD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any terms and conditions on the deployment and operation of an approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology the Secretary determines necessary to ensure public safety;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9B30D3FD20F4EA8BBA32F44244BE29C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the frequency with which the appropriate Federal agency representatives shall conduct periodic site visits to ensure compliance with the approved terms and conditions of deployment and operations of the approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2B8F7DF7B2B24BFAB52999EE3F46CFF7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the post-event reporting requirements specified in subsection (h)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA6B4EDD7866F4DACBF28255157CA0017"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 46502 of title 49, United States Code, or sections 32, 1030, and 1367 and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18, United States Code, any State law enforcement agency which has been approved through the application process described in subsection (b) may authorize personnel with assigned duties that include the safety, security, or protection of people, facilities, or assets to take such actions as are described in subsection (g)(1) that are necessary to detect, identify, monitor, track, or mitigate a credible threat posed by an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft system as defined in section 331(8) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/95">Public Law 112–95</external-xref>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HFA8E8C7592AD4FE0AC4D462A3F8A5B0B" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>FCC</header>
<paragraph id="HFAA7D33720664C92B8AC57618A40C622" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Other interference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing minimum performance requirements under subsection (c), the Administrator shall consider criteria, as determined by the Chair of the Federal Communications Commission, to determine the extent to which counter-UAS detection and mitigation systems, equipment, or technology can be safely operated without disrupting or interfering with the operation of civilian communications and information technology networks and systems, including such networks and systems that rely on radio frequency or cellular network communications links.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF78F46854A254838944697171DF87BFC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Spectrum impact consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, the Attorney General, and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall consult with the Chair of the Federal Communications Commission or the Administrator of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, as appropriate, to determine whether the use of a counter-UAS detection or mitigation system, equipment, or technology approved for use by the Secretary of Homeland Security does not present an adverse impact on civilian telecommunications, communications spectrum, internet technology, or radio communications networks or systems.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0A32CF676E024586A4170B0ABA085AEE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Equipment authorization</header><text>Any equipment authorized to be acquired under this Act may be authorized by either the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H714FB709495C48C3A521BE3C302C0A99"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Actions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The actions authorized in subsection (d) are the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H4D68D481D4C746AE86B3DE0044514500" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the operation of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, detecting, identifying, monitoring, and tracking the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, without prior consent, including by means of intercept or other access of a wire communication, an oral communication, or an electronic communication used to control the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7970462AD4544244AB9759BA15710F94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Warn the operator of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, including by passive or active, and direct or indirect, physical, electronic, radio, and electromagnetic means.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2B6CD67D36534B65B8BB093AA288D8A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Disrupt control of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, without prior consent of the operator of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, including by disabling the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft by intercepting, interfering, or causing interference with wire, oral, electronic, or radio communications used to control the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE5B32607811420E8B532DD0853B7B07"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Seize or exercise control of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0F2AEF2D266A42C69CA2F3756CAEA195"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Seize or otherwise confiscate the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0217B47D8E54103909AA3E20F9AA2BD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Use reasonable force, if necessary, to disable, damage, or destroy the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF0CF9D6EF13248CD9DF11B84092A84CD"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Required coordination and notification</header>
<paragraph id="H8E519AF6BB6D4D1E8183A8BF270E6BDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Until the date that is 180 days after the initial deployment of an authorized counter-UAS system, equipment, or technology, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall expressly approve, on a case-by-case basis, the mitigation of unmanned aircraft system by a State law enforcement agency under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H584D94271AAC4004A505D7FA3AB57DBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Verification and notification</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8A286E8248654F6C90567A33E16642BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>verify that there is a justifiable threat that warrants the use of such counter-UAS system, equipment, or technology;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8AB66E1CDF194CBFB6EE3B16838330C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>verify that the use of such counter-UAS system, equipment, or technology will—</text>
<clause id="HFAD9CA32B9794F63B13309A2E8B7F278"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be conducted in a manner consistent with the agreement between the Secretary and the State law enforcement agency; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3BBDA9CAD42D4C68950391ACD1C8E0AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>abide by all safety protocols, terms, and conditions established for the use of such system, equipment, or technology; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC395703D951F4A0B84CA84850B933D8D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>immediately notify the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration of the approval provided under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H422C9B6845094B60A03D12DBDE1A34A0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header> <subparagraph id="HB422D8CFC0FB4DE2AD800AC8DB43A2F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 24 hours after each mitigation of a UAS conducted under the authorities in this section, the relevant State law enforcement agency shall submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, and the Attorney General a post-event report.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD1294BE70A084318B97F1516C7933AE9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subparagraph (A) shall include all relevant information pertaining to the event, including the drone operation, and subsequent mitigation and enforcement actions, and subsequent enforcement actions, as specified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9411C11791CD44B6B555355BE7573C81"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Revocation</header><text>The Secretary shall revoke the authorization or approval for the deployment and operation of an approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology pursuant to this section if the Secretary determines that the covered entity has not—</text>
<paragraph id="H4B5F4D565E4E48259F054EF9CA3E2A54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintained an agreement that is acceptable to the Secretary with a State law enforcement agency to operate such approved counter-UAS mitigation system, equipment, or technology on behalf of the covered entity; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5746F863E9B346819406DCC5B6A5A246"><enum>(2)</enum><text>complied with the privacy protections under section 210G(e) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124n">6 U.S.C. 124n(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3F18CB3123EE48439D48085D7CDD9B58"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Attorney General in carrying out the application, agreement, and revocation processes under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3F9D149E71DE48A388B84BAF1FE3816F"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header> <paragraph id="H0282B0B764994F9BABD4AF2D4C75BF24" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Airspace considerations</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General, shall make a location-specific determination for each applicable State law enforcement agency selected under the approval process established under this section to ensure that any potential use of counter-UAS mitigation systems, equipment, or technology will not interfere with or adversely impact the safe operation of the national airspace system, including any airport that is located within the State.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H303720A8E01B4C03AF82C89DAC1301E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility for participation</header><text>If an adverse impact is identified under paragraph (1) and cannot be safely mitigated to the satisfaction of the Administrator, the applicable State law enforcement is not eligible to use counter-UAS systems within a range determined by the Federal Aviation Administrator of the site of interference.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H28172BBEC2854A2D8F391983866CD6B4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Mandatory drone deconfliction reporting</header> <subsection id="H5BB05DCFEAAD427FB6DB3C0E0C60C18D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, not later than 180 days after the first determination that a counter-UAS system with mitigation capabilities meets the requirements of section 44810(e) of title 49, United States Code, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall establish appropriate policies to ensure deconfliction between Federal, State, or local agencies regarding drones flown by other Federal, State, or local agencies.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H535933C6AEDF48A4B25B253F232F562E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting requirement</header>
<paragraph id="HD01ACA6DB71E41C38B6C21C42AC2245C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Administrator, shall establish a mandatory nonemergency reporting requirement mechanism for Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4CB899E4B83243C8A531880D3C251A21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting requirements</header><text>The reporting requirement described in paragraph (1) shall contain—</text>
<subparagraph id="HED309D8F8B2C4542A8DC50A5E5772E9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a database containing a drone which is currently being used in a nonemergency operation’s transponder ID and the date and time of its usage; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC673C318596A494EA725F67B99C215B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a method for Federal, State, and local law enforcement to check if a drone’s transponder is within the database and is currently in use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H97732AF136B4496FB4DD8A968D6EC239"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rapid response</header>
<subsection id="H25278C0F2EA14FFC9F6D647C0CCA90BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security may act rapidly to respond to a State request for assistance on a UAS mitigation situation in an emergency.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H03FA037F65684F6BA5C2F44D0A2F2386"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process for responding</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a process for the rapid response described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H59E44375099A4977AFEDE18008422B8E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Counter-UAS security grant program</header>
<subsection id="HD8C6DB09279B4255B78B5ACFA5BFB16D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department a program to be known as the <quote>Counter-UAS Security Grant Program</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>). Under the Program, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall make grants to eligible State law enforcement and emergency management agencies for the acquisition of counter-UAS equipment.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB7655E74BF0A4DA39C3CA3C7A13053FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text>Eligible recipients are law enforcement agencies of States.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0757CCEA890D4EB1B642788AEB87A5ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permitted uses</header><text>The recipient of a grant under this section may use such grant for any of the following uses:</text> <paragraph id="H99559AFB76054F41A28D4E9370FDCF66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Acquisition of approved counter-UAS systems.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4C24D585B597473B9BCABF89A8AD2A57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Fees for training approved personnel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5843D0395591448BAF65415935655373"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any other appropriate activity, including administrative activities, as determined by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3D8B6D2926DB4C688FBCA16CFE2948FB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of performance</header><text>The Administrator shall make funds provided under this section available for use by a recipient of a grant for a period of not less than 24 months.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE64766A4AC054F648AF54D6B38AFB6BB"><enum>7.</enum><header>Review and report on UAS activity</header> <subsection id="HD6118751E4024286839C571666345AD5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall conduct a review of potential foreign adversary connected UAS activity over critical military installations, vessels, aircraft, and the homeland, and other matters.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H31B1696689834F4CA7C66C3274195D16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General shall submit to the relevant committees a report on—</text> <paragraph id="H3D484BE046224924903ADEAA40A22798"><enum>(1)</enum><text>UAS activity over military installations in the United States and abroad;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA046D01D22874C7E9D848D70BD187A7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>UAS activity in close proximity to sensitive national security installations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC8F0C9F950C428A9DFE1111DBA0A2B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>instances of UAS activity in the vicinity of United States military and law enforcement vessels and aircraft;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBC899B36556C49A9BD1840439BDD4B8B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>instances of the executive branch not sharing UAS information with Congress when requested;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15E1F79894AA440291CA00B8876FFC63"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the process for deploying counter-UAS systems to assist State and local law enforcement;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEECD134E42BC4E2D8084349359E2DA2F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>instances where the Department of Defense deployed counter-UAS systems to assist State and local law enforcement; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7777A01A15BC4473982B45CA910A4984"><enum>(7)</enum><text>an analysis of near-peer actors who possess the capabilities to conduct such activities.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HAD4B66537DFE42CB8685EA56569CBF6B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of relevant committee</header><text>In this section, the term <term>relevant committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H7C9D6CD31BB344388A78A61121628251"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE069977DE4764A8E861D275759256829"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Government Affairs of the Senate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EC1ADDC1F3C4B55BD699268CFDC6063"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6954E7A3BAE448C7917A4A329DC950F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H292204493ED049D1A3EBDC3C2002EE61"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H62C11DDA4EBD4FE8A17D38BEFC8BFBD0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H199A007D9DC3441CB4B48B85AC292AA9"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1F7BC2CC3DDD434BBE0B1FE40E9C2957"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

