<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC78DC0A43BA840F29CF55275B0570291" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6441 IH: Puerto Rico Postal Equity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6441</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Postmaster General update the systems of the Postal Service to accurately recognize and preserve address data, including the proper use of linguistic characters and place names, in Puerto Rico, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDEB322EC03724B71BE4F9824ACEB8917" style="OLC"><section id="H4237FF9CE15143CBB51D246F9994B65C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Puerto Rico Postal Equity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB9913B558813471593397A318C4C6D18"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HCC8194DEEE034AEF981F26A55E4814F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The accurate identification, formatting, and integration of physical addresses are essential to the efficient operation of the United States Postal Service, the reliability of mail delivery, the facilitation of e-commerce, and the equitable distribution of Federal programs and services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB958BF97976144CA98AD9525C233FF6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Historical and structural complexities in Puerto Rico’s local addressing conventions create inconsistencies between locally assigned addresses and those recognized by the United States Postal Service, Federal agencies, and major private platforms, resulting in recurring delivery and validation failures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B2413371C264720A3D64FEA56557FF9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such inconsistencies include the omission or alteration of diacritical marks recognized in Spanish-language place names, street names, and surnames, which can lead to misidentification, delivery errors, and data mismatches in official records.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1016C037843B4618B91FCA0EE249F79F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The preservation of accurate orthography and culturally specific characters in Federal data systems is essential to ensuring the integrity of official records, compliance with civil rights and language access standards, and the protection of identity and property rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F0A37F136234B67AE87C942FCDFB8E2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthened coordination between the United States Postal Service and the Department of Commerce, including the Census Bureau, would enhance national data accuracy, support economic development, and advance equity across Puerto Rico by improving how the United States Postal Service identifies and resolves recurrent address recognition and delivery issues in Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8AA339F9BFDC4C96B72A2F748D9F1BC9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvements to accuracy of Puerto Rico address data</header><subsection id="HADBFE54825C94C0D975A91746E649B01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Postmaster General shall develop and implement improvements to the systems of the United States Postal Service to improve the accuracy and recognition of addresses in Puerto Rico, including—</text><paragraph id="H952ECCF25EF14CE59247DBE690F21FE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using existing operational indicators of the United States Postal Service, including Undeliverable-As-Addressed codes, mail delivery exception records, address quality data from the address management system of the United States Postal Service, delivery point validation results, consumer complaint information, and address validation outcomes data from the websites of the United States Postal Service, to identify locations in Puerto Rico with persistent address recognition or mail delivery issues;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CE4B0409C724B0A8367A787F20AB945"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">updating the address records, routing information, and validation tables of the United States Postal Service for the locations identified under subsection (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F0B966719D54A6DBCD357F239828486"><enum>(3)</enum><text>revising the relevant systems of the United States Postal Service, including address matching, address validation, and mail and delivery routing systems, to support the use of diacritical marks and other address elements used in Puerto Rico for addresses in Puerto Rico; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H230A4B1B8D784E2E9804AEAAF9903BF2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>taking such other actions as determined appropriate by the Postmaster General based on the relevant data to improve the recognition by the systems of the United States Postal Service of and the proper delivery of mail to properly assigned addresses in Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C6914453391428E8690EF21CAA6F63F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Postmaster General shall consult with the Bureau of the Census, including the Census Open Innovation Lab, the Puerto Rico Planning Board established by Puerto Rico Act 75–1975 (23 L.P.R.A. 62 et seq.), and appropriate local governments in Puerto Rico, to obtain information required to carry out such subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5EE413D00C5B46CBBC48640E2D238C0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for three years, the Postmaster General shall submit to Congress a report detailing—</text><paragraph id="H1878ADF732364D7BA2DE5BC7852922F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the actions taken under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68063C8D3EFC498F84E2BD0F1279C403"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the progress of the United States Postal Service in improving the recognition of and accuracy of delivery to addresses in Puerto Rico; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42A33D18E037499A9436C9AFD74E4E88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any barriers to carrying out subsection (a) and recommendations for legislative or administrative action to address such barriers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7CB5E5941774B3F95023FEA672C5878"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Diacritical mark defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>diacritical mark</term> means any accent, tilde, or other orthographic sign used by the Spanish language to indicate pronunciation or meaning in proper nouns and place names within Puerto Rico.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC1E80685519D4800891008556B77724D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Cutgo compliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional amounts are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act. The Postmaster General shall carry out this Act using amounts otherwise appropriated or made available to United States Postal Service.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

