<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7853CAD2D9454C19A85816A0EF000C72" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8720 IH: Campaign Finance Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8720</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to modify requirements regarding contributions related to elections for Federal office and to improve the operation of the Federal Election Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1141C11059F545D883B8BA86069F490E" style="OLC"><section id="H331CA551D9F54F62A0D39C0A73104BEB" section-type="section-one" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Campaign Finance Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6990B1653F214A958A861437FD87E024"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring disclosure of card verification value or card verification code as condition of acceptance of online contributions made using credit or debit cards in Federal elections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 302 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30102">52 U.S.C. 30102</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F3D056D7D1C4ED69479801C02DC47E6" style="OLC"><subsection id="H7BFB1DD896F3432ABA69AC1634BA9597"><enum>(j)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8F9160902CEB4C7DBCE68D0A1CB3DB1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>No political committee shall accept any internet credit or debit card contribution unless—</text><subparagraph id="HA3DAD66E24DE4C8993BC948290C37CD7" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except in the case of a contribution the political committee receives by mail, the individual or entity making such contribution is required, at the time such individual or entity makes such contribution, to disclose the card verification value or card verification code of such credit or debit card and the ZIP Code of the billing address associated with such credit or debit card; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64116FA4FBCA471C9DCCD366AE5F53F4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1E21DF90DC704E58B55DB111B691406F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mailing address of the individual or entity is located in a State; or</text></clause><clause id="HA9420C37227E42FFAA71823258018652" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a contribution made by an individual whose mailing address is not located in a State, the individual provides the committee with the applicable information described in paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F1106DEA21B4E0DBF52A99752B42842" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The applicable information described in this paragraph is as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H8410FC1EE52E4D96832C8718FE30462A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of an individual who is a citizen or national of the United States—</text><clause id="H0F2E67550FEE474AB8DF29EF5D690F3A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States mailing address the individual uses for voter registration purposes;</text></clause><clause id="HA0BD661C421C40A5B0885487DADC1277"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a copy of the individual’s United States passport; or</text></clause><clause id="HD09866F420484DD2932A919DC6B2BA3E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a copy of a comparable acceptable identification document, or the unique identifying number from such a document, for the individual.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F4CB3F02EA343918D25ACE417503BF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who is lawfully admitted for permanent residence, as defined by section 101(a)(20) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(20)</external-xref>)—</text><clause id="H9F90BAF9CCB64F349CC7A78B2D3CD46A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a copy of the individual’s permanent resident card; or</text></clause><clause id="HE8A41739BB5445A2BBA4202A7456FBA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a copy of a comparable acceptable identification document issued by the Department of Homeland Security.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AEACA160DCE43D59281EE37355B7B02" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A political committee that accepts any internet credit or debit card contribution as a recurring contribution shall require the individual or entity making such contribution to comply with the requirements of this subsection for the first such contribution, but shall not require the individual or entity to provide the information identified in paragraphs (1) and (2) for subsequent recurring contributions made using the same credit or debit card as the initial contribution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03BCC117AB9243DBBF3F65739AF0866E" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A political committee that stores or saves, or arranges to store or save, any credit or debit card information shall require the individual or entity making such contribution to comply with the requirements of this subsection for the first such contribution or at the time of storing or saving such information, but shall not require the individual or entity to provide the information identified in paragraphs (1) and (2) for subsequent contributions made using the same credit or debit card as the initial contribution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02729B08942D4B0BBB96D0C5C1E178F6" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An internet credit or debit card contribution received by a political committee made through the use of a digital wallet shall be treated as complying with the requirements of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CD30F434498426DAD49A4036CFACABC" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subsection (b) or (c), in the case of an internet credit or debit card contribution—</text><subparagraph id="H9F053C733EBF44DEB20984C5FAAE9C70"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no later than 10 days after receiving the contribution, the person who receives the contribution shall forward to the treasurer such contribution, the name and address of the person making the contribution, and the date of receipt; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA54880AF2B344A23A582314823593A65"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the treasurer of a political committee shall keep an account of the name and address of any person making any such contribution, together with the date and amount of such contribution by any person consistent with applicable regulations of the Commission, including regulations relating to the period for which contribution records must be preserved and the anonymity of certain contributors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5EFED7822074D94888F39D817792EC1" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0C863A49CFC44A8095480C31FD193A7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A treasurer of a political committee who is aware that a contribution to the committee is not in compliance with this subsection has an affirmative duty to refund the contribution to the individual or entity making the contribution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H410AE19E848545D5BABD0C06ED96E663" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the treasurer of a political committee shows that best efforts have been used to comply with the requirements of this paragraph, the committee shall be considered in compliance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F90729874A34188A0D15E0651DE7A59" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H770BFA974E2846C385D180B20DFE5F1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>digital wallet</term> means a software application that stores payment or account information to facilitate traditional payments that use bank and credit card information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70042A4E96FC490FBAF4C17772C9F88A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>Internet credit or debit card contribution</term> means a contribution that—</text><clause id="H70DFA3E51B7D43829E96AA0B921A353B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is made using a credit or debit card; and</text></clause><clause id="H41431FE137CD4C2B9CCA1E7302A6ECF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is received through an internet website or application.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H8F7CAA7E07CA4C398FF0DDB358E72846"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requiring name on credit or debit card to be name of donor as condition of acceptance of contributions in Federal elections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 302 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30102">52 U.S.C. 30102</external-xref>), as amended by <internal-xref idref="H6990B1653F214A958A861437FD87E024" legis-path="2.">section 2</internal-xref>, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="H8039118B505B4991B33B2C5E7231CFAE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H304C5BDCFFB74A2280783CF1BA8A5598"><enum>(k)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No political committee shall accept any credit or debit card contribution unless the name on the credit or debit card used to make such contribution is the name of the individual or entity donating such contribution.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H416EC7CF42AB4FC5830A3A8A4045AF3B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibiting acceptance of contributions made using gift cards in Federal elections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 302 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30102">52 U.S.C. 30102</external-xref>), as amended by section 2 and section 3, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="H778D729981EC4C3DBBFFD8D03224F9E7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H3D39F8D9A8CA4715B3B9129A55234761"><enum>(l)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No political committee shall knowingly accept a contribution made through the use of a gift certificate or store gift card, as such terms are defined, respectively, under section 915(a) of the Electronic Fund Transfer Act.</text><paragraph id="H02C765C133C547498089EA5403200561" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H15404696DACF4D46ABBCCD17EB3621A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A treasurer of a political committee who is aware that a contribution to the committee is not in compliance with this subsection has an affirmative duty to refund the contribution to the individual or entity making the contribution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD1F00FACBF74D72BCA11865F3C1914B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the treasurer of a political committee shows that best efforts have been used to comply with the requirements of this subsection, the committee shall be considered in compliance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H41E6A790299542F4B957F542FD078423"><enum>5.</enum><header>Removal of threshold for reporting contributions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 304 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30104">52 U.S.C. 30104</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HAC83E63720AF45CD97B5D112EBA637FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3)—</text><subparagraph id="HB9C3E3245A6E45768C60F7874B0C8A00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>whose contribution or contributions have an aggregate amount or value in excess of $200 within the calendar year (or election cycle, in the case of an authorized committee of a candidate for Federal office), or in any lesser amount if the reporting committee should so elect,</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA905F592199C4D9D910BC360541361C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking <quote>in an aggregate amount or value in excess of $200 within the calendar year (or election cycle, in the case of an authorized committee of a candidate for Federal office)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAAE2E371B2D4869A94D6A4BDD082D14"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking <quote>in an aggregate value or amount in excess of $200 within the calendar year (or election cycle, in the case of an authorized committee of a candidate for Federal office)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF8D0FC706D742C8839677AB66844570"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)(C), by striking <quote>in excess of $200</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF5D833125DC4CC0A6AEFA669FE3D72C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(3)—</text><subparagraph id="H5026A829FBDA4FC5B7E482031CEAEBC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>receipts or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD431BCE2ACA24CD19B86C66F0BB01E1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote> paragraphs (3)(A), (5),</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (5)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H423BC4110FF947B7AB26869B428959EF" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Prohibiting aiding or abetting making of contribution in the name of another</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 320 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30122">52 U.S.C. 30122</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE83AAD966C8B46E5A54856C099FF9141"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>No person</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEA3D4E309FB54E6F99404F574B8A2063" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H3BC975B25D89418F883EEE2C3B1D47A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD452A450B3F84EA5A94F61DDBF95DE1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H43DE448DD9904E5C84D69B5FBF02C50A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HACB8E4126A4C4548B0F087356C50BA4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person shall knowingly direct, help, or assist any person in making a contribution in the name of another person.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCEEE172F47CD4547A465F2FBD0420214"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting of suspected contributions</header><text>Any recipient who suspects that a contribution made to such recipient is a contribution made by one person in the name of another person shall report such contribution to the Federal Election Commission.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H36A9E3196821484FBA81A0A2F811EF59"><enum>7.</enum><header>Regulations</header><subsection id="H0D4520FEC3CC4BC98C712A7A7EC4E638"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Election Commission shall promulgate regulations to carry out the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1F51D8F94A0449D9C096283BF0C29DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation with credit card payment networks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In promulgating regulations under subsection (a) to carry out the amendments made by this Act, the Commission shall consult with representatives of payment card networks, as defined under section 921(c) of the Electronic Fund Transfer Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1693o-2">15 U.S.C. 1693o–2(c)</external-xref>), and other relevant stakeholders.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBF1E99FAD2CC4085A378A1C843A7BFDC"><enum>8.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to contributions made after the expiration of the 90-day period which begins on the date the Commission promulgates regulations under <internal-xref idref="H36A9E3196821484FBA81A0A2F811EF59" legis-path="7.">section 7</internal-xref>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

