<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H665442F0C5D94233B2F17DEDE9CD6371" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5909 IH: To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish procedures for reporting of condemned Federally assisted rental housing and to authorize penalties related to such condemned housing, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5909</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251104">November 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish procedures for reporting of condemned Federally assisted rental housing and to authorize penalties related to such condemned housing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H98E23788D0514A859F9851CEBED40DF8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9DEFC32FC23945D19C94E02B376DA018" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Reporting and penalties for condemned Federally assisted rental housing</header> 
<subsection id="HFDEEE05626EB4AFD9A86F0CB598221D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall establish procedures for tenants of Federally assisted rental housing to report to the Secretary if such housing has been condemned by a city, county, State, or Federal agency.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0EB269A59F1C4D52B25C826BD8B33E17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may impose a civil penalty of not more than $50,000 on any owner of Federally assisted rental housing which has been condemned by a city, county, State, or Federal agency.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFED4B9D653294C1F900BAAD45928078F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federally assisted rental housing defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>Federally assisted rental housing</quote> means a residential dwelling unit that is made available for rental and for which assistance is provided, or that is part of a housing project for which assistance is provided, under any program administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or the Secretary of Agriculture, including—</text> <paragraph id="H2D2BAF8B3ACF438BAD59981036117A84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the low-income housing credit under section 42 of title 26, Internal Revenue Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77048F1456574712BDF076424400ED09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the program for transitional housing assistance for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking under section 40299 of the Safe Homes for Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12351">34 U.S.C. 12351</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H367BE12BEEF34E41AC6A34643C3E576D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the program for financial assistance for supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing under section 2044 of title 38, United States Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B83EDAC62EE45548FD5333E7A6C5EED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the program for transitional housing assistance for homeless veterans under section 2011 of title 38, United States Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B21436D1163426284EC4B155AEF983A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the program for homeless veterans with special needs under section 2061 of title 38, United States Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H976C2B8BE7704EF7A02AA3FBCA366B86"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the program for rental and cooperative housing for lower income families under section 236 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715z-1">12 U.S.C. 1715z–1</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E24D77E7A1D49D4A1A2B3EAD2BD941F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the program for housing for moderate income and displaced families under section 221 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/17151">12 U.S.C. 17151(d)(3)</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E8E967A2C6841FF885AAF952D4EF231" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the public housing program under the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC32A08F01F374966AB0F07AACCFD488D" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the program for rental assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE586AD022484A58A9C2D97CAC42E290" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the HOME Investment Partnership program under title II of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12721">42 U.S.C. 12721 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08E3F7BF4E9A4405B243A1D1EC9CA35E" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11360">42 U.S.C. 11360 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4DF022763ACA4B58BDB4753F84E365C7" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the Housing Trust Fund program under section 1338 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFE178BF7C0F4858B73C3F5435048174" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the program for supportive housing for the elderly under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FA9DEDA81DF42EB8DAE6067697082A3" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the program for supportive housing for persons with disabilities under section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8013">42 U.S.C. 8013</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1918937D64F64502BFD19B5F46FD0B16" commented="no"><enum>(15)</enum><text>the AIDS Housing Opportunities program under subtitle D of title VIII of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12901">42 U.S.C. 12901 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66F9FDFD680D4CB494B849F46E10A86D" commented="no"><enum>(16)</enum><text>the program for Native American housing under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4101">25 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66C702F01B8D4B3AB2264E3D9AF72496" commented="no"><enum>(17)</enum><text>the program for housing assistance for Native Hawaiians under title VIII of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4221">25 U.S.C. 4221 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19C0926EC1B04AD08A400A73BD47AEA4" commented="no"><enum>(18)</enum><text>the programs for assistance for rural rental housing under title V of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1471">42 U.S.C. 1471 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC7775831AD9400E934CBB8572444C52"><enum>(19)</enum><text>any other Federal housing program providing affordable housing to low and moderate income persons by means of restricted rents or rental assistance, or more generally providing affordable housing opportunities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

