<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL26398-PW8-5J-S10"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4926 IS: State Firearms Dealer Licensing Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4926</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide grants for State firearms dealer licensing programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H82087EF5C3BB4FF5B362BC4034C4C069"><section section-type="section-one" id="HE0FFC904AD6146C99C4830C404D338AF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State Firearms Dealer Licensing Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCF974B1B06074411BAB728E937CD1CFA"><enum>2.</enum><header>State Firearms Dealer Licensing Grant Program</header><subsection id="H4F87BB4481D14A5A8CB4840CEF68181A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8094d829da764054a7b9191a2718d1ba"><part id="HC037896964D14B10BC66B8CB76B5F5EC"><enum>PP</enum><header>State Firearms Dealer Licensing Grant Program</header><section id="id54da2347e46f466896b7d401f8ee4742"><enum>3061.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part:</text><paragraph id="H7BE688385F2E42D7804DFF7AD5694CD8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible applicant</header><text>The term <term>eligible applicant</term> means a State or Indian tribal government that has in effect a law that, at a minimum, requires the following:</text><subparagraph id="H0B76F077C8854ABBBEC0922D2299265D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In order to engage in business as a firearms dealer in the area subject to the jurisdiction of the State or Indian tribal government, a person shall be a licensed dealer and be licensed as a firearms dealer under such law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDCC538383E84045BAAC7E29AF8F99C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A person shall only be licensed as a firearms dealer under such law upon successful completion of the application process set by such law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EB8041C4A074D248AC0A6193BCF4370"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A license to engage in business as a firearms dealer shall be valid for not more than 3 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69DF5D57531C493FB4EFF464FC09F213"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A person licensed as a firearms dealer shall submit to inspections under the law of the State or Indian tribal government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8B2DDB27D90492493EA3F5473C9877C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Noncompliance of a person licensed as a firearms dealer with a requirement for firearms dealers under the law of the State or Indian tribal government may result in—</text><clause id="HD147812E0A914F0B96BCDC05499E7DD8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the suspension or revocation of the license; and</text></clause><clause id="HDDBBCCDF25E94C05A094D45ED6922243"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the imposition of civil penalties or criminal charges.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB9AE1C542C24656823AE75E016DF83F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Licensed dealer</header><text>The term <term>licensed dealer</term> has the meaning given the term in section 921(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H73C890AC8E284131A2EE084240E79AA4"><enum>3062.</enum><header>Grant program</header><subsection id="H58D2CF88B0C141E2A4A029A99EE87A85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after amount to carry out this part are appropriated, the Attorney General shall award annual grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible applicants for the development, implementation, improvement, or evaluation of firearms dealer licensing programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F11089D969B43978773DA900D26F549"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible applicant desiring a grant under this part shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may require, including—</text><paragraph id="HE4909954BB114B4380E8DC05CEA7D125"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the law that the applicant has enacted to require a license for any firearms dealer, including a description of any exemptions to such law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C317436F3D14919A6E900A3F7070241"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the applicant will use the grant to develop, implement, improve, or evaluate the firearms dealer licensing program of the applicant; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB37CECC5CA843A38C3FEE18A6CC04C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the inspection bodies and procedures of the applicant used to inspect firearms dealers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66155D39BCFE463586D0BFDA91B78A43"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Subawards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that receives a grant under this part may make a subaward to a unit of local government authorized to oversee and enforce the development, implementation, improvement, or evaluation of the firearms dealer licensing program for which the grant under this part will be used.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF923157E911643AA9D01499C38FBA6DD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><paragraph id="H3E1EB3137F3244E5ADAB9B39D5EBB1E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports by recipients</header><text>An eligible applicant that receives a grant under this part shall provide an annual report to the Attorney General with the following information:</text><subparagraph id="H06CC9589B6C548A7ADBE4A87C6C60ACF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of inspections conducted in the jurisdiction of the eligible applicant of persons licensed as a firearms dealer by the eligible applicant during the previous year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BA88BC50C6C482F8B7D42EF9C918385"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of violations by persons licensed as a firearms dealer by the eligible applicant that were cited during the previous year, disaggregated by violation type.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE62937EC4E0F421485CA6AC78D2EBD0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The total number of persons licensed as a firearms dealer by the eligible applicant as of the end of the previous year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H790177FAD53B4F029EAC3ED38A8214DF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of licenses to engage in business as a firearms dealer in the jurisdiction of the eligible applicant that, during the previous year, were—</text><clause id="H22C4A9B1C887468C95FE34767938FE5B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>issued;</text></clause><clause id="H6E1710F4D48A4B91BB36C3C05E2CBC54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>renewed;</text></clause><clause id="HA977ECB902FB4974A9D7BFB319EE2CB6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>suspended; or</text></clause><clause id="H1FBD794DB4B94024BEEB6AC692C0AF62"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>revoked.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8661E020A70B425E8AE82933C5CE8F3A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>To Congress</header><text>Not later than 390 days after the date on which the Attorney General awards the first grants under this part, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress and make available publicly through print and electronic means a report that includes the following information:</text><subparagraph id="HE893830636C940A08CF9A7E72CE6E19C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of eligible applicants who received funds under a grant under this part during the previous fiscal year, including the funds awarded, cumulatively and disaggregated by grantee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37779C84A0864C479D9CA6C741F4948A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The information reported to the Attorney General pursuant to paragraph (1), disaggregated by grantee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF694F945824D45A980945AA04DBD495D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of eligible applicants that were denied grants under this part and the basis for such denials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B43684BEC234679BB2E7F7FFCA2B896"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on grant amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this part may not be in an amount that is more than $2,500,000 per fiscal year.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE94C89DB77F74794BEF4D7E38D0FC0A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1001(a) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10261">34 U.S.C. 10261(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8F44A87686547E88BB543AB6E1CEAD1"><paragraph id="HABACEFD548304F948D39F26796591E95"><enum>(29)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each fiscal year to carry out part PP.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

