<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6CF1A8E967BD4F15805FB6C934B450AD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9045 IH: Early Childhood Mental Health Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9045</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to identify, review, and implement effective interventions in Head Start programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7133E45B371A4C69989A861047174718" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7D2AAED1753944A48F256B1CFE498674" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Early Childhood Mental Health Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA225D08D96BF48ECBE82FAAC6BA05C9F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Identification of effective interventions in Head Start programs</header> <subsection id="H25E01CE53E0843A3B04993B428357C46"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Interventions that improve social-Emotional and behavioral health of children</header> <paragraph id="HFB8C240023BA4D5CB406CFE0FBE836BF"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families, (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall identify and review interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H866D8AD008B94A62BA7E3948146FB238">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>that improve the behavioral health of children; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H47AFD2E9E3124C8C9B67FD136A2F2832"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>that are evidence based.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC4F3DBF03AF441BE90E720F7AF9F3281">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Focus</header>
 <text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall focus on interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings that—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H9BD63E4AB4EE4FE2B30B2CE2FB044B28">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>can be delivered by a provider or other staff member in or associated with a Head Start program or Early Head Start center;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3DEC6AAECA6E4C9692905D17260CF252">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are demonstrated to improve or support healthy social, emotional, or cognitive development for children in Head Start or Early Head Start programs, with an empirical or theoretical relationship to later mental health or substance abuse outcomes;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3288AF50D2FA431287AEE4DF869FC90F">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>involve changes to center-wide policies or practices, or other services and supports offered in conjunction with Head Start programs or Early Head Start centers, including services provided to adults or families (with or without a child present) for the benefit of the children;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HA2EFEF1E44AA41BAAB37B14A2EF5E035">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>demonstrate effectiveness across racial, ethnic, and geographic populations or demonstrate the capacity to be adapted to be effective across populations;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB6A5AD2B07D842559629BED15EF413A6">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>offer a tiered approach to addressing need, including—</text> <clause id="H522D583A50D04A729333BEB37493FC52"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>universal interventions for all children;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HA50F7AA1A2994C23B522D6E7EDD7E2CD">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">selected prevention for children demonstrating increased need; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H591D3E6B88F140619B6CADBFEE0E01AB">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>indicated prevention for children demonstrating substantial need;</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H916C5D6A42BE4DDBA8005AF20262686A"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>incorporate trauma-informed care approaches; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H670794FC1EDC418B8CDD992EEA29DBEB">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>have a proven record of improving early childhood and social emotional development.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3CAED1EFDC664C9B834DC73B9C4BEC2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interventions that support staff wellness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall identify and review interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings that support staff wellness and self-care.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H756F315CD1FE4408B0635ACD8D684159"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credentials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary, in consultation with relevant experts, shall determine the appropriate credentials for individuals who deliver the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings identified by the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD80120B80E6B4F6E889E5429412984CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation; public input</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD2B077EDE5D546C8949FC9AD80005D43"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with relevant agencies, experts, academics, think tanks, and nonprofit organizations with expertise in early childhood, mental health, and trauma-informed care, including the National Institute of Mental Health, the Administration for Children and Families, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, the Institute of Education Sciences, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H702211BCE09B474C86B92F3535D394EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit public input on—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF702EA93BC44240B58516BB05B4DBC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the design of the reviews under subsections (a) and (b); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C5F672AABDE46FFBA6A5C956E181480"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the findings and conclusions resulting from such reviews.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4FAD7347DB3549B79769F3E60119199C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFE4C11AB410141EE923BDCBD4D5D1736"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complete the initial reviews required by subsections (a) and (b) not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF85D9C484F8448F6AE456854817B5194"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update such reviews and the findings and conclusions therefrom at least every 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDDE8792EA7D54882B31908F24676D3AC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the results of implementing this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HDA7057D04D5845E38CC7B0F9CA3B42BC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Implementing the interventions in Head Start programs</header> <subsection id="H9C90A515C3974E4BA280EF9D2B25580B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families shall award grants to participating Head Start agencies to implement the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings that are identified pursuant to section 2.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H559CEA9086754D4A8E79C2B948B85525"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall ensure that grants awarded under this section are awarded to grantees representing a diversity of geographic areas across the United States, including urban, suburban, and rural areas.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6ECDFC28360C48B9B6726B46341CC6F3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Evaluating implementation of interventions in Head Start programs</header> <subsection id="H70441BD2844347D39E1EB6B4BBB44B91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation and in coordination with the Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCA162DCA64C54315B136348332D26055"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings implemented pursuant to section 3—</text> <subparagraph id="H59E567602BE5420DB0F9096C8B0D9D46"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are effectively implemented pursuant to section 3 and other relevant provisions of law such that the anticipated effect sizes of the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings are achieved; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8A9F02CA254E439E918975B8D7E9AAE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">yield long-term savings;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE01A75E386C2470E8B66E3BECDD28648"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop a method for making the determination required by paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A61F6E7B5BE4080804BEEF27F68D44C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that such method includes competency and testing approaches, performance or outcome measures, or any other methods deemed appropriate by the Assistant Secretary, taking into consideration existing monitoring components of the Head Start and Early Head Start programs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1080EBFDDDA3460A956E30F697AFB942"><enum>(4)</enum><text>solicit public input on the design, findings, and conclusions of this process and shall consider whether updates are necessary at least every 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H34CFDE141EDF4122A79443F5AD37574E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEA242619A3644C80AF6C7335F04294DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct any research and evaluation studies needed; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H025BEE6C19F842F9BA1638DDDBC3D1B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit public input on—</text> <subparagraph id="H7E0729A959D44FA5BE5C86BA6610D1B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the design of the method developed pursuant to subsection (a)(2); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H362D25CA446D49A78BBFB7E0149FE144"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the resulting findings and conclusions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80A4478C3D0940DD8118319DAA12A4CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H578E45015AB745B29A47F254DA552899"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop the method required by subsection (a)(2) and make the initial determination required by subsection (a)(1) not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3675D638576C4F70BC84BF6874874325"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update such method and determination at least every 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA194F53D07E644589E7EAB3FF046E081"><enum>5.</enum><header>Implementing the evaluation framework for Head Start programs</header> 
<subsection id="H3728DE62D494482B9C9A2D9C507229B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation method</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families shall implement the evaluation method developed pursuant to section 4(a) in the Head Start program as a voluntary mechanism for interested Head Start programs or Early Head Start centers to evaluate the extent to which such programs or centers have effectively implemented the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings identified pursuant to section 2, with minimal burden or disruption to programs and centers interested in participating.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFC70DE4E03E64D7ABF43AB43D1B091DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families shall provide guidance, tools, resources, and technical assistance to grantees for implementing and evaluating interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings identified pursuant to section 2 and optimizing the performance of such grantees on the annual evaluations.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9F4C259D80AF4A4A8EF547B6581A14C3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Best Practice Centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families may fund up to 5 Best Practice Centers in Early Childhood Training in universities and colleges to prepare future Head Start agencies and staff able to deliver the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings identified pursuant to section 2.</text></section> <section id="H785CACAD800141769AA56BF2DB276520"><enum>7.</enum><header>Funding</header> <subsection id="HC2A7930A59EA44F5818D9950CFE60D8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $100,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2027 through 2036 for carrying out sections 3(b), 4, and 6.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBA4244B0FDA44381BE9888FB169CDAA0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts authorized to be appropriated by subsection (a) are authorized to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

