<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H84A53E4DD82A491EA86146446FD398E6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8958 IH: To grant to Crook County, Oregon, a right-of-way for the construction of a new road in Juniper Canyon, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8958</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000668">Mr. Bentz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To grant to Crook County, Oregon, a right-of-way for the construction of a new road in Juniper Canyon, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDBC9B34502F24B188023D5AECA58438E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9640CF88358A477A91F3F551D5E3DF10" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Grant of right-of-way to Crook County, Oregon</header> 
<subsection id="H0343F548E62C407FB230FC5868FC62AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, subject to valid existing rights, at the request of the County, the Secretary shall grant to the County a permanent 80-foot wide right-of-way from Oregon Route 380 to Juniper Canyon Road, as generally depicted as <quote>Proposed 80 Foot Right-of-Way</quote> on the Map, for the construction of a new road in Juniper Canyon and permanent public access and use thereafter.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1AE9FDADB7C746FCB0A3C9E5FB5CED4E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conveyance of land to Crook County, Oregon</header> <subsection id="H9BCC4821D8014D4C8D230E6455E74832"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, at the request of the County, the Secretary shall convey to the County, without consideration and without reservation, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the 4 parcels of land, each approximately 40 acres in area, generally depicted as <quote>BLM 40–Acre Parcel Proposed for Conveyance</quote> on the Map.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD07361D75B094FEE8AAC03682D73A335"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The conveyance under subsection (a) shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H1A3F62C4643D4E62BF99F390FA5D5920"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subject to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8E7022F337904B56A5616AC1F4C5992B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>valid existing rights; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74367C71322E44E28D02E2E096905716"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC45A6348CE564DD2B6DC3DDCA4D4FB28"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the primary purpose of establishing fire safe zones to be maintained by the County.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFC3FED6432974F278444C48911A57DA0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cost of conveyance</header><text>As a condition of the conveyance under subsection (a), the County shall pay all costs associated with the conveyance.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B8F962B65CA4B0A88D1A6057D983E56"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reversionary clause</header><text>If the Secretary determines that the property conveyed under subsection (a) is no longer maintained by the County as fire safe zones under subsection (b)(2), the property shall revert to the ownership of the United States.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HCC31FF4080F240A5A041BB5891BB1437"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE413BEE0F6004D55BDD41D5D2F7441EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>County</header><text>The term <term>County</term> means Crook County, Oregon.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FCDBCFAEE22442FA8AF03B0D21F56C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fire safe zone</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>fire safe zone</quote> means a parcel of land maintained for the primary purpose of facilitating emergency response, operational firefighter safety, fuel break integration, and other necessary uses during wildfires and other emergencies that pose a threat to public safety.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF791919B9B484917ACB914FC94C7A479"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map titled <quote>Juniper Canyon Land Conveyance</quote> prepared by the Bureau of Land Management and dated April 8, 2026.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41D5E883D59F44648E60F8660C17F41C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

