<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7247CEFE23454D5CB04B61161E97F948" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7466 IH: Safeguarding America’s Food Economy and Controlling Agricultural Threats to Livestock and Enterprises Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7466</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260210">February 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a memorandum of understanding or other interagency agreement, to carry out, and coordinate on, activities to prevent, control, and eradicate New World screwworm in wildlife and non-livestock species of animals on certain Federal lands, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDD5C3BDAD22949E280B850AEB099DB66" style="OLC"><section id="H2A97844BEAE04FCA902E4636622D7C54" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding America’s Food Economy and Controlling Agricultural Threats to Livestock and Enterprises Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE CATTLE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H038AB754826741D7A05E52E70DA54FFE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency cooperation on New World screwworm eradication and monitoring activities</header><subsection id="HF8F7E7F26F724C9683EA817013998106"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall enter into a memorandum of understanding or other interagency agreement, to carry out, and coordinate on, activities to prevent, control, and eradicate New World screwworm in wildlife and non-livestock species of animals on covered lands. Such activities shall include—</text><paragraph id="HB1C32A9162684B9D9121A212985930FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating joint surveillance and monitoring protocols for early detection of New World screwworm in wildlife and non-livestock species of animals on covered lands;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE11257F19AE04828B227CB258F9E3F99"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of controlling and containing New World screwworm in all species of animals on covered lands in the event of an outbreak, coordinating with (as appropriate) State wildlife and livestock health officers with respect to response procedures, the distribution of information, and notification procedures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H334FB58A28A14C1D9DC574CE91F67E25"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating New World screwworm eradication protocols to protect wildlife and non-livestock species of animals on covered lands, stabilize and reduce the threat to domestic animal agriculture, and safeguard the domestic food supply and the economy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAB850E31E3345C8948D22DB50006171"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing science-based and risk-based approaches and systems to facilitate continuity of business for non-infected animals of all species and non-contaminated areas on covered lands.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H877371B7C5CD4ACAB6FF29CE436681CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the date on which the Secretary of Agriculture certifies to the Congress that the New World screwworm has been quarantined south of the Darien Gap in Panama, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior shall jointly submit to the Committee on Agriculture and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report detailing the following:</text><paragraph id="H296D981D4E6D47FC89A4801225E9E57C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent of interagency coordination between each Federal agency involved in the prevention, control, and eradication of New World screwworm on covered lands;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7DE3C08929E4015BDFCA9032D0F31D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any progress made in the surveillance and prevention of New World screwworm outbreaks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC7FF7CCE05442D4BCC1624D0F56FAC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any incidents of infestation of New World screwworm in the United States and Federal collaborative activities undertaken to control the spread of such infestation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCD7FA48DB0A4942A4A068F37AAFA667"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any recommendations for legislative or administrative action to improve the Federal response capacity to the threat of New World screwworm.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0BCD3A8737C425F828A55234282F91F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered lands defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>covered lands</quote> means lands managed by the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, the Bureau of Reclamation, or the Forest Service.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

