<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25B68-2YD-P0-J3M"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 528 ATS: Supporting after-school programs and Lights On Afterschool, a national celebration of after-school programs held on October 23, 2025.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 528</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting after-school programs and Lights On Afterschool, a national celebration of after-school programs held on October 23, 2025.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas millions of children in the United States have parents who work outside of the home;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas high-quality programs that expand learning opportunities for children, such as after-school, before-school, summer, and expanded learning opportunities, provide safe, challenging, engaging, and fun learning experiences, including experiences that encourage the study of science, technology, engineering, and math that help children and youth develop social, emotional, physical, cultural, and academic skills;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas high-quality after-school programs and high-quality expanded learning opportunities provide students with hands-on, engaging lessons that are aligned with the school day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas high-quality after-school programs complement regular and expanded school days and support working families by ensuring that the children of those families are safe and productive during the hours parents are working;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas high-quality after-school programs engage families, schools, and diverse community partners in advancing the well-being of children and youth in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas high-quality after-school programs that partner with high-quality community-based organizations build stronger communities by integrating schools with the larger community; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lights On Afterschool, a national celebration of after-school, before-school, summer, and expanded learning opportunities programs will be held on October 23, 2025, to highlight the critical importance of those high-quality programs to children and the families and communities of those children: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate supports Lights On Afterschool, a national celebration of after-school programs held on October 23, 2025.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

