<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H04A9CCDF3E3E4084A1D54666A980E661" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8095 IH: Ensuring Medicaid Continuity for Children in Foster Care Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8095</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to ensure that children in foster care who are placed in a qualified residential treatment program are eligible for Medicaid.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1861A95655784E92BC6256DB9EAF4512" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H64407DEA7D83408BA4487E3E5901C382" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Medicaid Continuity for Children in Foster Care Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAE1E2D35BD0041B3876E6925C3369E80"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption of children in foster care who are placed in a qualified residential treatment program from the Medicaid IMD exclusion</header> <subsection id="H33D8B650CDF14CC99BBE0AB1910695A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)</external-xref>) is amended. in the matter designated as subdivision (B) following the last numbered paragraph of such section, by inserting <quote>and services provided to any individual who is a child in foster care under the responsibility of a State who has been placed in a child care institution that is a qualified residential treatment program (as defined in section 472(k)(4)), without regard to whether payments are made on behalf of such child under section 472</quote> after <quote>section 1915(l)</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H8E008D19A15A4030899B47F5D19CFCE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to items and services furnished in calendar quarters beginning on or after October 1, 2026.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

