<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HECD9D728D6224B40AB36514B4DDB95D9" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1380 IH: Commemorating 50 years of women at the service academies.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1380</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001245">Mr. Menefee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000197">Ms. Pelosi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating 50 years of women at the service academies.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, between June 28 and July 7, 1976, 395 women were enrolled at the military service academies, with—</text> <paragraph id="H2B3C5584A93247AC910008C45B2D09A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>157 women enrolled at the United States Air Force Academy and 38 women enrolled at the United States Coast Guard Academy on June 28;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H990BF443918A4AC493148BA6F885087B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>81 women enrolled at the United States Naval Academy on July 6; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD16DA6A19274415198927469BE016A60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>119 women enrolled at the United States Military Academy on July 7;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas over 24,000 women have graduated from the academies to date, and have risen to the highest levels of leadership within the military services, to include four-star rank, combatant command, General Officers, Flag Officers, and leadership levels at all of the academies;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, from 1976 to 2026, the percentage of women officers in the United States Armed Forces has increased from about 5 percent to about 20 percent;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas service academy women fought heroically in combat in Iraq and Afghanistan, leading troops, sustaining injuries, and in some cases paying the ultimate sacrifice;</text> </whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas service academy women have equaled or outpaced their peers in every branch of the service, including meeting male standards in ground combat arms roles, and served with distinction in roles from the infantry to submarines to pilots and astronauts; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas service academy women have broken barriers, and include—</text> <paragraph id="H41E512F6BD344AE383182FB450BA82FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the first three women to earn the Army Ranger tab;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C6311C31F3A4C72B895351CD5E9F6B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the first woman to command an aircraft carrier;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0768E604032742548634CEF576AEBB0C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the first woman Thunderbird;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD6CD9055F6F140EC94A0E59240074A1D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the first woman Blue Angel;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28C6BA78AAA0424F854E29D339549FD7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the first African-American woman to command a United States Navy ship; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F3F7BDAB34846649BCB4B28EE6D05BA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the first woman service secretary, among many other examples;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas evidence has shown that women have strengthened the Armed Forces, adding their talent, intelligence, fitness, strategic thinking, character, and competence to the benefit of the United States Armed Forces;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas service academy women have continued to serve out of uniform, as senior leaders in the executive branch, CEOs of nonprofit and for-profit organizations, Members of United States Congress, and as Governor; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, since 1976, service academy women have distinguished themselves in all areas of endeavor in service to their country: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H234BA07C54BE4D21A92D77E5E1EE7C61"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA67CCCE89D9C4F2896E1C01D1F6F5A6A"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HC67C673090434BA3AFB01E11730630E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>50 Years of Women at the Service Academies Day</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H883025A24B15478BA3898B4A11247E98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the extraordinary service to the Nation of the women cadets and graduates of the United States Military Academy, the United States Naval Academy, the United States Air Force Academy, and the United States Coast Guard Academy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBEBB78D9567644E188AB84B28F8F55EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors past, present, and future women who serve in the United States Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

