<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA8F2956A020F4BF8BC9EDCF243168FAB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7064 IH: AI in Health Care Efficiency and Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7064</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a study on strategies for the application of artificial intelligence technologies that can be used in the health care industry to improve administrative and clerical work and preserve the privacy and security of patient data, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H64F155FAD6C5477AA76A326ACD37CE33" style="OLC"><section id="H374C224D655F46A19F21ABA0712F64A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AI in Health Care Efficiency and Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H12C3707BFA5F44D09FF96CFCAB2CAFAF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H9ADD94ED78BA4ADFAF6F3B4D5C1987ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administrative and clerical work contribute significantly to health care costs and health care provider burnout.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA64D85E13E7B4147BB837CA818717B58"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial intelligence technologies have the potential to streamline clerical work and record keeping, allowing health care providers to spend more time with patients.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29EC4EE6279A412AAEC4EF823068B2F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Protection of patient privacy and compliance with regulations promulgated pursuant to section 264 of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d-2</external-xref> note) are essential in the development and deployment of artificial intelligence tools in health care.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEEB52FDF1EB84571B003586F6768AD7B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on artificial intelligence in the health care industry</header><subsection id="HD311EF54708A4A60B9BDD2C5516EED07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct a study on strategies for the application of artificial intelligence technologies that can be used across the health care industry, including health care providers and health plans as defined under section 262 of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d">42 U.S.C. 1320d</external-xref>) and covered entities and business associates as defined under section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, to improve administrative and clerical processes and protect the privacy and security of patient data in programs and activities within the jurisdiction of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1743133EFFF4662A0461CCBCC311A70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Secretary shall evaluate existing strategies and identify additional strategies to apply artificial intelligence technologies to—</text><paragraph id="H866C60BC6BF144FAAFBA2DF166F81C4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce administrative burden and improve efficiency in administrative and clerical tasks, including scheduling, claims processing, documentation, prior authorization workflows, and other operational tasks performed by health care providers and health plans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4E9FCB343CB4887BCFB0A72130FA828"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the accuracy, timeliness, and interoperability of patient record-keeping, including electronic health record documentation; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E76D947DD934633B6FA18C260F57A19" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the privacy, security, and integrity of patient data, including compliance with regulations promulgated pursuant to section 264 of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</external-xref> note) and any applicable standards established by the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1AD273A19D84F1190CDE57D2D95A449"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate how artificial intelligence technologies can be used to detect, prevent, and mitigate cybersecurity attacks on health care providers, including—</text><subparagraph id="H65F06A0D69234A678799C9A0049A2B41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ransomware incidents;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD127260EEC04F10B196EF3F5B2030F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>data breaches; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD3A09DC418049A99F23A68DB8F4EB42"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other threats experienced by healthcare providers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7EEC905D307407CAE0E6617446E041F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the study required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall seek to consult with—</text><paragraph id="HBE46F41FDA3D4BBF85E75F947F1E27ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA63AA7B340AB4B3A9533AD7A2D35DC69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Director of the National Institutes of Health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82B93C920ACB4CF8BDB1616C7E4C9F0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C7859FF43194FA787B9C559D4AC889D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Assistant Secretary for Technology Policy/Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology for the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8650E68D4530452B801A265654A71557"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the Office for Civil Rights for the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECC0912D6C974F72B86155D9FCF14204"><enum>(6)</enum><text>academic institutions; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76CAB514F07A49F98B38E45742163084"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">artificial intelligence developers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AA8CD1112B34A0FB6860F9DCBFAD771"><enum>(8)</enum><text>civil rights experts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AF13E6CA76444898236631958D34A7E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>health care providers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5276F75B04794F6FA1F1C68696EFA82C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>hospital associations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA11E9FA5301C4826999D53B8316C6744"><enum>(11)</enum><text>information technology vendors that serve the health care industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ACB95E779EC474495FE1791969A97C8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>nonprofit research institutions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56516D92848740A7BBF695755F0F4B2A"><enum>(13)</enum><text>patient privacy experts. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58F880F354064E62889A2E223C48DDE5" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the Secretary completes the study required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on the study conducted under subsection (a) that contains—</text><paragraph id="H03AD978125564EE39B34DF0AE672478A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the findings and conclusions of the study, including identified risks, opportunities, and implementation challenges; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF49646B481D45AC85A877A7DF74812A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of existing artificial intelligence tools currently in use for administrative or clerical functions in the health care industry, including their effectiveness, limitations, and implications for provider burden;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45CA65E9F1A741CE93248BBCF37883C5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for future research and pilot programs led or supported by the Department of Health and Human Services relating to the use of artificial intelligence in administrative and clerical functions within the health care industry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1CBFAA4CEDE4F6AAAE948063D829169" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policy options for Congress and the Secretary to support the development, testing, implementation, and oversight of artificial intelligence tools that enhance administrative efficiency in health care while ensuring strong protections for patient privacy and data security.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

