<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25A61-J95-W6-0MG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 475 ATS: Designating November 1, 2025, as “National Bison Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 475</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251029">October 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating November 1, 2025, as <quote>National Bison Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 9, 2016, the North American bison was adopted as the national mammal of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas bison are considered a historical and cultural symbol of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas bison are integrally linked with the economic and spiritual lives of many Indian Tribes through trade and sacred ceremonies;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas there are approximately 87 Indian Tribes participating in the InterTribal Buffalo Council, which is a Tribal organization incorporated pursuant to section 17 of the Act of June 18, 1934 (commonly known as the <quote>Indian Reorganization Act</quote>) (48 Stat. 988, chapter 576; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5124">25 U.S.C. 5124</external-xref>);</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas numerous members of Indian Tribes are involved in bison restoration on Tribal land;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas members of Indian Tribes have a combined herd of almost 25,000 bison on more than 1,000,000 acres of Tribal land in 22 States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas bison play an important role in the health of the wildlife, landscapes, and grasslands of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas bison hold significant economic value for private producers and Tribal and rural communities;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, as of 2022, the Department of Agriculture estimates that 192,477 head of bison were under the stewardship of private producers, creating jobs and contributing to the food security of the United States by providing a sustainable and healthy meat source;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas a bison has been depicted on the official seal of the Department of the Interior since 1912;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Department of the Interior has launched the Bison Conservation Initiative, a 10-year cooperative initiative to coordinate the conservation and restoration of wild American bison;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas a bison is portrayed on 2 State flags;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the bison has been adopted by 3 States as the official mammal or animal of those States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the buffalo nickel played an important role in modernizing the currency of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas several sports teams and businesses have the bison as a mascot, which highlights the iconic and cultural significance of bison in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Indigenous communities and a group of ranchers helped save bison from extinction in the late 1800s by gathering the remaining bison of the diminished herds;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, on December 8, 1905, William Hornaday, Theodore Roosevelt, and others formed the American Bison Society in response to the near extinction of bison in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, on October 11, 1907, the American Bison Society sent 15 captive-bred bison from the New York Zoological Park, now known as the <quote>Bronx Zoo</quote>, to the first big game refuge in the United States, now known as the <quote>Wichita Mountains Wildlife Refuge</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, in 2005, the American Bison Society was reestablished, bringing together bison ranchers, Native American leaders and bison herd managers, Federal and State agencies, conservation organizations, artists, writers, young people, and natural and social scientists from the United States, Canada, and Mexico to create a vision for the North American bison in the 21st century;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas there are bison herds in national wildlife refuges, national parks, national forests, and other Federal land;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas there are bison in State-managed herds across 11 States;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas private, public, and Tribal bison leaders are working together to continue bison restoration throughout North America;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas there is a growing effort to celebrate and officially recognize the historical, cultural, and economic significance of the North American bison to the heritage of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas members of Indian Tribes, bison producers, conservationists, sportsmen, educators, and other public and private partners have celebrated the annual National Bison Day since 2012 and are committed to continuing this tradition annually on the first Saturday of November: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id2c67055bebc24fe5b4439efeb11266dd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates November 1, 2025, the first Saturday of November, as <quote>National Bison Day</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id71a3e0f0de5f4a4f818ff16cf8d1d168"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe the day with appropriate ceremonies and activities. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

