<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H057900897B794017BE088F206DCF23B6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5891 IH: Withhold Member Pay During Shutdowns Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5891</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reduce the annual rate of pay of Members of Congress if a Government shutdown occurs during a year, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C53115DD7D342828AD071BBF0FC5BC3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7EA7041CF94C4189A0777C4C47CF1620" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Withhold Member Pay During Shutdowns Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4468C13364AC49A1BB66643D4AB313D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>No pay for Members of Congress during Government shutdowns</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HFD5D0314CF6342AEBCF7CE379BB423EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text>
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H5D1F90EA2216472786EFC2B202F1F1C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Government shutdown</term> means a lapse in appropriations for 1 or more Federal agencies or departments;</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H1C9EFE0700794F84A9557E5CFEFA74D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means an individual serving in a position under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 601(a)(1) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501(1)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H11961F884FA14F9287D211426F1753F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>payroll administrator</term>, with respect to a House of Congress, means—</text> <subparagraph id="HEBD4C427348C4FE9BD90DC1E0D78B5AA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of the Senate, the Secretary of the Senate, or an employee of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate who is designated by the Secretary to carry out the requirements of this section; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H959DF4C04053471681297A1869D7B7B3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, or an employee of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer who is designated by the Chief Administrative Officer to carry out the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0E43423145964182A151D8319B7C1752"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requiring reduction of pay of Members of Congress if Government shutdown occurs</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE321D8BB7C1C4E7EBA7FE4A881EE6E45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If on any day during a pay period a Government shutdown is in effect, the payroll administrator of each House of Congress shall exclude from the payments otherwise required to be made with respect to that pay period for the compensation of each Member of Congress who serves in that House of Congress an amount equal to the product of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H01B90E48319D4C0C8E89B80D9A68DEEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an amount equal to one day's worth of pay under the annual rate of pay of the Member under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09DA85CAD8074B8B9F3267129BFF01AA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of 24-hour periods during the pay period during which the Government shutdown is in effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H6DDFE77AC39C43C49E3CB83C7FE6A86A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall apply with respect to days occurring after the date of the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2026 (in this section referred to as the <quote>pay reduction effective date</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EBC123B923844B681FD26D34E486A2B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rule for Members of Congress before general election</header> <paragraph id="H213C8B7F32D34D02B3E3569159C2CAF1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Holding salaries in escrow</header><text>If on any day before the pay reduction effective date a Government shutdown is in effect, the payroll administrator of each House of Congress shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H168A863279C44700B1CFB6F5B1ECFA16" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>withhold from the payments otherwise required to be made with respect to a pay period for the compensation of each Member of Congress who serves in that House of Congress an amount equal to the product of—</text> <clause id="H51C1C3E913A14712A53F5A55F0879B5F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to one day’s worth of pay under the annual rate of pay applicable to the Member under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H69F40C343CDB46E19C79DBCC688A980D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of 24-hour periods during which the Government shutdown is in effect which occur during the pay period; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H427523520E6242BCA2AFDB894FC309EC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deposit in an escrow account all amounts withheld under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8552FCD018FA422E97C208719F2EB3F4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Release of amounts at end of the Congress</header><text>In order to ensure that this subsection is carried out in a manner that shall not vary the compensation of Senators or Representatives in violation of the 27th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, the payroll administrator of a House of Congress shall release for payments to Members of that House of Congress any amounts remaining in any escrow account under this subsection on the pay reduction effective date.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C72C91CF3B04A8B9487F3C427759EF4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This subsection shall apply with respect to days during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the pay reduction effective date.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8ED913587D794580B1D2741D2CB00F2F" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Role of Secretary of the Treasury</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall provide the payroll administrators of the Houses of Congress with such assistance as may be necessary to enable the payroll administrators to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

