<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GOE25880-C6H-GR-9G1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3379 IS: Expedited Access to Reemployment Learning Yields Benefits for Workers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3379</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title III of the Social Security Act to provide flexibility in grants for reemployment services and eligibility assessments.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="not-changed" id="HEC51D9281C09411D9EB64AB8CAF7CFF3"><section section-type="section-one" id="HF3BF37C6FAA546068D71D9E1E3A82F2D" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expedited Access to Reemployment Learning Yields Benefits for Workers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EARLY Benefits for Workers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id3203B25328B544BD8A7F66D001E15BC6" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Flexibility in grants for reemployment services and eligibility assessments</header><subsection id="id3D97BB51776C4F8CB5CB6AE2D3017614" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 306(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/506">42 U.S.C. 506(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3ce3ec9221e43e7ab0d3c9cb2b86eca"><subsection id="id606f765018994196acc3a2918f0fc882"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authority for early interventions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id673bdf3f453d4a3186e2746cdd49564d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out a State program of reemployment services and eligibility assessments using grant funds awarded to the State under this section, a State may use up to the lessor of 20 percent of such grant funds or $3,000,000 to provide reemployment services and eligibility assessment services and tools to claimants for regular compensation as soon as a claimant files an initial claim for regular compensation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfacd3b73b8fd482eab4d6d9f0ec5a18e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of eligibility</header><text>In adjudicating an initial claim for regular compensation with respect to a claimant, a State shall not make a determination that such claimant is ineligible for such regular compensation based solely on such claimant's failure to participate in the early interventions under paragraph (1) during the period between such initial claim and such claimant's first week of such regular compensation that is based on such initial claim.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13723e3394004a9fb53df19e8f42c738"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent determination of ineligibility</header><text>In the case where a claimant is provided reemployment services and eligibility assessment services and tools by a State pursuant to the early interventions under paragraph (1) but is subsequently determined by the State to be ineligible for regular compensation, the following shall apply:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide02d1d16c1814078a5c3c00d35a2b672"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Such claimant shall be ineligible to continue to be provided such reemployment services and eligibility assessment services and tools unless such services and tools are funded by another source or are generally available to members of the public.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10ec6a02692c4149807373eb506c533d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such State—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44eeec801ce14b40b4b8de1250c95750"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be considered to be out of compliance with the terms and conditions of the grant program by reason of the provision of such reemployment services and eligibility assessment services and tools to such claimant prior to such determination; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40d749e28799423da383dc37d3a91a31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be required to return any grant funds used in providing such reemployment services and eligibility assessment services and tools to such claimant prior to such determination.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id888685f42f0345c28885b23f0e179dc6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall preclude amounts expended by a State on the early interventions under paragraph (1) from being used to meet the threshold requirement under subsection (c)(2) if the expenditures otherwise meet the requirements for interventions under such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id114C7A483EEE4BC5A4BB73266ED564AB" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

