<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H31FABDD8DC4C4DBE97E06B995F1B968E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8114 IH: Endless Mountains National Heritage Area Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8114</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act to designate as a component of the National Heritage Area System the Endless Mountains National Heritage Area in the State of Pennsylvania, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H38E0C180541541D79B4EC5AB2E122AA2" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H6BCEEBE9C30346BFA9C32A5CA1DBD8C3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Endless Mountains National Heritage Area Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9503BAE972CD4AD2A9DED9001BC56B3E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of Endless Mountains National Heritage Area</header> <subsection id="H8C7915847DC34FE98A7BA2847E959134"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>Section 6001(a) of the John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/9">Public Law 116–9</external-xref>; 133 Stat. 768; 136 Stat. 6163) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF4FC5DA858542048A9B679470ED5403"> 
<paragraph id="H6E8A61C79D0F44CC99FC31FFFE98C1E7"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Endless Mountains National Heritage Area</header> 
<subparagraph id="H48BF3B278B3D4904B7A0DB3D6E3804BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established as a component of the National Heritage Area System the Endless Mountains National Heritage Area in the State of Pennsylvania, to consist of Bradford, Sullivan, Susquehanna, and Wyoming Counties, Pennsylvania, and any portions of other counties in the State of Pennsylvania identified in the feasibility study for the Endless Mountains National Heritage Area, the specific boundaries of which shall be established by the Secretary based on that feasibility study.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H70BC4244649D4E6ABC990072E0F178D1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Local coordinating entity</header><text>The Endless Mountains Heritage Region, Inc., shall be the local coordinating entity for the National Heritage Area designated by subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E0FC597F66B454D9EEBF9867B668D8E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>For the purposes of section 6001(c) of the John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/9">Public Law 116–9</external-xref>; 133 Stat. 772; 136 Stat. 6173), the local coordinating entity for the Endless Mountains National Heritage Area designated under the amendment made by subsection (a) shall submit to the Secretary of the Interior for approval a proposed management plan for the Endless Mountains National Heritage Area not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF070350505B94FD38AA79D68746528D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text>For the purposes of subsection (g)(4) of section 6001 of the John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/9">Public Law 116–9</external-xref>; 133 Stat. 776), the authority of the Secretary of the Interior to provide assistance under that section for the Endless Mountains National Heritage Area designated under the amendment made by subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is 15 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

