<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4CAFAA752CE74D3B80E81C8F349222F6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6226 IH: Latino Youth Mental Health Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6226</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for a national awareness and outreach campaign to improve mental health among the Hispanic and Latino youth population.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5BC28BC9AD894F138DA296A5CBF57759" style="OLC"><section id="H7FD08C039ACF4CAE8BE090F2A5A32F99" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Latino Youth Mental Health Empowerment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBCF101726594436BAD9253882A9CBB5B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HF5DD97CCC7244FEDAC64AEED59F5B875"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hispanic and Latino youth often experience and suffer from toxic stress, which stems from prolonged stress, trauma, or adverse childhood experiences.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF17E4C783EA142F19633EBEC5458AD19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At least 78 percent of Hispanic and Latino youth suffer from at least one adverse childhood experience, which can harm a child’s physical and mental health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDADB316C84F04A3FAECDC34309129E3D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Among Hispanic and Latino youth, approximately 60 percent were more likely to report poor mental health compared to their counterparts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57256E0645024A828220885DAE81E9C5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">About 42 percent of Hispanic and Latino youth have reported persistent feelings of sadness or hopelessness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H703316C92E1840FAB2F547DDBEA3ED12" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 18 percent of Hispanic and Latino high school students have seriously contemplated suicide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3A7E62BE0014782A05ABEFF5F016A2E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Hispanic and Latinos are less likely than any other ethnic groups to receive clinical or school-based mental illness treatment and medication.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6A411D33EC7401692B676159C01D3F3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Hispanic and Latino youth are less likely to use mental health care services compared to children of other ethnic groups.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6DDFF2B97A14831B44558A201F968D2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>There are numerous factors that impact accessibility to mental health services and mental health outcomes. For instance, lower rates of health insurance, language and cultural barriers, and lack of parental education on mental health all contribute to adverse mental health outcomes for Hispanic and Latino youth.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BD780226A364398B59F01162FA721A9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Increased awareness and outreach about mental health to Hispanic and Latino parents, caregivers, and youth are vital to ensure that Hispanic and Latino youth can experience positive mental health outcomes and reduced mental illness.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H02A96BD71CAB4C36AD8607C29E9D33CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>National hispanic and latino mental health awareness and outreach campaign</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd">42 U.S.C. 290dd et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="HCE14D765A5DA413DBCDD696CC842E6DC" style="OLC"><section id="HE3F25942037B4AC7BC5D1E64C4D3246A"><enum>554.</enum><header>National hispanic and latino youth mental health awareness and outreach campaign</header><subsection id="H291EB58E67C047CDB02CBF53D539AA3B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study on prior campaigns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall conduct a study on—</text><paragraph id="H77D1FD37A95145FD93B43648CC357B18"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any education and outreach campaigns to promote mental health and reduce stigma associated with mental health that were carried out by the Secretary on or before the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Latino Youth Mental Health Empowerment Act</short-title>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4D35284D540485DA617D129971C9E0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>which messaging delivered through such campaigns was most effective within the Latino community.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09C53E87E6EB4466A4AE8D5172CF871F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of campaign</header><paragraph id="H9219A7C7774F4CBF822B8E3C926F7963"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary, shall develop and implement a national awareness and outreach campaign to promote mental health and reduce stigma associated with mental health within the Hispanic and Latino youth population. Such campaign shall be developed—</text><subparagraph id="HBC24BBCFFDE6491E9A3A006263EC409D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>taking into account the results of the study conducted under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ABB9D034B61423FADFC8182E3C9D750"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in coordination with the Director of the Office of Minority Health, the Director of the National Institutes of Health, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, and the Secretary of Education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77F788512EF9465D8EA291ABC397E185"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in consultation with relevant advocacy and mental health organizations serving populations of Hispanic and Latino individuals or communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5BC242C2D1F43BB99A2CACEAB1FED5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements of campaign</header><text>The campaign under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="HF9756E8F82E344B1BD029E3D230E3A3D"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a culturally- and linguistically-competent awareness campaign, targeted at Hispanic and Latino parents, caregivers, youth, teachers, school personnel, and school clinic staff to meet the diverse needs of Hispanic and Latino youth, including—</text>
                                <clause id="H84E63B31F8AD48A3A85DD54FAFF4AFF0">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>increasing awareness of symptoms associated with mental illnesses, including their prevalence and misconceptions among youth;</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H4E6E0440D39143298DB18A39A6CD21FA">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing awareness of factors driving mental illness among Hispanic and Latino youth, including factors that are social determinants of health, taking into account differences within population subgroups, such as gender, gender identity, age, sexual orientation, ethnicity, geographic region or location, immigration status, and history of adverse childhood experiences;</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="HDC490644AF3747D5A00A162488FA030A">
                                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>combatting the stigma of mental illnesses that are common in the Hispanic and Latino community, taking into account differences within such population subgroups; and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H215E1A54CAE541C38ED372CD267C5AC9">
                                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>increasing awareness of evidence-based, culturally-tailored, and trauma-informed mental illness screening, intervention, and treatment options, taking into account differences within such population subgroups; and</text>
                                </clause>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF507BE75AC4447549A2C881962AB7896"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a culturally and linguistically competent outreach campaign, targeted at Hispanic and Latino parents, caregivers, youth, teachers, school personnel, and school clinic staff to meet the diverse needs of Hispanic and Latino youth, including—</text><clause id="H3CAD5CEB9C81482989941A40C44DB387"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating and distributing mental health materials and resources (including materials relating to the National Suicide Prevention and Mental Health Hotline under section 520E–3) in collaboration with local, State, and national community advocates and stakeholders, taking into account differences within population subgroups, such as gender, gender identity, age, sexual orientation, ethnicity, and geographic region or location;</text></clause><clause id="H8F623DA2540B4C828DDCD00A90CFE947"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hosting in-person and virtual mental health workshops at relevant locations, including elementary schools and secondary schools (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965), community centers, and other appropriate sites;</text></clause><clause id="H81F37C3A958740D7BF0400A39815171C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing youth mental health first aid training to parents, caregivers, teachers, school personnel, and school clinic staff, and other personnel that consistently interact or work with the target population;</text></clause><clause id="HE5E4D41775D4490880F99CFE419CF002"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing partnerships between local, State, and national mental health agencies and elementary schools and secondary schools (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965), after-school programs, and other appropriate sites that serve Hispanic and Latino youth; and</text></clause><clause id="H496B66ECC09D4088BBE94111D4B22FF9"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing mental health screenings and on-site consultations at elementary schools and secondary schools (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965), community centers, and other appropriates sites.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAF3BEC1A1554F9FAFFAFDF61BD805CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H6514FC4C76B34612B83861F3B7F3C579"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study and report on the Hispanic and Latino youth mental health crisis</header><subsection id="HC37AF7CB1CC7471AB4E8D14BAC1AB0D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><paragraph id="HC47E09FBECAF45E793F68EB7C48EC0BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, in coordination with the Director of the National Institutes of Health, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Director of the Office of Minority Health, and the Surgeon General of the Public Health Service, shall conduct a study on mental health among Hispanic and Latino youth.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DB334D8212E4A9BA9B59B6AC9F45ACA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Such study required under paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="H3C03BA68F18C420CA27585ACD91C30BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the prevalence and risk factors of mental health and substance use disorders among Hispanic and Latino youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC744A090C22842D1969A72F6A9B9B164"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the prevalence of attempted suicide and death by suicide among Hispanic and Latino youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45A125875F7D4903BCBA703EAC0F0391"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the prevalence of treatment for mental health and substance use disorders among Hispanic and Latino youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28B03248982F4947AD48ECAB0B680EAF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the awareness and utilization of the 9–8–8 National Suicide Prevention and Mental Health Hotline under section 520E–3 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-36c">42 U.S.C. 290bb–36c</external-xref>) and other mental health and suicide prevention hotlines among Hispanic and Latino youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0E3CFF979C54B5BB1C8776D0343E29F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the awareness, utilization, and availability of mobile crisis care teams, dispatched through the 9–8–8 National Suicide Prevention and Mental Health Hotline or other mental health and suicide prevent hotlines, among Hispanic and Latino youth; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D013D916DF34755B18FCCF07102D2E7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the awareness, utilization, and availability of crisis centers for Hispanic and Latino youth in acute mental health or substance use crisis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42355A297D9F4D7EBADB1F0189D2DAC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Latino Youth Mental Health Empowerment Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and make publicly available, a report on the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a), including—</text><paragraph id="H058D03ED3F7E4CC78B9913F5392BD52D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification of the barriers to accessing mental health services and treatment for Hispanic and Latino youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7473DF92418746FB9AD7B83D70F60749"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations to improve mental health services, outreach, and treatment among Hispanic and Latino youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7366F3714E7646AF8076B8F18C585CDC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations to reduce rates of mental health and substance use disorders and suicide among Hispanic and Latino youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E93C437523E4E92AF40BAB5799EA3B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations to improve awareness and utilization of the 9–8–8 National Suicide Prevention and Mental Health Hotline and other mental health and suicide prevention hotlines among Hispanic and Latino youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9A8FAF3D0F04FEEB4C2726FB05F4B7C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations to improve access to, and utilization of, mobile crisis care teams among Hispanic and Latino youth, when clinically appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A6A0DDBE3764988A972E9964B682B83"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recommendation to improve access to, and utilization of, crisis centers for Hispanic and Latino youth in acute mental health or substance use crisis, when clinically appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99A2AA35F1B14E55843DC9837A9E0B45"><enum>(7)</enum><text>such other recommendations as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC79D3D2E6B6448CB5790B8C3FE93960"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any data included in the study or report under this section shall be disaggregated by race, ethnicity, age, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, geographic region, disability status, and other relevant factors, in a manner that, as appropriate and feasible, protects personal privacy and that is consistent with applicable Federal and State privacy law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H88C40407B07F43A79B7D6C1D3114A457"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subsection></section><section id="H60215256541C4622A407885A04F2EB98"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study and report on the Hispanic and Latino mental health workforce shortage</header><subsection id="H8DDE6155E8164DDDAB93DEC327E8C367"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><paragraph id="HA252C5CFA7EE476AB82B6BB199CF49F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, in coordination with the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Director of the Office of Minority Health, the Surgeon General of the Public Health Service, and the Secretary of Labor, and shall conduct a study on strategies for increasing the mental health professional workforce that identify as Hispanic or Latino.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF2076774C1D420BABD2F2DD2995C241"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Such study required under paragraph (1) shall address—</text><subparagraph id="H1F740F11EAD74681BC20F2EFFC19AF63"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of licensed clinical and non-clinical mental health providers who identify as Hispanic or Latino;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB61DBABA13D4D12959FEBB64F3170EF"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each such provider, information regarding the current license type, geographic location of practice, and type of employer (such as a hospital, federally-qualified health center (as defined in section 1861(aa)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)(4)</external-xref>))), elementary school or secondary school (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>), or private practice);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81EDE4EA83AD4035940787F07A1F3D6D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information regarding the languages spoken among providers, including the level of proficiency in speaking, reading, and writing such languages; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7DF9732C93D4C2897590BC430A3693F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current enrollment of Hispanic and Latino individuals in mental health professional education programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD3385A8624140EC8E4A3BE0AA5A4BEC"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Report</header> <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and make publicly available, a report on the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a). Such report shall—</text>
                <paragraph id="H11EE5769CCC74B98BE5D0E1C42F4F76E">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess Hispanic and Latino clinical and non-clinical mental health providers’ knowledge and awareness of the barriers to quality mental health care services faced by Hispanic and Latino individuals;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HDF598BFAEC484C92AEF2A68761162FAF">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include recommendations for actions to be taken by the Secretary to increase the number of Hispanic and Latino clinical and non-clinical mental health professionals;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4474C9E103024D02B880DB915CE05473">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include recommendations to improve enrollment in mental health professional education programs among Hispanic and Latino individuals; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBB6F38109E2241C3A8F6D30614ECF819">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include such other recommendations as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
                </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="H15C7692122864CBC9D685D80C47FBB4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data</header><text>Any data included in the study or report under this section shall be disaggregated by race, ethnicity, age, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, geographic region, disability status, and other relevant factors, in a manner that protects personal privacy and that is consistent with applicable Federal and State privacy law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC08C4D37D8214F8B90166D90DFC98765"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>clinical and non-clinical mental health provider</term> means any individual licensed to provide mental health or substance use disorder services, including in the professions of social work, psychology, psychiatry, marriage and family therapy, mental health counseling, substance use disorder counseling, peer support, primary care, pediatrics, nursing, and other fields as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H35DE36BED39E4A81B647452FECD494DC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

