<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE689A651423B40D6AC54884E26734C3D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8334 IH: Taxpayer Protection and Somalia Accountability Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8334</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the suspension of bilateral and multilateral foreign assistance to the Government of Somalia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFB7F17094AF44D729D07DF154888D308" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H86C7FECC35ED4069B442F79BF6CC116F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taxpayer Protection and Somalia Accountability Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8C503587CED8498AA2F8AC237D115477" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE341576FD4FC4B118D65307A623D349F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President should direct the heads of appropriate Federal agencies to restrict, prevent, or stop the transfer of all remittances from individuals or entities in the United States to individuals or entities in the Federal Republic of Somalia until such time as the President determines—</text> <subparagraph id="H403E6593A31B41AF83104BFF3431CABD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>funds remitted are not United States funds disbursed through Federal, State, or local government support programs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H39E1706C6B6B4BFA9415D1A7DA3E53A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sender of the funds remitted is not receiving financial or other support through a Federal, State, or local program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A6176B796B24CE3A008343BCFA18BC0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the funds remitted to persons in Somalia are not being transferred to officials within the national Government of Somalia; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCCBA624D72DE4878A562317DA096D467"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the funds remitted to individuals or beneficiaries in Somalia are not being directed to or benefitting foreign terrorist organizations; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B1217DD4EAB4EF1A4BE8867FD17D2F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President should direct the heads of appropriate Federal agencies to review all instances of reported or suspected acts of fraud, waste, or abuse in United States foreign assistance programs in Somalia in which such acts are suspected to have been carried out by officials of the national Government of Somalia or at their direction or for their benefit.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H215FB483CE474DEC8967091BE54AEBBC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Briefing</header> 
<subsection id="H9AAAA19FA4BE4A3A8BC5F32DEEAD16BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on—</text> <paragraph id="HCA9D6E39DDF3476C8DBCB4FAB846DC4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evidence of United States funds being transferred to persons or entities within the Federal Republic of Somalia, including an identification of individuals who facilitate or support the transfer of such funds;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDE856AD9FAE4BC6AB7123996A236A2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evidence of the remittance system between the United States being used to benefit officials of the national Government of Somalia; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14D454D8AAD145FB9AF99A03BBF5935B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evidence of remittances being received or otherwise benefitting foreign terrorist organizations or organizations benefitting from foreign terrorist organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H21D8EC2AA3B845858FFFB1AD0311E908"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The briefing required by this section shall—</text> <paragraph id="H851E4D5AB5B8431FBFF9E467CE9E2E97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be provided in unclassified form; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A17C926879245F990CC6D59E7B224FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include a classified annex as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H7CA2B21A4F424684A83F07CEE0F6E13F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Suspension of bilateral and multilateral foreign assistance to the Government of Somalia</header> <subsection id="H8F332EAB49E04ED1942A85951065998C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bilateral assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no bilateral foreign assistance, including assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 and the Arms Export Control Act, should be provided to the national Government of Somalia only if adequate safeguards are in place to mitigate the risk of diversion of such assistance.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7EDE96F5187443CB17F89D6FBF54191"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Multilateral assistance</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no contributions or funding to international organizations or non-governmental organizations may be used by such organizations for the direct benefit or use of the national Government of Somalia.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA4EED26B80174C7BAA39827EA7303802"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary of State may waive the suspension of bilateral foreign assistance to the national Government of Somalia under subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis if the Secretary certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the provision of such assistance is in the national interests of the United States.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA933E277B77A43538CE4741D39482E60" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Visa restrictions</header> 
<subsection id="H97E03561E1224D6CAAAC5FD7C8C5308D" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall apply the restrictions under section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref> note) to any current or former official of the national Government of Somalia whom the Secretary has information was involved in—</text> <paragraph id="H9B6D74963D1747E890E627D6F588DDB7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>significant corruption related to the diversion of United States foreign assistance;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2EAE25A176284026B02FAA8E08728448" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the destruction or seizure of United States-funded humanitarian facilities; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44D25F107FD149ADB3B54F3B56ED1387" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitating the provision of United States foreign assistance to foreign terrorist organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFCF5E5636BB14C80909371ACFE36AD60" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of Diplomatic and G visas</header><text>The Secretary of State may not exempt individuals from the application of the restrictions under subsection (a) if such individuals are holders of, or applicants for, A-category (Diplomatic) or G-category (International Organization) visas if such individuals are determined to be involved in the activities described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H79C55A937450445EA9D64995088404B2" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Family members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The restrictions described in subsection (a) shall also be applied to the immediate family members of individuals who are determined to be involved in the activities described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6C166EF3F89643469C478F3CF784F027" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Other sanctions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President may impose the sanctions under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/10101">22 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to any foreign person that the President determines—</text> <paragraph id="HFD5890AB9DB24A10921C0D9E9C939414" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is collaborating with the national Government of Somalia to engage in corruption or other activities relating to the diversion of United States funds intended for the people of Somalia; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC84B3C5322424FB89AC7B42688FCED58" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services in support of, corruption or other activities described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HFC6125564B764F768B31C4F05FEB0F64"><enum>7.</enum><header>Department of State rewards program</header> <subsection id="HA8AFFDC0D7D94D898C692CDD0C25D445"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall exercise authority under section 36 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2708">22 U.S.C. 2708</external-xref>) to offer rewards for information leading to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCD3BEAA9A4B4409CB12AD1796C40D96F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the identification and location of nationals of the Federal Republic of Somalia or officials of the national Government of Somalia involved in defrauding United States Government programs; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9E4ABF10B6F47B4A8698F5F4F902414" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the recovery of assets stolen or defrauded from the United States Treasury by Somali-based networks.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6053C6A2EFE343C184CE732320B0E2A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Rewards under this section—</text> <paragraph id="H78D20BAB7FB84639A2640DE863897981"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may be paid from the Emergencies in the Diplomatic and Consular Service account; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD607DD41E8246BC8D681CA47CBFBBA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not to exceed $250,000 per reward.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H71F9540443F44DCB8A018A57D79D820E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCDB7F48538C3453482658026BC9E028B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H352384DE1EA340DCBB4578C45886AD64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6BC3FA55FC03462B8CAF3F4150B148EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Finance of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8692BD7C4D04E6789F0266966B3C28E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>foreign terrorist organization</term> means an organization designated by the Secretary of State pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

