<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE801C7754C1945C6841194E8C0E087A3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8875 IH: Improving Home Dialysis Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8875</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to include certain additional services as self-care home dialysis support services under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H459699811A44461CA78A739B08DA5331" style="OLC"><section id="H7ED0ECC4CC7945F4A71B9A38D124FEC4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Home Dialysis Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1343156BC61D40E2A160B1AF6CAEF5E0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Including certain additional services as self-care home dialysis support services under the Medicare program</header><subsection id="H95C7C2CB46C74F0C986A78B29F7AA7EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1881(b)(9) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395rr">42 U.S.C. 1395rr(b)(9)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0E88CE9CCC774B9792E13789805C99B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H273EAC9C7AE84FB09AEB78160C7301DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (F); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9900B19C192D446B9664E020CD3D7C84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE93FA72972484984B41BE18DF8AFFEAE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H79DC6415220D486692E9EC775898C1D4" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning January 1, 2028, staff-assisted home dialysis respite care furnished to a patient in the place of residence used as such patient’s home (other than a skilled nursing facility or a nursing facility (as defined in section 1919(a)));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39562562CBD9484081108AC75D4A3A93" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning January 1, 2028, renal mental health services furnished to a patient in the place of residence used as such patient’s home (other than a skilled nursing facility or a nursing facility (as defined in section 1919(a))); and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H57C4F97B4AFC4A49BE6A08EF694CDCDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following flush matter:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3D46ADF287EE44BC9A69A7B6D4E08C59" display-inline="no-display-inline"><quoted-block-continuation-text indent="up1" quoted-block-continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of subparagraph (D), the term <quote>staff-assisted home dialysis respite care</quote> means dialysis services furnished by qualified personnel to a patient dialyzing at home who is temporarily unable to competently dialyze at home independently during the 30-day period beginning on the first day that the patient initiates home dialysis (or, in the case of a patient whose temporary inability to competently dialyze is attributable to a physical limitation, at any time). For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <quote>qualified personnel</quote> means a registered nurse, a licensed practical nurse, a certified patient care technician, or another qualified medical professional specified by the Secretary, who meets requirements (as determined by the Secretary) that ensure competency in patient care and modality usage, including completing training specific to staff-assisted home dialysis respite care as specified by the Secretary. For purposes of subparagraph (E), the term <quote>renal mental health services</quote> means services described in section 494.90(a)(6) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), furnished to a patient dialyzing at home during the 60-day period beginning on the first day that the patient initiates home dialysis by an individual who meets the standard specified in section 494.140(d) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5234A60A98341F1AB86E8B975C63E9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment adjustments for certain self-care home dialysis support services</header><paragraph id="H5126B369A8134D47911FD84751FB0695"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1881(b)(14) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395rr">42 U.S.C. 1395rr(b)(14)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H65B5B86942BA4EFB8AA66832C261CE05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)—</text><clause id="H23DC526265744C108221E6FD4931657D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="H2D8CAA4AFA704BFB9FAED053B86CC9A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iv) as clause (vi); and</text></clause><clause id="HF7F9043996A14A20A16C4B1C29FEA117"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iii) the following new clauses:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEB458269408A450A9F5DC81847C24819" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HF3396E3597984FC3AD853A05AFA19D0D" indent="up2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include a payment adjustment for staff-assisted home dialysis respite care (as described in paragraph (9)(D)) in accordance with subparagraph (J);</text></clause><clause id="H48F46C4C16D149BCB36DE8F1E1D7CBA9" indent="up2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>shall include a payment adjustment for renal mental health services (as described in paragraph (9)(E)) in accordance with subparagraph (K); and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6833BA486514439B03B81AA539A1FE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3310438CD2584425AE853183C39D1124" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H64FAA7F7AF184F87BAD922AC6231AF22" indent="up2"><enum>(J)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5D46345B682E4857A65F3C338BC4D075"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (D)(iv), subject to clause (ii), a payment adjustment shall be made for each session of staff-assisted home dialysis respite care (as described in paragraph (9)(D)) furnished during a year equal to the amount of the add-on per treatment adjustment for home and self-dialysis training furnished in 2025 (or, in the case of such care that is not furnished in a rural area (as defined for purposes of such subparagraph), 75 percent of such amount).</text></clause><clause id="HC30BBD7192AF44FDB2DAE902AE05CD5D" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In no case may a payment adjustment under subparagraph (D)(iv) be made for staff-assisted home dialysis respite care furnished to an individual—</text><subclause id="HEEA295086CFF44E892020B1A3450588A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for more than 20 sessions in a calendar year; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB89110DADFBA41389EB54E46C9DD3102"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on a day when such individual was not dialyzing at home.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFFB6C332930E490287C4013237C98486" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any payment adjustment under subparagraph (D)(iv) for staff-assisted home dialysis respite care shall not be made in a budget neutral manner.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6E03026976D43BBA9166127C7E83878" indent="up2"><enum>(K)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H441D8C8A6D5841069FFF1FC6D6497308"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (D)(v), subject to clause (ii), a payment adjustment shall be made for each session of renal mental health services (as described in paragraph (9)(E)) furnished during a year equal to 50 percent (or 25 percent, in the case of such services that are not furnished in a rural area (as defined for purposes of subparagraph (D))) of the amount of the add-on per treatment adjustment for home and self-dialysis training furnished in 2025.</text></clause><clause id="H0A8B6DACA24640869B7040355AE88EC6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>In no case may a payment adjustment under subparagraph (D)(v) be made for renal mental health services furnished to an individual—</text><subclause id="HD8992B58AE0E49A3AB6D1F0E7C13CC6D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for more than 4 sessions occurring during the 60-day period beginning on the first day that the individual initiates home dialysis; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H783B61DAE6724F118146948450DE22D2"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on a day when such individual was not dialyzing at home.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H655BC059FAE444CF826157E258A91722" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any payment adjustment under subparagraph (D)(v) for renal mental health services shall not be made in a budget neutral manner.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4508424FE9BD4E538D0251A91E490D6F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1834(r)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(r)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>subparagraph (D)(iv)(II)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (D)(vi)(II)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

