<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LAN26165-LJY-8C-8WD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4199 IS: Youth AI Privacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4199</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require entities that make artificial intelligence chatbots available to minors to implement certain safe design features, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Youth AI Privacy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1dc6501ce319452ea7dd6297db931982"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7364bfdf2c942ffb0135faacf4880fc"><enum/><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id48788750a8854a7293139afd1926541c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Millions of teenagers are using artificial intelligence (referred to in this section as <quote>AI</quote>) chatbots for personal, sensitive conversations, disclosing intimate details about their lives, relying on AI chatbots for advice, and developing deep emotional bonds with AI chatbots.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1b146f618f04092a0695951d80c9b6b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2025, approximately <fraction>2/3</fraction> of teenagers reported using AI chatbots, and roughly <fraction>1/4</fraction> reported using them daily. <fraction>1/3</fraction> of teens have chosen to speak with AI chatbot <quote>companions</quote> over a real human for a serious conversation. In a couple tragic cases, a teenager died by suicide after encouragement or advice from an AI chatbot.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida65b3d9f55f243319d294c1539316d8c"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Although compulsive use of AI chatbots may pose risks for all users, users who are minors, whose cognitive, emotional, and social capabilities are still developing, are especially likely to misunderstand that an AI chatbot is not a real human and disclose sensitive personal information to the AI chatbot or turn to the AI chatbot for social companionship. Minors are also more susceptible to addictive design features, anthropomorphized systems, and potentially harmful outputs generated by AI systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3121b5115c445d29ba441a548c32704"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">AI chatbot companies are employing manipulative engagement features to keep users engaged on their platforms, including high-frequency push notifications, unprompted AI chatbot responses, typing bubble indicators, and more. These features create serious risks of emotional dependency and compulsive use among minors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0e8baa374224fd3831a23f73d7c1515"><enum>(5)</enum><text>AI chatbots mimic human-like conversations by employing profiling tactics to personalize outputs for users. AI chatbots are also often designed to resemble direct messaging user interfaces. These personalization strategies and anthropomorphic design features can easily confuse users, especially minors, who may believe they are interacting with a real person rather than AI.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ebdee7f2f384b9b8d28001a42ada15b"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Advertisements delivered through AI chatbots may be woven directly into responses or may subtly steer users toward certain products based on how the model was trained. This advertising would be far more covert and harder to recognize than traditional digital advertising, especially for minors. As highlighted by the Commission, many young users lack the skills or cognitive defenses needed to identify such covert or <quote>blurred</quote> advertising.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f305d046ae14049ba5f1d3df304c84d"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Extended, multiturn conversations with AI chatbots degrade safeguards against harmful conversational patterns, increasing the likelihood of minors receiving harmful outputs generated by AI systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d2f5ec094fc40afb319dd8b3e3e1b4b"><enum>(8)</enum><text>AI chatbots introduce new privacy risks, as they often retain user inputs and personal data to personalize responses and to train the underlying large language models. This practice creates the potential for serious privacy violations, particularly when companies retain and process highly sensitive information from minors.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7efbd53bc06840b1bfa39c8e938f6277"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Congress has a responsibility to address the novel risks posed by AI chatbots and protect minors from potential harm related to anthropomorphism, prolonged engagement, deceptive advertising, and invasive privacy practices.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id995012ee13e1412a8359f3cb3f7ea151"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbadf653542e481eae8e4dd142d98079"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">AI chatbot</header><text>The term <term>AI chatbot</term> means a natural language interface that uses a covered algorithm to provide adaptive responses to user inputs via text, audio, image, video, or any other mode of communication, simulating interpersonal interaction with a user.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94bc8e1f6e934b7b96fd20d9563b44c7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collect</header><text>The term <term>collect</term> means, with respect to personal data, to buy, rent, gather, obtain, receive, access, or otherwise acquire the personal data by any means.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id455d372f7cde4693bbb22142176caa98"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id865cd5d6b0994cfaad6fc3bd47cf4ced"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered algorithm</header><text>The term <term>covered algorithm</term> means a computational process derived from machine learning, natural language processing, neural networks, or other technology of similar or greater complexity.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3184f4dd6e0e434e814a440191595683"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Deployer</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3c4d14ef5f5f4ccfbeaa53cda917619c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>deployer</term> means any person that owns, operates, or otherwise makes available to users an AI chatbot in or affecting interstate commerce.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16f5d42d48fc4058bf36649f92660697"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The terms <term>deployer</term> and <term>developer</term> shall not be interpreted to be mutually exclusive.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3cf9c88b9e5641c1b9234cf154e62d1a"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Derived data</header><text>The term <term>derived data</term> means data that is created by the derivation of information, other data, assumptions, correlations, inferences, predictions, or conclusions from facts, evidence, or another source of information.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f0a01dddf3346578ffa15eace9e02db"><enum>(7)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developer</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda9d8657692d427383489f8a5a5a3010"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>developer</term> means any person that designs, codes, produces, or substantially modifies a covered algorithm for use in an AI chatbot.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida604397c882248a28f0b5516a283de71"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The terms <term>developer</term> and <term>deployer</term> shall not be interpreted to be mutually exclusive.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0fa28a64f6814593895401c1c751b2c4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Input data</header><text>The term <term>input data</term> means, with respect to an AI chatbot, all information, including text, photos, audio, video, or files, provided to the AI chatbot by a user of such AI chatbot.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id163b9940ca4243c688d1b80c0175c81d"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Knowledge</header><text>The term <term>knowledge</term> means actual knowledge or knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6241b4a86654431eb435a172fd2896e9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Minor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minor</term> means an individual who is under the age of 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2cb582799b064159aa0fe603aeeb96f9"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Output</header><text>The term <term>output</term> means, with respect to an AI chatbot, any information, including any text, photo, audio recording, video, or file, provided by such AI chatbot to a user.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida156b9c3f3164d64a4143ef80f128e91"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Personal data</header><text>The term <term>personal data</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66b5912057d7494a89b93b7dc4365514"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means information, including input data, derived data, inferences, or unique identifiers, that identifies or is linked, or reasonably linkable, alone or in combination with other information, to an individual or a device that identifies or is linked, or reasonably linkable, to 1 or more individuals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f2fb3de58fb4cbaa1afbce7405260c1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include publicly available information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id80c81d69525e4f3c9fe8748ffac7bf0b"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Profiling</header><text>The term <term>profiling</term> means processing data for the purpose of detecting and classifying or designating personality and behavioral characteristics of a user of an AI chatbot.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2215f8ae727e4fe095d7afadc0a516ce"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Process</header><text>The term <term>process</term> means, with respect to personal data, any operation or set of operations performed on the personal data, including analyzing, organizing, structuring, using, modifying, or otherwise handling such data.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide06af56d660a4f24aab84019922e3346"><enum>(15)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Publicly available information</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc2181d8815f34821b5df4b1f7d304987"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>publicly available information</term>—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5204d1a30f4403abaa4515e201b70aa"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any information that a deployer has a reasonable basis to believe has been made available to the general public by—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08b0f79b3ec14d928b548142626f162c"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal, State, or local government records;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide625c83d331c4262ab1dc6962ff12293"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">widely distributed media;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd928fa53de464a7fbc3fe6747ae8cc3a"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a website or online service made available to any member of the public, for free or for a fee, including a website or online service that any member of the public can log into; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide49cfb3c447e4b28afb68cafe1514215"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a disclosure to the general public that is required under Federal, State, or local law; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbcebd877de944646b72be596df4886d5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98e3d1709afc489382f7fffeb7e5d385"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any obscene visual depiction (as such term is used in section 1460 of title 18, United States Code);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02ebdd5b393241d8813da7ce36eb92be"><enum>(II)</enum><text>biometric information;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17dfcec927de4ae8b25d23cf066c0468"><enum>(III)</enum><text>genetic information, unless made publicly available by the individual to whom the information pertains by a means described in subclause (II) or (III) of clause (i);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b59ca9a1af1480c8f4318451eb6d43b"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>personal data that is created through the combination of personal data with publicly available information;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3843de282f1e4a6584726ab587b9f7f9"><enum>(V)</enum><text>intimate images that are authentic or computer-generated, known to be nonconsensual; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a5ffd3e85864df6b5422e1ee4c1fd86"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>personal data made available by a data broker.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35885e13d8ff438d876db153530a7e0e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, information from a website or online service is not available to any member of the public if the individual to whom the information pertains has restricted the information to a specific audience or maintained a default setting that restricts the information to a specific audience.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0bc2309022e94bceb12d6300e705962b"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text>The term <term>transfer</term> means, with respect to personal data, to disclose, release, share disseminate, make available, sell, rent, or license the personal data (orally, in writing, electronically, or by any other means).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca68ba0fb6234050bb4562c3c1dc98d2"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Widely distributed media</header><text>The term <term>widely distributed media</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide68c70e012c14c7ab1782b4dac768668"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means information that is available to the general public, including information from a telephone book or online directory, a television, internet, or radio program, the news media, or an internet site, that is available to the general public on an unrestricted basis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id799c2edfc7a04dc8aec89aa31958018a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an obscene visual depiction (as such term is used in section 1460 of title 18, United States Code).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idf38230a0d6ea40de8a03d50e55d3e908"><enum>4.</enum><header>Safe design features</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f1614f016434392a541bd871124ca88"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required disclosures</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1bbb8cdae24418391189164b315f813"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A deployer with knowledge that a user of an AI chatbot is a minor shall disclose that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id049ccee6295f41069e1ee6d72296ebe2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the user is not interacting with a human; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc222aec706dd47c5b3a10b10bf814237"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any content provided by the AI chatbot is generated by artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11a97c1446b449cbb2b82d35e60f351e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content and duration of disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A disclosure made by a deployer pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa408f3f902b49d8b66d5d2ccfdd1265"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be stated in clear, plain, and easy-to-understand language suited to the age of minors likely to access the AI chatbot;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36f943e20794427193303eca5702b5ef"><enum>(B)</enum><text>occur at the beginning of every session (as defined by the Commission);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86c0f5e4db654e7da7e1155709606c6d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reoccur not less than once every 30 minutes during a session (as so defined); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf71d8209dd04e91b3a3cb01382f4e85"><enum>(D)</enum><text>be appropriate for the medium of the content, as determined by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2bafad81eec4b34b243eefdb72cf1b7"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Limitation on the processing of personal data To provide outputs</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idded2e0777ca54b50b465970474a0cb05"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate regulations to prohibit a deployer with knowledge that a user of an AI chatbot is a minor from processing any personal data of the user to generate, personalize, or otherwise affect an output provided to such user, unless the personal data was collected during the current session (as defined by the Commission) more recently than the maximum permitted period of use established by the Commission under paragraph (2).</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="iddcb71d7597f542aeab08a59f9f83e1d1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Maximum permitted period of use</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In promulgating the regulations described in paragraph (1), the Commission shall determine a maximum permitted period of use during which a deployer with knowledge that a user of an AI chatbot is a minor may collect personal data from such a user and process such data to generate, personalize, or otherwise affect an output (as defined by the Commission) provided to such user during a current session (as defined by the Commission).</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05faef99b1774f4993db9ef54958cf2d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion of features that encourage compulsive use</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate regulations to prohibit a deployer or developer with knowledge that a user of an AI chatbot is a minor from configuring such AI chatbot to include, with respect to such user, the following features:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcf549dc81794438b0bf5425e1b58ecd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any reward or incentive based on the frequency of use, time spent, or activity using the AI chatbot.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd16039416fd74b6bb128f156988b96da"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notifications and push alerts, other than a disclosure required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9b4733cd1c54ee9ac21ab1aa2da3094"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any badge or other visual award symbol based on the frequency of use, time spent, or activity using the AI chatbot.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd107d5e4c6f346e492d58ba330019924"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Generation of an output absent a user-initiated input or any form of solicitation of engagement from a user.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d4098e4917746e985c08e0afff3cd3a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Usage traces that mimic social interactions with a human, such as typing bubbles or indicators showing that the AI chatbot is available or online.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1749e15a3db04d2b88bf43371138cc16"><enum>5.</enum><header>Data privacy protections</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1790005145084595a22c5405c09c2513"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on advertising and promotion</header><text>A deployer or developer with knowledge that a user of an AI chatbot is a minor shall not configure or modify an AI chatbot to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46104c4299ea4103b3d6760d2277484a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advertise to such user; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2cc0769c1144fb69a1942249fff84f2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>generate an output that promotes, markets, recommends, or endorses a product or service to such user if the weight or credibility of such promotion, marketing, recommendation, or endorsement is materially affected by a financial connection between the deployer or developer and the seller of such product or service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d5c34cc2c6c4f67b7f4a257bb61941e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on processing of personal data for profiling</header><text>A deployer with knowledge that a user of an AI chatbot is a minor shall not process any personal data of the user to engage in any profiling of such user.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9953cc3ceb5343098dc291b2b0d01691"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on the processing or transferring of personal data To train a covered algorithm</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida13538cda9dd46b6809dc97fd54e7ddb"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), a deployer with knowledge that a user of an AI chatbot is a minor shall not—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="idac8145ef9936485da60ce0c034ba2414">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">process the personal data of such minor for the purpose of training a covered algorithm; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id944b8cc7a78b4e41a855fba8441f67c4">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>transfer the personal data of such minor to a third party for the purpose of training a covered algorithm.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="idc4afec64d53c404f86fddc980f768aa8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Exceptions</header>
 <text>A deployer with knowledge that a user of an AI chatbot is a minor may process personal data of such minor for the express purpose of—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id5a4413fa719e42b59c92fdd18869133c">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">testing and identifying risks of harm to users; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id8256142755774f6c8fbc894bec10a1f8">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>addressing identified risks of harm to users.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection><subsection id="id7f8dc7e4454e467fbfb856c4c3bcc535"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on processing of input data</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 30 days after the Commission promulgates regulations under section 4(b)(1), a deployer with knowledge that a user of an AI chatbot is a minor shall not process any input data provided to such AI chatbot by such user for any purpose, other than for the express purpose of—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15ed78b7308f4840ae34d8e6a5ae2bde"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">generating, personalizing, or affecting an output provided to such user when the input data was collected during the current session (as defined by the Commission) more recently than the maximum permitted period of use established by the Commission under section 4(b)(2);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53923d09424b49dfb9ae5b33dfa46b46"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">testing and identifying risks of harm to users; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ea22863f419440a9b259b1e5a910333"><enum>(3)</enum><text>addressing identified risks of harm to users.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7289dc3c42de407d98cbbc70a1107a3a"><enum>6.</enum><header>Whistleblower protections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A deployer or developer may not, directly or indirectly, discharge, demote, suspend, threaten, harass, or otherwise discriminate or retaliate against an individual for raising a concern regarding a violation of this Act, reporting or attempting to report a violation of this Act, or cooperating in any investigation or enforcement proceeding pursuant to this Act.</text></section><section id="ide75237d0a8d14bb3a735483a5410e65d"><enum>7.</enum><header>Research on the health and developmental effects of AI chatbots on minors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1432 of the Restoring Hope for Mental Health and Well-Being Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285g-11">42 U.S.C. 285g–11</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida243d8c93f0a494bb33d54066792dc17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting, <quote>AI chatbots,</quote> after <quote>augmented reality,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd091a1f2796942cbb06a0aad0721ff91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74b3669fccbb4e07ac00bf4a41cb56be"><subsection id="id8adba9d1d28a4d6eb16fceee57fee3b9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="idb3154fd472164b9299f5aa5ef1d245e7"><enum>8.</enum><header>Survey inclusion requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and in coordination with the Director of the National Institutes of Health, shall incorporate questions related to the use, by youth and by adults, of AI chatbots into national health and behavioral surveys conducted by the Department of Health and Human Services, including the Household Pulse Survey and the Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance System of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, including questions designed to capture the following:</text><paragraph id="id00fcbda3fa504750a91f9f2818ce6a28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Frequency and duration of AI chatbot uses.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8522453f2924c1eb5959cd77851b507"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Types of AI chatbots accessed, such as AI chatbots designed for mental health, educational, or entertainment purposes or general purpose AI chatbots that are engaged for such purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id361d26a261974641892e545aef6f1c49"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Age of first use of, and primary contexts of engagement with, AI chatbots.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4359e6836be443e8a93fa821bc83772d"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Emotional, psychological, or behavioral impacts perceived by users of AI chatbots.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id858656fe18274814a97004144d691293"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exposure to content that the user perceives to be harmful or inappropriate.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idfb788007590f4827841c8c697e45289c"><enum>9.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacb4c778839d4e528c6dd19f5e083e52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Commission</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6edde738f094e098b85d2b2c7efa464"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of section 4, 5, or 6, or a regulation promulgated thereunder, shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idced7eca8b3b442a6a0b7b08044aa6de5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a3337d2f5e945c6b77eefe4166ed408"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce sections 4, 5, and 6 and any regulation promulgated thereunder in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide031a11cbf09441eb80d5f3ceaa8b967"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any deployer or developer that violates section 4, 5, or 6, or a regulation promulgated thereunder, shall be subject to the penalties, and entitled to the privileges and immunities, provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf961f4277ebe47098313abf9117a5bf2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide43cea2e856e4709818313c3fbf0603b"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>In addition to the specific rulemaking requirements described in section 4, the Commission shall promulgate in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such rules as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idde8ab974906b4120bcb53225d7b672a8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc72cb3911805479db486ab7fb020a342"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by the engagement of any deployer or developer in an act or practice that violates section 4, 5, or 6, or a regulation promulgated thereunder, the attorney general of the State may, as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in a district court of the United States of appropriate jurisdiction to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26675621327440708679d56d2ed454ee"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enjoin such act or practice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f8765343f4249a69d4b41d81e677d39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with section 4, 5 or 6, or a regulation promulgated thereunder;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee9d5267fd3141979276f1131131b0b1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide80e0c1a19d44ee0990710f38dd02410"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain such other relief as the court may consider to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfef93ac0204a458f8d0044c1c8b1a760"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights of the Commission</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35841a4ae43c4fab9c6e1acaa6d3afa2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice to the Commission</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idade08148947841618b2c6426f78f1165"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (iii), before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the attorney general of a State shall notify the Commission in writing that the attorney general intends to bring such civil action.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a79a0482bd24d6c98e5cc4f1226bacd"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notification required to be filed by clause (i) shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate the civil action.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75b8c6cdc8694fc6a981aaf8392a66a3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If it is not feasible for the attorney general of a State to provide the notification required by clause (i) before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the attorney general shall notify the Commission immediately upon instituting the civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96c40b3b861f441dad972918911ef46b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Intervention by the Commission</header><text>Upon receiving the notice required by subparagraph (A), the Commission may intervene in the civil action and, upon intervening—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e8817d0230a4226903d3a7428287ef1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be heard on all matters arising in the civil action; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id646046cd27c649c49d7a5bea99bec25f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in the civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c49f0ac08554e3fa927ded8b6cf424f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Preemptive action by the Commission</header><text>If the Commission has instituted a civil action for a violation of subsection (a), no State officer may bring an action under paragraph (1) during the pendency of that action against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission for any violation of subsection (a) alleged in the complaint.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56cce883950744ebb00301410e33884e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investigatory powers</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent the attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, to administer oaths or affirmations, or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3c7383d711704bbb9aa80c0838ae1c15"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Venue; service of process</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6dab8af1ae0641fb98c9bcc070e5e443"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Venue</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any action brought under paragraph (1) may be brought in the district court of the United States that meets applicable requirements relating to venue under section 1391 of title 28, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75046a94acb9457a89bf438558196cdd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an action brought under paragraph (1), process may be served in any district in which the defendant—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f782289a3f1469f8e1806cdce9ee4df"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an inhabitant; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf9b44a11dc146d1a5943026065f866a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be found.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3ccfb4d71874be5b380df4bce232199"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b8a223f016845fabca3a73eea33c2a3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any parent or legal guardian of a minor may bring a civil action in any court of competent jurisdiction against a deployer or developer for a violation of section 4 or 5, or a regulation promulgated thereunder, by the deployer or developer.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce29c6d82d6e4e249899f65fc4a99f83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In a civil action brought under paragraph (1) in which the plaintiff prevails, the court may award—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida07f52c9c7684658a41389d2582ce452"><enum>(A)</enum><text>actual damages;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13ec4afbe63d4e9880ab1144b414c6e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">punitive damages;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b0768877f8f46c79e1c114e1088d927"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reasonable attorney's fees and litigation costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ef3be10361c4e2c90e025c97131853b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>injunctive relief or declaratory relief; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83f85ad8b3bc44b78870b8f50565c407"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other relief that the court determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04671864711d47a1ac60bd247d6e81a1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relationship to State law</header><text>The provisions of this Act shall preempt any State law, rule, or regulation only to the extent that such State law, rule, or regulation conflicts with a provision of this Act. Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit any State from enacting a law, rule, or regulation that provides greater protection to minors than the provisions of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0b8aa9a62d9b4277b448dc654493558b"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of this Act, and the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances, shall not be affected by the invalidation.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf710d5e64154838afd3e16149156460"><enum>10.</enum><header>Determination of whether an AI chatbot deployer has knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances that an individual is a minor</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e8ad6ab95c84c4087b2e261cf96ed1e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>For purposes of enforcing this Act or a regulation promulgated thereunder, in making a determination as to whether a deployer has knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances that a specific user is a child or teen, the Commission or the attorney general of a State, as applicable, shall rely on competent and reliable evidence, taking into account the totality of the circumstances, including whether a reasonable and prudent person under the circumstances would have known that the user is a child or teen. Nothing in this Act, including a determination described in the preceding sentence, shall be construed to require a deployer to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id708e21df9a014df69484160623ee8190"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affirmatively collect any personal information with respect to the age of a child or teen that an operator is not already collecting in the normal course of business; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc13a9a2c9274da18fb2300bad217755"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement an age gating or age verification functionality.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e428f4134904cd78b2dcf4e11788179"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commission guidance</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb59b9cc3da8a49c6be593241cc426b69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall issue guidance to provide information for deployers to understand the Commission’s determination of whether a deployer has knowledge fairly implied on the basis of objective circumstances that a user is a child or teen, including best practices and examples.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2946f393e154e0d8f6b548b47da2578"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>No guidance issued by the Commission with respect to this Act shall confer any rights on any person, State, or locality, nor shall operate to bind the Commission or any person to the approach recommended in such guidance. In any enforcement action brought pursuant to this Act, the Commission or the attorney general of a State, as applicable, shall allege a specific violation of a provision of this Act. The Commission or the attorney general of a State, as applicable, may not base an enforcement action on, or execute a consent order based on, practices that are alleged to be inconsistent with any such guidance, unless the practices allegedly violate this Act. For purposes of enforcing this Act or a regulation promulgated thereunder, the attorney general of a State shall take into account any guidance issued by the Commission under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

