<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H58B53B58B71C4F919A1325899C05C976" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8199 IH: Scheduling for Community Health and Easy Data to Understand for Legislators to Evaluate Services Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8199</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260406">April 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000622">Mr. Patronis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a comprehensive standard for timing between referrals and appointments for care from the Department of Veterans Affairs and to submit a report with respect to that standard, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC57D72C9304045BFA0D54B3F13B35AD2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H44E1FE5A4339413F9318EFB12E5A2401" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Scheduling for Community Health and Easy Data to Understand for Legislators to Evaluate Services Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SCHEDULES Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81B93A6A2A8A488DA1160FB3657E04B5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of comprehensive standard for timing between referral and appointment for care from Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0B3F2AB1E874F63A245E3810E3C3C52"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment of standard</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C3B55AA51F74720A2F53634AA712DB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a comprehensive standard for timing between the date on which a referral for care for a veteran under the laws administered by the Secretary is entered into the care coordination system of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the date on which an appointment for care for the veteran occurs, whether at a facility of the Department or through care in the community.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92C650A96B1A4506B705E94EC0DAD99E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modification</header><text>The Secretary may modify the standard established under paragraph (1) as the appointment scheduling processes of the Department for care at a facility of the Department or through care in the community are updated.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4BAC8E207ED64F94ACC7F40FF2E96C66"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 30 days before establishing under paragraph (1) or modifying under paragraph (2) the comprehensive standard required under this subsection, the Secretary shall publish such standard in the Federal Register and on a publicly available internet website of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0E4CA547D12A482095086DD3E9C8ABAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2047BEF91CEE4C6986F6C0EAF9B71CFD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than quarterly, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the number and percentage of referrals from the Department to facilities of the Department or providers in the community that meet the standard under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C21F48522CE4AB0A8CA773CC728B857"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC8965B4B6D44CB9891361142389FAF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and percentage of total referrals from each facility of the Department that meet, for the quarter covered by the report—</text> <clause id="H889AE4807624460697F9F096029D064D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the standard under subsection (a);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7184CDF18BE54957BDDACCD272A075DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to referrals to a facility of the Department, the three-business-day standard for scheduling an appointment at a facility of the Department; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF494A367081445BA961FE4E5083224A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to referrals for care in the community, the seven-calendar-day standard for scheduling an appointment for care in the community.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H682C76D93E9F4133890D0313D831038A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number and percentage of referrals from each facility of the Department that meet each of the standards specified in subparagraph (A), disaggregated by each of the five, or more, most in-demand categories of care provided at such facility (such as mental health, cardiology, neurology, oncology, etc.).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBE055319459416B95AD940A601A6E8D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A list of all medical centers of the Department ranked from best to worst in meeting the standard under subsection (a), including a disaggregated list by State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6AB4FB0CC424C09AF92CF9786F8FB3E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annually included information</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, the Secretary shall include in the report required under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89FCF45C96B14C27A013A1EF4024E2A0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aggregated data for the four-quarter period preceding the date of the report; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H679AE9A2223B46A8ACC6465A1CE27ADC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of steps taken by the Department to improve the timeliness of the provision of care by the Department and an estimate of when the Department will be fully compliant with the standard under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A0B701A0F9F4234B7B884B83FAAC661"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make each report required under paragraph (1) publicly available on a website of the Veterans Health Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

