<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN26125-PJH-10-Y8K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4048 IS: Public health Response and Emergency Detection through Integrated wastewater Community Testing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4048</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260311">March 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service to require the Secretary to award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to establish, maintain, or improve activities related to the detection and monitoring of infectious diseases through wastewater for public health emergency preparedness and response purposes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id07df2ae108c040f1a1f1b9f55a6856c3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public health Response and Emergency Detection through Integrated wastewater Community Testing Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PREDICT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id64e0916ea6a54cc29c471e69ad4b3ba2"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public health response and emergency detection through integrated wastewater surveillance</header><subsection id="id134f6735691f4fc8b943c3cdaa04dfdb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle C of title XXVIII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300hh-31">42 U.S.C. 300hh–31 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id169c262d0a454c5d9149446c34ffe836"><section id="idd647ef50254648df83bfdfbc20be2d40"><enum>2827.</enum><header>Wastewater surveillance for pathogen detection</header><subsection id="idb1798f3a5c17418cb12c87ece924cd1e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Wastewater surveillance system</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (in this section referred to as the <term>Secretary</term>), and in coordination with other Federal departments and agencies, shall award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to establish, maintain, or improve activities related to the detection and monitoring of infectious diseases through wastewater for public health emergency preparedness and response purposes.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7e71f2acfb9d4099a0140b5e1510db78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive an award under this section, an entity shall—</text><paragraph id="idcd32936ca9ea4676807c49f093e4ca2c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be a State, Tribal, or local health department, or a partnership between such a health department and other public and private entities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e9e110eef9443e5b428e383fd4a5dc0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="id574a9467b4244d1abf5ae66de70578ff"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of activities proposed to be carried out pursuant to an award under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcae89866cd754008b25dbc51def82e2d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>factors such entity proposes to use to select wastewater sampling sites;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84fa6db8f60f48279a69774f53bd97c1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a plan for responding, as appropriate, to findings from such wastewater sampling, consistent with applicable plans developed by such entity pursuant to section 319C–1;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2f6834186484b9084d483d217553a24"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a plan to sustain such wastewater surveillance activities described in such application following the conclusion of the award period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a98a9add5104534b72ad42e2acf5c05"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any additional information the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idab2ca9bcf7044e9f92cbe47a8d85096e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In making awards under subsection (a), the Secretary may give priority to eligible entities that have submitted an application that—</text><paragraph id="idd4c315762f384eda9e876e368caf0a33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>details plans to provide public access to data generated through such wastewater surveillance activities in a manner that enables comparison to such data generated by other recipients of an award under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c3608d257fc42fb92eba893a6515743"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides an assessment of community needs related to ongoing infectious disease monitoring, including burden of infectious diseases that can be detected in wastewater and availability of other forms of infectious disease surveillance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide4c8f82eecbb4e09b5b166954d5d72da"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity shall use amounts awarded under this section to—</text><paragraph id="idc7a61ccac1e545cc87cbbb83082e1291"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish, or enhance existing, capacity and capabilities to conduct wastewater sampling and related analysis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4411c9aafd6e42e1ace535c5f4274cf5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct wastewater surveillance, as appropriate, at individual facilities, institutions, and locations in rural areas, in which there is an increased risk of infectious disease outbreaks and wastewater is not treated through the relevant local utility of the jurisdiction; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida14d7516a3ae4d9e86e3c693e3b34311"><enum>(3)</enum><text>implement projects that use evidence-based or promising practices to conduct wastewater surveillance activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6a3d8c177f844e6ca0eee986defe3aea"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>In carrying out activities under this section, eligible entities shall identify opportunities to partner with other public or private entities to leverage relevant capabilities maintained by such entities, as appropriate and consistent with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id19c3caeee56642f399a71ccbf8d67ba4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the heads of other applicable Federal agencies and departments, as appropriate, shall provide technical assistance to recipients of awards under this section to facilitate the planning, development, and implementation of activities described in subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="id023f07f5c6e04517ac30378c0089abe0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Wastewater surveillance guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>PREDICT Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue draft guidance—</text><paragraph id="id3a59a875215b4d24bb38532fb41c3655"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide recommendations for recipients of awards under this section regarding—</text><subparagraph id="idce574c1a504948eebde755cba6291593"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of assays to promote efficient wastewater surveillance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04b20c253ffb40d7beea85f91a935129"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of assays for data on multiple infectious diseases; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8dd3920dd6f44faaa9da1c63f7785065"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to establish standards for—</text><subparagraph id="id83d88e2b36e44b6e994e7571add8277b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>wastewater testing methods and metrics used by such recipients that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f50b85e785340878b362ca4ad6fcffe"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use a consistent protocol and process; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e163f789c8848d1a969dcf1a6e2edfb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sample using scientifically rigorous and sensitive methods; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6caee16f87584c55825199b6d0147b76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>wastewater sample data reporting by such recipients to the Secretary, to be published by the Secretary in a publicly available wastewater surveillance database and dashboard.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide7a01e6df98c4ad09ae1118eacf2b9de"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idc08cb6f2cfb44ce4b9e17bda00ad7f46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Wastewater surveillance research</header><paragraph id="idfcff828c8c15471f8c97a7eaa2f51c2c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall continue to conduct or support research on the use of wastewater surveillance to detect and monitor emerging infectious diseases, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="ida833ed4a2a6c4583894b91f23da52e8a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>research to improve the efficiency of wastewater sample collection and analysis and increase the sensitivity and specificity of wastewater testing methods; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbdbceee147df43ada22681350fdf77aa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implementation and development of evidence-based practices to facilitate the estimation of population-level data within a community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c7157b276284b5a80c545c6b71f19e6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-duplication of effort</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that activities carried out under this subsection do not unnecessarily duplicate efforts of other agencies and offices within the Department of Health and Human Services related to wastewater surveillance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

