<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5FDA4118F7834C8BA255D70A5FD42A6E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 153 IH: To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against the Republic of Cuba that have not been authorized by Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 153</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260324">March 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against the Republic of Cuba that have not been authorized by Congress.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HA941877D983F4913A5A32936D0A5A571"> 
<section id="HFBB00C120FA748318F838B118D06A811" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HBC603D177AA04489B568BA5B1CC9D2F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress has the sole power to declare war under article I, section 8, clause 11 of the United States Constitution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3F47291F0784B769843D9553D0571E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The President has a constitutional responsibility to take actions to defend the United States, its territories, its possessions, citizens, service members, and diplomats from attack.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H347C4A474584410489FFF5822AEC3AD6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress has not declared war upon Cuba or upon any person or organization within Cuba, nor enacted a specific statutory authorization for the use of military force within or against Cuba.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H897DE410ACD842D2BB692C28449B15B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The use of force by the United States Armed Forces within or against Cuba, including the use of the United States Coast Guard and other components of the Armed Forces to conduct a blockade or quarantine of Cuba, constitutes the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities within the meaning of section 4(a) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1543">50 U.S.C. 1543(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H34D4849677854DB3A5DAF85A7022B267"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>) provides that any joint resolution or bill requiring the removal of United States Armed Forces from imminent engagement in hostilities without a declaration of war or specific statutory authorization shall be considered in accordance with the expedited procedures under section 601(b) of the International Security and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/329">Public Law 94–329</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE5EF92EF095545638F1A8A3FB14EAA91"><enum>2.</enum><header>Removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against Cuba</header> 
<subsection id="HAAC1E714B8BB4B49B341EAA448A3FCB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>Pursuant to section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>), and in accordance with section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/329">Public Law 94–329</external-xref>), Congress hereby directs the President to remove the United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against Cuba, unless explicitly authorized by a declaration of war or a specific authorization for use of military force.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H04AC2556F31348A7B1D8FCEA8548DF1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prevent the United States from defending itself from an armed attack, the threat of an imminent armed attack, or the lawful execution of counternarcotics operations.</text></subsection></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

