<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD935FFBE7AEB4534BC68BC9FF977464B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6764 IH: Veterans Affairs Advisory Committee Oversight Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6764</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish new, and terminate certain, advisory committees of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD0E8E13CCA8E4D76874BFF539FC77D3D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1639AAF09CA24954932C41ACA0485A97" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Affairs Advisory Committee Oversight Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2B45AA3120584A079E5394103B3082FD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of new advisory committees of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new sections (and amending the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HB577054F56ED4EFF8D920DADD84E3610" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HBF1553B8F8D8445CB8D381A6FDFB1151" commented="no"><enum>549.</enum><header>Veterans Health Advisory Committee</header> 
<subsection id="H848C3AC40984426584ABC1D023A84BF9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is in the Department an advisory committee to be known as the <quote>Veterans Health Advisory Committee</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H14251B4903ED4C63BEF2D5912903AA79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership; terms; chair</header> <paragraph id="H5516DCF2BF7D45DEA71C4D5947986ECF" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall appoint the members of the Committee, including the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDF8D81D8E4A74D62B44A97E95AEEF0E9" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A veteran who uses prosthetic or rehabilitative health care services of the Department.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H483A040D3AB04F439E4F072AAEF3F3F3" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual with expertise in prosthetics or rehabilitative health care for disabled veterans.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB5E4C51036824DE282D6F300817C019F" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual with expertise in geriatrics or gerontology, including long-term care for veterans.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB2F2357231744468E6753F188D686DD" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual with expertise in environmental health or toxic exposures described in subchapter VII of chapter 11 of this title.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0F28A9159BF54526B0719EE41662CB78" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual with expertise in mental health or readjustment counseling for veterans.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D9C90D563D64146BDC234BF2D3C12F7" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A representative of a veterans service organization, recognized under section 5902 of this title, that represents disabled or aging veterans.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H70355065F75B49CBBE77B296E6D41FFE" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Other individuals the Secretary determines appropriate to ensure various perspectives on veterans’ needs for health care, across regions and populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF92E0B5ACA434F9789AA6B52DF9DAF6B" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Committee shall be appointed for staggered terms of two years and may be reappointed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H961EC9AB2C2A48AC82EF7AC858C51B18" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary shall designate one member of the Commission to serve as Chair.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFCE35139944040BDBDAF705AA618FF20" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Committee are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H74F78FFC20244E6E918647557603799A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To advise the Under Secretary for Health regarding policies and programs of the Department related to health care for veterans with specialized health care needs, including prosthetics and other special disabilities programs, rehabilitative services, and long-term care for elderly veterans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9DB040BF50C4DC9A472BF9FF5C0827A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assess the efficacy of, and recommend improvements to, health care furnished by the Secretary relating to a new veteran’s readjustment to civilian life, including mental health counseling and outreach programs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FCB7E29AC934518A50691CFFEB65520" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To evaluate the programs of the Department that relate to health conditions related to environmental or toxic exposures, and to advise on emerging health hazards and appropriate responses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5AFB7F5EDAE4C45B9F063D5A26D1A62" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To review the coordination of prosthetic and rehabilitative research and development initiatives within the Department and with external partners, and to recommend ways to enhance innovation and information exchange.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B0967EC45CE4122AC09B217C02D4540" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To identify gaps in health care furnished by the Secretary for a disabled, ill, or aging veteran, and propose strategies to improve the quality, accessibility, and equity of such health care.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H453516D83F384C089DEECCA132B5F1A5" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="HDDDBADD24713407896ABA7B65A673076" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 1 of each year, the Committee shall submit to the Under Secretary for Health a report summarizing its activities, findings, and recommendations under subsection (c). Each such report shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H554AEB6398AE42A4B16A6F783E1A573C" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An review and assessment of the hospital care and medical services furnished by the Secretary, including such care and services for veterans with disabilities, geriatric and aging veterans, and veterans exposed to environmental hazards.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA122A2D049334CC4AEB5C50833FC4C26" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Recommendations for administrative or legislative action that the Committee determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15E0C939AEFB48DBB22DC1EB3E1458DA" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after receiving each report under this subsection, the Under Secretary for Health shall submit the report, together with the Under Secretary’s comments and recommendations, to the Secretary. The Secretary shall submit all such documents to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A36EBB8C49442BC91A4A148A45A160E" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative matters</header> <paragraph id="H70EAB40C55B147FFBB8CA881A05384DA" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide such staff, information, and administrative services as necessary for the Committee to carry out its functions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD88AA5DBD694480B042EAD5AC0E3085" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Members of the Committee shall serve without compensation, but shall be entitled to travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, when engaged in the performance of Committee duties, as authorized by section 5703 of title 5.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0193BA67D3A41B08BC54C27140A553F" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Committee shall meet at the call of the Chair or the Under Secretary for Health, but not less frequently than quarterly each fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77FDF17FEF714039A70D360211DAD99E" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Unless renewed pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Federal Advisory Committee Act /14">section 14</external-xref> of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.), the Committee shall terminate not later than September 30, 2028. The Secretary may terminate the Committee at any time before such date.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD4F8815EDCA9403BB3AB890F7658A702" commented="no"><enum>550.</enum><header>Veterans Economic Opportunity and Transition Advisory Committee</header> <subsection id="H9B1A8B589CD842DA88447488C956B2F0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department an advisory committee to be known as the <quote>Veterans Economic Opportunity and Transition Advisory Committee</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H38CBECCFF6AD4FD58430F91579207ECA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership; terms; chair</header> 
<paragraph id="H83852DBA27D9442895D83670841411F1" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall appoint members of the Committee, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HC11DF9CC441749E38A1A93F3443E0EFF" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An individual with expertise in educational benefits and programs under this title.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FB8F4729F3D4280A1F2C67566E0906F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A representative of an institution of higher education or training program that serves veterans.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF0761489F5341D894EA7A222A9BF188" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual with expertise in employment and job training programs for veterans.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B71D444AB8D4B9280EE8A2ACF934306" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual with experience in hiring or training veterans.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93A25FEB98614873B63A80C046CD9E22" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A veteran who separated from active military, naval, air, or space service less than 10 years before being appointed under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7EB6755E30B548F9A8A2B7C95B16A4C8" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An individual who was a homeless veteran or an advocate for veterans’ homelessness prevention and recovery programs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E91A53252C44E158BC0D2FBCB9AA653" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Other individuals the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14F752CF7C8C47499668623047549E5B" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of a member appointed under paragraph (1) shall be two years, staggered to ensure continuity. A member may be reappointed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DE37F082F534B93855B0EEC90557FE5" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary shall designate one member of the Committee to serve as Chair.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H676E91620DC640CF99196D63D0DE7D2E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Committee are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H52C0B69EB42349C29C401900D9DE926A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To advise the Under Secretary for Benefits regarding the effectiveness of the educational benefits, vocational rehabilitation, employment assistance, and transition services furnished by the Secretary in enabling veterans to successfully readjust to civilian life and achieve economic stability.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84A57A7667754B39A3D3EBF21BF20F05" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To assemble and review information on the needs of veterans in readjusting to civilian employment, higher education, and job training. Such information shall include identified barriers that veterans (including women, minority, and economically disadvantaged veterans) face in such readjustment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83383B29B0994CCBB1D5D9322B32B160" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assess the effectiveness of the educational benefits, vocational training, job placement, and entrepreneurship training furnished by the Secretary in improving economic opportunities for veterans.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47807C81D56B48869A6005ABB58F5754" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To advise the Under Secretary regarding means to improve interagency coordination and partnership between the Department and other Federal, State, and local entities to promote employment, skills training, and financial stability for veterans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC91AAC5CD01045C785E430F233220895" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To identify and recommend strategies (including early intervention, supportive services, and employer outreach) to assist veterans at risk of homelessness or unemployment.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H725CDEE8A27E42FFA6649668F8A3EE25" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H37A3086296604E8CAE702966DC4DAE3A" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than March 31 of each year, the Committee shall submit to the Under Secretary a report on the programs and activities of the Department that relate to the issues of transition, education, employment, and economic opportunity for veterans. Each such report shall include the following, with regards to such issues:</text> <subparagraph id="HBD6F41D47F7E452C9541A0D4B3A8E893" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the unmet needs of veterans.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80E7F122286645028417E8C56F059704" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A review and evaluation of programs of the Department designed to meet such needs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H90249A07092C4852808204A91EAAEC26" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A summary of the activities of the Committee during the preceding year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEE70912E7776432F8549ED840DD0167F" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for administrative or legislative action that the Committee determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB35C1AD1CC9348D3A64CB523B9C4D113" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after receiving each report under this subsection, the Under Secretary shall submit the report, together with the Under Secretary’s comments and recommendations, to the Secretary. The Secretary shall submit all such documents to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives,</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3ED55F46E66044BD8A242286A4C8EEF1" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative matters</header> 
<paragraph id="HCBC8E3E6F4624938BE59D6E706EB0D2B" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide such staff support, information, and administrative services as necessary for the Committee to carry out its responsibilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82BF33A537AB46AAB527BE56FE3B36D7" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Members of the Committee shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed for travel expenses and per diem in lieu of subsistence in accordance with section 5703 of title 5.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H123BD40215104EC69D24B2C94DBE3F89" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Committee shall meet at the call of the Chair or the Under Secretary for Benefits, but not less frequently than twice each year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC488379EFFED418FAF41062B08A34368" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless renewed pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Federal Advisory Committee Act /14">section 14</external-xref> of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.), the Committee shall terminate not later than September 30, 2028. The Secretary may terminate the Committee at any time before such date.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0705BF5DBBF64F3BA22009F78F7FA9C6" commented="no"><enum>551.</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Veterans Special Populations</header> 
<subsection id="H7D022629D4E44E38BB426F66778B04CC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department an advisory committee to be known as the <quote>Advisory Committee on Veterans Special Populations</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE8DC7BE7B2474788957C1FA877E5E7B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership; terms; Chair</header> <paragraph id="H5D8326F35A2B42159C3CA6B3FE1133A2" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Committee shall consist of members appointed by the Secretary for their expertise regarding the needs of historically underserved veteran communities. Members shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF408F1232EC44D3C9B6C0FA5C89F598F" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not fewer than two women veterans, representing different service eras.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H030516C5799C4F40BD028871EE7B535C" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not fewer than two veterans from, and with experience advocating for veterans from, the outlying areas of the United States or the Freely Associated States (including American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, the U.S. Virgin Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, and Palau).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2C29E07CECB43DB8AA5A25B0B795D1A" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals who are recognized authorities on issues affecting minority veteran populations, including—</text> <clause id="HF16645C94127418D9BE3B23C9FC71B67"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least one individual with expertise in health care or benefits for women veterans; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCE0694D419B3412A8358B702A8796CF6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one individual with expertise in issues regarding veterans in tribal or insular area communities.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H387492F171584AC58F9CEB02A071EE92" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such other members the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H702F0A6C2C4D420D973DDD52ED2564DC" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of a member appointed under paragraph (1) shall be two years, staggered to ensure continuity. A member may be reappointed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4C948A2B41446C4B490CDC63452F514" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to members appointed under paragraph (1), the Committee shall include, as ex officio members, the following officials (or their designees):</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7BF86240F96648018F93BB39102F4C07" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Deputy Assistant Secretary for Tribal Government Relations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9C6D8584705441E9281A5BD25634019" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Director of the Center for Women Veterans of the Department.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0D550FEE7A2423B9A00BC29316F7E24" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Director of the Center for Minority Veterans of the Department.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2C3B2419EA84946B32EED81B5F411E5" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary shall designate one member of the Committee to serve as the Chair.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF3DF39BFE2F94A739864FD11F7174D5E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The functions of the Committee include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HEBC574F18FAD4651BC3440AD4EB8EFE5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To advise the Secretary on the administration of benefits and services for veterans who are members of populations that have been historically underserved, under-represented, or faced unique barriers to access.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C87E80D86CC4A0994FB9345580796E4" commented="no">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>To assess the needs of such veterans with respect to compensation, health care, mental health, rehabilitation, outreach, and other benefits and programs administered by the Secretary.</text>
                        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAEDDDD00E054A9595601DDE20E046DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To evaluate the extent to which programs of the Department meeting needs described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18E1483A75034EE78917CEA65ADBBF15" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To review and make recommendations regarding reports, studies, and program data pertaining to the experience of such veterans, including trends in health outcomes, benefit usage rates, and disparities in access or quality of services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE2C0F43154640859BCE087077D8A79E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To examine and make recommendations to outreach activities of the Department and strategies for engaging with veterans in such communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6AC5695CF24A4DDD81C9A3BC0E62A83F" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To advise on the effectiveness of offices and programs of the Department that are specifically charged with assisting such veterans (including the Center for Women Veterans, the Center for Minority Veterans, and the Office of Tribal Government Relations).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD21C197BC90B4696B550326380525AE4" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H0A2FA61D5D9D48059F3D0ED50430295A" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than July 1 of each year, the Committee shall submit to the Secretary a report on the programs and activities of the Department during the preceding year. Each such report shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HA79621A54A2A41EBB3FAC663E1CBD3B2" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the needs of such veterans for benefits and services furnished by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A04C812F58E4739B4FAC3E468E58503" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A review and evaluation of the programs, activities, and research initiatives of the Department designed to meet such needs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED5EF69330AF401698ACBC193A4E2A36" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for administrative or legislative action that the Committee determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H131A2047573D4FF69A0B90587C512617" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after receiving each report under this subsection, the Under Secretary for Health shall submit the report, together with the Under Secretary’s comments and recommendations, to the Secretary. The Secretary shall submit all such documents to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H29B7B340CBFC4E8092E7DF9137E72F3A" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative matters</header> <paragraph id="HFCF43234DF2C433D931471E7F509A648" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide such staff, data, and administrative support to the Committee as necessary for the Committee to carry out its duties.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61A3BDF702B54D379C520B5EB4235EE1" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Members of the Committee shall serve without pay, but shall receive travel expenses and per diem for any travel performed in the course of service on the Committee, in accordance with section 5703 of title 5.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84F8E55FD1D443F5938523C09665BDB7" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Committee shall meet at the call of the Chair or the Secretary, but not less frequently than twice per year. Meetings may be conducted in person or through electronic means, as the Secretary deems appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H747895DCA24D4529B6058FCE98640E01" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless renewed pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Federal Advisory Committee Act /14">section 14</external-xref> of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.), the Committee shall terminate not later than September 30, 2028. The Secretary may terminate the Committee at any time before such date.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7D994AA011BD4141A789C4195B4EB1E2" commented="no"><enum>552.</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Former Prisoners of War, Compensation, and Memorial Affairs</header> <subsection id="H98735217522C45A9826DEA767E3E7C75" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department of Veterans Affairs an advisory committee to be known as the <quote>Advisory Committee on Former Prisoners of War, Compensation, and Memorial Affairs</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H02EB2BCEBE424F568FED2B8577B3A4E0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership; terms; Chair</header> 
<paragraph id="H427E5707AB504AC9A4BD6D9BB6EA5C19" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Members of the Committee shall be appointed by the Secretary and shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H5CA5DE01E917440189D2DC38F792BDA7" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A veteran who is a former prisoner of war, or a family member or advocates for former prisoners of war (hereinafter, <quote>POWs</quote>), to provide insight into the experiences and needs of such veterans.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16CB4C13F82D4D12AD41242BE300085B" indent="up1" commented="no">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Individuals who are recognized authorities in fields relevant to disabilities prevalent among former POWs, such as epidemiology, mental health, nutrition, geriatrics, or internal medicine.</text>
                            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3AA7FB33E2E4771A683928E32334244" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Representatives of veterans with service-connected disabilities and experts in veterans disability compensation policy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H919976B403E5414F9833D6A06135E43F" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Individuals with expertise in memorial affairs, funeral services, or military or veteran burials.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD36628FDED8B46F5B6527C6531A38FCA" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other individuals the Secretary determines appropriate to ensure a comprehensive representation of perspectives on compensation, POW issues, and memorial matters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB35167EE03794829A8DDDEF9FFA2A8C2" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of a member appointed under paragraph (1) shall be two years, staggered to ensure continuity. A member may be reappointed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEFB72FD9B37D413A800CE90423ED2700" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall designate one member of the Committee to serve as the Chair.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB047BC534B324C9D87209A75B6791555" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Committee are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA1F431629548494D83FC6AA6C7A53E6E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To advise the Secretary on the administration and adequacy of benefits for disabled veterans, including compensation and the schedule for rating disabilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85BCF0A2910A433F8755B858A70ACF60" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assess the needs of veterans who are former POWs (including disability compensation, health care, and rehabilitation) and to evaluate the programs and policies of the Department meant to address such needs (including presumptions of service connection for former POWs, the provision of specialized health care (including mental health care) to such veterans, and outreach efforts to ensure former POWs are aware of and receiving benefits).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H51FC612FF5C74D528823AA359926F197" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To advise the Secretary on the administration of burial benefits and memorial programs for veterans and their eligible family members, including policies on burial allowances, headstones or markers, and the operation of national cemeteries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43F524003CA14DA191EFB79481E123BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The review and make recommendations regarding the services and plans of the National Cemetery Administration to address the needs of veterans and survivors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8060EF757D0848F3A1723E0A3FA6AC0F" commented="no">
                            <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assess and make recommendations regarding the effectiveness of the programs of the Department that commemorate and honor the service and sacrifices of veterans and their families, (including the maintenance of cemeteries, availability of gravesites, and memorial tributes for under-recognized groups of veterans).</text>
                        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3078A0BE472F4F18AA2924166E8BC764" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To identify and make recommendations regarding legislative or administrative barriers that hinder the ability of the Secretary to promptly and fairly compensate veterans for service-connected disabilities or to provide appropriate memorial benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A6B8791655E48DFA7BA458066B2D7DD" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H30C787CBFEAC41FA8BB8791434FAE9A2" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than July 1 of each year, the Committee shall submit to the Secretary a report on the programs and activities of the Department during the preceding year. Each such report shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE8393BE8266649FC90AC9F1E47114245" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the needs of veterans and their survivors for disability compensation, including an evaluation of whether the current compensation structure (such as the rating schedule and ancillary benefits) adequately compensates veterans for the loss of earning capacity and quality of life.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HECFA2F7D76F74429B1CA6F5500E456EC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the specific needs of former POWs for compensation, health care, and rehabilitation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E51F35BCDA7421F90DAA17FE8A7C05C" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of needs related to burial and memorial services for veterans and their families.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5354C0B83464EDA8643A48AEDD36E7E" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment review of the programs and policies of the Department that address issues related to functions described in subsection (c).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6CF78E5D32684E569D221BF8A4730CB4" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for administrative or legislative action that the Committee determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAFDBDDD9F2645F993A21C369C14752E" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after receiving each report under this subsection, the Under Secretary for Health shall submit the report, together with the Under Secretary’s comments and recommendations, to the Secretary. The Secretary shall submit all such documents to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H91A9E60C6B8A40F3ACB954A487027283" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative matters</header> 
<paragraph id="H86B5C2792D5544B79925FA2DFBFCEC4C" commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide such staff, data, and administrative support to the Committee as necessary for the Committee to carry out its duties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CBC73C46B904CC4AA99273A8DB94A6F" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Committee shall serve without pay, but shall receive travel expenses and per diem for any travel performed in the course of service on the Committee, in accordance with section 5703 of title 5.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C951FE90FDE43E9A02563A6CBA192B3" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall meet at the call of the Chair or the Secretary, but not less frequently than twice per year. Meetings may be conducted in person or through electronic means, as the Secretary deems appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC232F61BDD5E49BBBB1CDBB720125548" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless renewed pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Federal Advisory Committee Act /14">section 14</external-xref> of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.), the Committee shall terminate not later than September 30, 2028. The Secretary may terminate the Committee at any time before such date.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HD730EF231887460DA239036BFF945C74"><enum>3.</enum><header>Termination dates of certain advisory committees of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="H70920C8E4EF94FD5BFFFAF31293E1511"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Former Prisoners of War</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 541 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H6EE0CF06C4724DE3A5E75164A5E2606C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H365F7380DE6E4D98AE4461A815C6DF46"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F97C1AA146345929F48DE4F4B0E3E84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Women Veterans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 542 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6839503209A44AACB0A4AE9B5888699B"> <subsection id="H28C531EC706841808CC75D58D56177A5"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBEC084FEBB424A2C81D174507EAB20D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Prosthetics and Special-Disabilities Programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 543 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE30DEEEF78F54735985F0FCDD397DD9E"> <subsection id="HA28597E055FB4CE38A1997A8F8A977C4"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H099E6A8CCC404381B492BDC62A6DD81A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advisory Committee on the Readjustment of Veterans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 545 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE5745925DFE4C9B846A4E61161D495D"> <subsection id="HB7C5E93B81C84481B6487CB23F9B7B44"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF276CA597BD4CB6846A95C9B530CC5B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Disability Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 546 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (f) and inserting the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64F3C23173FE4A8AABFB279ABC8150CA"> <subsection id="H1E0616DD1E924B1080632A0D33164C85"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD168E2A20CA64F39B45CF124344EF1CC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Tribal and Indian Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 547 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (i) and inserting the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H565E7CD8F7BE4C179EF79663B00ED326"> <subsection id="H958F4F16234F436089A5085C0D591E86"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A4E7320400A422E87A47FB3DC78D758" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Advisory Committee on United States Outlying Areas and Freely Associated States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 548(k) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2026</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCF4F19FC851C4B20A7818578312341DB"> <enum>(h)</enum> <header>Advisory Committee on Cemeteries and Memorials</header> <text>Section 2401 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</quote>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H233B1E54B661415DA2F96BB0C866CC84"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Veterans' Advisory Committee on Rehabilitation</header> <text>Section 3121 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H5764DC789C1B48C8BF206D75DA58458F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H18E8B737D84A4BE1A35379DD6FF39D9B"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4D11F0670D7B49518396930A84FFF0E3"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Veterans' Advisory Committee on Education</header> <text>Section 3692(c) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>December 31, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2026</quote>.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H4F31B35ACDFE4F5FB59CE903AD90BE01" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Veterans Employment, Training, and Employer Outreach</header> <text>Section 4110 of title 38, United States Code, is amended, in subsection (h), by striking <quote>continue until terminated by law</quote> and inserting <quote>terminate on September 30, 2026</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4AA5810F86CB48899484F60C825CF575"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Academic Affiliations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7313 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H67C6F15F853848EB9F9C9576D4565AF3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HD12590B9F7434AA39E4C1C7B2A5C7E80"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any such advisory committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026. The Secretary may not establish a new such advisory committee after such date.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEC58F5C963024C55BEAA76CF1DA38D73"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Geriatrics and Gerontology Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7315 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4EC130B6C654914894CC5889817EEED"> <subsection id="H9045E7CE0B69461E85C45A0A27F6C6AB"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H878143D09F5D4221BADB7AE73968DB2B" commented="no"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Parent Advisory Committee for Child Care Centers</header> <text>Section 7809(e) of such title is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Any such committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</quote>.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HC8A3D72AC03740178291A5D3E3A05098"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Structural Safety of Department Facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8105(b) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0FB8C9B78EF44CFA2C1092EDDEC5BCE"> 
<paragraph id="HE9F735BAF83446939B7CDF5AA696E810" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HBD04899744A84E179B61844364136700"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Veterans’ Advisory Committee on Environmental Hazards</header> <text>The Veterans' Dioxin and Radiation Exposure Compensation Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/542">Public Law 98–542</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1154">38 U.S.C. 1154</external-xref> note), is amended, in section 6, by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H11F274EE278F49DBBA7D59F10677B88B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H2461BFD8F3B34273B1ECF5A4E4DB7570"><enum>(h)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall terminate on September 30, 2026.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H13947A7D511B43BDB24EE089C15B636B" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Repeal of defunct advisory committees</header> <subsection id="H653A9C66109C4F15A6E6BFFBC18569D1" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Professional Certification and Licensure Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3689 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (e).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8417FBC7D82744B28DAB5CFFD1F8BD70" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing a list of advisory committees of the Department of Veterans Affairs—</text> <paragraph id="H649E18C7CF0E4C4B85A6E494E0024FAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that are authorized and inactive; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4021A9C1C79549F9B6811B95CC0F460E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for which authorization has lapsed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

