<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9E821A4F37CC4BE8BA596355AE8E2CAD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1341 IH: Expressing support for the recognition of June 7, 2026, as “Tourette Syndrome Awareness Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1341</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260604">June 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the recognition of June 7, 2026, as <quote>Tourette Syndrome Awareness Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Tourette Syndrome is an inherited neurological disorder that is characterized by involuntary physical and vocal tics that occur many times a day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tourette Syndrome is often accompanied by other mental health disorders such as attention deficit and obsessive compulsive disorder, learning disabilities, and anxiety;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Tourette Syndrome and Persistent Tic Disorders affect approximately 1 in 50 children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 30,000 school age children in the State of Tennessee and 82,000 in New York alone are dealing with Tourette Syndrome;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, although some of these cases are aided by medication, there is no standard treatment or known cure for the disorder;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is an important need for more professional help with interest and expertise to identify, counsel, and treat people with Tourette Syndrome, a disorder that is often misdiagnosed and misunderstood;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas positive actions to assist children and families living with Tourette Syndrome would result from a broadening of public and professional knowledge and acceptance of Tourette Syndrome;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Tourette Association of America is actively providing services to families, educating medical professionals and teachers, and supporting research to better understand the signs and treatments of Tourette Syndrome; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June 7, 2026, would be an appropriate date to recognize as <quote>Tourette Syndrome Awareness Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE72AC69F9DE84F9F88AF7F54BA13BD04"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H831D63CB657B495D86E3B05A0EA9E66C"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives expresses support for the recognition of <quote>Tourette Syndrome Awareness Day</quote> as a special day to promote understanding, compassion, and acceptance for all of our fellow citizens who deserve and need our support to break the stigma that surrounds Tourette Syndrome.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

