<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE2D802D788164EE4BA394A965BE1C915" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6689 IH: Ensuring Transparency, Honesty, and Integrity for Contracting, Acquisition, and Lifecycle Procurement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6689</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251212">December 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of Defense from awarding contracts to entities of which certain current Government employees are officers or owners, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7ED9A420159F43FEBC6680F5C0C58CA9" style="OLC"><section id="H4DED849C82D34DBA8C03D5DC20F92814" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Transparency, Honesty, and Integrity for Contracting, Acquisition, and Lifecycle Procurement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ETHICAL Procurement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H337B822F70F744C7B1D52F16BFD37518"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on eligibility for defense contracts for certain entities</header><subsection id="H433D12F1F70141628542C2A8CEBF0044"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Defense may not enter into, renew, or extend any contract or other agreement for the acquisition of any good or service produced or provided by an entity if—</text><paragraph id="HEACC4862BEA240E996CD722E5A14819D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an officer, director, partner, or majority owner of such entity—</text><subparagraph id="HBE9130FD2819424C9C3392A2E0755B54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>holds a position to which such individual was appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A2143DF05FE471FABECB21A46331C43"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">holds a position in the executive branch of the Government of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H433FCBB23C954FAA8152861333FA97B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a special Government employee; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2C4CC292FEE4EF5A513F5545D081CE1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>holds a position in the Senior Executive Service (as defined in section 2101a of title 5, United States Code); or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5DF1DCB63DF40A9A4C2C353262271F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an individual who is an immediate family member of the President, an individual holding a position described in subparagraph (A) or (B) or paragraph (1), or a special Government employee—</text><subparagraph id="HD13C678518894361876F2EE530A3DA96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a officer, director, or partner of such entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0392F4F0584D493186C0C8772FF346CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>holds a significant ownership interest in such entity or would derive a substantial financial benefit from the Secretary entering into, renewing, or extending such contract or other agreement, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FDF537FDD6B465AA408B0541CE47879"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall issue regulations to implement this section, including definitions, thresholds, and procedures for identifying individuals and entities with respect to which the prohibition under subsection (a) applies.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3E5FEBFBD5B345F192AA59997379E54E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB6C08C7B71F249B18531FE869F47265C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Immediate family member</header><text>The term <quote>immediate family member</quote> means a parent, child, sibling, spouse, or domestic partner.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF68CB1AE3E3642D99B5A8A238CA8A263"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special Government employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>special Government employee</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 202 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

