<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFEF7B4725018455191EECC66779367A6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7674 IH: Venezuela Democratic Transition Strategy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7674</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to submit to Congress a strategy to support a democratic transition in Venezuela, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H905BB193C8A44B53B83CD8FB0B297C3B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H37B9901143354F8EB7BCC8882682D428" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Venezuela Democratic Transition Strategy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H16D6B0FFD35B44008D96F28F2575B773"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy to support a democratic transition in Venezuela</header> <subsection id="H82677916274F4451884B548BEE324D73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy</header> <paragraph id="HA555D3D8CADF45BABBCB68EC065C6FBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive strategy to support a democratic transition in the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE26E7E4F821457C85A217590CD7D0E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HB9ABBC2D7A874A2A81B5C238C558EAE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of United States diplomatic efforts to support a democratic transition in Venezuela;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F51A0FFAC184DE182E597CF25A1ED4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to prioritize the release of all individuals arbitrarily detained in Venezuela, including through diplomatic engagement, coordination with international partners, and support for monitoring and documenting cases of political detention;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2CAD9572134B46BA84FA59C1C6763221"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of United States efforts to curb foreign authoritarian influence, including the influence of the Republic of Cuba, the Russian Federation, the Islamic Republic of Iran, and the People’s Republic of China, within the military, security services, and Government of Venezuela;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2BF758AD736B4C2A835DD9C297264CF8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a plan for the use of United States foreign assistance to support the Venezuelan people, including humanitarian assistance, democracy and governance programming, and efforts to strengthen access to basic services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53D5A9378C004ACEAC50A63DDDFB5EA2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of efforts to support Venezuelan civil society, including independent media, human rights defenders, independent journalists, and other nongovernmental actors working to advance democracy, the rule of law, and accountability for atrocities and gross violations of internationally recognized human rights.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H56E2A9A3B5394E478D52A7C26EBFAF43"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the submission of the strategy required in subsection (a), and annually thereafter for 2 years, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing progress made in implementing such strategy and any recommended changes to such strategy.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H76835C4BFF61424098A2BEF7D85E01E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees on a semi-annual basis regarding the strategy required in subsection (a) and the implementation of such strategy.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2499F3904BE04E70AE271A1A22249068"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HEB6182B8CAFF4FA689F615D6979C2C56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3231B6DBD67C44E48F71D29681CB61FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

