<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5D3DB2F9092D4D679AD606C018B699F8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9129 IH: Guarding the U.S. against Adversarial Robotics Dominance Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9129</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260603">June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for certain humanoid and quadruped robotics communications equipment or services to be placed on the covered list of the Federal Communications Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE5C8A82B51534C748EE5717268AFB304" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE16029DEC107410F8511093016ED1306" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guarding the U.S. against Adversarial Robotics Dominance Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GUARD Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2367F4C69A7741D5B9BD03FCBF5EA8D6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Analysis of certain humanoid or quadruped robotics communications equipment or services</header> <subsection id="H3C3A03D715304BD08E52A71E2DC8DF26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation of covered robotics communications equipment or services</header> <paragraph id="H54FE03BE39254BBBAC2F3F843F5829F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Placement on covered list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, an appropriate national security agency shall determine if covered robotics communications equipment or services pose an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United states persons.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64B37F08F46C432EB02ECEB9433AE2D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to any covered robotics communications equipment or service that an appropriate national security agency determines, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, does not pose an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDA81998D0664459A5A3364073CDB561"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Addition to covered list</header><text>If the appropriate national security agency does not make a determination as required by paragraph (1) within 1 year after the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall add all covered robotics communications equipment or services to the covered list.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3DA1A662D2E4D588C29F19BDE217E55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of other determinations</header> 
<paragraph id="HD626F4A3567B494F8AAA814D0210D5D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determined to pose unacceptable risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after an appropriate national security agency determines that any covered robotics communications equipment or service poses an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons—</text> <subparagraph id="HB3F74DD7EA494FD88834653C88A2B729"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Commission shall place such covered robotics communications equipment or service on the covered list; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBCC0B6ABFAEA42EFAAA376918B9C0398"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appropriate national security agency shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the determination of such agency, which shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF526C6003A0145439343D40B2B811450"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determined not to pose unacceptable risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an appropriate national security agency determines that any covered robotics communications equipment or service does not pose an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE5E4900477C94A91A707A58F9AA0BDD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the determination, such agency shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and all other appropriate national security agencies a report on the determination, which shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA6496704E5E4622B93111DAEBDDA81B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the determination, all other appropriate national security agencies shall review the determination and shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the respective determinations of such agencies, which shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H696BE4EF5207403AA9F6172E9B05E177"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H04F158DB72134AE2A1D72DEB2921D491"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF33080F8BE1F4D609D6B4C1F5F60D0DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF49B302332BB47C9BE23C7ABD5B2E701"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H819BC6A1A84E4FDC8CE860FEF8A2BB8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate national security agency</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate national security agency</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 9 of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1608">47 U.S.C. 1608</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H350B42A40CD9488E8BD481B00A6845CA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA24917DC2C4E4676858E27BBB4BDA6FE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Communications equipment or services</header><text>The term <quote>communications equipment or services</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 9 of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1608">47 U.S.C. 1608</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4B289CF0544425EB71DC7058B41846B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Country of concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>country of concern</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1(m)(1) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">22 U.S.C. 2651a(m)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3296E293086B42C487E464A9993A6623"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Covered foreign entity</header><text>The term <quote>covered foreign entity</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HC7D0F175556D45488AD5DC505E2FE6FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity that—</text> 
<clause id="H0692F9A1444940048E7F15F8FD8D4D21"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is headquartered in, has its principal place of business in, or is organized under the laws of a country of concern; or</text></clause> <clause id="H5C564BB814F647F8BC0C92479D9E0D2B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is subject to the influence, direction, or control of the government of a country of concern;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H65DA73E8B3614B76B514436FD0B4EA92"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an affiliate or wholly or partially owned subsidiary of an entity described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD12424A5F9FF40C5B496D23765AE4B1E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity in a joint venture with an entity described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFCE3E403FF30452290B00958BF32586C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an entity with which an entity described in subparagraph (A) has a technology sharing or licensing agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1A93C341A6E4B29B150B6872789CDE0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Covered list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered list</quote> means the list of covered communications equipment or services published by the Commission under section 2(a) of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1601">47 U.S.C. 1601(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84DC5D150F744A03BF61F1400ECBD014"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Covered robotics communications equipment or service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered robotics communications equipment or service</quote> means any humanoid or quadruped robot, or software designed to control such robot that is a communications equipment or services produced or provided by a covered foreign entity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED42A61D1E78405498C3BAFFC6BC3D3D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Humanoid or Quadruped robot</header><text>The term <quote>humanoid or quadruped robot</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H06F9B7113C3549DEB878966EE7042E64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a mechanical device that—</text> <clause id="HDB0D38E68BE94158BA2E911D8944543F"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">possesses a body structure that uses 2 or 4 articulated limbs for locomotion, navigation, or movement on the ground; and</text>
                        </clause> 
<clause id="H1774862F3168464BA277A1D42F3DDF53"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operates at a distance from a human operator or supervisor autonomously, semi-autonomously, based on commands or response to sensor data or any combination thereof; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31304B8DA30D42779F588B76DF52C193"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any external device designed to control a mechanical device described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFE9CCEC521684616998E9A942BEAAB17"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to apply to any country that is not a country of concern, including a North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) ally and a Major Non-NATO Ally.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

