<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFDE399F69D184096A12268A2662C2609" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6043 IH: Manage Your Data and Allow Only Trusted Access Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6043</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251112">November 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit covered entities from preventing the use of certain data by individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1852D73C5C814FCEAD2F600D98CD0BAA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB1473A30F0E44B17A16E1CD44C2E3982" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Manage Your Data and Allow Only Trusted Access Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MY DATA Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3B9B02EB00864264B48BAEAD0326A179"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on covered entity action against consumer privacy</header> <subsection id="H7A5BAF7AC0E74D3CA8DCB01593A1BC07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> <paragraph id="H05C570FAFF2144E38F0F768709488FF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered entity may not prevent an individual from using de-identified data or cloaked data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE38891F6F962462291E5E8AEF24D11B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The prohibition described in paragraph (1) does not apply to a covered entity to the extent that the covered entity acts as a service provider.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6820B558099148F7B10B4A55C791DD00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> <paragraph id="HB35A3EB136EF43CCA4468DA219181C6E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of subsection (a)(1) shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE9721070125487396582D2EBA581728"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce subsection (a)(1) in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section, and any person who violates subsection (a)(1) shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H74E8E68C4B1B47F586AD6841E2775C60"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H84ED0960F81349AF8FC03166368543EF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cloaked data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cloaked data</term> means unique persistent identifiers that serve to adequately replace and conceal the covered data and identity of an individual while enabling communication between a covered entity and the individual.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC68F4DA08C13464295DF19FBFD148202"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered data</term> means information that identifies or is linked or reasonably linkable (alone or in combination with other information) to an individual (or a device that identifies or is linked or reasonably linkable to an individual).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6247BC594AD1418BB64F42521EA535C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered entity</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB76E05AA73494FE9863FF900093316C1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered entity</term> means any person (other than an individual acting in a non-commercial context) who (alone or jointly with others) collects, processes, or transfers covered data.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7BD29B6A2584430AEA127B00D0E338A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> does not include any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="H6683189AA06E47B5985D1AED9D7F9116"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal, State, or local government entity, such as a body, authority, board, bureau, commission, district, agency, or political subdivision of the Federal Government or a State or local government.</text></clause> <clause id="HD2631F693B6148EFAF0B90B790476108"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An entity that serves as a congressionally designated nonprofit, national resource center, and clearinghouse to provide assistance to victims, families, child-serving professionals, and the general public on issues relating to missing and exploited children.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE9C0F19E51B49F3832AE3EE323962C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>De-identified data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>de-identified data</term> means information that does not identify and is not linked or reasonably linkable to an individual (or a device that identifies or is linked or reasonably linkable to an individual), regardless of whether such information is aggregated.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7E4E6B10A084EA59F317B661EB2F23E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Unique persistent identifier</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unique persistent identifier</term> means an identifier—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7E17608B6A54475CBF561CCC3BA6B748"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the extent that such identifier is linked or reasonably linkable to an individual (or a device that identifies or is linked or reasonably linkable to an individual); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC05C2C00614C4CAE8A2205D5F3098C5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is created uniquely for communication between such individual and a covered entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

