<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9A39772CE23B46A6A1A7D5E889D3C5E5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7967 IH: Heidi’s Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7967</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to revise the Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing Programs to include testing for methadone use and to require the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations to include testing for methadone use in Department of Transportation drug tests.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA6480035ED7A472F9D5B65364F40D1B8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0270704D2710401AAA14E323A1DA60A4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Heidi’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDDB020F877C046DAA6DBBADDEB47D492"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inclusion of testing for methadone use in certain drug testing procedures</header> <subsection id="H16AE4869DD464D719CBF059A9CC73AFD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Revision of mandatory guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall revise the Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing Programs, established pursuant to section 503(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/71">Public Law 100–71</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/7301">5 U.S.C. 7301</external-xref> note), to expand the opiate category on the list of substances authorized for testing to include methadone.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HFE99161DCD5E47F39BF37EFD38491222"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication of notice</header><text>Upon completion of the revision required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall publish a final notice in the Federal Register of such revision.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6BC9A250F5904F84AEC5DC6D6AF2472B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inclusion of methadone in Department of Transportation drug tests</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the final notice required under section 2(b) is published, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update any regulations containing procedures for transportation employee workplace drug and alcohol testing programs to include testing for methadone use in drug-testing panels, consistent with the Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing Programs as revised by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 2.</text></section>
<section id="H1D2CC2BD2F0F442DA52F82429F59AF40"><enum>4.</enum><header>To compel the Secretary to periodically update the mandatory guidelines for Federal workplace drug testing</header>
<subsection id="HE4C4562EF1E54887AABA276855F3C285"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an annual basis, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall review and if necessary revise the Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing Programs, established pursuant to section 503(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/71">Public Law 100–71</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/7301">5 U.S.C. 7301</external-xref> note), to expand the list of substances authorized for testing to include any such drugs which may not have been previously included, and which the Secretary believes should be included.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF20768F7E8254E4E8C8EC89190989F70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication of notice</header><text>Upon completion of the revision required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall publish a final notice in the Federal Register of such revision.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HB06CF8A185FF4AF4A0508A5A7C7AB0DD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Inclusion of newly established drugs in department of transportation drug tests</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the final notice required under section 4(b) is published, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update any regulations containing procedures for transportation employee workplace drug and alcohol testing programs to include testing for newly identified substances in drug-testing panels, consistent with the Mandatory Guidelines for Federal Workplace Drug Testing Programs as revised by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 4.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

