<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8468D14EE7C64C87808E63FB24A84FB1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6526 IH: Clarity on Care Options Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6526</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish and maintain a publicly available directory of health care providers that accept assignments under the CHAMPVA program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0645A04D3C1A4AD2A7CD0BBD7F521B1F" style="OLC"><section id="H0C72B716EE324B7796C62901E7A3C0CE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clarity on Care Options Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDA55CF010E9A4DCDACEEE553995AD603"><enum>2.</enum><header>Publicly available directory of health care providers that accept assignments under the CHAMPVA program</header><subsection id="HB4463BA9F0064A26834AA06DEAB44E43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual query</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall require each entity that administers a network of health care providers under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code, to, on an annual basis—</text><paragraph id="HAE191E2CD2F14552A5279631412E46F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>query each provider in such network to determine whether the provider accepts assignments under the CHAMPVA program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6D09A7E9DA943CBA5FCF9BD9D738650"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit the results of such queries to the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB49AF8DF6FA2477BB2FC24DEFE7C40D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Directory</header><text>Utilizing the information submitted under subsection (a) and any other information available to the Secretary, the Secretary shall establish and maintain a publicly available directory of providers in such networks that accept assignments under the CHAMPVA program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5FA44FACB727479CBEA996A867BF7D0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="H04E7ED51061248B4B1C9057F5F3F7F77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual queries</header><text>The first queries required by subsection (a) shall be completed, and the results submitted to the Secretary, not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E6D3394C0054955A754E580F863F408"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List of providers</header><text>The first directory of providers required by subsection (b) shall be made publicly available not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EDF21B05C7F45AB8535C6121A66840D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for four additional years, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the extent to which the providers in such networks accept assignments under the CHAMPVA program. The report shall include the following information, broken down by State (as defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code) and by Veterans Integrated Service Network:</text><paragraph id="H5DD66F39B14E4F3F93590C21FC79FAD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of providers in such networks that accept assignments under the CHAMPVA program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H319F5FF183484300A3DF67A3C252B013"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The percentage of providers in such networks that accept assignments under the CHAMPVA program and the percentage of providers in such networks that do not accept such assignments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F05579BC3194D6CA98453F9A0967F8E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The specific geographical areas that contain CHAMPVA program beneficiaries but do not contain providers that accept assignments under the CHAMPVA program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DD2701BDC4444D6A11E4D17E7024D05"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD8D75EA7B18D4F5E89B8BB567CDC4811"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>accept assignment</quote>, with respect to the CHAMPVA program, means to accept responsibility for the care of a CHAMPVA program beneficiary and thereby agree to accept the amount determined allowable under the CHAMPVA program as full payment for services and supplies rendered to the beneficiary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE495D0A8207445F8BC9F3E76E8BAE244"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>CHAMPVA program</quote> means the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs under section 1781 of title 38, United States Code, and Part 17 of title 38, Code of Federal Regulations. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

