<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HDB022B58E1714B6C98A8CDA1CD14F5C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 573 RH: Studying NEPA’s Impact on Projects Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 342</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 573</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–393]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250121">January 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on January 21, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Council on Environmental Quality to publish an annual report on environmental reviews and causes of action based on alleged non-compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HB4ABE6AF57C64C41A2D5EDE76502939D"><section id="H913C3989BAE044468B029DC891D912B7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Studying NEPA’s Impact on Projects Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAF0435FF47754E58A65FB042392E20D8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report on NEPA’s impact on projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4341">42 U.S.C. 4341</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H462A59BB200A43A899A7448C616B4F90" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><section id="H10286F8CD06E4C629ABD06734B84499E"><enum>201.</enum><header>Annual reports on NEPA’s impact on projects</header><subsection id="H5A27644B4BDC4765B189F13E8AF7C9AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submissions by lead agencies</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2026, and annually thereafter, the head of each lead agency shall submit to the Council on Environmental Quality a report on—</text><paragraph id="H24F131045E16491EB778535C80BFEFFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each civil action alleging an agency action in violation of this Act that was active during the period beginning June 1 of the preceding year and ending June 1 of the current year, which shall identify—</text><subparagraph id="H41CD106BF60C4C5CBB4561B69CA3AE19"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each such civil action—</text><clause id="HC84B8D785DEA4B31A5D0899DC283A8EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the defendant lead agency, where applicable, and each plaintiff; and</text></clause><clause id="H17032DCB0FAC4DE99E4D701B3AFE2CBA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the court in which the civil action was brought and any court to which a decision on the civil action was appealed;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFB51B9718934957BD1ACDB39CA7348C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of such civil actions, disaggregated by the defendant agency, with a single entry denoting the lead agency, where applicable, for cases involving multiple Federal agency defendants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC66DCA361E6248FA9037ADDCFF095361"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alleged basis for each such civil action, disaggregated by covered sectors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B82770A4CF94F8BB59B64CDC658933D" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the status and outcome, if applicable, of each civil action alleging an agency action in violation of this Act that was active during the period beginning June 1 of the preceding year and ending June 1 of the current year, including whether—</text><clause id="HCDD408048A8443D0993A058CD52153B0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the civil action resulted in a decision to hold unlawful and set aside the agency action within the meaning of section 706(2) of title 5, United States Code;</text></clause><clause id="H00AA4456463443B5BFFE097492304BC2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the civil action resulted in a decision allowing the Federal agency to proceed with the major Federal action;</text></clause><clause id="HD46F139DF52846C38CF4F3AA83D507DB" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the civil action resulted in an order remanding the matter to the agency for reconsideration without vacating the analysis;</text></clause><clause id="H25A4AC33357143CD888868ECBDE1FF09" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any claim under the civil action was resolved by a settlement agreement or consent decree between any plaintiff and the defendant lead agency;</text></clause><clause id="HFDD1900017E546619DC1F312A5B710AE" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the civil action is still active; and</text></clause><clause id="H9F980A4D3827447B82682A70A2543F48" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any of the plaintiffs received an award, including an award of costs pursuant to section 2412 of title 28, United States Code, except that if such information is received after the lead agency submits the applicable report to the Council on Environmental Quality, the lead agency shall include such information in the subsequent report;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAC38BB884B447C6AEEB7D760358B1AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the length of environmental impact statements made publicly available pursuant to section 102(2)(C) during the period of 5 years that ends on June 1 of the current year, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HC14E210B907340AE97D5440F4387EA16"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average and median page count of all such environmental impact statements (not including the page count of any citations or appendices), including such page counts disaggregated by quartiles;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC65020D4E3C4A24A3A30199377A0D65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average and median page count of any citations and appendices included in such environmental impact statements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CA62BC12E4943A28D86B7D610CBE40B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of such environmental impact statements, disaggregated by lead agency and subagency as applicable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7563472E7C44686AD831609D542B803" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of trends in average and median page count of such environmental impact statements and any citations and appendices included in such environmental impact statements compared to prior reports published by the Council on Environmental Quality; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4236B7D1840A4C32A9A388D98C2D2BB9" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each report submitted under this section through 2028, a disaggregation of the data from before and after the date of the enactment of the Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2023;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H61C6424EBF374FF1AED70A70A2D7E98A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an estimate of the cost to prepare the environmental impact statements described in paragraph (2), including—</text><subparagraph id="H89A941122115433EB216B5267CA36F54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the full-time equivalent personnel hour costs, contractor costs, and other direct costs of the lead agency that prepared the environmental impact statement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27607FF1D07D4B3CAB5C3B11C985BCA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if practicable, and noted where not practicable, the costs incurred by cooperating agencies, participating agencies, any project sponsor that prepared an environmental impact statement under the supervision of the lead agency, and contractors; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A6BA17846BA446AB1F8BC43059701DE" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the timelines to complete environmental impact statements pursuant to section 102(2)(C) during the period of 10 years that ends on June 1 of the current year, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H6ED0C86FA55542C38149162ABCC5BAC9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to each major Federal action commenced during such period of 10 years, the date on which (as applicable)—</text><clause id="HE10EAC1A6B114C63BC32B050217B0B51" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the project sponsor submitted an application for any permit or other authorization for the project;</text></clause><clause id="HD2110C9D1FDE414E988CD09033D84BF2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the lead agency began the scoping;</text></clause><clause id="H54E0F1A01462457694748DC398164C98" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the notice of intent to prepare the environmental impact statement was made publicly available;</text></clause><clause id="H40218E10DE8E456595BFC52641445768" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the environmental impact statement was made publicly available;</text></clause><clause id="H1EAC0604BAA64DF883FD9E37B9074A6D" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the record of decision was made publicly available; and</text></clause><clause id="H3CC840BE65214F97A49C0D102B60AD16" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the lead agency provided to the project sponsor notice to proceed on the project;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86171707CAFF4C368AE02832DDACF876" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average and median completion timelines during such period of 10 years for each document described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F879CB3289043419A26A282D34F605C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of trends in completion timelines during such period of 10 years for such documents compared to prior reports published by the Council on Environmental Quality; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H179B0AB0344142D8B64648B4CFA4AA57" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each report submitted under this section through 2033, a disaggregation of the data from before and after the date of the enactment of the Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2023.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B5AEDDCDC0D4A04AA0549FC90531AD4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication and submission of reports by the Council on Environmental Quality</header><paragraph id="HAEF1F7F15260471E843C59AA4C897E2F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Council on Environmental Qualify shall annually—</text><subparagraph id="HE031501EE04B41DEACEA26A2F03B4E46" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish the reports received under subsection (a) on the website of the Council on Environmental Quality; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58E549BBEE534245A253221C4827FAA6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit such reports to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40D274D2F06A43D8973110769204FEAF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion in other reports</header><text>The Council on Environmental Quality may carry out paragraph (1)(B) by including the reports received under subsection (a) in the report submitted under section 107(h).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H624B6AD4C6EF423A92E8AF74B9967461"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council on Environmental Quality shall publish with each report published under paragraph (1)(A) the underlying data used to prepare each such report and include any citations or other information necessary for the public to locate records related to the court proceedings for any civil action described in subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC19577383AE64AFA8999BE612C7CC01B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Format</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the information included in each report submitted to the Council on Environmental Quality under subsection (a) shall be disaggregated by covered sector.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7E4876D1F18B494AB64CB388A455D659"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Covered sector defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered sector</term> means any of the following sectors:</text><paragraph id="H8B3EEB90C5B64F529B991C6AD0D049D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Aviation and space.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE15DD54F178542A38B39924370B8207B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Broadband.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68811C8CBD5F4BE285E3A97DBA632983"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Carbon capture and sequestration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFA55A26BBFA44D880E24A9ECF525724"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Conventional energy production.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD8C135E66E84D6CB49DF94C3353982D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Electricity transmission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56B5FF3A759E455CAFE1D91F17CD1619"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Forestry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4749849928742A8A722351A6087046F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Information technology infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CC170C6DFBB4EB29394294891F5D764"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Manufacturing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF90510D8B5094A2FB7C4AB25CC301288"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Mining.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE537F0F5EE09415DBFAAA93BDA171821"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Pipelines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H402A4EC346174DA3A9948B8DC8C7C2FD"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Ports and waterways.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32FDAC1B82A74ED38D52783E75231908"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Renewable energy production.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F8D69378B0D4D2AB83EB1950C8D51D2"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Surface transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05E9CCCCCF2A41F3912EA2044C4368A5"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Water resources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E23C8145FE042C39E7604823A7F2351"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Any other sector as determined by the Council on Environmental Quality or lead agency.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

