<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26379-P03-D7-KF1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 S4685 IS: Ending Double Dealing Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4685</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260604">June 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the Department of Defense from contracting with consultancies providing services to certain foreign entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Double Dealing Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id42a2415347454b9eaa13221b82e6d7ab"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on contracting with certain consultancies</header><subsection id="id87fe5345a2cb40deadf41c9a527312b7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id94c8fd72b6d84a46a372c02ecf2c1449"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The reliance by the Department of Defense on consultants for mission support services can create potential organizational conflicts of interest related to national security matters due to competing interests as a result of business relationships with foreign adversarial nations and entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc58e8221ca5f48508f0e8d61a7c48484"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It is imperative for consultants providing mission support services to the Department of Defense related to national security matters and foreign policy interests to not be providing mission support services to foreign adversaries regarding efforts counter to the national security and foreign policy interests of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e02bdf4a7fd499ea4bf857a1241f48b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Protecting against organizational conflicts of interest related to foreign adversarial nations and entities providing Federal mission support services is essential to the national security and foreign policy interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id300f0eb44bd946729dbec797ebdeba33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition related to certain contracts or grants</header><paragraph id="idf2d2235494914f788013831e98f43869"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may not after the date of the enactment of this Act enter into, renew, extend a contract with, award a grant to, enter into an other transactional agreement with, or otherwise effectuate any legal instrument resulting in any financial benefit accruing to, a covered consultancy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a10788352fd44c28e1dbdb1cc0c10eb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Any individual or entity that submits an offer or bid to provide consulting services to the Department of Defense shall disclose in such offer or bid any information relevant to the individual or entity with respect to the prohibition under paragraph (1), including—</text><subparagraph id="id454fd01f73fb4121966f72412bec5e44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the individual or entity has entered into a contract with, or received grants or other financial awards from, a covered entity in the five years prior to submitting the offer or bid; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa93eeb433f646b98b88fb98d8828aa0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at the time the contract to provide consulting services to the Department will be entered into, whether—</text><clause id="id93ba998202a04ecfbece212e320a2900"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any contract entered into by the individual or entity with a covered entity will still be in effect; or</text></clause><clause id="id0770e0297211470b92a69c098b647e40"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the individual or entity will be receiving funds from, or have any unobligated or unexpended funds received under, any grant or other financial award from a covered entity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idda7ece86dc8c4ab9b0910cddad6fba74"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties</header><subparagraph id="ide14cb7c9377e4d7fb098a37b4bbc3aa4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a contractor of the Department failed to make the disclosure required by paragraph (2), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="id478b9925085d47fd8fb08eeecf6c6e7e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>terminate the applicable contract for cause; and</text></clause><clause id="id06d056b3657a47adaf1bb82af976f217"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>initiate a suspension and debarment proceeding with respect to the contractor.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4c44e394741d4eaebefa2bb1fcda56e5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum length of debarment</header><text>The maximum length of a debarment of a contractor pursuant to this paragraph shall be a period of 5 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1fa803f841364f56ae78e8bd9c3f3feb"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><paragraph id="id925e880ce3294e0791c1e67fa22105d5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After a determination by the Secretary that a company is a covered consultancy, such company may submit to the Secretary a written and signed certification that—</text><subparagraph id="idd9be6794525945c7b867f345c0654295"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the consultancy no longer is—</text><clause id="id53114bcd898a4b908fd0aca081a29907"><enum>(i)</enum><text>performing under a contract with a covered entity;</text></clause><clause id="idc53f65c2ab294674afaf5af074e7719c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>carrying out activities under a grant received from a covered entity; or</text></clause><clause id="id711ffe2ad1984a05b87db50cdddb9f54"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>receiving funds, or has any unobligated or unexpended funds received, from a covered entity; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc2c4fdddf902474c8cf31228508c7d48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will not enter into, accept, or pursue a contract with a covered entity or a grant or other financial award from a covered entity—</text><clause id="idba1ed95dc32f4ba1b76c65fc8373033d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>during the term of a contract with the Department of Defense; or</text></clause><clause id="id54ab9ee768bb4316bf6867a9df0369fb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>while receiving funds from the Department of Defense, or obligating or expending any such funds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9bd8852927c74d6ea41b28e11ccde767"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Status change</header><text>Upon the approval by the Secretary of a certification submitted under paragraph (1), a company is deemed to not be a covered consultancy for the purposes of this section until the expiration of the certification under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2afeee5fe3b24fc7af2da78e6384b1f5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expiration</header><text>A certification submitted by a company under paragraph (1) shall expire on the earlier of the date on which the company, after submitting such certification, enters into, extends, renews, or performs under a contract with a covered entity for consulting services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id13e5c8ed47f341c9a0ac8c81ac7e76c0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Policies and guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue the following policies and practices:</text><paragraph id="id3a5c768cb0de4b30aea6596322709680"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Policies to implement the prohibition under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc69ae487603745b591f382df625fc8af"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Best practices for consultancies to avoid becoming covered consultancies under this section and for covered consultancies to end their status as such.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0c90f77ace64d95934f32a543af353c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A policy articulating the exact provisions and terms to be included in solicitations, contracts, and grants of the Department of Defense pursuant to paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0ac85740cb2344ddb2a0fed005e74560"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Revision of Department of Defense acquisition regulation</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement to implement this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id69310ba3e81a46ff900e59b5e589a9a5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id828eef426bd840a19b9889882f4140fc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consulting services</header><text>The term <term>consulting services</term> has the meaning given the term <term>advisory and assistance services</term> in section 2.101 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation, except that—</text><subparagraph id="id26fd4f55e0cf4832971779f68184747c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term does not include the services described in paragraph (3) of such section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee4f7fc724074e1aa8005450887268ce"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each instance of the term <term>Federal</term> is replaced with <term>client</term>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ca24da7c6a84e24a4b05fda0411369f" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contract employee</header><text>The term <term>contract employee</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id7da5259dd75d4552858bcc0a0c47ad02" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employee of a contractor; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4eff928f9fb843a7974c1a855f04d99c" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a contractor who is an individual who directly enters into a contract with the Federal Government, that individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id35d92bac3e4b46d49b42d939b5e77db9" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contractor</header><text>The term <term>contractor</term> has the meaning given the term in section 7101 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1207429e381f4137b5a60f3df054d508"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered consultancy</header><text>The term <term>covered consultancy</term> means a company that, itself or any subsidiary or affiliate thereof, in the later of the five-year period preceding the date of the relevant requirement or the effective date of the relevant requirement—</text><subparagraph id="idf30aab8a57e84fff93ae2ef1e965fd7f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>failed to disclose information to the Secretary related to any activities involving a covered entity as required by any law, regulation, or contract term, or terms of other agreements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5735fb127fae441fb97373a967ea6d7c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was found to have submitted false or misleading information to any Federal agency in any Federal proceeding; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6e6b730213141e89b4cb2cc7b397227"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was found to have failed to disclose an actual or potential conflict of interest as required by any law, regulation, or contract term to any Federal agency or in any Federal proceeding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id87832f0aec8347aab2211e90d5ca485e"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id83e1e7ff94524e428be8a362aa1799f3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide7e56ef97ccc49c4bca1fed976b62977"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Chinese Communist Party.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17773255ec31470c985decc414cd3e9b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The People’s Liberation Army, the Ministry of State Security, or any security service or intelligence agency of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a12ac0592664c4daa4bb02681e10a20"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any entity on the Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List (NS–CMIC–List) maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury under Executive Order 14032 (86 Fed. Reg. 30145; relating to addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People’s Republic of China), or any successor order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida0202e6bed1d4fdb94ec22e46bfab768"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any Chinese military company identified by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to section 1237(b) of the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/261">Public Law 105–261</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddb7f7a93052d43d9a14cfc2b9dc693e9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any entity owned (25 percent or more) or controlled, directly or indirectly, by the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party, including through board representation, voting rights, contractual arrangements, or other means of effective control, that is engaged in one or more national security industries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf744c073add44473926785befe59977b"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Government of the Russian Federation, any entity owned (25 percent or more) or controlled, directly or indirectly by the Russian Federation, or any entity sanctioned by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd3b46f81bfe84a0b82ebaafd983e3030"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The government or any State-owned entity of any country if the Secretary of State determines that such government has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism pursuant to—</text><clause id="idaa60b35d0f884fc2a3ac82536e03f903"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 1754(c)(1)(A) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="id972369cdf0944c3481cb0ff5db313c7a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="id26ebd1e0d7b64af7b13dcb77251080ed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="idf82b9e24dde1459882a86e47e345d85f"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide62e4b567dc4429eaf929756392f44fa"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Any entity included on any of the following lists maintained by the Department of Commerce:</text><clause id="idfc68c4c574ac45118de2930bd1f6af7c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Entity List set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of the Export Administration Regulations.</text></clause><clause id="idd43f587700e94898afc1e5a4f85a483a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Denied Persons List as described in section 764.3(a)(2) of the Export Administration Regulations.</text></clause><clause id="id9788c966410c44f593ba7b8f546c00e0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Unverified List set forth in Supplement No. 6 to part 744 of the Export Administration Regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfc2632d495c14aa39944b381d2255d92"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The Military End User List set forth in Supplement No. 7 to part 744 of the Export Administration Regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf8998d098d9e479abbd4d4c3b26da7bb"><enum>(K)</enum><text>A foreign adversary, as that term is defined in this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59662409a52747b494c12028580b5d47"><enum>(L)</enum><text>An individual or entity included on any sanctions list administered by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury or of the Department of Justice, including any successor list.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id87e3f9f730a1444cbb6ac8da0e23097a"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Export administration regulations</header><text>The term <term>Export Administration Regulations</term> means the regulations set forth in subchapter C of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf20f540e31e04f09a5c68ef5ae4988ca"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Foreign adversary</header><text>The term <term>foreign adversary</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="id2c071db7ce5641adb01c0b0281ea9ba7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Democratic People’s Republic of North Korea.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf3a8eaa424b44c49817171821e1ba10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id82361be95bde4e0c80aec6173ac95ebe"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Russian Federation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideaf218f95eae47cbb9c8cc392bdb2dab"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2213298d1f84b27b8ec4c74f18b4700"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Republic of Cuba.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65be854adbb94f3fa51d815aca5932f1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Venezuelan politician Nicolás Maduro (the Maduro Regime).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b8bc86dcce94ae9993ee4323a209b66"><enum>(8)</enum><header>National security industry</header><text>The term <term>national security industry</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id1f98d793157e4d55994c04b99789751b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a military-related industry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1e68fa76b2040039534256e65bbfa56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>semiconductor production;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca262d0d56c14630b0f484771421c25d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>researching or commercializing quantum computing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide66115d052214afab024dd419deb4a11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developing artificial intelligence products or services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f69da5ea1ec4fa1b73896aeff753709"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the biotechnology industry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id545f67282c5940eaaa817ddbd4baeefa"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the cybersecurity industry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58f39b118ff9496d9d5ba00c30e7780c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the mining, processing, or refining of critical minerals (as such term is defined in section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>)) for use by a covered entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3615b4554c8c40c18a651efe13c1a63a"> <enum>(H)</enum> <text>other emerging technologies (as that term is defined in section 6701 of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3024">50 U.S.C. 3024</external-xref> note)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id08142e6590de4cbfa6433780186d1473"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

