<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL25A47-8SC-6C-85S"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3228 IS: Stop the Importation and Manufacturing of Synthetic Analogues Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3228</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Controlled Substances Act to clarify how controlled substance analogues that are imported or offered for import are to be regulated, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD36087320A224957854A22A18212B763"><section section-type="section-one" id="H26E1AF1FBFEA488E842A9F77A42E12D4"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HE9D945B77C3D4415AE800E7C9773FB5F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop the Importation and Manufacturing of Synthetic Analogues Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SIMSA Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7BDA88409F6445DEB096206CA9A0023B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H26E1AF1FBFEA488E842A9F77A42E12D4">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HCC42D9ED0E604BC3B18B5E64907C47A1">Sec. 2. Establishment of Schedule A.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H6BB061D622AD4A388C60D88BAF55326E">Sec. 3. Temporary and permanent scheduling of schedule A substances.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA338E8D1232547B09DE33539172218EF">Sec. 4. Penalties.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H206FE801EF0345D791622A23E5B1BA62">Sec. 5. False labeling of schedule A controlled substances.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H0AAC2189B8F04741B42399074439F4DC">Sec. 6. Registration requirements for schedule A substances.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H148938E42C5A49B78A70F6B1ECD87F7A">Sec. 7. Additional conforming amendments.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id887089D424364787850C92C7FF6D4F16">Sec. 8. Sentencing review.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H98910A4932584BE9874DEFE3841DF209">Sec. 9. Rules of construction.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HCC42D9ED0E604BC3B18B5E64907C47A1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Schedule A</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8AB505381D994ED4BA61145150F5F673"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>five schedules of controlled substances, to be known as schedules I, II, III, IV, and V</quote> and inserting <quote>six schedules of controlled substances, to be known as schedules I, II, III, IV, V, and A</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2772856A141E4EA79954D0944F4ED4D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD5CDC330D2041D9AA63D5AFA405435C"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1782107E06EE4B8F962AB87CDDD3F387" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Schedule A</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7E4193853BE4530A6B8ACE9C5D19E6D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The drug or substance—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B7A0F60A52F44488079D90582FC00A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is or has been imported, or is offered for import, into the United States;</text></clause><clause id="HA86680DCE26447DE8A39684B49B3C167"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCDC2F616E664462951D479BB74C034D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a chemical structure that is substantially similar to the chemical structure of a controlled substance in schedule I, II, III, IV, or V; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EF1AE64089B4E7FA391C7E8F5ACC78B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an actual or predicted stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system that is substantially similar to or greater than the stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system of a controlled substance in schedule I, II, III, IV, or V; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21E05BDFE2DC4448A1DA9350F59EA7C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not listed or otherwise included in any other schedule in this section or by regulation of the Attorney General.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C31B619E69140EEB4D00034C8A670FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Predicted stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect</header><text>For purpose of this paragraph, a predicted stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system may be based on—</text><clause id="H6D4EDA3307924AC8A7043C33EBA17B48"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4B093011E02B414E953507774FF21D47"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the chemical structure; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6297D1CFBB0443FCAB8195C649B90B07" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8FD84C7CB2CD4D83B049AA8CD38253CB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the structure activity relationships; or</text></item><item id="H1F1F1FB0FBDB4025A7ECF2E1D60310D7" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>binding receptor assays and other relevant scientific information about the substance;</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H13E86209C8254982830B4B9539FB4839"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2A5DCB19391A42928BB1D38027F4C7FC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the current or relative potential for abuse of the substance; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HFC0087E06A114C21B28BF2CE395E77F1" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the clandestine importation, manufacture, or distribution, or diversion from legitimate channels, of the substance; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H661D3229218742DB9D5F846F2E8CF9B2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the capacity of the substance to cause a state of dependence, including physical or psychological dependence that is similar to or greater than that of a controlled substance in schedule I, II, III, IV, or V.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1A9CE77DA084D9683B1307FEAE2D1FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HA5E41F61C1D941FCA634FCBC9EE13619"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding schedule I, by striking <quote>IV, and V</quote> and inserting <quote>IV, V, and A</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCF4402B45F64DF6AF27F0EE5D44BF6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5EC61E2CCDB41C6AB9FB114143ADA87"><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2409C7D87AF04A2A991F16ADDC8F1650"><header>Schedule A</header><text>Any substance temporarily or permanently scheduled by the Attorney General in accordance with section 201(k).</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H6BB061D622AD4A388C60D88BAF55326E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Temporary and permanent scheduling of schedule A substances</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A96D4281C2543EC9EE2E01CB90519BB"><subsection id="HACF31B9FB7F54C36A92559FC43C45C20"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Temporary and permanent scheduling of schedule A substances</header><paragraph id="H06E1738950D34988ACF952475D4DD492"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may issue a temporary order adding a drug or substance to schedule A if the Attorney General finds that—</text><subparagraph id="H299BA5C723AB44B49A77E3E576B2BEB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the drug or other substance satisfies the criteria for being considered a schedule A substance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9149D9A65A8460BAB59829AB728476D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adding such drug or substance to schedule A will assist in preventing abuse of the drug or other substance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12F2E8FF10734E77A3225D3E0535098B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration of temporary scheduling order</header><text>A temporary scheduling order issued under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H0D59138D7DF740468535FEE471DDAAC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not take effect until 30 days after the date of the publication by the Attorney General of a notice in the Federal Register of the intention to issue such order and the grounds upon which such order is to be issued; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8FCA72B329B4EF1BF3B217BFEF004EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expire not later than 5 years after the date on which the order becomes effective, except that the Attorney General may, during the pendency of proceedings under paragraph (5), extend the temporary scheduling order for up to 180 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FC6EF5B4BBE4AC3A5819EA8142DF918"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of issuance of permanent scheduling order</header><text>A temporary scheduling order issued under paragraph (1) shall be vacated upon the issuance of a permanent order issued under paragraph (5) with regard to the same substance, or upon the subsequent issuance of any scheduling order under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9012674E21D14A19A57ABD822C8CE32E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on judicial review</header><text>A temporary scheduling order issued under paragraph (1) shall not be subject to judicial review.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D34F3F4405A431094D560D515EA7BCB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Permanent scheduling order</header><subparagraph id="HC72F055DCB3E4D26BFEB188F1ECC8FA1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), not earlier than 3 years after the date on which the Attorney General issues an order temporarily scheduling a drug or substance under this subsection, the Attorney General may, by rule, issue a permanent order adding the drug or other substance to schedule A if such drug or substance satisfies the criteria for being considered a schedule A substance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB0BB69890D64B0C930518B2EA4ACBDD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>If the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Attorney General, has determined, based on relevant scientific studies and necessary data gathered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and gathered by the Attorney General, that a drug or other substance that has been temporarily placed in schedule A does not have sufficient potential for abuse to warrant control in any schedule, and provides a 30-day written notice of such determination to the Attorney General, the Attorney General—</text><clause id="H3331D3ACF6874C27AE81146B7D5FF21D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not issue a permanent scheduling order under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="H34AAEAA7F7D5404FAFEEF493ED5E0C15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date on which the Attorney General receives such notice, shall issue an order immediately terminating the temporary scheduling order for the drug or other substance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H038CF9F66EB940E1AA88AB7CD486AC02"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Notice to HHS</header><text>Before initiating proceedings under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall transmit notice of a temporary order proposed to be issued to the Secretary of Health and Human Services. In issuing an order under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall take into consideration any comments submitted by the Secretary of Health and Human Services in response to a notice transmitted pursuant to this paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" id="HA338E8D1232547B09DE33539172218EF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1010 of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/960">21 U.S.C. 960</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H5CD18F5ABE3543DFBDFFDD0D333C4047"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>or a drug or substance in schedule A</quote> after <quote>controlled substance</quote> each place it appears; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4590C02998FC4C268D429BBF2629C3AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H016B57879387409A8FF0D1977BFE71A7"><paragraph id="H899F330BCDFD4DB5A3ACEF5EC0461BBD" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In the case of a violation under subsection (a) involving a controlled substance in schedule A, the person committing such violation shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not more than 20 years and if death or serious bodily injury results from the use of such substance shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment for any term of years or for life, a fine not to exceed the greater of that authorized in accordance with the provisions of title 18, United States Code, or $1,000,000 if the defendant is an individual or $5,000,000 if the defendant is other than an individual, or both. If any person commits such a violation after a prior conviction for a felony drug offense has become final, such person shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment of not more than 30 years and if death or serious bodily injury results from the use of such substance shall be sentenced to a term of imprisonment for any term of years or for life, a fine not to exceed the greater of twice that authorized in accordance with the provisions of title 18, United States Code, or $2,000,000 if the defendant is an individual or $10,000,000 if the defendant is other than an individual, or both. Notwithstanding section 3583 of title 18, United States Code, any sentence imposing a term of imprisonment under this paragraph shall, in the absence of such a prior conviction, impose a term of supervised release of not less than 3 years in addition to such term of imprisonment and shall, if there was such a prior conviction, impose a term of supervised release of not less than 6 years in addition to such term of imprisonment. Notwithstanding the prior sentence, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the court shall not place on probation or suspend the sentence of any person sentenced under the provisions of this paragraph which provide for a mandatory term of imprisonment if death or serious bodily injury results.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H206FE801EF0345D791622A23E5B1BA62"><enum>5.</enum><header>False labeling of schedule A controlled substances</header><subsection id="H7073CADDA13F42A79C921ED3BE54F326"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 305 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/825">21 U.S.C. 825</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA109966BF5D4B7B8F470E6DEC5B9545"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2405CED87304487966156486996D0F0"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">False labeling of schedule A controlled substances</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H797FBE8D69004E419B3CC70BF7470B4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful to import or export, with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense, a schedule A substance or product containing a schedule A substance, unless the substance or product bears a label clearly identifying a schedule A substance or product containing a schedule A substance by the nomenclature used by the International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry (IUPAC).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBDABC4FCB5847D2AA642729B2BF89E9"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBC04C48F21654E12B76FD8F01897371B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A product described in subparagraph (B) is exempt from the International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry nomenclature requirement of this subsection if such product is labeled in the manner required under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H121EEEA18E044D288B387D2A258FC256" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A product is described in this subparagraph if the product—</text><clause commented="no" id="H62447D3BBDC84BDDB6FEA95A4285D63E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is the subject of an approved application as described in section 505(b) or (j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H5E7978A9C5B34746BDA8F0B4BAA73E64"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is exempt from the provisions of section 505 of such Act relating to new drugs because—</text><subclause commented="no" id="HE4FF9F0974EA4B73B49799EAB771ACC2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>it is intended solely for investigational use as described in section 505(i) of such Act; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H6A8CC9E8BF22498F8F5136E23219F242"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such product is being used exclusively for purposes of a clinical trial that is the subject of an effective investigational new drug application.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA082741D5E01495EB18E39CB91470161"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Section 402 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/842">21 U.S.C. 842</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HFEC00C3CC6644D618AC7B274141B9330"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="idAE9D97A35B584A24B62F1AB950C73F55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (16), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66A24572A2454F41ABB9AD32310C6DFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (17) as paragraph (18); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id82B79082E48246D79BD26932CA825777"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (16) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id946EF6903F8E4BA1802F0B038313A67D"><paragraph id="id6036D006CFAB4DA2BE0D2F130B07E073" indent="up1"><enum>(17)</enum><text>to violate section 305(f); or</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF37828881B4E42C5B26C0BA1F4EA1C7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAF404AC00EA64E0E8A7D855A07085F4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id538EA1DC845541409DFF0095B3651812"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i), by striking <quote>(17)</quote> and inserting <quote>(18)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2B8A860227C74731BB38B45CABE99A8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote>or (17)</quote> after <quote>paragraph (16)</quote> each place it appears; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id36FA3F10C0E84ADCA5EC16B6DF5A0D34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(D), by striking <quote>(17)</quote> and inserting <quote>(18)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0AAC2189B8F04741B42399074439F4DC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Registration requirements for schedule A substances</header><subsection id="idB41E00F4856942F8B2E4D16454F797C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Registration requirements for importers and exporters of schedule A substances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1008 of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/958">21 U.S.C. 958</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5DC44A11B1E43A2A916D74D774B98C9"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H658BDBEF6F7543C897D3D993AEA2723D"><enum>(j)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H108426AAF2E448378A398935987E43ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall register an applicant to import or export a schedule A substance if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03CA732599FC426B8FF2AE2C5B0756DF" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicant demonstrates that the schedule A substance will be used for research, analytical, or industrial purposes approved by the Attorney General; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C6708D44E0742DABA76A29EF891D63A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Attorney General determines that such registration is consistent with the public interest and with the United States obligations under international treaties, conventions, or protocols in effect on the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25DA1D70510C4EDCA3778C9C3D11730D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the public interest under paragraph (1)(B), the Attorney General shall consider—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H10BD02C397C54B8EA37BBB8A8B3BECA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintenance of effective controls against diversion of particular controlled substances and any controlled substance in schedule A compounded therefrom into other than legitimate medical, scientific, research, or industrial channels, by limiting the importation and bulk manufacture of such controlled substances to a number of establishments which can produce an adequate and uninterrupted supply of these substances under adequately competitive conditions for legitimate medical, scientific, research, and industrial purposes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC1DE97575A074B828F3CFD2EAF43DD37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compliance with applicable State and local law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H83E178439F8A4DF393A1550FAFCFFCEE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promotion of technical advances in the art of manufacturing substances described in subparagraph (A) and the development of new substances;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0FF222DC0CBD45AFB023288A0694C733"><enum>(D)</enum><text>prior conviction record of applicant under Federal and State laws relating to the importation, manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of substances described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC1523E7FDB764963B12C0F83E3CDB9BA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>past experience in the importation and manufacture of controlled substances, and the existence in the establishment of effective control against diversion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7023BDE288E24352909446D872A6D0D6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other factors as may be relevant to and consistent with the public health and safety.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD540C445BF1F440E955738716D36988D" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If an applicant is registered to import or export a controlled substance in schedule I or II under subsection (a), the applicant shall not be required to apply for a separate registration under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="ide2e95f33ceb04846abe1b24da032b0fc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research on substances newly added to schedule A</header><text>Section 302(e) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/822">21 U.S.C. 822(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEEE2CEE876FF497086F598AA5512DF92"><paragraph id="id59e1153c531a43939a5da58dd9bacb47" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5062b7dddb694e12a9fd0dbe30e7853d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If a person is conducting research on a substance at the time the substance is added to schedule A, and such person, subject to an exemption that is in effect for investigational use, for that person, under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) to the extent conduct with respect to such substance is pursuant to such exemption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id6AA606ADE0834411B7BA8783D2B66051"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Continuation of research on substances newly added to schedule A</header><text>Section 302(e) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/822">21 U.S.C. 822(e)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b) of this section, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8A3AAA651A44400D958BFA2BF64217D8"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up2" id="id64718c6006e24c2091b98e9961b8e7e6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a person is conducting research on a substance at the time the substance is added to schedule A, and such person is already registered to conduct research with a controlled substance in schedule I or II, then—</text><clause id="idEA517C137FB34A03A23F056BEA368147"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the person shall, within 30 days of the scheduling of the newly-scheduled substance, submit a completed application for registration or modification of existing registration, to conduct research on such substance, in accordance with the regulations issued by the Attorney General;</text></clause><clause id="id0DBE59C309594026B543F8889B53D58F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the person may continue to conduct the research on such substance until the application described in clause (i) is withdrawn by the applicant or until the Attorney General serves on the applicant an order to show cause proposing the denial of the application pursuant to section 304(c); and</text></clause><clause id="id65F6CA89E89F4803BB908AF3BA71A42F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the Attorney General serves order to show cause under clause (ii) and the applicant requests a hearing, such hearing shall be held on an expedited basis and not later than 45 days after the request is made, except that the hearing may be held at a later time if so requested by the applicant.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up2" id="idFA0CE2FB197442E4BA4D5802D9D64B19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A person who is registered to conduct research with a controlled substance in schedule A may conduct research with another controlled substance in schedule I, only if—</text><clause id="id94A74A18D704400BB5495084DD0C0059"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the person has applied for a modification of the person's registration to authorize research with such other controlled substance in accordance with the regulations issued by the Attorney General;</text></clause><clause id="id0B3F012F07D54B4A910BAB593F138FBE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Attorney General has obtained verification from the Secretary that the research protocol submitted with the application is meritorious; and</text></clause><clause id="idF69B6A0DAC03458887BF3CBE5CFAA448"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Attorney General has determined, not later than 30 days after receiving the application described in clause (i), that such activity is consistent with United States obligations under the Single Convention on Narcotic Drugs, 1961.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up2" id="id2CA6021938C34DA6AE7B1A678E240E79"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to alter the authority of the Attorney General to initiate proceedings to deny, suspend, or revoke any registration in accordance with sections 303 and 304.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H148938E42C5A49B78A70F6B1ECD87F7A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Additional conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/951">21 U.S.C. 951 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H670CA7E3A3894E84A6214D025C7D9AC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1002(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/952">21 U.S.C. 952(a)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H9B791C7815D2441195FB2B222DCDB67F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or drug or substance in schedule A</quote> after <quote>schedule I or II</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7927696CB37E4F6A9F3E86B08BB6C296"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or drug or substances in schedule A</quote> after <quote>schedule I or II</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8C44812A5E74C1DB35B675538513A91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 1003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/953">21 U.S.C. 953</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HEF520B17DF5C4483B924E966A219C68D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or drug or substance in schedule A</quote> after <quote>schedule I or II</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65CDE432FA4F4913AB1222E3593F54C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by inserting <quote>or drug or substance in schedule A</quote> after <quote>schedule I or II</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65183462BCE14B9E9B2128881A0D7112"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 1004(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/954">21 U.S.C. 954(1)</external-xref>), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or drug or substance in schedule A</quote> after <quote>schedule I</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F45EC8C213A486B8D9965BD08DF8200"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 1005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/955">21 U.S.C. 955</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>or drug or substance in schedule A</quote> after <quote>schedule I or II</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H623882C0DA274DEAB09E9EE371259FB6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 1009(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/959">21 U.S.C. 959(a)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>or drug or substance in schedule A</quote> after <quote>schedule I or II</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id887089D424364787850C92C7FF6D4F16"><enum>8.</enum><header>Sentencing review</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77C3BF082DBC4D66B2529774CDF45986"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Covered offense defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered offense</term> means an offense involving a schedule A substance for which the penalty was established under section 4 or 5 of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5CDF5E10B55B47B395175FBB0DE1D0F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sentencing review</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEBE5E35928D84EB5860B48DD5662A745"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Petition for review</header><text>If a schedule A substance that is temporarily or permanently scheduled under section 201(k) of the Controlled Substances Act, as added by this Act, is subsequently descheduled or rescheduled on a schedule with lower penalties, any individual convicted of a covered offense involving such schedule A substance who is awaiting sentencing or is still serving a term of imprisonment for such covered offense on the date of the descheduling or rescheduling may petition the court that imposed the sentence for a sentencing reduction hearing for such covered offense.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD9BF25ECFC1A4CE5B7848CE39E79376B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sentencing review</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a petition is filed under paragraph (1), the court shall conduct a sentencing reduction hearing and may modify the sentence of the petitioner as if the descheduling or rescheduling described in paragraph (1) had been in effect on the date the covered offense was committed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H98910A4932584BE9874DEFE3841DF209"><enum>9.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, may be construed to limit—</text><paragraph id="H787304E76930419BAD5E5D55944CD2BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the prosecution of offenses involving controlled substance analogues under the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6614685D239746A38BCC37990148C629"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the authority of the Attorney General to temporarily or permanently schedule, reschedule, or decontrol controlled substances under provisions of section 201 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/811">21 U.S.C. 811</external-xref>) that are in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

