<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4C85BF7B99B0443692FB805ED94B20F0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8754 IH: No Delay for Immigration Oversight Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8754</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security and any entity that contracts with the Department of Homeland Security to grant access to Members of Congress to covered facilities to carry out oversight responsibilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC2ACF3657E434CA3A33AEA68B2647145" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H20C296AF38E44F9EA407F94205CD0F09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Delay for Immigration Oversight Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H867DA28D3EC9459DA3FC43D5EDDA2135"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HD3DE928409FB4BB6B8D7CBEEBA1D47B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Oversight by Members of Congress is a core constitutional responsibility necessary to ensure transparency, accountability, and compliance with Federal law within executive branch agencies and facilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5A4FE0851AB4233AA8D5E64B3452975"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Since at least 2019, Federal law has prohibited the Department of Homeland Security and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement from preventing Members of Congress from entering, for the purpose of conducting oversight, any facility operated by or for the Department used to detain or otherwise house aliens.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB4F9E0B125A146549B50822A9A9128F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recent actions and policies by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement have attempted to limit, delay, or undermine the ability of Members of Congress to carry out lawful oversight of immigration detention facilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B68B5D76F454575A24160150C392D54"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Congressional access to immigration detention facilities is necessary to ensure the humane treatment of detainees, the protection of civil rights and civil liberties, and compliance with Federal law and detention standards.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H29D3873572504688AAE92CCDB9E7781F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Congress has a continuing interest in reaffirming and permanently protecting the oversight authority of Members of Congress with respect to immigration detention facilities.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H80D456A09272437B95CD2573C0B7544D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Members of Congress access to covered facilities</header> <subsection id="H9A80DE7415C74B1E878C50BD06C507E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall grant Members of Congress, without delay and without obstruction, access to covered facilities to carry out oversight responsibilities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B30C570535745ADBF5DE1AEFC6C64BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to Federal contractors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure compliance with subsection (a) by any entity, including any employee or representative of such entity, that contracts with the Department of Homeland Security for a covered facility with the requirements of subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD8B1519803BD4F9990BC1F178AA24623"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification of requirements</header><text>Each entity that contracts with the Department of Homeland Security for the use of a covered facility shall certify, in the process of contracting with the Department, that all personnel of such entity are trained on the requirements of subsections (a) and (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4BBF6AC6E8554A5E83DA911BBE466C95"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalty for noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, in the determination of the inspector general of the Department of Homeland Security, an entity does not comply with the requirements of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall cancel any agreement or contract between the Department and such entity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7A1B53FA6BA8463E810611087208A6DD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to require a Member of Congress to provide prior notice of the intent to enter a covered facility for the purpose of conducting oversight.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0F1E412D52444A6843EEDADD712F869"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H1B14221BDB284098987E19ABFC1521EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Congressional identification</header><text>The term <quote>congressional identification</quote> means any form of identification issued to Members by the Clerk or Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives (in the case of a Member of the House of Representatives) or by the Secretary or Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate (in the case of a Senator).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED7F72E2CC8D440284DFFF17D655F0D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered facility</quote> means any facility operated by or for the Department of Homeland Security used to detain or otherwise house aliens.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5C65CABD8514548A6690CF5787E41D7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Member of congress</header><text>The term <quote>Member of Congress</quote> means a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H597085D490714C79BAE57BE91CB2AD12"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Without delay</header><text>The term <quote>without delay</quote> means the immediate admission to a covered facility without waiting outside such facility.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

