<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HED311A91CAB7457CB5C0E7DD924FBEC4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8793 IH: Veterans Suicide Prevention and Care Enhancement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8793</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260513">May 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a list of covered providers that complete annual training on the prevention of suicide among veterans and to make such list available to veterans.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC7EF19C4FDE044ECBD4A941665706CB4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0AC8970464BD4CBEB616C132026B0207" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Suicide Prevention and Care Enhancement Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H9B7E276599344CFA8358B49317B8AF59"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of preferred provider list for veterans community care program of the department of veterans affairs</header>
<subsection id="H10D7EEBF4A4F42ECA76D139E03DA940A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make available to covered providers annual, evidence-based training on the prevention of suicide among veterans.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3F6986B6F88F4658B11220610013603D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preferred provider list</header> <paragraph id="H8073155990534241A928FCEDAED02B23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H107A7DBB8E0647138B11D6A77043FC66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish and maintain a list (to be known as the <quote>preferred provider list</quote>) of each covered provider that completes the training under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B183563B8224D968928494CB8EC26AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such list publicly available to veterans eligible for health care under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5E4E95584C0A4227BBD063635872A90A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-department training</header><text>The Secretary shall include on the preferred provider list any covered provider that the Secretary determines has completed training that—</text> <subparagraph id="HAAB1BD27704547819905C75E94B159DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is substantially similar to the training required by such subsection; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0FB6416A7C9A47F69D7251EA04F5716F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meets the applicable competency standard for military health care professionals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C28D9DD22C544B6B434CB8EBF5223BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Opt-out</header><text>A covered provider desiring to be removed from the preferred provider list may submit to the Secretary a request in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDEDC1D26A4B3473E96F0787F0A29F7CA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Annual review</header><text>The Secretary shall, on an annual basis, review the preferred provider list to ensure each covered provider included on such list has completed such training.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA9BAEFFDAA634557B3938C71B2436315"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered provider defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered provider</quote> means—</text>
<paragraph id="H4278569E175246FA8049DF81DB180385"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a health care provider specified in subsection (c) of section 1703 of title 38, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81A22C9AFEC64DDDB52D62D51707624B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an eligible entity or medical provider that has entered into a Veterans Care Agreement under section 1703A of such title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H6321EE4800384D4CB154689E2D1E4F75"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header>
<subsection id="HBF0E4051363D46A3A460BB003833A7E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the day of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD50DF0DFDD314DD9B2625B131759861A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of providers who completed the VA-offered suicide prevention training prior to the implementation of the Preferred Provider List outline in Sec. 2(b).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCA3EE321106F4A31B3212FBC675B9299"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of Community Care Network providers who completed a different suicide prevention training not offered by the VA prior to the implementation of the Preferred Provider List.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F9C8770982E481CA6EE63639D0491BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of providers currently on the Preferred Provider List, bifurcated by those who utilized the VA-offered suicide prevention training and those providers who received the waiver outlined in Sec. 2(b)(2).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4ACBA354D8C044C3A8ABFEA666626B77"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The likelihood of veterans utilizing providers on the Preferred Provider List rather than a provider not found on the Preferred Provider List.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2849632301574C369796A26DE5FA561F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any patterns apparent to the Secretary based on the review of the implementation of the Preferred Provider List.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5AD1183A5F4A409F98100727F88A5EAF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any recommendations for further action that would improve and enhance the Preferred Provider List with the objective of increasing access to care for veterans.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2828102904EE475180D21D8007011E11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text>
<paragraph id="H665ABD66C2224436ABE0F34C736FE12E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CA9FF4ACC654B9E96A3B975F5B6A6C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

