<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WIL26207-FSX-PP-R8X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4377 IS: Climate Change Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4377</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to establish a Climate Change Education Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Climate Change Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idfbb1ea5237844345a6c6e5fdf1829052"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="idbf9fbf2ba94d4436a5830111fb658c70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The evidence for human-induced climate change is overwhelming and undeniable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04b623d1d08b4e1c945bdb0bdf67f171"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the Fifth National Climate Assessment, atmospheric carbon can be significantly reduced through conservation, by shifting to renewable energy sources such as solar, wind, tidal, and geothermal, and by increasing the efficiency of buildings, including domiciles, and transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id353cbd3ff79449f8885f8158c43d80f1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing clear information about climate change, in a variety of forms, can remove the fear and the sense of helplessness and encourage individuals and communities to take action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id36afcd26fa0442b48237deba83bc7164"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Implementation of measures that promote energy efficiency, conservation, and renewable energy will greatly reduce human impacts on the environment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide470133918bb4aa0aa21190f9484d504"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Informing people of new technologies and programs as they become available will ensure maximum understanding and maximum effect of those measures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idff4214ee582042bfba3b8aeca8ff5de0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>More than 3,500,000 students graduate from high schools and colleges in the United States each year, armed with attitudes, skills, and knowledge about the climate that inform their actions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idacc72701ed9f49fe81452943f0fe93d8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The effect on the climate, positive or negative, of each of those 3,500,000 students lasts beyond a lifetime.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id711440fa3bd640709a423175fe3ec615"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Those students need to be prepared to implement changes in professional and personal practices, to support and help develop new technology and policy, and to address the coming social and economic challenges and opportunities arising from a changing climate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id54c7f27cd15345ffabbadba6416b10cf"><enum>(9)</enum><text>It has been demonstrated that the people of the United States overwhelmingly support teaching students about the causes, consequences, and potential solutions to climate change in all 50 States and more than 3,000 counties across the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id479cd5b5c6464a53aa706269c2483759"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Only 30 percent of middle school science teachers and 45 percent of high school science teachers understand the extent of the scientific consensus on climate change.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id865a849573144500afa37b88daa71681"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Section 4002(a) of the America COMPETES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/893a">33 U.S.C. 893a(a)</external-xref>) requires the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to <quote>conduct, develop, support, promote, and coordinate formal and informal educational activities at all levels</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id904461671f524bd487cc6bc835e34f6a"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The existing Environmental Literacy Program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration was established in 2005 by the Bush administration as a backbone to an agency effort to advance sound environmental education for children and adults.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42875b54da04449b995424f77b4cb8b6"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Expanding the popular Environmental Literacy Program (less than 5 percent of applications in 2020 received funding) to include climate education for professional educators and students is within the established expertise of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and will effectively leverage critical resources for foundational learning and career preparation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idcbaaa66a9def4717aa9288031a2ea0f9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idbd3cf869ff544db6b27d90fd46c7e75a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Climate change education</header><text>The term <term>climate change education</term> means nonformal and formal interdisciplinary learning at all age levels about—</text><subparagraph id="id2186fae551ed4e09a013d056638603a8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>climate change, climate adaptation and mitigation, climate resilience, and climate justice; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id331c9054e31e4a2eb3b064e46b9ac1b2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effects of climate change, climate adaptation and mitigation, climate resilience, and climate justice on the environmental, energy, social, and economic systems of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBD9040D3489942CC983229114BA52BF0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Climate justice</header><text>The term <term>climate justice</term> means the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people, regardless of race, color, culture, national origin, or income, with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of policies and projects to ensure that each person enjoys the same degree of protection from the adverse effects of climate change.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40c2f90caf81467c982bd3680f57234c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Climate literacy</header><text>The term <term>climate literacy</term> means competence or knowledge of climate change, its causes and impacts, and the technical, scientific, economic, and social dynamics of promising solutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0654b5f5f254abe8d787a20aaede3b3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice</term> means the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people, regardless of race, color, culture, national origin, or income, with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws, regulations, and policies to ensure that each person enjoys—</text><subparagraph id="id3e13fddc36d84394953e057465e6fc4c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the same degree of protection from environmental and health hazards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida6604116499d40ee9560a3636d7c2c05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>equal access to any Federal agency action on environmental justice issues in order to have a healthy environment in which to live, learn, work, and recreate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4952bccec89043f181e8107f69074d93"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice community</term> means a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or Tribal and indigenous communities that experiences, or is at risk of experiencing, higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects as compared to other communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id500edbf764874ec7af4136d33283c6bb"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Green economy</header><text>The term <term>green economy</term> means an economy that results in improved human and economic well-being and social equity by significantly reducing environmental risks and ecological scarcities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id271e719a3d184125ac43d7d695b1009b"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60b97114b84d4198b251d4142fb7171a"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Local educational agency; State educational agency</header><text>The terms <term>local educational agency</term> and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide42a7066593c4df5afc90ac84bf4b678"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Nonformal</header><text>The term <term>nonformal</term> means, with respect to learning, out-of-school educational programming carried out by nonprofit organizations and public agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6cb52cd9f01346e6abe1daf7444045a8"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of that Code.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id2f5bc10456bb4ebd933459d2894f0dbf"><enum>4.</enum><header>Climate Change Education Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall establish a Climate Change Education Program within the Office of Education of the Administration to—</text><paragraph id="id1c8406ba54944c3f9cbfd04f7183fa4f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase the climate literacy of the United States by broadening the understanding of climate change, including possible long-term and short-term consequences, disproportionate impacts of those consequences, and potential solutions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc53e4d5ff4b5477ab8cdcfb584301956"><enum>(2)</enum><text>apply the latest scientific and technological discoveries, including through the use of the scientific assets of the Administration, to provide formal and nonformal learning opportunities to individuals of all ages, including individuals of diverse cultural and linguistic backgrounds; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf668a52721984bd4acec3a68d4e8bc04"><enum>(3)</enum><text>emphasize actionable information to help people understand and promote implementation of new technologies, jobs, career training, programs, and incentives related to climate change, climate adaptation and mitigation, climate resilience, climate justice, and environmental justice.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc9d68d74f9124a35833e8eb54413f4fd"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grants and cooperative agreements</header><subsection id="idabcc268d944f4016bc9db61c4b1c414f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, as part of the Climate Change Education Program established under section 4, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall establish a program to award grants to, or establish cooperative agreements with, the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id26db69f3dd9a489597350e3785636025"><enum>(1)</enum><text>State educational agencies, in partnership with local educational agencies and local nonprofit organizations, and, subject to subsection (c), local educational agencies—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5cba59832b0a4fc6a813d358d6d1b6f2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the development and implementation of aspects of climate literacy plans for grades 4 through 12 formal and nonformal climate change education that—</text><clause commented="no" id="idACB3E497755E40EC97C3B8EB66D975A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are aligned with State education standards; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idFFEA475FA65740E9BF6209A9752059BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that students graduate from high school with climate literacy; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3a470639c524bb5bf723da4bf8f891c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the implementation of projects that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49c3239bb5a34451b454f3fab1e37201"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of State educational agencies, include—</text><subclause id="id3bbd7929f7ef4742a673f20a00d21252"><enum>(I)</enum><text>relevant training and professional development for educators, which may include tiered mentorship frameworks;</text></subclause><subclause id="idb30f5652b7d94a2da396c29e9dc62551"><enum>(II)</enum><text>integration of key climate change concepts into State education standards for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM), civics and social studies, career and technical education, and other relevant subject areas during the next revision of such standards;</text></subclause><subclause id="id2dad7c3f534b46b6b4bc7fbfbce1b100"><enum>(III)</enum><text>development of climate change education frameworks and model curricula and curation and dissemination of existing such frameworks and curricula;</text></subclause><subclause id="ide022638c39fd40d1aa2a0835f9e5fbcd"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>creation of applied learning project-based models, particularly those that allow for student leadership in project development and applied field work, such as models making optimum use of green features improvements, such as low-cost environmental monitoring sensors, to school facilities such as energy systems, lighting systems, food systems, water management systems, waste management systems, and school grounds; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id905141ff2622415398e3e179ac62c55e"><enum>(V)</enum><text>incorporation of climate change mitigation and green technologies into new and existing high-quality career and technical education career pathways and work-based learning experiences in high-demand climate-related jobs, including development of partnerships with labor organizations, trade organizations, and apprenticeship programs; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id2ee7825192864b2da04d729e2ec1c297"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of local educational agencies—</text><subclause id="id0315f33c19684a2a8aeb344340c0390e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>develop, modify, or implement district-level plans to advance climate change education that consider facilities, curriculum, environmental health, professional development for educators, student experiences, and equity; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idc8c7b639af8c40b4bcbc67a5711dc30f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>support community partnerships among local educational agencies, nonformal education providers, community-based organizations, and other partners to advance climate change education priorities.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="ida3e3bb504cd141ccb89acb9f984eb12c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education and networks or partnerships of such institutions to engage teams of faculty and students to develop applied climate research and deliver to local communities direct services related to local climate mitigation and adaptation issues, with priority given to projects that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id080E8CF176484B4AB1801F03CD288F61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>foster long-term campus-community partnerships;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idE46E2631C689473F94E56FE0749D6459"><enum>(B)</enum><text>show potential to scale work beyond the term of the grant or cooperative agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida91da4cec0bc4cda8ab1f75ea68b636a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>involve significant student input in the project development process;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idE2373E18C3EF4A5F8E41BD87DE468AE2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are inclusive for all segments of the population; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idFACD5112D09F4657B00BD8D69E946D69"><enum>(E)</enum><text>promote equitable and just outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id988bc7fc98db4ac6a204645b1896c31e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Professional associations and academic disciplinary societies for projects that build capacity at the State and national levels for continuing education by practicing professionals and the general public in green economy fields.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idfbceca6a446445548dace6e15d8642af"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Youth corps organizations to engage in community-based climate mitigation and adaptation work that includes a substantive educational component.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4C357F0947EE45FD8143E05ABE6F93FD"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Communities of practice</header> <text>The Climate Change Education Program shall establish communities of practice with respect to each of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a) in order to accelerate learning.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6A5CF87B58A8496CBDF584382CE531D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Local educational agencies</header><text>The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration may not award a grant to, or establish a cooperative agreement with, a local educational agency in any fiscal year under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) unless amounts appropriated for grants and cooperative agreements under such subsection for that fiscal year exceed $5,000,000.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id9C4651E240F34E6C804973A8F822D5FC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Allocation of amounts</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idA74CACEEAB89483A94FE8F49F6ACEF95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), amounts appropriated for grants and cooperative agreements under subsection (a) shall be allocated as follows:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idF4DB0ABE22724658AFE07DA0B0EBB254"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent for grants and cooperative agreements under paragraph (1) of such subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idAA9718A0B9234629B7C3713E452A45B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">30 percent for grants and cooperative agreements under paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idCED071AF9EC245A093AC3EBE3619454D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">10 percent for grants and cooperative agreements under paragraph (3) of such subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id46EF9E2506104B5A9157F7E055639A36"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">10 percent for grants and cooperative agreements under paragraph (4) of such subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idEB0A19DE645E4DC4ADE87250C4BD4C6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If amounts appropriated for grants and cooperative agreements under subsection (a) do not exceed $5,000,000 in any fiscal year, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration may use in that fiscal year—</text><subparagraph id="id4CEA990375F44AF7AB3EDB4327570A15"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">60 percent of such amounts for grants and cooperative agreements under paragraph (1) of such subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0C09F09D259F4304836B65124C21BF58"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">40 percent of such amounts for grants and cooperative agreements under paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id49854b4be1964c27bb68a1b900d87484"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental justice communities</header><text>40 percent of all amounts allocated for grants and cooperative agreements under paragraphs (2) and (4) of subsection (a) shall be directed into environmental justice communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id10cfd58747f0485988d07b4836918934"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant and cooperative agreement minimum</header><text>If amounts appropriated for grants and cooperative agreements under subsection (a) exceed $5,000,000 in any fiscal year, any grant awarded to, or cooperative agreement established with, an entity under paragraph (1) of such subsection shall provide the entity a minimum of $1,000,000 in that fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><section id="id6627aa2bf36f4d99a4c95f7940cbf4b2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall submit to Congress a report that evaluates the scientific merits, educational effectiveness, and broader effects of activities carried out under this Act.</text></section><section id="id8421a0a7d3244d44812a11a7b4772a68"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to carry out this Act $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2032.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

