<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0AE93DC259B84E81939E0F9A5D044F87" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9366 IH: Eastern Frontier Defense Infrastructure Readiness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9366</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a report on Eastern Frontier infrastructure readiness.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8B3C67DC0C09493A8AC7AEEDD5BC5B75" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5FE1A78B7CA34D56B52C8EFDE261C4C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eastern Frontier Defense Infrastructure Readiness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HD945604894634801B030F01A73326ECF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and sense of Congress</header> 
<subsection id="HF56DB0D0C0E74569AC9FC8600168E72F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA0D09E800D1C43EAB1C9181863DDF99B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Government of the Russian Federation continues to pose a long-term threat to Euro-Atlantic security, as reaffirmed by allies in the Hague Summit Declaration issued on June 25, 2025.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34F39CC110B34801BA0C1C0D0C1191C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Under that Declaration, allies of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization committed to invest five percent of gross domestic product annually on core defense requirements and on defense- and security-related spending by 2035, of which up to 1.5 percent is to be accounted for to protect critical infrastructure, defend networks, ensure civil preparedness and resilience, unleash innovation, and strengthen the defense industrial base.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5433EAC533104A59A8CA09B7208B949C"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>The Supreme Allied Commander-Europe, has identified military mobility, host-nation infrastructure, and theater-wide resilience as essential to executing the Alliance’s new family of regional defense plans approved at the 2023 Vilnius Summit.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE93B2B527D404EE098787E5BA28933BB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Allies located on the Eastern Frontier of the Alliance bear disproportionate first-responder responsibilities under those plans and require infrastructure that can sustain large-scale reinforcement, sustainment, and combat operations in the event of conflict with the Russian Federation. Gaps in transportation, energy, communications, and financial infrastructure along the Eastern Frontier directly affect the ability of the United States Armed Forces and the forces of other allies to deter aggression and, if necessary, to defend allied territory.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H275A7D75445F48C8AF2E263F7800EE8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the United States has a vital national security interest in the timely and verifiable integration of the infrastructure of Eastern Frontier allies with the requirements of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H062770A8648744E78330A6885C6DB152"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on Eastern Frontier infrastructure readiness</header> 
<subsection id="HDDDA735234FF40219EC952A3B75875FA">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State and in consultation with the Supreme Allied Commander-Europe, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the progress of each Eastern Frontier ally in integrating its national infrastructure with the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) infrastructure requirements.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1EDE5583B1B947E4BA4553590CBD2DD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H0036961F7FC8459B88424A63D36CA862"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For each Eastern Frontier ally, an assessment of such ally’s progress, as of the date of the report, in meeting NATO infrastructure requirements, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H013C9F04140A4483BC2A43F905BBB7FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transportation infrastructure, including roads, bridges, rail, ports, inland waterways, and airfields, with particular attention to military-mobility corridors and dual-use capacity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEBAEE1209A5044E691576D9B504FA16D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>energy infrastructure, including pipelines, refineries, electricity generation and transmission, fuel storage, and grid interconnections;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A6613567D934888AB55F9FCAA68A5B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>communications and digital infrastructure, including telecommunications networks, undersea cables, satellite ground stations, and cybersecurity of national networks;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H071B9F276DFF467782E635ECD0D75947"><enum>(D)</enum><text>financial systems infrastructure, including the resilience and continuity of payment, clearing, and settlement systems necessary to sustain mobilization, host-nation support, and Alliance operations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA860509F53404D4A980F495B48F0BA9D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>civil preparedness and resilience, including water, medical, and emergency-services infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD46C3E1040114353B5308F8DF2EDE29A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>defense industrial base infrastructure, including munitions production, maintenance and overhaul capacity, and storage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC32F537E47EC416D970A5021AC78005F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the ally’s progress toward, and the credibility of its plan to reach, the 1.5 percent of gross domestic product commitment described in section 2(a)(2), including a description of the categories of expenditure being counted toward that commitment and whether such expenditure is materially improving infrastructure relevant to Alliance defense plans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7E29EC975D646188DC1CCDE27F63E1B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An identification of the most consequential infrastructure shortfalls, including any shortfall that would, in the event of conflict with the Russian Federation—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2447FC49E2384327841967F117602234"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impede the timely reinforcement of the ally by United States forces or by other allied forces;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB45ADBC71AB147DBB51CCE70380EB589"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impede the sustainment of combat operations in the ally’s territory; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H458FDE9B3815434D9E9C1A32945B4E9F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>create a single point of failure exploitable by the Russian Federation, including through cyber or sabotage operations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11DB933A4C8240FD8622D0898714C8DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations to address the shortfalls identified under paragraph (3), including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0DF24959EF0E4DC68A872FA08BDA085F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommended adjustments to United States security cooperation programs under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/16">chapter 16</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H972586E8E68E4CD1AC9CABC505006128"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommended prioritization within the European Deterrence Initiative;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA7C226C9B859440B80C060551E1F63BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommended use of authorities under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 and the Arms Export Control Act, in coordination with the Secretary of State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37FBD8C308E346138525D383EEB54BF8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>opportunities for cost-sharing with the ally, with the Alliance through the NATO Security Investment Program, or with the European Union; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H531811CC334C4AB7BF355170F9400214"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any legislative recommendations the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFABF93DE50DF4C4B8C2CCD6E6F2564C0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of Russian Federation activities, including cyber operations, sabotage, and hybrid operations, targeting the infrastructure described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD22F525F033D405BBD598D2B6A00D7D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, and may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1D3B2DE7479E492BBB272B93F459DFBB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Comptroller General review</header> <subsection id="H9732A8CFA4764C859F56C8910C8E7B26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the report required under section 3(a) is submitted, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a review of that report.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H50CF3FEF3AAD4F5E833B32B2175834A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The review required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H5C0BBCB5A74E410494E9FA0A61DCAC0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an independent assessment of the methodology, data sources, and analytic rigor of the report and an evaluation of the extent to which the recommendations in the report are supported by the underlying findings;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H987DA72C28654D5F962B2EBBB85E7310"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the extent to which expenditures counted by Eastern Frontier allies toward the 1.5 percent of gross domestic product commitment are materially improving North Atlantic Treaty Organization infrastructure requirements; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAD4A3922D95497A9FE1ADD7E4FC9E6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Comptroller General to improve the prioritization of United States security assistance and security cooperation for Eastern Frontier allies.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H68DAE3EDDAB54B4C9D83312449B2DF02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The review required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, and may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H84FB3CDA0E9A4493AD5B8E8C845063E9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization for security assistance and security cooperation prioritization</header> <subsection id="HAEBF5811E108493DA6495F0F173FA50A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense is authorized to prioritize security assistance in the European Deterrence Initiative, and in programming security cooperation activities under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/16">chapter 16</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, for Eastern Frontier allies.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H74F9DD9659BD46A28C70067EB73C0D1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual briefing</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the submission of the President’s budget under section 1105 of title 31, United States Code, for each of fiscal years 2028 through 2032, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the manner in which the budget request implements subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6EE95EC0E59A41C39548061B0A0C8D0C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8360377A15A348E88282A1BAE05BF1F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HF5A43903DBAC477BBA6D3A6C77BAA60C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committees on Armed Services, Foreign Affairs, and Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H36AEF0238C4742868490412AE67DB38E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committees on Armed Services, Foreign Relations, and Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB70C28CDD0F44081BDF4517910C0D233"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>Eastern Frontier ally</term> means each of the following member states of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBAE1C087A54F4A95A743C4760FA026C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Republic of Estonia.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC80A4EC7B460462BB45FEF6A4AE3A0F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Republic of Latvia.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC36EF6B76CB4B54B21015C20ADDCE89"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Republic of Lithuania.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H24E23F2C0C88410A8864C1D2567B7D01"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Republic of Poland.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF5D9DE411A74B80BD65C55F5CF453E2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Czech Republic.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H94A0CEFF8C9341D5BB78B408CB8675F4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Slovak Republic.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5BB59FB4C5A04D978ED296A7B937793A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Hungary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44B373EDF6C44D3092F02C59DBA9FBF4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Romania.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2D8A5159FD4548339BBA54A07A171540"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Republic of Bulgaria.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF44EC18D3B424342A6B6A45285342323"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The Republic of Finland.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD775C10D034F4FF282A7863FFC2359C0"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The Kingdom of Sweden.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84E431A9AA8F4CD1A87314D0AE57F0CE"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The Kingdom of Norway.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

