<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution dms-id="H778A3B706922446EA78D60D3B63B9208" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1399 EH: Directing the Committee on Ethics to preserve and publicly release records relating to .monetary settlements involving acts of sexual harassment.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="no">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. RES. 1399</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber> 
<action> 
<action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date> 
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="no">Directing the Committee on Ethics to preserve and publicly release records relating to .monetary settlements involving acts of sexual harassment.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas transparency is essential for accountability in government;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas sexual harassment and unwelcome sexual advances by Members, Delegates, or Resident Commissioners, in violation of clause 9 and clause 18 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House, affect the safety, dignity, and the integrity of the proceedings of the House of Representatives: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> 
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB01591607D4346E39B17D5DE2B33306D"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD13F5897FB824D69863AEAC68D4B3065">
<paragraph id="HB4E7632FD9AD44A187E1DCDBA18A42DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>That with respect to reviews, investigations, or matters which the Committee on Ethics or the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights have reviewed, conducted, or facilitated, the Committee on Ethics and the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights shall, not later than 60 days after the adoption of this resolution, make publicly available—</text> <subparagraph id="H21CFC08B10474B82BD3B86817AF34ED6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a single consolidated list that sets forth separately for each Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner—</text>
<clause id="HF38FEDA1847842C1A403AAE5BB8882EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name of each Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner who was the subject of any review or investigation involving a violation of clause 9 of Rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives, as it pertains to acts of sexual harassment, or clause 18 of Rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives, or any case involving sexual harassment or sexual abuse, if it resulted in a payment of taxpayer funds; and</text></clause> <clause id="H690F939F4385417A8CCCF8DE652D9E44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adjacent to each such name, the total amount of taxpayer funds included in all settlements, payments, reimbursements, awards, or other financial considerations paid in connection with such matters;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H26E17AF513F6408F91ED419040710344"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate total amount of taxpayer funds included in all settlements, payments, reimbursements, awards, or other financial considerations paid in connection with such reviews, investigations, or matters involving Members, Delegates, or Resident Commissioners that did not, in any portion of the settlement, involve sexual harassment, sexual abuse, or sexual misconduct;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAB718F52E2F4024A2E7FF027649A86C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate total amount of taxpayer funds included in all settlements, payments, reimbursements, awards, or other financial considerations paid in connection with such reviews, investigations, or matters involving, in part or in full, sexual harassment, sexual abuse, or sexual misconduct by employees of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7C79B61183F64859995699DA80EF1D10"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate total amount of taxpayer funds included in all settlements, payments, reimbursements, awards, or other financial considerations paid in connection with such reviews, investigations, or matters involving conduct by employees of the House of Representatives that did not, in any portion of the settlement, involve sexual harassment, sexual abuse, or sexual misconduct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C423F35F73E472BA4F5DA4BCB258571"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That for purposes of this resolution, any such settlement, payment, reimbursement, award, or other financial consideration shall be treated as involving sexual harassment, sexual abuse, or sexual misconduct if sexual harassment, sexual abuse, or sexual misconduct was any component of the matter, regardless of whether the matter also involved, was classified as, or was resolved under another claim, violation, or category.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body> 
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
</resolution> 


