<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA7EDC5A77DD24B03AA02F0DF48AEB42D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7520 IH: Efficiency Adjustment Delay Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7520</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to delay the implementation of an efficiency adjustment to work relative value units under the Medicare physician fee schedule.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBB48142FCB764C00BBDB65B438757E9E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC99222169B8A4CAEBC58DF5162627CCD" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Efficiency Adjustment Delay Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0328191C663740EFB60D459067935A6D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Delaying the implementation of an efficiency adjustment to work relative value units under the Medicare physician fee schedule</header> <subsection id="HBE7381C36A094B299DFE614A6138AA6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1848(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFDD1253CCB404CA58B8B805D15395E11" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H4EAF637396764F219EF90EE37B2C55BB" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Delayed implementation of work RVU efficiency adjustment</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE97DF5896F744580BDDCB5C5663FA1BC" commented="no">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
              <header>Delayed implementation</header>
 <text>The Secretary may not implement the policy established in the final rule published on November 5, 2025 (90 Fed. Reg. 49266 et seq.), that establishes an efficiency adjustment to work relative value units, and makes corresponding updates to the intraservice portion of physician time inputs for non-time-based services, before January 1, 2030.</text>
            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C2C6BC858E54C45893A2F14715D11A7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Finance of the Senate, a report containing an assessment of whether it is necessary to apply a one-time, across-the-board adjustment to work relative value units, and to make corresponding updates to the intraservice portion of physician time inputs for non-time-based services, with respect to services that have not been revalued or reviewed within the 10-year period preceding the calendar year in which such one-time adjustment would be applied. Such report shall include supporting evidence for such assessment.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B11E74229A047769FD1297648B13645"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitations on future implementation</header> <clause id="H785E58860E5A4ABA8F9F7ED594AF1B43"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to <internal-xref idref="H6F98A73C353C4A7D8F123FA451F4B192" legis-path="(9)(C)(ii)">clause (ii)</internal-xref>, in the case that the report under <internal-xref idref="H7C2C6BC858E54C45893A2F14715D11A7" legis-path="(9)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref> supports the implementation of the efficiency adjustment described in <internal-xref idref="HE97DF5896F744580BDDCB5C5663FA1BC" legis-path="(9)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>, the Secretary may implement such adjustment on or after January 1, 2030, if the following conditions are met:</text> 
<subclause id="HC24D38E40CC44ABB888AB4333721F006"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Before implementing such adjustment, the Secretary consults with representatives of physician specialties affected by the potential implementation of such adjustment.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H13BBA232327E47B3B8755B570E7FA994"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary does not implement such adjustment with respect to services that have been revalued or reviewed within the 10-year period preceding the calendar year in which such one-time adjustment would be applied.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7AE3661A7B22497491B4253355BDDB37"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary establishes a methodology for calculating such adjustment that does not rely on a factor that is used for determining productivity relative to inflation unless the update to the nonqualifying APM conversion factor under section 1848(d) for the year in which the one-time adjustment would be applied is greater than or equal to the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) over the previous year.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6F98A73C353C4A7D8F123FA451F4B192"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Multiple adjustments prohibited</header><text>The Secretary may not implement such an efficiency adjustment more than once.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0010B399EA3C4DC8889084EEA5EA75C0" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in <internal-xref idref="HE97DF5896F744580BDDCB5C5663FA1BC" legis-path="(9)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> shall be construed to prevent the Secretary from revaluing misvalued codes for specific services or assigning values to new or revised codes for services.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H2AC3FDC78D3B43A7B77FC3CC75BB0471"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustment to conversion factor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1848(d)(20) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-4">42 U.S.C. 1395w–4(d)(20)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9F48A2ED9997405F91CE1DA76D2DEF95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>0.75 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>1.24 percent</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40728A1D3C604724A8BF9122165DD76E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>0.25 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>0.74 percent</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H445D35FBDB2D4D34B03729534623AF1A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>For 2026 and each subsequent year</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAA2499E222F14DC18FB08E90CFC526C1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HA7B69DD3BD0649E4A217CD7E5DCF6F0E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Update for 2026</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For 2026</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A9C7AD20B134582A8A8B4736827A46B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA458A982CDFB4459B872C56D81768C86" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H0891F367B8334441AB8060F4E232B076"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Update for 2027 and subsequent years</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For 2027 and each subsequent year, the update to the qualifying APM conversion factor established under paragraph (1)(A) is 0.75 percent, and the update to the nonqualifying APM conversion factor established under such paragraph is 0.25 percent. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

