<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBBEE8B56E2684D158EC6DCCB05045C8E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7877 IH: Shane DiGiovanna Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7877</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260309">March 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a demonstration program to test mandatory coverage of treatment for wound care for epidermolysis bullosa under the Medicaid program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC46161D1CF5C4285BC51CC41992DF273" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4DE373C9B3594B299D2FEB866076A084" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Shane DiGiovanna Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEC5EAC4D894945FBBBCF9128716F81C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Demonstration program to test mandatory coverage of treatment for wound care for epidermolysis bullosa under the Medicaid program</header> <subsection id="H06E3A29C24F64E8B87EC32847C6F867A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct a 2-year demonstration program under which items and services specified in subsection (b) furnished for the treatment of epidermolysis bullosa are required to be included as medical assistance under a State plan (or waiver of such plan) under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) for individuals described in section 1902(a)(10)(A)(i) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)(i)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCB8CE9896FB14DE1A5C99B2A13006E9E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified items and services</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the items and services specified in this subsection are over-the-counter antihistamines, acetaminophen, nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, antiseptics, zinc oxide, antibiotic ointments, and necessary wound care supplies, including wound care dressings (inclusive of primary and secondary dressings), gauze, and bandage retainers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H53294CC396C64B44AFA1C0BCD57990E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of demonstration</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct the demonstration program described in subsection (a) on a nationwide basis.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB97260505C6B4AC68772F7242E69723F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the end of the demonstration program described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on such program. Such report shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC6528059672F411BB4A39E46F19781F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An evaluation of the effect of such program on expenditures for treatment of individuals with epidermolysis bullosa under the Medicaid program (taking into account any such treatment avoided due to such program).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5207AD2880DC41A7AB94659D22593ABC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An analysis of health outcomes for such individuals compared to such outcomes before such program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EE740245E294815BD36A49FD66860CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any recommendations relating to how to prevent hospitalizations relating to epidermolysis bullosa.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

