<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H28BB6C9ADA924A349F914A857765A0AF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6754 IH: To exempt Members of the House of Representatives and Senators of the Senate from certain Federal passenger and baggage screening, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6754</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To exempt Members of the House of Representatives and Senators of the Senate from certain Federal passenger and baggage screening, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H55A007BA87E84A339846BE6DD8001B2D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H71AE00C5EA0A427DB24381D1B8027CF0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Exemption of Members and Senators from certain Federal passenger and baggage screening</header> 
<subsection id="H52EFD0F2DBC3436791076046184EF6BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 218 of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Members of the United States House of Representatives and the United States Senate, including the leadership; the heads</quote> and inserting <quote>The heads</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H102D2F6310D44E84AA55AD1AB2DF3072"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nonapplicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 218 of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2024 shall not apply to the amendment made by subsection (a) and shall not have any force or effect at law relating thereto.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE530867658014A04A9739053C12F65C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall exempt a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator of the Senate, including the leadership of either of such House, from Federal passenger and baggage screening if such Member or Senator, as the case may be, is traveling between the home airport of such Member or Senator, as the case may be, and any other location.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

