<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H35D3E5DE635542868900E20AFE54F439" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7827 IH: Stop Militarizing Our Streets Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7827</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to restrict the sale and procurement of certain weapons and ammunition by the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H56798A2311DB431AAFD45B9036AF270E" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HA35FA1A715C247ECA925AD94A2F20B55"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Militarizing Our Streets Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CBDA727539549B49213B2F63771E66F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restriction on sales and procurement by Department of Defense of certain weapons and ammunition</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDB9717281274DA292B3B039052A40F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restriction</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF745A8E3436D4567A43834CF582D44B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/763">Chapter 763</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/7544">section 7544</external-xref> the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38E8F94571A7413DADFEE2018145C520">
<section id="HF33EFEDAEDF547DB90E1F9E69CF6AD49"><enum>7545.</enum><header>Restriction on sales and procurement of certain weapons and ammunition</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BDA3A1F8D88401786F6D7E215E38B2D"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibitions relating to certain highly dangerous military-Grade weapons and ammunition</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B4D26FED32D49D7924F48A459E43D88"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sales in commercial marketplace</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense or a private operator of a government-owned plant may not sell to any dealer, directly or through a private contractor, in the commercial marketplace—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90DAF8BBC4584FC29E9E1123694AC9F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any military-grade assault weapon; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BA9A6CEDC2741E882892A1DAE978128"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any covered ammunition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF76BFDDF859442C79A07B7795EBB34DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procurement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may not procure any item from a dealer or manufacturer of firearms or ammunition that sells a military-grade assault weapon or covered ammunition in the commercial marketplace.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HCAD2F6D901B64C65B6CCED5C9BCE3631"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations Relating to other weapons and ammunition</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04E9F555ED724759BF64D240E14F4790"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this subsection shall apply to all firearms and ammunition, other than military-grade assault weapons and covered ammunition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B2EB7EA4DE14D0C9B46F2923EBF42DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sales in commercial marketplace</header><text>The Secretary of Defense or a private operator of a government-owned plant may not sell any firearm or ammunition to any dealer in the commercial marketplace that fails to meet the requirements described in paragraph (4).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H451093740D5B4933952170FDC8618015"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Procurement</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may not procure any item from a dealer or private manufacturer of firearms or ammunition that sells firearms or ammunition in the commercial marketplace if the dealer or private manufacturer—</text> <subparagraph id="H49C7DA5B60A743619A82CA687BEAABE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>directly sells firearms or ammunition to individual purchasers in the commercial marketplace and fails to meet the requirements described in paragraph (4); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0762A5E8963F45A9A50E3851827F68F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sells any firearm or ammunition to any dealer in the commercial marketplace that fails to meets the requirements described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80709369297A44A580B8E582BBF09D6A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The requirements described in this paragraph for any dealer of firearms or ammunition are the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H8C3C5FD33F994449B064EA5E2B962830"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The dealer must—</text> <clause id="H5CDF7FCE3390436A9ED65B9FBA90A37B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to a dealer of firearms, have a license under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18;</text></clause>
<clause id="H4BAD175E014C4113A8A641DCBE97B41A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to a dealer of ammunition, have a license under subsection (d)(1); and</text></clause> <clause id="HCC89FF8F14E44414A0E6E75E402A110B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>comply with all requirements under Federal law for licensees under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1033F3AB9DFE4157B450E5B5B92F31BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In each of the previous 3 calendar years, the Attorney General has traced not more than 24 firearms used in crimes back to the dealer with a time-to-crime of less than 3 years.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE1F6E66759B24165B9E580C857478003"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to a dealer that sells ammunition, during any 30-day period, the dealer may not transfer to the same individual purchaser—</text>
<clause id="HAF6A63C43C304BF1B68B1F1B609A7EA1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>more than 500 rounds of covered ammunition; or</text></clause> <clause id="HD61D62CF90BB484E8029E59BC6B432E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>more than 1000 rounds of other ammunition.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAE1281265FBA4E28A66996EEE835B450"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The dealer must agree to a minimum code of conduct that includes the following:</text> <clause id="H4A25DA2C55664717BC24D429A816756F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A refusal to transfer a firearm or ammunition until the NICS background check system has verified that the transfer is not prohibited.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9CDBD1458C645F1B89CA4F89CA6A024"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The implementation of a security system, including adequate locks, exterior lighting, surveillance cameras, alarm systems, and other anti-theft measures and practices that the Attorney General may through regulations prescribe.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6A4522EB034442DA7E609FCF6183693"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A refusal to sell firearms in any marketplace, including online or at a gun show, unless the marketplace requires every firearm seller to complete a NICS background check on prospective firearm purchasers.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H046BC117F091488DAEC2A51A6D6AB081"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A refusal to transfer firearms or ammunition to any person that exhibits signs of alcohol or drug intoxication or cognitive or mental instability (as those terms are defined by the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services).</text></clause> <clause id="HBC11D6A3021540CF86FD7E1E072698B8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A refusal to transfer a firearm or ammunition to any person the dealer knows or has reason to believe poses a danger to that person or others.</text></clause>
<clause id="H90B5D13593CE4E3FA4BD9AC33643A0D3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>With respect to firearms, the implementation and maintenance of a remotely searchable electronic record of—</text> <subclause id="H33512BEDEC8543D4BFF854478249EA53"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the make, model, caliber or gauge, and serial number of every firearm in the inventory of the dealer; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HA080DE0AF7164B9D8D33AFA789D675F1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the performance of quarterly inventory checks.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H268419B0B79A4F569C756AA1043F68A1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>With respect to ammunition, the dealer must implement and maintain a remotely searchable electronic record of—</text>
<clause id="H486E31A74DBD464E8EA694E531E98353"><enum>(i)</enum><text>importation;</text></clause> <clause id="H7A89F5FCE8584FC0BC920A139582C838"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>production;</text></clause>
<clause id="H45DD6950456B4E8BAE85232867B3ACEA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shipment;</text></clause> <clause id="H930B35512EF24907953FE978D0248133"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>receipt;</text></clause>
<clause id="HDF48E255C04A49FE9F616374559AFCA8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>sale; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1CA0A88176074EC2B1B8D885DC553DCD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other disposition of ammunition at the place of business of the dealer for such period, and in such form, as the Attorney General may by regulations prescribe.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59206AE611E844A592B7E762683849D2"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The dealer must implement a mandatory training course developed by the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, where appropriate—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9A8ECFA33EB488DAD13241A1CED94CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which, with respect to each employee of the dealer authorized to engage in the transfer of firearms or ammunition in the course of the business—</text>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H313EC42BB1A54A94869661A26798DD28"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employee as of the date of enactment of this section completes not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C1811FE63184ABD84D8EA49200AD8ED"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employee hired after the date of enactment of this section complete not later than 30 days after the date on which the employee is hired; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2417F1BE2CD747CC853075CFC2FCE142"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that trains employees on—</text> <subclause id="HACE8DF4DC3E446089CD4F3057FCD6594"><enum>(I)</enum><text>how to recognize and identify—</text>
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14E6205FB59C47DABF68FC6A3C26691F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">straw purchasers; and</text></item> <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CCED023093C43508B5B1E11261D4845"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other fraudulent activity described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code;</text></item></subclause>
<subclause id="HA88CC5D49DFB46F391F8E0F6D880FBF9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>indicators that a person is attempting to purchase a firearm or ammunition illegally;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1AD1B07B0F054F6FAF5A95DE8B5589C7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>how to recognize and identify indicators that an individual intends to use a firearm for unlawful purposes;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HDD655F8CE677407FB4F981A29C1E4B27"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>how to recognize and identify indicators that an individual intends to use a firearm for self-harm;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H149240CBC5F24A13B0FF6B5C9B9782A0"><enum>(V)</enum><text>how to prevent theft or burglary of firearms and ammunition;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H3FE6C2E5A72E4AF59B03A8EA6467252F"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>how to respond in the circumstances described in subclauses (I) through (V) and the applicable reporting requirements;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H35E6073436B44F05BE79CDEE48E4F23F"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>how to verify the age of a purchaser of a firearm or ammunition;</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA508E13A9EE44EDB99CDA5DADC8987DB"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a dealer of ammunition, how to detect whether a single purchaser has reached the applicable ammunition purchase limit to prevent a violation of subparagraph (C); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA0D109BD8CFA419D9AA531E1745B745F"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>other reasonable business practices that the Attorney General determines will deter firearm trafficking or deter the provision of a firearm to an individual who indicates an intent to use a firearm for unlawful purposes or for self-harm.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95456EA2CB124800A8B778E4DBC30EA1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives releases to the dealer results of any compliance inspection conducted by the Bureau, the dealer must report the results of the inspection to any manufacturer or wholesaler dealer from which the dealer obtains firearms or ammunition.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BFE574ABAAB4CF0A9C4A59352C33746"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The dealer does not maintain financial ties valued at more than $1,000,000 annually with an entity that—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0D1C6E019BE4FC58866204F3F0A2ED9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the 5-year period preceding the date of a sale or procurement described in paragraph (2) or (3), separated from the dealer through a spin-off transaction; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1662EA0699EB4B54A2DFB30D7584958A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not comply with the requirements of this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E07A66B1A214BD98E1BBF92D59A0455"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Inspection results</header><text>With respect to an inspection of a dealer described in paragraph (4)(G), not later than 30 days after the date of the inspection, the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives shall send to the Department of Defense a copy of the report. </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C424A133B7846DDA71A95FF1DFD9986"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may promulgate necessary regulations to implement the requirements of this subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H536C6183A09644EE8EB2BCD0679E8A4C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Interdepartment coordination</header><text>The Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall monitor compliance with paragraph (4) by dealers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28555245558246D49109ECC80F345953" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>A dealer that violates paragraph (4) may not participate in a sale or purchase described in paragraph (2) or (3).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDAEB86FB474444C9CD2259F08AC98AB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Data sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other law, the Attorney General may share crime gun trace data with the Department of Defense as necessary to carry out this section. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFDBA87481E824DBFB982096594EDD3F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> <paragraph id="HA212D0BDFA2D41BAA2ABF7BB4915E6E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Government-owned plant report</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, each government-owned plant that produces any ammunition or firearms that are commercially sold shall submit to Congress a report that includes, for the year covered by the report—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE9BF7A59D78F46C3A1829C34A586E737"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of customers of the plant for ammunition or firearms in the commercial marketplace, disaggregated by the State in which the customer is located;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABCFA57B155B42EDB73488CC60019195"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the revenue of the plant from sales of ammunition or firearms in the commercial marketplace;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6D94745136514216B2B05693F21243C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount of ammunition or firearms sold by the plant in the commercial marketplace;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2689921A26E74980BF3455AFEB54963F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an operational plan for avoiding any diversion of firearms or ammunition into the illegal market or to customers not authorized for purchase under this section; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H51D11381453946EA948F20B05F4533DA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>steps taken to implement the plan described in subparagraph (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EC43759B048444FB7255AD74AD7BAAC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of Defense report</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report containing the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H96254B4AEB6540D997B71E2AB4A6E67E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of manufacturers and dealers from which the Secretary procures firearms that also sell firearms in the commercial market.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39FA084C0CE541FF9C017CB9B3A5FD41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A list of the types of firearms those dealers sell in the commercial market.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDA26AAA9EFB34ABF980F8D755F88C202"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The amount of money the Secretary pays to those dealers for firearms each year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB6DB3EEE25F44A284B11D1FB6A3EFB4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Licenses for dealing ammunition</header> <paragraph id="HDD3337BE81164E89B10CB720662953B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall make licenses available to dealers of ammunition, who may apply for such licenses for the purpose of subsection (b)(4)(A)(ii) to be eligible to make the sales or purchases described in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (b).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H05D17E55251B47449BB37FCFC7FCA266"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In making licenses available in accordance with paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall apply in a substantially similar manner the requirements under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18 for licenses of dealers of firearms to dealers of ammunition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A2A1D6EF8AD4BF884E11C6C3E0F3A5C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>NICS system</header> <subparagraph id="HCF9FF6BC354C4884BAF4210A14B0B628"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Stop Militarizing Our Streets Act of 2026</short-title>, the Attorney General shall authorize a dealer of ammunition licensed in accordance with paragraph (1) to access and use the NICS background check system in accordance with laws applicable to the use of the NICS background check system.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8323800ED7946FFB4E91FAE7119989A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A dealer of ammunition authorized under subparagraph (A) may use the NICS background check system for the purpose of subsection (b)(4)(D) to be eligible to make the sales or purchases described in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9318E119CAA4EE989729A7D44EF3510"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Ammunition background checks</header><text>A dealer of ammunition licensed in accordance with paragraph (1) may perform a NICS background check on an individual purchasing ammunition from the dealer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C78F2EEF14444D58AE341505C527225"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Attorney General shall promulgate a rule with requirements for dealers to comply with the recordkeeping requirement described in subsection (b)(4)(E).</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C00AE8E56E84C9DAF5692DF9DEFB66D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6F091B015F9404289C5D1CC12603992"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ammunition; firearm; manufacturer</header><text>The terms <term>ammunition</term>, <term>firearm</term>, and <term>manufacturer</term> have the meaning given those terms in section 921(a) of title 18.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA63F01F580E44C9903E955B826106DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered ammunition</header><text>The term <term>covered ammunition</term>—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1890C429610E4340AD0EACD3066FC93E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means ammunition that is .22 caliber or larger; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H163216F1D3EB459AB26928B76298453D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes .223 Remington ammunition and 7.62 North Atlantic Treaty Organization ammunition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4AA1DB445F6D4324A8B2E6246F0A3893"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Dealer</header><text>The term <term>dealer</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDBC6FEF11F3B4CEFB137EC1A400631F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given the term in section 921 of title 18; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0905A585A7F44437907DC284C64E880B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any person engaged in the business of selling ammunition at wholesale or retail, including an unlicensed private vendor of ammunition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1316F2ABA5974A5CA8B6B9190A647C96"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Financial ties</header><text>The term <term>financial ties</term>—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H070A9542827945D1ABE341BA01D62A35"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given the term by the Secretary of Defense in a regulation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3BAE4EC6FC14584AE2157D6FB23CBB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a revenue sharing agreement or a transfer of assets through a purchase or sale transaction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBAB32516FDA4734A8D9EE9D8275E819"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Gas-operated</header><text>The term <term>gas-operated</term>, with respect to a firearm, means that the firearm harnesses or traps a portion of the high-pressure gas from a fired cartridge to cycle the action using—</text> <subparagraph id="H0BB31FEA667C46D79A5A296585EA0D7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a long stroke piston, in which gas is vented from the barrel to a piston that is mechanically fixed to the bolt group and moves to cycle the action;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H35CB4A238CE04EBB81F48A8D3690B2EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a short stroke piston, in which gas is vented from the barrel to a piston that moves separately from the bolt group so that the energy is imparted through a gas piston to cycle the action;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H82075E97C1D44F7EBD0CD50F595F4B38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a system that traps and vents gas from the barrel or the chamber to directly strike or impinge the bolt, bolt carrier, or slide assembly to unlock and cycle the action;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H87B1B64B796346839A0EA1F17E8936B0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a hybrid system that combines elements of a system described in subparagraph (C) with a system described in subparagraph (A) or (B) to capture gas vented from the barrel to cycle the action; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA64C7C3A18C04E5A8B90282553021624"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a blowback-operated system that directly uses the expanding gases of the ignited propellant powder acting on the cartridge case to drive the breechblock or breech bolt rearward.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF643AA39E97944AFB35AB1FB94D0E894"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Government-owned plant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>government-owned plant</term> means a facility owned by the Federal Government that produces firearms or ammunition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD41A8AEF13984FC597C720C1A621CBBC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Gun show</header><text>The term <term>gun show</term> means a gun show or an event described in section 478.100(b) of title 27, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7044F53EEC814E03ABE02EC6872EBA1B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Large-capacity ammunition feeding device</header><text>The term <term>large-capacity ammunition feeding device</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H493D62DF100A493E97569716A5413720"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a magazine, belt, drum, feed strip, or similar device, including any such device joined or coupled with another in any manner, that has an overall capacity of, or that can be readily restored, changed, or converted to accept, more than 10 rounds of ammunition; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H47465A43349E4EBBBF809CA744ECBBC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an attached tubular device designed to accept, and capable of operating only with, .22 caliber rimfire ammunition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D1BB6FDC66D4E69AA590A328D211CF6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Military-grade assault weapon</header><text>The term <term>military-grade assault weapon</term> means a firearm that—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE685BADE7DF408EA5834270870260D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is semi-automatic;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C87D3997DA545BA8F0F6643F3D83ACF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is—</text>
<clause id="HF65A5EDD057C4C44A711273F18D594D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>gas-operated or has been modified to operate as a gas-operated firearm;</text></clause> <clause id="HD76F7A9B8CB048CCAAA124A5E74AF7E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recoil-operated or has been modified to operate as a recoil-operated firearm, unless the firearm is a handgun or pistol; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H2FB45DE59558490287B5F5A6CD5E67FF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>designed and functions, or can be readily modified, to materially increase the rate of fire of the firearm; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28215A3EAC74473C9957182030979570"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has—</text>
<clause id="HB49D64C1E958427CB641EDC0BB0F57BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a fixed ammunition feeding device with the capacity to accept more than 10 rounds of ammunition; or</text></clause> <clause id="H7CD97202C22B4876B50438A01C1E59F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the capacity to accept a large-capacity ammunition feeding device.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51BAD30A6CA343DEBF00A440F8E76C0E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>NICS background check</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>NICS background check</term> means a background check through the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC697AB4B3B84D06A6412ED7CE588EE1"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Recoil-operated</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recoil-operated</term> with respect to a firearm, means that the firearm uses the recoil force to unlock the breech bolt and complete the cycle of extracting, ejecting, and reloading.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD81FA29D05CB4A3D80DF65DC52382F60"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Semi-automatic</header><text>The term <term>semi-automatic</term>, with respect to a firearm, means any repeating firearm, other than a machine gun, that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25EF7524D22C4D5DBBEE84F753D51C54"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uses a portion of the energy of a firing cartridge or shell to extract the fired cartridge case or fired shell casing and chamber the next round; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31C9FFC071A24B66951934A17BE28AED"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requires a separate pull, release, push, or other method of initiation of the trigger to fire each cartridge or shell. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H11DC24477C7F4A43B7EEE3FB02D785C9"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Spin-off transaction</header><text>The term <term>spin-off transaction</term> means a transaction that separates a division or line of business from a parent company of an entity.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A2FC86152784F82B36FBFCA81CCF901"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Straw purchase</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>straw purchase</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAF5D08662BC4D64AD4925BD60292FF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a firearm, means a purchase described in section 932(b) of title 18; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D3767BB75AC4A93B8BA6A2D3686B6E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to ammunition, means a purchase described in 932(b) of title 18, except that, for the purpose of this subparagraph, any reference in that section to <term>firearm</term> shall be deemed to be a reference to <term>ammunition</term>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC556E8B43D6546A9861F5049A1660412"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Time-to-crime</header><text>The term <quote>time-to-crime</quote> means the period of time between the retail sale of a firearm and the recovery of the firearm by a law enforcement agency as a result of the use or suspected use of the firearm in a crime.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD36410D37ADB4C3CB60A26C1A4BF47DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7544 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HA9C02330B09A4262B4D076B75B1D2ED3"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section" idref="HF33EFEDAEDF547DB90E1F9E69CF6AD49">7545. Restriction on sales and procurement of certain weapons and ammunition.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6635D34D21904721BCA3F82B02587D49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3B8636F1DAF4E56B21C51BC39747BD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cooperative activities with non-Army entities</header><text>Section 7544(c) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA41CEE0697064C5B9324FFBEC0C3DC84">
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAF2D2DF669B408DB66274BA43E09769"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The non-Army entity abides by the commercial sale restrictions set forth in section 7545 of this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5524231DD2924A00B790F4B42DD9FBBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Policy</header><text>Section 7552 of such title is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>It</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to the restrictions set forth under section 7545 of this title, it</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H296DAD0D467A4E61B664FF6F0F3F32F4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Armament Retooling and Manufacturing Support Initiative</header><text>Section 7553(b) of such title is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to the restrictions set forth under section 7545 of this title, the</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F58B22C0E3C49B3A9D6CC76DF704270"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for increased NICS funding</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General such sums as are necessary to carry out the amendments made by this section, including to upgrade and maintain the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>


