<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H567AE6DF7F1E41989862A47FDE480D80" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7968 IH: Small AI Innovators Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7968</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Department of Commerce to carry out a study on challenges faced by United States small artificial intelligence businesses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5C8DD9F10B8043CF9C549E2A37AFFD75" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H04D2592B5E88470F88810BA7B5C453F9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small AI Innovators Empowerment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HC8178B1D0BCC46C494E2B130C548C687" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on challenges faced by small artificial intelligence businesses</header> 
<subsection id="H110BCBA9D67E474D99FDD0A642C736C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and in consultation with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, shall seek to enter into an agreement with an appropriate entity with relevant expertise, as determined by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, which may include a federally funded research and development center, to conduct a study on challenges faced by United States small artificial intelligence businesses located across the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H98CDCBA4A76148F89327CD1096F96DCD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE09959DBADAB4C0DBAC6E7429F0CA5CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An analysis of Federal and non-Federal resource funding opportunities for United States small artificial intelligence businesses, including relating to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H0044427036944E8DAD4E2C5F8568351B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Data on early and seed funding sources.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H068C094FFA344BAD8D67050A4D684B6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Accessibility of Federal funding opportunities, timeline of receiving such funding, and the impact of physical asset collateral and other loan requirements on United States small artificial intelligence businesses.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2CE9B03D983D435582BCA13253C0FAF2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Availability and use of non-Federal funding opportunities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EA7B31B39054C87ACB21162E44F4430"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Usage of research and development tax credits, and the impact of tax credit restrictions or changes on United States small artificial intelligence businesses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8A5D20395754D7EB65819C4F76DDB09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Usage of accelerators and incubators in the process of establishing United States small artificial intelligence businesses.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF6BBDF1927E41B197B03F3396F833AC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An analysis of downstream impacts of Federal policy on United States small artificial intelligence businesses, including an assessment of technology stacks, with consideration of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HA6FCDDAAB56D403D8BAD3AFE19F0D64E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Differences in usage of artificial intelligence tools between United States small artificial intelligence businesses and other businesses across the infrastructure, model, and application layers of the artificial intelligence ecosystem, and the role of access to computing resources, cloud services, and data.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCBDE534CCDF54AA4B26483E8FC8BC8B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Impact of regulatory uncertainty on exit strategies and acquisition opportunities for United States small artificial intelligence businesses.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H094760BB79664C7C974C7E6BBD044FCA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Impact of partnerships with larger firms and competition policy frameworks on opportunities for growth of United States small artificial intelligence businesses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD64AA6D9D49C483480AD980439CBF286"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An analysis of talent recruitment and retainment challenges faced by United States small artificial intelligence businesses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H972E30D8434543139E5DBC8A02FC538E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An analysis of any other potential challenges faced by United States small artificial intelligence businesses the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15D6385CA12E4EDFB17766EF9FE935DB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Proposals and recommendations to address any such challenges.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC5E80F6C5C5A4FB8B3EB27AD5ADD5890"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H692E770A1C73458DBCC40ED4AEEFE875"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D6FE1CE84BC4BE0B13BD8C7D424AD43"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States small artificial intelligence business</header><text>The term <term>United States small artificial intelligence business</term> means a business that creates, develops, or customizes artificial intelligence products or services as its primary business activity and that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H778DA40B520F4435B7F78FF416004386"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is headquartered in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE04BACEF5AB34C2FB68D883716B5F777"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is organized for profit;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H538944842B5D4FA3A2499073641E7D07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>operates primarily within the United States or makes a significant contribution to the United States economy through payment of taxes or use of American products, materials, or labor;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E86D9E7B5284F7D98F2DAA3793BF57C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is independently owned and operated, including a business that is backed by private funding, equity financing, or an institutional investor; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H673DC26FF72C416AB04771F4398AEF56"><enum>(E)</enum><text>employs 250 or fewer people.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A711691C64146FCA5BB258375BA2476"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technology stacks</header><text>The term <term>technology stacks</term> means the collection of technologies, tools, and infrastructure utilized by such businesses.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

