<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H32EB6E37061D4835A420497DACA35028" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7494 IH: Preventing Domestic Violence Homicides Through Lethality Assessment Training and Technical Assistance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7494</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Attorney General to make grants to establish a
                                    national training and technical assistance center to provide for
                                    the ongoing promotion and adoption of lethality assessment
                                    programs to reduce domestic violence-related homicides, and for
                                    other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6DF16F03F6524947A516C6D7899E412D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7601B18FE40F4DBB87855C867A7B9F45" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Domestic Violence Homicides Through Lethality Assessment Training and Technical Assistance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HEA0FBFAE0D804FF193CA9F32B3E86ADF"><enum>2.</enum><header>National lethality assessment program resource center grant</header> 
<subsection id="H843D9BAB6C434B7697F6B911B43DF092"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may make an award to one or more nonprofit or tribal organizations to establish a national training and technical assistance center to promote and support the adoption of lethality assessment programs by States, units of local government, and Indian Tribes.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HF33041FB79994A44BAC4EEBC79FA76E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an applicant shall demonstrate national experience in developing, implementing, evaluating, and disseminating a lethality assessment program for the purpose of reducing domestic violence-related homicides.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7E25D80A16AA4CBBA349753FE587FC89"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each fiscal year beginning in fiscal year 2026, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H419D488FC7A949EC94CECFB1496B6740"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA4527D2A609B4F6CB4BCE3ECF4CCF1B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>lethality assessment program</term> means a program that—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D59E0A55A1C4FC2AF65E0B4F54E265D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>rapidly connects a victim of domestic violence to local community-based victim service providers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A0E401CEA824D9E8613EFE8F56C9C36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>helps first responders, such as law enforcement agencies, identify and respond to domestic violence situations that may result in death; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BE934DB446A4EF8A136027094C79800"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifies victims of domestic violence who are at high risk of being seriously injured or killed by an intimate partner through evidence-based tools that are validated for the community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64F62EC5FFE44CF3AD80E92FCE11FD3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The terms have the meanings given such terms in section 40002 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

