<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7E1765DE37C4502AE72D951C53263EA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8456 IH: Rural Child Care Access Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8456</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support infrastructure investment in small and rural child care facilities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF3CBF62CB2EE417BAD6FEE2176AB3415" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4EB5CE0EE10949FEAFD812FB888AEB9B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Child Care Access Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDDC3A94AEAB64954BA3F1215079512B8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Building up infrastructure for local child care grant program</header> <subsection id="HCAF993D2C6BB4B49B4CDDA6791B8903C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services is authorized to make grants to State and local child care facilities that serve jurisdictions with fewer than 50,000 residents for use in accordance with subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8088902D032A4E128E02C5DFA012EAEA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="HB9737E1D56964FADA942A81E5776EB11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available to a State or local child care facility under this section shall be used for projects to modify, upgrade, or construct a child care facility, which projects shall have a substantial nexus to—</text> <subparagraph id="H81161C065E55419198F1B08825217F2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the improvement of the provision of child care;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA85652D4D3574F09B2FF0A444EDF36E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the training and development of child care providers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H120773E79A75448E9602BD115ED0949B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recruitment and retention of child care providers; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H57DFA5FD1DDE415E95A9570527E01BBD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>community engagement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F4E638AC6FF40A38720542868BA06C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No portion of funds made available under this section for a project to modify, upgrade, or construct a child care facility may be used for any part of the facility that does not have a substantial nexus to subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H071AFCC36B4949D2ACC0F4213BE2214C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of a child care facility seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary of Health and Human Services may reasonably require, including an estimate of the cost of the project for which the grant will be used, as well as a demonstration of financial need for the grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0B5729837B194FB4B5E4FF716A0BB3CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties of the Secretary of Health and Human Services</header> <paragraph id="HD153450F55C14AB7A873E1FFEAD1E13D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue guidance to carry out the grant program under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8C0BF22B4064F49B6378ED04CC28FB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall distribute information about the grant program under this section to eligible child care facilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91AE0D8421F14E3AAF0D26963FF26BB5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Equitable distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall ensure, to the extent practicable, an equitable geographic distribution among the regions of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H334E59AF01A34B3F9ED69FE19B55E1F8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, and biannually thereafter until the date that is 6 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report on the grant program administered under this section, which shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HDE3C87A285104036B1C2407E3A561FE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">updates on building progress for projects funded by grants awarded under this section, including information on whether projects are complete or experiencing delays;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAD671BFDA36E447A98A8C85F609D948C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impacts of the project on the community; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2789C124DB7241D9B7088D36A46FC42E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>existing project needs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H21FB9D3ADC654526A35E1F57ABBBD039"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this section may not exceed $4,000,000.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC91E07410E1B49F9BA3AF5E6BE708E7D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out this section $250,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2029.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9FF914A83FDC4336B4AE08C6B88AAE7C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall periodically conduct and publish a study of the met and unmet construction and renovation needs of a national sample of child care facilities.</text> </section> </legis-body></bill>

