<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6E7C7271C57D4683BC3D12E705F978BB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7079 IH: Bike the Border Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7079</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To facilitate non-motorized border crossings across the Gordie Howe International Bridge, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD77AA706AF3040578D06E9289D5195CA" style="OLC"><section id="HB8CF0C8B2F05491092F35C1A5C1D2A3D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bike the Border Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HED6E46B525C14C04885F2C7133427FB2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Facilitation of non-motorized border crossings across the Gordie Howe International Bridge</header><subsection id="HB2DFBB7AD2C44E6CAF3ED15B9419FB05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall take such actions as may be necessary to effectively and vigorously facilitate, including through expedition, of non-motorized, including bicycle and pedestrian, border crossings across the Gordie Howe International Bridge.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7617B33B988849CABC7FC30107021C8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that—</text><paragraph id="HC7F6992CD12246A0B72E74A489698362"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reviews the progress of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s handling of non-motorized, including bicycle and pedestrian, traffic across the Gordie Howe International Bridge; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D37468BCE0348F39468A4596758DC47"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text><subparagraph id="H9EC419EFC93644CBA2DB801AA74F2CEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a determination regarding whether U.S. Custom and Border Protection has facilitated, including through expedition, such non-motorized border crossings across the Bridge;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B8981DD54D44E61B5C20DE013985651"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations regarding how U.S. Custom and Border Protection may further such facilitation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9D7433C8A6A43248EFAFF3F0828EDF8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations regarding what, if any, incentives could be utilized to encourage such non-motorized traffic.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

