<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HBDA95136AEC744E787DF5358253BDB46" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5631 : Geothermal Energy Advancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5631</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260603">June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote responsible geothermal energy development on public lands, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBC821682AB4F41FCB525984477F8B89D" style="OLC"><section id="HC64B501DF49C456FADC51AEA153DC39E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Geothermal Energy Advancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H800127BAF1D64757A661371D04BC9C9F" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Effect of pending civil actions on processing applications related to geothermal leasing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4 of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1003">30 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46949C110BB947EE94FE468078216EC6"><subsection id="H37FC0BEBCCB040C0834F62DF90FC2D17" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effect of pending civil actions on processing applications related to geothermal leasing</header><paragraph id="H5D747B8736B646489292CAA2648966D0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement to process applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the existence of any pending civil action that affects an application for a geothermal drilling permit, sundry notice, notice to proceed, right-of-way, or any other authorization under a valid existing geothermal lease, the Secretary shall, unless a United States Federal court vacates or provides injunctive relief for the applicable geothermal lease, geothermal drilling permit, sundry notice, notice to proceed, right-of-way, or other authorization, approve and issue, or deny, each such application not later than 60 days after completing all requirements under applicable Federal laws and regulations, including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8894A4CE3CF4583BB7F31D3CB31E5E1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No new authority for Federal courts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as modifying any existing authority of a Federal court to vacate or provide injunctive relief for a geothermal lease, geothermal drilling permit, sundry notice, notice to proceed, right-of-way, or other authorization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59AA536ECD9D4EFE8B4B827FB2BF0247" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>authorization</term> means any license, permit, approval, finding, determination, or other administrative decision issued by a Federal agency, or any interagency consultation, that is required or authorized under Federal law or regulations in order to site, construct, reconstruct, or commence operations of a geothermal project administered by a Federal agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H2FA671457F93492F87FB6936F871F695"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cost recovery from geothermal leasing, permitting, and inspections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1005">30 U.S.C. 1005</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAED44718F0EF4DBB890EAB5282B78211" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H04C57399A7FB487B92F805A73954D605"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Cost recovery</header><paragraph id="H6B814ECA917C45ECBA90580B462EE38B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the period that begins on the date of enactment of this subsection and ends September 30, 2033, the Secretary may require an applicant for, or a holder of, a geothermal lease to reimburse the United States for all reasonable administrative and other costs incurred by the United States from—</text><subparagraph id="H7BE4A281F1F648E69B53DD55DE28BEAD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">processing the application for the geothermal lease, including any application for an operations plan, geothermal drilling permit, utilization plan, site license, facility construction permit, commercial use permit, and any other approval associated with a geothermal lease; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD076FC5C7934CD18B4DF4B5040C41FC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inspecting and monitoring—</text><clause id="H0A0ABB1B898F44829F1FEA606F6AF89E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>geophysical exploration activities;</text></clause><clause id="HEAF0B93F93054D0CB4E464CDC167C6E5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the drilling, plugging, and abandonment of wells; and</text></clause><clause id="H92466EAF5D4049D6B290BE121C1066DA" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the construction, operation, termination, and reclamation of any well site or facility for the utilization of geothermal resources pursuant to the geothermal lease.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AF6D707E7794477BB32A29F6DA07EF4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to require reimbursement under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider whether there is in existence a cooperative cost share agreement between the United States and the holder of a geothermal lease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F1E9FFE4E9D4C77B4BA1189582101F3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><text>The Secretary may reduce the amount to be reimbursed under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines—</text><subparagraph id="H3F07661C5FBB4DB08AA78B1223CD4D34" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that full reimbursement would impose an economic hardship on the applicant; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E0BF73067ED47FC81BC14F525AB79E8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that a less than full reimbursement is necessary to promote the greatest use of geothermal resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H725AC2BA6D6D4667A7F111942D87C0E5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use</header><text>The amounts reimbursed under this subsection shall be credited to the currently applicable appropriation, account, or fund of the Department of the Interior as discretionary offsetting collections, and shall be available only to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts for—</text><subparagraph id="HBA1BAF8F91E2473EAAB7E8FB3E53E382" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">processing the application for geothermal leases, including any application for operations plans, geothermal drilling permits, utilization plans, site licenses, facility construction permits, commercial use permits, and any other approval associated with geothermal leases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8454F26140F7472380038AAABAE21CA0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inspecting and monitoring—</text><clause id="H10745CA152784229AF560AB0B7DA11F5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>geophysical exploration activities;</text></clause><clause id="HCC2037C141E3423B83F1B5F01E98A5ED" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the drilling, plugging, and abandonment of wells; and</text></clause><clause id="H255DFB342F1D4D04944640855568FB18" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the construction, operation, termination, and reclamation of any well site or facility for the utilization of geothermal resources pursuant to geothermal leases.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HA1B8D7E1D3A24879A93B513B29D48A9E" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H40B1B9F6FE9948B280885CFCCB46AEEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the geothermal industry and other stakeholders, shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and make publicly available on the website of the Department of the Interior, a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H8BE10B968DF64DE49ACA07008863BFFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of how the amendments made by section 3 of this Act affected the Bureau of Land Management’s geothermal program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C54461C33CF4284A096AEA42DE4F2CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendations for reauthorization of section 6(j) of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970, as added by this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7F8549EBB8F4368B63897BC5E96ECE2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other recommendations for updates to such section and the Bureau of Land Management’s geothermal program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1D9CE70270E4BC1A32A6F70CEE77D3E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the report required in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Interior shall solicit facts or information from the geothermal industry and other stakeholders.</text></subsection></section><section id="H68AC67BC493147D88BCC225654E09883"><enum>5.</enum><header>Publication of <quote>Gold Book</quote> for geothermal operations on Federal lands</header><subsection id="H8C68A7527AC24E87AFB5055F6AD8DA24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with other relevant Federal agencies, shall identify standard procedures and guidelines for efficient and environmentally responsible geothermal leasing and permitting to the extent such standard procedures and guidelines are not addressed in the fourth edition of the Bureau of Land Management’s <quote>Surface Operating Standards and Guidelines for Oil and Gas Exploration and Development</quote>, commonly known as the <quote>Gold Book</quote> and last revised in 2007.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8F0A8D98D6E9457889136EFF4587695C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication</header><paragraph id="HBBA9F78E132940379F1821E041898DBE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after identifying standard procedures and guidelines under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Interior shall publish an updated version of the Gold Book incorporating any changes necessary to support efficient and environmentally responsible geothermal leasing and permitting for use by the field offices of the Bureau of Land Management and geothermal operators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC2F8586C3BE440E945DD3C11A297BF4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renaming Gold Book</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall rename the Gold Book to reflect the incorporation of standard procedures and guidelines related to geothermal development.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H109768C3443D41E28CA1954D5D1EDF19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before publishing an updated version of the Gold Book, the Secretary of the Interior shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="H360651DB6D594AA49FFA737989C94F0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>other relevant Federal agencies, including field offices of the Bureau of Land Management; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5CDEE02A6874F9EA90523D6805A698A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>outside stakeholders, including developers and other experts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54E2E59BAAB44335979530EAF1308CD0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each updated version of the Gold Book shall include standard procedures and guidelines for ensuring the efficient review and approval of environmentally responsible geothermal development, including—</text><paragraph id="H39E7BD0BC4814DA1BE88E9F47D70586E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>exploration and geophysical operations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA805E6AB7824BD5AA56A5A6E6AC149F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>permitting lease operations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11421A044167403FA74AFA371294CD7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>compliance with all applicable laws and regulations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB14EFB8B74A64D6ABD8C166955041916"><enum>(4)</enum><text>construction and maintenance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H325CFA741D8A4886BFCEF658B45D9E06" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">drilling, production, and utilization operations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64E2B7E4C7954AF68A8C27D3975C943D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Periodic revision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall—</text><paragraph id="H591FFC83F7FA4229BE68D3A78E9841C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least once every five years, review the most recent version of the Gold Book; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0FF144B767D4C92A71A85FD6116EB57"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if determined necessary by the Secretary of the Interior to support efficient and environmentally responsible geothermal leasing and permitting, publish an updated version of the Gold Book.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE2D2E52901AE4A13AB6280AF1D2E3FB1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Geothermal ombudsman and permitting task force</header><subsection id="H7E1E339B78544B4FBB2066BCE78C4DAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3E4E75EC34494A7ABD78203083E69A9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Geothermal authorization</header><text>The term <term>geothermal authorization</term> means any license, permit, approval, finding, determination, or other administrative decision issued by the Bureau of Land Management and any interagency consultation that is required or authorized under Federal law in order to site, construct, reconstruct, or commence operations of a geothermal energy project administered by the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF023ACF5B8A41FCBFFCD48BCD271821" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geothermal energy project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>geothermal energy project</term> means a project wholly or partially located on public land that uses geothermal energy to generate heat or electricity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95B9D7D9D0804EFFA78772450DFFA96F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public Land</header><text>The term <term>public land</term> means lands subject to geothermal leasing under section 3 of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1002">30 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EC7FF8C17524E79B72052DAE333832E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30510C60C579468A93F0D2AE73B3755C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Task force</header><text>The term <term>Task Force</term> means the Geothermal Permitting Task Force established under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE97227F957E74C3B92035CCDE43B46C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Geothermal ombudsman</header><paragraph id="H94626B57ECF343A6B784A6DAD7E59652"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall appoint from within the Bureau of Land Management a Geothermal Ombudsman.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC6CF07B300E46A1A746850F3A160732"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Geothermal Ombudsman appointed under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H5D8E36FEAFD94B8D80E85A90A3ED75C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>act as a liaison between—</text><clause id="HA85A2909EA254BF8874695FFB0095202"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the individual field, district, and State offices of the Bureau of Land Management;</text></clause><clause id="H6A161CB4CF4A40EAACC04D3AF919D3D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Division Chief of the National Renewable Energy Coordination Office of the Bureau of Land Management; and</text></clause><clause id="HB8452C748B474345AB1A131E96F3FFAC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Director of the Bureau of Land Management;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98069F5F7CE94E6CBA9C6B64BBEA4F4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide dispute resolution services between the individual field, district, and State offices of the Bureau of Land Management and applicants for geothermal authorizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82039AEBA2764E5EAFC80A9277DAB6AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>monitor and facilitate permit processing practices and timelines across individual field offices of the Bureau of Land Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E0A6A3CF50443C487D4E4C4B0E9869D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>develop best practices for the permitting and leasing process for geothermal resources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65F8B3798D3B4058A55E3A4F78FD220F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinate with the Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB01D87B71A1471AB40236E2ED19F5D2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Geothermal permitting task force</header><paragraph id="HCD1AE1FDFE2343DD842B8C2D6E3EB279"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish within the Bureau of Land Management a Geothermal Permitting Task Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA132EB9312E4788A39A50B9C5820EC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text>The Task Force shall be headed by the Geothermal Ombudsman appointed under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6953455438B14D8AA33F2F529B39D08D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Permitting support</header><text>The Task Force shall support the duties of the Geothermal Ombudsman appointed under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4183542D12F54D4793FF210A92DB01EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cross-office personnel assignments</header><subparagraph id="H6716DB420F084AC0822AF5053BB0299E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In their capacity as head of the Task Force, the Geothermal Ombudsman may coordinate with any Departmental bureau or office to assign personnel with relevant expertise to assist with completion of geothermal authorizations in field, district, or State offices other than the official duty station where such personnel are located if—</text><clause id="HAB09659AD0CF484D8A9A0E1A1ED723E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Departmental bureau or office determines that such assignment will not materially delay ongoing completion of authorizations within the office where the employee is located; and</text></clause><clause id="H048EE96BFFD440CFAED57ED1C54F574E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>approval is received from the head of the official duty station where the assigned employee is located.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H271DC90D929646B5B522E7973B34912D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assigned personnel requirements</header><text>Department personnel assigned to assist with completion of geothermal authorizations under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="H6DDBF297AEAD489CB94F48830B38B73F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>work in-person full-time at an official Department office;</text></clause><clause id="HC27A887482694CDB9C13E2CE08E11220"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if necessary as determined by the Geothermal Ombudsman, travel to the Bureau of Land Management field, district, or State office with jurisdiction over the geothermal authorization to which the employee has been assigned by the Geothermal Ombudsman;</text></clause><clause id="HA7708142793F4931A3D119F6E62A0078"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>participate as part of the team of personnel working on geothermal authorizations to which the employee has been assigned by the Geothermal Ombudsman; and</text></clause><clause id="HEA2605E00FEC474DB4E1AC5672AE59AE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>regularly report to the head of the field, district, or State office of the Bureau of Land Management with jurisdiction over geothermal authorizations to which the employee has been assigned by the Geothermal Ombudsman.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41C73BF449C84B69957C9A830A6801FC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Retention allowances</header><clause id="H664D7F7288E94228879B5FC76D0BEB6C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Geothermal Ombudsman may pay a retention allowance to an employee assigned to assist with the completion of geothermal authorizations under subparagraph (A). Retention allowances—</text><subclause id="H8B4974937B654D3099B638941B07E3D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall be stated as the percentage of the rate of basic pay of an employee, and may not exceed 25 percent of such rate of basic pay;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC26A3BDA67DC47FCABB5A22A5BB85CAD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may not be considered to be part of the basic pay of an employee, and the reduction or elimination of a retention allowance may not be appealed; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H770E88AA545A42D38C2BFBC3537C27F6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>shall be paid at the same time and in the same manner as the employee’s basic pay is paid.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB127329F3B6648ECB8B083197A6AFE03"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In exercising the retention allowance authority described in clause (i), the Geothermal Ombudsman shall consider—</text><subclause id="H91DF8FD27F25497C9F805F2812FE11C8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an employee’s specialized expertise related to geothermal authorizations;</text></subclause><subclause id="H8FF30844C4574D1B88E73DA39EA97BC3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the demonstrated need to retain an employee to meet the performance improvement objectives for geothermal authorization timelines and develop best practices for completion of geothermal authorizations; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H1F69A4E4F68742C8BA1E1F6FE76596DF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the difficulty in recruiting or replacing qualified personnel with relevant expertise related to geothermal authorizations.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H929B6A0A0A7E408E9A39CFF58B650386"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Cross-office personnel assignments carried out under this paragraph shall not alter the underlying jurisdiction of other offices of the Bureau of Land Management over applicable geothermal authorizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC426DF336EBF417EB5AA72DED36A39FC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Geothermal Ombudsman shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives an annual report that describes the activities of the Task Force and evaluates the effectiveness of geothermal permit processing during the preceding 1-year period.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBC5F7DD7ACAC4B5DB44F52DB6EC2976B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Geothermal royalties</header><subsection id="HC12AC47CBAA041EC8018C508712DC723" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1001">30 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAEAA3D75A2604787A463014D56703E6C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HEFFAECCB77A4425280632730CE7F4EF7" commented="no" indent="down1"><enum>(h)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>Geothermal electric generating facility</quote> means a facility, including all necessary equipment or structures (including turbines and cooling equipment), that produces electricity using geothermal resources. For purposes of section 5(a)(1), a facility described in the preceding sentence shall be considered a separate facility from any other such facility unless the facility shares a turbine with any other such facility.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3A6CB50033454EE9B8044D4B344D13C2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="down1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>In-service date</quote> means, with respect to a geothermal electric generating facility, the date on which the geothermal electric generating facility begins operating.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H23E0228051134C80A8BCE8025B7CDECB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Geothermal royalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5(a)(1) of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1004">30 U.S.C. 1004(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4C576DAFDB5E4FA090F5F40F653C3077"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subparagraph id="H6FA857F0E2034279A34E185EDEF8DA56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>with respect to a geothermal electric generating facility producing electricity from such resources,</quote> before <quote>not less than</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE5853CA4BB74E07BC2EB5A4DA54D33D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>by the geothermal electric generating facility</quote> after <quote>produced</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63F468F7EA414E838DEBC5161AA87515" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>the first 10 years of production under the lease</quote> and inserting <quote>each year of the 10-year period following the in-service date of the geothermal electric generating facility</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51B26F582FDD46A68ADBC79D1DD2965B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subparagraph id="H838CF8C1B9A24FB5BE2E90EB355E3FFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>with respect to a geothermal electric generating facility producing electricity from such resources,</quote> before <quote>not less than</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19870E7FD5844ACCB61D587E421805D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>by the geothermal electric generating facility</quote> after <quote>produced</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H723C607A6AFD4F76850770224DA3324B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>such 10-year period</quote> and inserting <quote>the period of 10 years described in subparagraph (A)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA6DBE957B43E4EB79E861265772223D9"><enum>8.</enum><header>NEPA review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 390 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15942">42 U.S.C. 15942</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H20E2CE35722B4567B852C0F25C029F4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>, or the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1001">30 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) for the purpose of exploration or development of geothermal resources</quote> after <quote>or gas</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA47E5068DC34F1FB4F0F3028E64ACF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H34EA0F0B84744899B7559C39A39EF99E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>or gas</quote> and inserting <quote>, gas, or geothermal</quote>; and</text><pagebreak></pagebreak></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H074616602FEC488E88A66CF169C21128"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>or gas</quote> and inserting <quote>, gas, or geothermal</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260602" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 2, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

