<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HBDA95136AEC744E787DF5358253BDB46" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5631 RH: Geothermal Ombudsman for National Deployment and Optimal Reviews Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 574</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5631</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–660]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on September 30, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To appoint a Geothermal Ombudsman and establish a Geothermal Permitting Task Force from within the Bureau of Land Management, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H674E72AE90074DAF91F769AB25B96EB1"><section id="H0BB827869D174ACBB8978E4DDB6EC4E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Geothermal Ombudsman for National Deployment and Optimal Reviews Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H01568E8B923F43B4A53654ED767F8B46"><enum>2.</enum><header>Geothermal ombudsman and permitting task force</header><subsection id="H793C72704FAF4D558303B5027DBCE5DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HBB1E8AB0697B460796A22FDA748BEC23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Geothermal authorization</header><text>The term <term>geothermal authorization</term> means any license, permit, approval, finding, determination, or other administrative decision issued by the Bureau of Land Management and any interagency consultation that is required or authorized under Federal law in order to site, construct, reconstruct, or commence operations of a geothermal energy project administered by the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7377248B692B44148311F71A11E0FB2C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geothermal energy project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>geothermal energy project</term> means a project wholly or partially located on public land that uses geothermal energy to generate heat or electricity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H451CE896D05B472BA144A2CC3CFD94FF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public Land</header><text>The term <term>public land</term> means lands subject to geothermal leasing under section 3 of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1002">30 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6AFE15BF2DD4AA6BC9748277D8A9A18"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56CB0B6B7E7048E2889D36989542956F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Task force</header><text>The term <term>Task Force</term> means the Geothermal Permitting Task Force established under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAFBD26DD9D0E40F7BF4F2A3A276FC5AE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Geothermal ombudsman</header><paragraph id="H8D4EFCF33BA343A8832ECAA65ECBD522"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall appoint from within the Bureau of Land Management a Geothermal Ombudsman.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91AD2B1BA6674AFF9C36C6D6E220A299"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Geothermal Ombudsman appointed under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H4AF03AEBDCA94038B8A71578A69BBE90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>act as a liaison between—</text><clause id="H37AD8EDE716C4C999C527488D069A14B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the individual field, district, and State offices of the Bureau of Land Management;</text></clause><clause id="HABE5166FD68F4B99B8964D900705626D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Division Chief of the National Renewable Energy Coordination Office of the Bureau of Land Management; and</text></clause><clause id="H7C3D16321A8340218655B99F269A28D2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Director of the Bureau of Land Management;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46EB155579134B70A71EADC1C4D3DABC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide dispute resolution services between the individual field, district, and State offices of the Bureau of Land Management and applicants for geothermal authorizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4545A9163E1841689E7F134E83FAD54A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>monitor and facilitate permit processing practices and timelines across individual field offices of the Bureau of Land Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H277F699C32A3402CBF0C968B45582ACF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>develop best practices for the permitting and leasing process for geothermal resources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H371AFFC8818D43DAB9D4D9493141D430"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinate with the Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF82B30378AD74C00AFAAE6131CB467FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Geothermal permitting task force</header><paragraph id="H1F9045E51E1F4AE0A3EFD33DA7BC1F65"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish within the Bureau of Land Management a Geothermal Permitting Task Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H043FD4AA5594486FB9663D3BAD6E5BF5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text>The Task Force shall be headed by the Geothermal Ombudsman appointed under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF9D239484404DD482F8AD756447FC7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Permitting support</header><text>The Task Force shall support the duties of the Geothermal Ombudsman appointed under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7452CAEFBA4F423F89BC53650AB164A3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cross-office personnel assignments</header><subparagraph id="H211FF5B7A2284F9DADA71605E3B7FE8B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In their capacity as head of the Task Force, the Geothermal Ombudsman may coordinate with any Departmental bureau or office to assign personnel with relevant expertise to assist with completion of geothermal authorizations in field, district, or State offices other than the official duty station where such personnel are located if—</text><clause id="HF4CD63B7C5224B9389BCE3991683B18E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Departmental bureau or office determines that such assignment will not materially delay ongoing completion of authorizations within the office where the employee is located; and</text></clause><clause id="H5ACCA83E36F34FF3B9997E235849F93B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>approval is received from the head of the official duty station where the assigned employee is located.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD453EF8BA5648E3AD28A7C85BE287D3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assigned personnel requirements</header><text>Department personnel assigned to assist with completion of geothermal authorizations under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="HC85F844C9B6E4BB486317864D467580F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>work in-person full-time at an official Department office;</text></clause><clause id="HE2FAE05229F84BE688F42DC21B38C54B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if necessary as determined by the Geothermal Ombudsman, travel to the Bureau of Land Management field, district, or State office with jurisdiction over the geothermal authorization to which the employee has been assigned by the Geothermal Ombudsman;</text></clause><clause id="HE1C9A61742664BA697543992018DBEB0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>participate as part of the team of personnel working on geothermal authorizations to which the employee has been assigned by the Geothermal Ombudsman; and</text></clause><clause id="H377524C045234D179931B415B0C4902B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>regularly report to the head of the field, district, or State office of the Bureau of Land Management with jurisdiction over geothermal authorizations to which the employee has been assigned by the Geothermal Ombudsman.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA114A531EAFE4A14BB695DD89230DE71"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Retention allowances</header><clause id="H799A3B264D9F4A3A9F362C4E87195F50"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Geothermal Ombudsman may pay a retention allowance to an employee assigned to assist with the completion of geothermal authorizations under subparagraph (A). Retention allowances—</text><subclause id="H0242833B4687431686E5E71FB6871917"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall be stated as the percentage of the rate of basic pay of an employee, and may not exceed 25 percent of such rate of basic pay;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE845248D22E2488D9507C9295FF06BD9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may not be considered to be part of the basic pay of an employee, and the reduction or elimination of a retention allowance may not be appealed; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3B286335252D4C0BB7FE927730F527B4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>shall be paid at the same time and in the same manner as the employee’s basic pay is paid.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB3A27F8F4F42441699D670B3FB867714"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In exercising the retention allowance authority described in clause (i), the Geothermal Ombudsman shall consider—</text><subclause id="H2E19EC51FC274F739AAC801FA2C34ABE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an employee’s specialized expertise related to geothermal authorizations;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD77EF01C765D46ADAD522211154E5FC8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the demonstrated need to retain an employee to meet the performance improvement objectives for geothermal authorization timelines and develop best practices for completion of geothermal authorizations; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HEAC2C095BB0444218329A6B9A87E05D4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the difficulty in recruiting or replacing qualified personnel with relevant expertise related to geothermal authorizations.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F6AC1D79F144FFF92DE42FFA0503603"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Cross-office personnel assignments carried out under this paragraph shall not alter the underlying jurisdiction of other offices of the Bureau of Land Management over applicable geothermal authorizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H995979216BA141BCB0F5FE914F079DC2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Geothermal Ombudsman shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives an annual report that describes the activities of the Task Force and evaluates the effectiveness of geothermal permit processing during the preceding 1-year period.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

