<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25L27-P49-CP-MGK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3511 IS: Permit Reform In Mining for Energy and Defense Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3511</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require that certain actions taken by the Secretary of Defense be treated as an eligible transportation project, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HDC8D162865054FF7A61020AF44509AA6"><section section-type="section-one" id="H0C5CADBB97CB4A41A034B4A340CD2296"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Permit Reform In Mining for Energy and Defense Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PRIMED Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H71F72D2C70F646B28D6273E893359AC8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of certain actions by Secretary of Defense under the Defense Production Act of 1950 for Federal permitting improvement purposes</header><subsection id="H6108206AD7AD4D539217DBDF2DD60784"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), an action described in subsection (b) shall be—</text><paragraph id="HFFCF462FA5B541558F45983E98EC66E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>treated as a covered project, as defined in section 41001(6) of the FAST Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4370m">42 U.S.C. 4370m(6)</external-xref>), without regard to whether the action would qualify as a covered project under that section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H527A3817B3694B3EAD1F184ABECF70CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>included in the Permitting Dashboard maintained pursuant to section 41003(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4370m-2">42 U.S.C. 4370m–2(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EE4A806BBEB4447A7DA1CD959DEF169"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions described</header><text>An action described in this subsection is an action taken by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to Presidential Determination 2022–11 (87 Fed. Reg. 19775; relating to certain actions under section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950) or the Presidential Memorandum of February 27, 2023, titled <quote>Presidential Waiver of Statutory Requirements Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Department of Defense Supply Chains Resilience</quote> (88 Fed. Reg. 13015) to create, maintain, protect, expand, or restore sustainable and responsible domestic production capabilities through—</text><paragraph id="H1C23D44123794692AD1B6187FA201C70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting feasibility studies for mature mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H205C13AA530E4B05BF813322C2CD1489"><enum>(2)</enum><text>byproduct and co-product production at existing mining, mine waste reclamation, and other industrial facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17456BA522D7457B8275A7CE5BFBF05C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modernization of mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing to increase productivity, environmental sustainability, and workforce safety; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC94B8274F9BB4EE69623FC24CF7E834B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other activity authorized under section 303(a)(1) of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4533">50 U.S.C. 4533(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01B1A61D6F114F4997A8F09347E3DB99"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>An action described in subsection (b) may not be treated as a covered project or be included in the Permitting Dashboard under subsection (a) if the project sponsor (as defined in section 41001(18) of the FAST Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4370m">42 U.S.C. 4370m(18)</external-xref>)) requests that the action not be treated as a covered project.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

