<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25126-8PC-JM-PMW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 446 ATS: Recognizing the 250th birthday of the United States Navy.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 446</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251009">October 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to </action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 250th birthday of the United States Navy.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on October 13, 1775, the Continental Congress, representing the citizens of the 13 American colonies, passed a resolution establishing a Continental Navy to protect North American trade from British blockades and predation and to intercept British ships carrying supplies for British forces in North America;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the founders recognized the essential nature of a Navy to the strength and longevity of the country by providing authority to Congress <quote>To provide and maintain a Navy</quote> in article I, section 8 of the Constitution of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Continental Navy began a proud tradition, carried out for the last 250 years by the United States Navy, to protect the interests of the United States on, under, and above the seas, projecting American values and maintaining the freedom of navigation across the globe;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of the date of this resolution, the United States Navy is a global force of more than 290 ships, 3,700 aircraft, and 590,000 active duty, reserve, and civilian personnel;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Navy’s Sailors, past and present, have demonstrated unmatched courage, skill, and dedication during every major conflict in the history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Navy has played a vital role in humanitarian missions, disaster relief, deterrence, and diplomacy, fostering peace and stability in regions far beyond the shores of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Navy remains at the forefront of technological innovation, all-domain warfare, and strategic deterrence in the 21st century;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Navy’s core values of <quote>Honor, Courage, and Commitment</quote> have guided generations of Sailors and reflect the enduring spirit of service to the country;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Navy’s 250th birthday provides an opportunity to recognize the sacrifices of Navy families, veterans, and civilians who have supported the fleet and fought for the maritime superiority of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas communities across the United States continue to provide critical industrial and workforce support to sustain fleet readiness and national defense; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, whether in peace or at war, the people of the United States can rest assured that their Navy is on watch, ever vigilant, and ready to respond when and where it is needed: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ida6328110b601437f88e2fffc1cd1d5ef"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the historic significance of the 250th birthday of the United States Navy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a6863a9ce0b48fd950d144521b7368c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses the appreciation of the people of the United States to the men and women of the Navy, past and present, for their 250 years of dedicated service and defense of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8420f51eb1e44a2aa5c67f958fc0b85e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the Senate’s commitment to supporting the United States Navy as a vital instrument of national power and global stability.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

