<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8D5C71E8E5AD4711840B39CC22C50F98" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9270 IH: Dignity and Due Process for Children Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000197">Ms. Pelosi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001094">Ms. Hoyle of Oregon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001246">Ms. Mejia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address the enforcement of the immigration laws with respect to unaccompanied minors.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2E04100894754DB9A830D4442F3EBC36" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9C68F6B29E9847FFBE6CE8ED792AE34E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dignity and Due Process for Children Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H12B0DD3822314E56A17CC8C2C38B35B8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enforcement of immigration laws with respect to unaccompanied alien children</header> 
<subsection id="HCDB15EA13E2443EC981F9A7CE482442F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H406359E921BE4EF88336CD79B2144F61" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H91560C68E858437DB31BF92157065E97"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien under 18 years of age, encountered by an immigration officer encountered in the United States beyond a border or port of entry without a parent or legal guardian at the time of such encounter, may not be arrested or detained pending a decision on whether such alien is to be removed from the United States unless a warrant is issued for such arrest by an immigration judge.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF5F7C4A282F741FE9E53FC0494ABA543"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on military transport</header> 
<paragraph id="HBA2747460F8F47C9A771E73EEE19713C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HEBA40E5F4E3F4CEE856052F5F5357AE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no member of the Armed Forces, or contractor of the Department of Defense, may be deployed or otherwise used to transport an unaccompanied alien child for the purpose of enforcing the immigration laws, including any deportation, expulsion, or removal; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF565D9ECCE5245B798F1A1AF34447BC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no vessel, aircraft, or vehicle owned or operated by the Department of Defense may be used for such transport.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCEA2127AB2984F2DBAEE4B7CB4DA185F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to the use or deployment of a member of the Armed Forces, or the use of a vessel, aircraft, or vehicle specified in such paragraph, in a location in the United States under a presidential declaration under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) in response to a natural disaster or other weather-related event.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD0E73C845738471183DE2544C294712A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Representation requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or the head of any other agency, as applicable, shall not require or in any way induce or coerce an unaccompanied alien child to sign any legal document impacting their custody, placement, or immigration status to waive their right to a hearing or the opportunity to file applications for immigration relief, accept removal or voluntary return, accept criminal liability, or concede to removability without a meaningful opportunity to consult confidentially with a lawyer. If the child does not have a lawyer, the government shall immediately provide the child a referral to and ensure the child is provided an opportunity to consult confidentially with a legal services provider at the earliest point practicable and not more than 5 business days after the date on which the agency presents the unaccompanied alien child with the legal document.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF97CD78B9FC64918894F51D3E5097FAE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to supersede the Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7101">22 U.S.C. 7101</external-xref> note).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H7BA62F65025A4DBE8C2C31128F56737B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2573A1F96C204AC0AC5494C23DF372B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Immigration laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>immigration laws</term> shall have the definition given such term in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA81437D95A0645E3A9F0F6F210D5B1B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unaccompanied alien child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unaccompanied alien child</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 462(g) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279(g)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

