<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF34D98B24FF94BC0993A3E14A9C4F318" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9664 IH: K–9 Hero Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9664</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the establishment of a grant program to assist with certain veterinary expenses of retired Federal working dogs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H36F6999C5ADE439A903D54300A416788" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB6A764F0FA0A4A93A50087546034C1FD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>K–9 Hero Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4E08530D5A5143ECAECD69717081124B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0920C669BA4445D79804A3ECCEA7E589">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2022, the Government Accountability Office report titled <quote>Working Dogs: Federal Agencies Need to Better Address Health and Welfare</quote> (GAO–23–104489) included a finding that, as of 2022, approximately 5,100 working dogs were managed pursuant to 40 Federal programs, including as follows:</text>
        <subparagraph id="HC97D4A3954104D548C96ED2F154AEADB">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>2,942 for the Department of Homeland Security, including—</text> <clause id="HA43B3DB3D1D9486EB5E162C02372192F"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1,097 for the Transportation Security Administration, carrying out duties relating to explosives detection;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H7FAE151C89F34443B12AABBF975F08F4">
            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">863 for the United States Border Patrol of United States Customs and Border Protection, carrying out duties relating to human detection;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="HD976E910E0044A9D88A7F80121F8E6C6">
            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">498 for the Office of Field Operations of United States Customs and Border Protection, carrying out duties relating to human detection;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H1280869920FE41F6AD27D9162B04B9AF">
            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">151 for the Office of Training and Development of United States Customs and Border Protection, carrying out duties relating to human detection;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="HD597071013BA4F5099D75DBE5A06E9ED">
            <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">130 for the elements of United States Customs and Border Protection involved in agriculture activities, carrying out duties relating to disease surveillance;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="H0A6D978804AC4A728E22FEF3B4068AEE">
            <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>111 for the United States Secret Service;</text> </clause> <clause id="HAF46425DE0724D9190F939CF067FA05D"> <enum>(vii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">70 for the Federal Protective Service, carrying out duties relating to explosives detection;</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="HC950EC6469FF46D1B468031A23886CB8">
            <enum>(viii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">18 for the United States Coast Guard, carrying out duties relating to explosives detection; and</text>
          </clause>
          <clause id="HA1E213F3ED1A482A906A1A947669E162">
            <enum>(ix)</enum>
 <text>4 for the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE859B9E8F7B04AC29D0A0666FD01091D"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>564 for the Air Force.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H240EDDEB150244788859B578B88C660F">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">469 for the Army.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76836F53E3904287B21F45FEA0E17286"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">319 for the Navy.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H7D4A44427D9B4491A6F4A98F05CD695A">
          <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">189 for the Marine Corps.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78696943464D4CDA9F4CA43BC844D4D8"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">140 for the United States Special Operations Command.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H03367A75331045FAB19EBF42834D6836">
          <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">32 for the National Security Agency.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA664F342BFEB494283233EC4ECC69943"> <enum>(H)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">24 for the Pentagon Force Protection Agency.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="HDEFB7DD5BA994D0AAEBAAD09BA82E62B">
          <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">19 for the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H56692FE511AA48038ED1DFF318FC83B9">
          <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">9 for the National Guard Bureau.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87BE1A3B486744F1AD45288C8483A1EC"> <enum>(K)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">4 for the Defense Intelligence Agency.</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F66119A737C4E508998A306C1A43630">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report of the Government Accountability Office titled <quote>Medical Conditions and Care for End-of-Service Military Working Dogs</quote> (GAO–17–358), issued in 2017, included a finding that the average cost of care for a retired military working dog is an average of $1,182 per fiscal year, excluding the cost for specialty medical expenses required for such dogs, such as extensive surgeries from service-related injuries, medical supplements vital for health, and treatments for other illnesses accumulated through service.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H964DC50DE5DB4CD58C2145FE2331CF40"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Owners of retired Federal working dogs are therefore required to rely on nonprofit organizations to assist in paying for such medical expenses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0120D3B03DFA41B6BE32584A2FA89AB6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Nonprofit organizations secure funds for such payments to owners via fundraising and donors, but do not always receive the necessary amount of funds to assist owners in covering such medical expenses.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H539FF516DCF14D24BAE462B64C61F032"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Awarding Federal grants to such nonprofits for such payments to owners would ensure the coverage of such necessary amounts.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H1A7D8A12BD5C41859DCDB1F4DC63D55F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant program for certain medical expenses of retired Federal working dogs</header> <subsection id="HD4225849174B4DC8AA8FEACBD38D48EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2026, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly carry out a program under which the Secretaries, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, may award grants to eligible nonprofit organizations to assist with the covered medical expenses of retired Federal working dogs (in this section referred to as the <quote>program</quote>).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFE352B721D97402FB194841F3206AC1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonprofit organization is eligible to receive a grant under the program if the primary activities of the nonprofit organization are to provide care for retired Federal working dogs or financial assistance to the owners of such dogs for the purpose of covering the costs of covered medical expenses.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9DA8E13D7E654B12A445C6721EDFC50E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To receive a grant under the program, an eligible nonprofit organization shall submit to the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretaries may require, including information that demonstrates that the nonprofit organization meets the eligibility requirements under such subsection.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDAE2F05372E94B73A20C7AC3801EDB0D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations on grant amounts</header> 
<paragraph id="HF2F142CA9E234F44B273366586A417A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Total amount limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total amount of grants awarded under the program to an eligible nonprofit organization may not exceed $1,000,000 per fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D457ABB72F64194B9AECD7E1322FE5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reduction in grant amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an eligible nonprofit organization does not expend the full amount of a grant awarded to such organization under the program for a fiscal year, the grant amount awarded for any subsequent fiscal year shall be reduced by an amount equal to such unexpended amount.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF4438A3B3E44776901222A2F07A02D7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of grant amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under the program may only be used for the purpose of covering the costs of covered medical expenses of retired Federal working dogs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2E00C739040C42059A6406C12FF57A6A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Oversight</header> <paragraph id="H15BDF6048D844A24AB9EF8F417E2830A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H44ADFD1B068C45A6938DE9442343A3D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop data and statistics relating to health outcomes for retired Federal working dogs, to be used by eligible nonprofit organizations that receive a grant under the program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59E405380A1A4C6BA9C197A46777C74C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish processes to monitor and document the amount of funding necessary to support a retired Federal working dog with respect to covered medical expenses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11D95879C1E24CB793EB110989538221"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collection of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall collect such information from eligible nonprofit organizations that receive a grant under the program as the Secretaries determine appropriate to monitor and evaluate the use of grants, including to monitor health outcomes for each retired Federal working dog supported by such a grant over a five-year period following the receipt of such grant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H000818EA78674AD7AE32BDA7FFAA1D7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recipient reports required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of receiving a grant under the program, an eligible nonprofit organization shall agree to submit to the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, on an annual basis for the duration of the period during which the eligible nonprofit organization uses such grant amounts, a report describing the purposes for which such amounts were used.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1D5B6D9CB90646E495B41E70381994C5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2027, and on an annual basis thereafter until September 30, 2031, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of the program. Such report shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H3198995C4D4845AE83711009AB59EEE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the number of retired Federal working dogs supported pursuant to a grant awarded under the program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA428C07ACCE4D36AD3EA0CEDF1009BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the average annual covered expenses for each retired Federal working dog supported pursuant to such a grant, and a description of how the Secretaries used such average to determine grant amounts.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00AAB858E92A4AB38F2B55FE65655193"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the disbursement of grant amounts awarded under the program with respect to categories of retired Federal working dogs and eligible nonprofit organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H19C394A5E6354CACA6D121B2E7263A4D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the program $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA94902AA7FCB4B30853FFA87FC9FE3B3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0EAFBD4C1F4B473CAEB0F68A4E5FE861"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB7F24C849A5046D7BE85F5AAB6698D80"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80F5662E284D45408F09A69E2147D12B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73A909544D0249F8AD6DB08F8FBDE3BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>average annual covered expenses</quote> means the average amount of covered expenses for a retired Federal working dog during a fiscal year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE4215BAB0C6438A80425C35B35BD4D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered expense</quote> means any expense that derives from medical treatment or health care provided to a retired Federal working dog, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H13A2C33622C1410D8750B1C390AD8B4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any expense resulting from the treatment by a veterinarian of an injury, illness, or other health condition, regardless of whether such condition manifested in such dog during the period in which such dog conducted work on behalf of a Federal department or agency; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCD9D2CD6F6A04F8CAD667EA4E9A6A5F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any expense relating to a medical procedure, diagnostic test, medication, medical supplement, or dietary alternative necessary to preserve and maintain the health of such dog.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H116C60973D904C60A9816A30A42A85DD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>eligible nonprofit organization</quote> means a nonprofit organization that meets the eligibility criteria under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B63A60586234677AD19BAA4B703DFB2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>retired Federal working dog</quote> means any dog previously owned and managed by a Federal department or agency and assigned work on behalf of such department or agency, that is retired from such work.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

