<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB5AD828B753C4BAE82053BBF091A6EE8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6058 IH: Semiconductor Technology Resilience, Integrity, and Defense Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6058</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251117">November 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for multilateral semiconductor technology supply chain coordination, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0250344EE295424AA98DDF32061BDDAA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1F61F33C083E4609898F64B4A8044C9D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Semiconductor Technology Resilience, Integrity, and Defense Enhancement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STRIDE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA508831B9FA947D0B961F88434E4772D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8DFBE2A018804F4FA7FA43E094F181AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the global semiconductor technology supply chain is critical to United States and allied national security, economic competitiveness, and technological leadership;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6EFCCAE86C64F81AEFB2B8E2C28075D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Chinese Communist Party is pursuing strategies to dominate the semiconductor technology industry to assist in its military modernization efforts and human rights abuses through non-market practices, export control violation and avoidance, economic espionage, military-civil fusion, and predatory investment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF654125C48F54FA5B30B3505D5ECDBB8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the integrity of the global semiconductor technology supply chain requires coordinated action with allied and partner nations to prevent technological capture by the Chinese Communist Party and other foreign adversaries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H34AFA72353354BC193DA5C0A0B1DF8EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>unilateral export controls for protecting critical semiconductor technologies can be amplified with multilateral coordination; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B986D3BBC9F4B2B92D6D3D397E68FDF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>fully utilizing certain unilateral United States export control authorities, including the Foreign Direct Product Rule, has proven effective at preventing circumvention or avoidance of United States export controls through third-country production.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HAE23DA6BDFAD43D2BD4A264A207FF167"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCE2E04F372A84D2C90385CB7D6257D76"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain United States and allied partner technological leadership in semiconductor technology research, design, manufacturing, and advanced materials;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H701D8FDA79CA44C9BF9275D8785D769E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent adversarial capture of key chokepoints in the global semiconductor technology supply chain;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D68990597424FE8AF3995FDA35FF9EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordinate with allied and partner nations to expand and enhance semiconductor technology protection;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FAEEDA435B74676B6F8480DD9B94FB4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that United States-origin technology and intellectual property, including the direct products of United States-origin technology, do not contribute to the Chinese Communist Party’s military modernization, human rights abuses, and pursuit of technological dominance over the United States and its allies and partners; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD78EA45BF18044B69F3D0505C0992DDC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>promote resilient, secure, and trusted semiconductor supply chains among United States allies and partners.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H95D5C640B75544DDA290A252B5283A19"><enum>4.</enum><header>Multilateral semiconductor technology supply chain coordination</header> <subsection id="HBDDD693225A449078AFF925BC806FF5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall coordinate with governments of countries that maintain significant capabilities in semiconductor technology research, design, manufacturing, materials, equipment, or equipment subsystems and components to establish coordinated and expanded approaches for protecting critical semiconductor technologies from acquisition by the Chinese Communist Party and other foreign adversaries of the United States and its allies and partners.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5D5D480BE60F4938B5BC612935BF139A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination objectives</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall seek to achieve—</text> <paragraph id="H2487A8622AF94C03AEEBFFE11E871515"><enum>(1)</enum><text>alignment of export control policies regarding semiconductor technology manufacturing equipment, including lithography systems, deposition equipment, etching tools, thermocompression bonding equipment, resist processing tools, chemical mechanical planarization tools, cleaning tools, handling tools, assembly, packaging, and test tools, and inspection systems and the critical subcomponents needed to produce such equipment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7E02BF244E64442A658A5B26EBC3A86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expanded restrictions on semiconductor technology design tools, intellectual property transfers, equipment servicing, and technical assistance that could enable indigenous semiconductor technology development capabilities in countries of concern;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H541DBCA473044732B562B0FA5D5502E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>harmonized approaches to controlling dual-use semiconductor technology materials, including photoresists, specialty gases, and advanced substrates;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB2853981E7141B0857E8805DBAAA166"><enum>(4)</enum><text>joint monitoring, enforcement, and administration mechanisms to prevent circumvention of semiconductor technology controls through third-country entities as well as prevent foreign backfilling of restricted items;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACB40F3B35BA4EA79DC1AD257D991A24"><enum>(5)</enum><text>information sharing regarding semiconductor technology transfer risks, end-user verification, and supply chain security threats; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90739B9D7F234AF2AAA0ABB4EC4C49D0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establishment of trusted supplier networks for critical semiconductor technology components and manufacturing services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1C5E129BE2B54151B2A9A0DF36AF66B3"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Consequences for non-Cooperation</header> <paragraph id="H98B3A68138CF404AB5365EA86FD46FA3"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Assessment of cooperation</header> <text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall regularly assess the extent to which countries engaged pursuant to subsection (a) are implementing measures consistent with United States policy described in section 3.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF6EE82F532134862A4AD5F6883843430">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Determination of insufficient security measures</header>
 <text>If the Secretary of State determines that a country engaged with pursuant to subsection (a) is not implementing security measures sufficient to fully prevent semiconductor technology transfer to countries of concern, the Secretary shall—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HF9EC17AA383840EBB0FCDB80899412CE">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>provide a detailed explanation of the specific deficiencies in the country’s semiconductor technology protection measures;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H948324C7A8154AEE80C826975EBDE3EF">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>request the Secretary of Commerce to convene a meeting of the Export Advisory Review Board to identify and execute a plan of action to address the insufficient security measures within 21 days of the Secretary of State’s determination of inadequate cooperation; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HDB6FFEA03C354867868FBCBB3A730140">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>notify the appropriate congressional committees of such determination not later than 30 days after making such determination and provide routine updates on the Export Advisory Review Board meeting request and plan of action described in subparagraph (B).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H424CE73665F548B189A1D4C46B974850">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Enhanced foreign direct product rule application</header>
 <text>In carrying out the process described in paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary of State shall provide to Export Advisory Review Board—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HD3BEDE027E7F4F96B87C3C04768556D6">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>recommendations for the application of Foreign Direct Product Rule restrictions to semiconductor technology produced in the non-cooperating country that incorporate United States-origin technology, software, or equipment;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HDC6CD613223F4335B72FABA73619EF91">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>recommended entities for the expansion of Entity List designations for semiconductor technology supply chain companies or research institutions in the non-cooperating country that pose technology transfer risks; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HE251CDDC4C7B438587212A19672C2C48">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>guidance on what additional steps may be needed to prevent foreign backfilling of U.S. technology in restricted sectors or entities in countries of concern.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFF99CDFE84714CEBA49D874F9F6C807C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H3685263A723E49EB8CDDF5C3AA03349B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text> <subparagraph id="H6DF2E64F3C9042DCBDBCA48D990E76A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the status of diplomatic engagement with key semiconductor technology-producing countries;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B38D3427A6B4EFB99101DF3DB12CDD6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>progress toward achieving the coordination objectives specified in subsection (b);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H75B71A1741A14AFF8926DCE2983FBC4C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any determinations of inadequate cooperation made under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H96DC37E71D95439E9796B9F5318E4D4D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the effectiveness of multilateral coordination in preventing semiconductor technology transfer to countries of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H503BEA2B2CAC4B85BCB526F36F064450"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C225B65A1124540B72B35959EC37CF4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7D11951D9A27400C9D8B4585542C44B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4414FD105214406AA3BE0CE5A8331537"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBAA5060FAA5D4F7EB55A4EC3F26617C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F755044974D45C8AD413F1FA0173EA3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Countries of concern</header><text>The term <term>countries of concern</term> has the meaning given the term <term>covered nation</term> in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H752AD3A5AFC14D5DACF279B5C96C528B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entity list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Entity List</term> means the list maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF7D0E78767A41A0B42FEFD711674063"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign direct product rule</header><text>The term <term>Foreign Direct Product Rule</term> means the rule exercising United States export controls on an item produced in a foreign country for shipment or transmission to another foreign country or foreign person, if the item—</text> <subparagraph id="H0358364E44404B09B09789B433CF6B01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is produced using technology or software that is otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72FC476CCDE4498FB33B56A7249DF473"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is produced with the use of a plant or major component of a plant that—</text> <clause id="HBB64193B601146D2BBD9B5FC812FFD48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is located outside the United States; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD7659661AC8E4193AFC63C6C37530348"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has been created using the technology or software described in subparagraph (A); or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED21B46D804240ACA8D2D88CE9ABE269"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contains, is commingled with, is bundled with, is drawn from, or is produced by an item described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H365AF9C85E2D4873A2638C9A449A79E5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Semiconductor technology</header><text>The term <term>semiconductor technology</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H49E95565E06D4E2CB99C1763DB9B24DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>integrated circuits, microprocessors, and memory devices;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA40CC90CC95B4AE9AF61D77875AD9120"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">semiconductor manufacturing equipment and tools, including subsystems and components;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1129CC7D165B4713B1564424079C0FF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>semiconductor design software and intellectual property;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDFE8AE8C6B7418691D6CAF2745E151D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>semiconductor materials and specialty chemicals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17DF8959C5714092895F2F3C3E13A94C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>testing, assembly, and packaging equipment; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4776B0545A214F8593CEE9E162EFEE3C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any technology, component, or service that is essential to semiconductor design, manufacturing, or testing processes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

