<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC3F1B6BD8C0B42AE84D5C22C4B7AE733" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1204 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that as the United States marks 250 years of independence, establishing a “Veterans Appreciation Month” offers a simple but powerful way for the Nation to recognize the men and women whose service has protected American freedom for generations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1204</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that as the United States marks 250 years of independence, establishing a <quote>Veterans Appreciation Month</quote> offers a simple but powerful way for the Nation to recognize the men and women whose service has protected American freedom for generations.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, for 250 years, American servicemembers have defended the freedoms established in 1776;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, as the Nation celebrates the 250th anniversary of the United States in 2026, Congress has an opportunity to focus national attention on the millions of veterans who have served and sacrificed in defense of the country;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a <quote>Veterans Appreciation Month</quote> would create a national moment of recognition during America’s 250th anniversary;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a Veterans Appreciation Month would encourage businesses, schools, and civic organizations to honor veterans;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a Veterans Appreciation Month would expand awareness and appreciation of the sacrifices made by military families;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a Veterans Appreciation Month would reinforce the connection between American freedom and those who defend it;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas many American businesses already provide voluntary military discounts;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a Veterans Appreciation Month would encourage broader participation and create a visible, nationwide expression of gratitude from the private sector;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas businesses that participate could identify themselves as America 250 Military Appreciation Businesses, demonstrating their support for veterans during this historic national milestone;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas supporting veterans is one of the most bipartisan priorities of Congress;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas military families are deeply woven into the economic and civic life of communities across the United States; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States Armed Forces is the greatest military in the world: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6315B4FB5B97404C80C1D11AB26963F5"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9B069CEAD656402E94CBEB8736F16C9A"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that as the United States marks 250 years of independence, establishing a <quote>Veterans Appreciation Month</quote> offers a simple but powerful way for the Nation to recognize the men and women whose service has protected American freedom for generations.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

