<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BOM26422-99W-CT-2TG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4864 IS: Providing Understanding of Paraprofessionals in Learning Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4864</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct a study on paraprofessionals and education support staff.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Understanding of Paraprofessionals in Learning Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PUPIL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ID292326e9c62948e8974f43a56235d0ab"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="ID6ac6b4dbe07f4346a9da321ef0a960a8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA</header><text>The terms <term>professional development</term>, <term>Secretary</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef80127bf6f74d43897712fb5f36776b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Education support staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>education support staff</term> (also sometimes known as <quote>classified school employees</quote> or <quote>education support professionals</quote>) includes professionals who work in early childhood education settings or schools that serve children in prekindergarten through grade 12 in clerical and administrative services, transportation services, food and nutrition services, custodial and maintenance services, health and student services, technical services, and skilled trades.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4677c91723294c49b65f2fee5c222b07"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Paraprofessional</header><text>The term <term>paraprofessional</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3201 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7011">20 U.S.C. 7011</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="ID09bb46780fe44069bd4fc35288844e9a"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="ID6c67ed19fcc04957aef5d6fc4e1f0ed5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Paraprofessionals and education support staff are invaluable members of the education system and school community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4efedeb40974012bb9aa60026018f38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>More than 2,000,000 paraprofessionals and education support staff are the frontline workers who transform public elementary and secondary schools in the United States from brick and mortar buildings to places of learning and support for more than 54,000,000 students across the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID83f9805c73d74cff8cff6b219b7962e6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Many paraprofessionals and education support staff are, as a matter of practice, laid off at the end of each school year and rehired annually, and lack job security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1659c6d13f1946bcaea79a1de93872cc"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Over 500,000 paraprofessionals provide essential support for children with disabilities to access a free appropriate public education in the least restrictive environment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID31b7c5ce489149abae4c4f86c167a916"><enum>(5)</enum><text>While paraprofessionals and education support staff are often the most diverse subset of school employees, are more likely to have grown up in the communities they serve, and are trusted school community members for many students and parents, the voices of paraprofessionals and education support staff are not always reflected in school policies.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ID4b376e8464dd4f52bea80931212415b5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study on the paraprofessional and education support staff workforce</header><subsection id="id6d590b98d15c42d9997f0e52b59d9004"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall seek to enter into a contract with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to conduct a study examining the paraprofessional and education support staff workforce that serve children in prekindergarten through grade 12 in the United States enrolled at public elementary schools or secondary schools. Such study shall contain the elements described in subsection (b) and shall assess the characteristics, roles, effectiveness, preparation, compensation, and career pathways of paraprofessionals and education support staff, as well as the policies and investments that shape the paraprofessional and education support staff workforce.</text></subsection><subsection id="id94cff87fb409403b9cdb5731e26aeefb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study described in subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="id8f4d9fec85094be19ff92c3c828c97b9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>examine—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a8b6b7131b84948aabab5855f8a7805"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the demographic, educational, and professional characteristics of the paraprofessional and education support staff workforce that serve children in prekindergarten through grade 12;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id374efbfda69240e8826fc8f62751e05c"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pathways into the paraprofessional and education support staff roles and patterns of recruitment, retention, and tenure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e6d096e954543a7b91779e95243c84a"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">minimum qualification and credentialing requirements, including variations across States and local educational agencies and compliance with the certification and licensure requirements of section 1111(g)(2)(J) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(g)(2)(J)</external-xref>), and for paraprofessionals serving children with disabilities, compliance with section 612(a)(14)(B) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1412">20 U.S.C. 1412(a)(14)(B)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="IDb388bb8ba1084e45b8376ddb8ededcfa"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review the roles and responsibilities that paraprofessionals and education support staff assume across prekindergarten through grade 12 settings and student populations;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id395bd65499ed4063b3e1e73caf3a4af2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the available evidence on the impact of paraprofessional and education support staff on student academic, social-emotional, and behavioral outcomes, and identify the conditions under which paraprofessionals and education support staff are most effective, including considerations of training, supervision, role clarity, and instructional context;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID9888458d57dc485dae3f129d1ec9aa8e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>analyze compensation structures, including salaries, benefits, and employment conditions, and document variation across States, local educational agencies, and school contexts, and identify evidence-informed approaches to improving compensation, stability, and overall job quality;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID343720e1df6c44cd80466580f1a9bc13" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assess the availability, quality, and effectiveness of professional development opportunities for paraprofessionals and education support staff, and identify strategies to strengthen those opportunities;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44efc674754f4395aecb5ec8457b94b9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine career advancement pathways, including model programs and policies that support progression to certified teaching and other educational roles;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ID44bd50bd9c1b4fb1ab343f3b79b647c1" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify Federal, State, and local policy levers and investments that influence the recruitment, preparation, effectiveness, advancement, and retention of the paraprofessional and education support staff workforce, and recommend actionable strategies to strengthen and sustain such workforce in ways that support educational quality and student outcomes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="IDaabf726678fc403595d60d07ddd3093d" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>identify data gaps and areas where additional research is needed;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91e9709ad6504c2da7efe82fa596a586"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each classification established under subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb717d92b409443418aea7e5095547868"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze the average starting salary for each such classification and the average salary for each such classification; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa0c0405126c42c3adaa8685595442e3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compare those starting and average salaries by classification and location, to the cost of living or livable wages for the respective locations in which those education support staff and paraprofessionals reside;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8525c75ba0c3485ba608581f906a08db"><enum>(10)</enum><text>examine relevant employment models and workforce arrangements, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ad3756d79e24dc7808d151e6b81b231"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use and prevalence of contracted, privatized, or outsourced education support staff and paraprofessionals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5a9ea4db1d74aab8427692693636a1b"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the implications of those employment models and workforce arrangements on workforce stability, training, supervision, and working conditions, the alignment of those models and arrangements with school goals, and the effects of those models and arrangements on educational quality and student outcomes; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID515bb0bdea6e41e28859e9a42d112f96" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>make recommendations for Congress, Federal agencies, States, local educational agencies, and other relevant stakeholders, based on the findings of the study.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide665f0fc82e340c0a92882890c015f4f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Position classifications</header><text>In carrying out the study under this section, the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine shall establish classifications for the different education support staff and paraprofessional positions, and with respect to each element of the study, as described in subsection (b), disaggregate data based on those classifications, to the extent practicable.</text></subsection><subsection id="ID44acc4e404f94d82864744fd8fe67093"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The agreement under subsection (a) shall direct the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to complete the study under this section, and transmit to Congress and make publicly available a report on the results of the study, not later than 24 months after the date of entry into the agreement.</text></subsection><subsection id="IDf3fca867d066462c8dbd95dc75234815"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $2,000,000.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

