<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1098EEADB0B04FB88091D947C4410856" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1044 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the year 2026 as the “National Year of the Volunteer”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1044</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the year 2026 as the <quote>National Year of the Volunteer</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas volunteers play a critical role in our communities in public safety, health, education, and civic life;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas volunteerism unites people of all backgrounds in common purpose, bridging divides and strengthening the bonds of citizenship;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas volunteerism bolsters organizations that keep neighborhoods safe, healthy, and connected;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas volunteers contribute billions of dollars’ worth of service annually, driving local economies and offsetting government costs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas volunteerism inspires younger generations to see service as a cornerstone of United States life and civic responsibility;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, despite rising demand, critical civic organizations, such as volunteer fire and EMS departments, scout troops, youth sports, houses of worship, food banks, shelters, mentoring programs, and nonprofit organizations, report struggling to recruit and retain volunteers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas national volunteer rates have dropped significantly over the past decade, a trend accelerated by the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the year 2026 marks the 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States of America, a milestone that offers all United States citizens the opportunity to renew the spirit of service, unity, and shared purpose that has defined the Nation since its founding;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Congress passed and the President signed into law the United States Semiquincentennial Commission Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/196">Public Law 114–196</external-xref>), which created the United States Semiquincentennial Commission (the Commission) to plan, encourage, develop, and coordinate the commemoration of the history of the United States leading up to the 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the many programs planned by the Commission include America Gives, an initiative that challenged individuals, businesses, nonprofits, schools, youth groups, faith-based networks, and organizations of all kinds to commit to increasing their level of volunteering and impact starting this past year;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Commission tracked the number of volunteer hours given by every United States citizen who participated in America Gives; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas designating 2026 as the <quote>National Year of the Volunteer</quote> would celebrate the enduring United States tradition of neighbors helping neighbors and encourage a nationwide recommitment to community service: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4B7E9524A0EF475EAB648C5DAEC3F5A5"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9B05537256294A75A06FF4E0EBCCFF39"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H9C1D5FB0AC7D4FF7ACDA2CB9E38F72A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of the <quote>National Year of the Volunteer</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9172FE18D72B4275A9B1676CD224BB6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the millions of volunteers whose selfless service strengthens communities across the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12509D3CD9974DABBB0030D77AA365AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages Federal, State, and local efforts to highlight volunteer opportunities and drive public awareness of the value of service;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F8D03E3EF164BE3B66D57183A335B83"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages nonprofit organizations, schools, veterans’ groups, civic associations, and companies to partner and engage in volunteer opportunities across the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEB158F4AB4A4A72A3787F551131B198"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls on all Americans to celebrate the 250th anniversary of the United States, as the <quote>National Year of the Volunteer,</quote> by participating in acts of service and community improvement.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

