<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25E44-M1N-H7-654"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3348 IS: Dream Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3348</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status of certain individuals who are long-term United States residents and who entered the United States as children, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H703BB40936D94513B6C6837BEEE5A561"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dream Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idd91a9dd3c38740168b2dc8abe557ad53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idfd0f5f3b7366463786ddb5849f18f690"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise specifically provided, any term used in this Act that is used in the immigration laws shall have the meaning given such term in the immigration laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA555B66BAC814255B515B788CFBA3B5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applicable Federal tax liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable Federal tax liability</term> means liability for Federal taxes imposed under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, including any penalties and interest on Federal taxes imposed under that Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idC2A156932EF74FBF877EB336D96105E8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Armed Forces</header><text>The term <term>Armed Forces</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>armed forces</quote> in section 101 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id765ad27d39d24e3db8bbcf34b69bdd85"><enum>(4)</enum><header>DACA</header><text>The term <term>DACA</term> means deferred action granted to an alien pursuant to the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals program announced by President Obama on June 15, 2012.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD50E537D8A3B45CF9D76D718EDE31315"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>The term <term>disability</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(1) of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAF5200E0CFE94D82A603F398C655998C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Early childhood education program</header><text>The term <term>early childhood education program</term> has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id48D0E3099D874320A60A6B05E5F03199"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Elementary school; high school; secondary school</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>high school</term>, and <term>secondary school</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9079BA7FD56C40A5A108ED43A9D79285"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Immigration laws</header><text>The term <term>immigration laws</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87e9c16d88394217a683c0fbe0c8455a"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id825CC3856F26475899DC3F51017BFA65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as provided in subparagraph (B), has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id453CA4C2AD13471F876F21EC1308ED70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an institution of higher education outside of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5734477a24ca481484f806c9c3cfdd85"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Permanent resident status on a conditional basis</header><text>The term <term>permanent resident status on a conditional basis</term> means status as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence on a conditional basis under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5A26095EFBEF41D88959E3B239FD213E"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Poverty line</header><text>The term <term>poverty line</term> has the meaning given such term in section 673 of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0D24A7D84425416AA9ACA646F820A9FC"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>Except as otherwise specifically provided, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0e97da30bcf45f2970d637e9302bdff"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Uniformed services</header><text>The term <term>Uniformed Services</term> has the meaning given the term <term>uniformed services</term> in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc8e2f1af0f244e2cbcf39e3925c34a08"><enum>3.</enum><header>Permanent resident status on a conditional basis for certain long-term residents who entered the United States as children</header><subsection id="idb8d4c75a5d444410924185cd4d717b03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conditional basis for status</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an alien shall be considered, at the time of obtaining the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under this section, to have obtained such status on a conditional basis subject to the provisions under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbc679d0f530a46ada81955990cad11f4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph id="id0aaf58d7492a46e68a87e23e4a87e119"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall cancel the removal of, and adjust to the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence on a conditional basis, an alien who is inadmissible or deportable from the United States, is in temporary protected status under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</external-xref>), or is the son or daughter of an alien admitted as a nonimmigrant described in subparagraph (E)(i), (E)(ii), (H)(i)(b), or (L) of section 101(a)(15) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</external-xref>) if—</text><subparagraph id="idd6636d94ab3042d48dc46ac9f9ffbcbb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the alien has been continuously physically present in the United States since the date that is 4 years before the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida139a4d14b1843f79662ede5a6889949"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the alien was younger than 18 years of age on the date on which the alien initially entered the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce3c29ad8dcb4cfa8debe021ace55149"><enum>(C)</enum><text>subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the alien—</text><clause id="ida50eb0cf304441f68d2b986069d7c577"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not inadmissible under paragraph (2), (3), (6)(E), (6)(G), (8), (10)(A), (10)(C), or (10)(D) of section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="id9aed8ab3b87447a2801d8f3e4cf92e66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has not ordered, incited, assisted, or otherwise participated in the persecution of any person on account of race, religion, nationality, membership in a particular social group, or political opinion; and</text></clause><clause id="id1653be8eb1d84e75a7505a43e348a3df"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has not been convicted of—</text><subclause id="id689a94dc97464992a48e31407aabea48"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any offense under Federal or State law, other than a State offense for which an essential element is the alien’s immigration status, that is punishable by a maximum term of imprisonment of more than 1 year; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id0b6ec3e5cbbe461e957e616fbe008e9c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>3 or more offenses under Federal or State law, other than State offenses for which an essential element is the alien’s immigration status, for which the alien was convicted on different dates for each of the 3 offenses and imprisoned for an aggregate of 90 days or more;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id33f3f3de751041bcacfb005771fb946d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the alien—</text><clause id="idba8de3ea86c24c2c8733c34c26b804a7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been admitted to an institution of higher education;</text></clause><clause id="idfeb57241a5ce42308dfff9156c3027a8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has earned a high school diploma or a commensurate alternative award from a public or private high school, or has obtained a general education development certificate recognized under State law or a high school equivalency diploma in the United States;</text></clause><clause id="idb3cde6101b2e4b4db5e1a751e4163440"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is enrolled in secondary school or in an education program assisting students in—</text><subclause id="id4B5F631107454872944C19942D61395D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>obtaining a regular high school diploma or its recognized equivalent under State law; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idC698AB350B5940D9BB764D62B05A776F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in passing a general educational development exam, a high school equivalence diploma examination, or other similar State-authorized exam; or</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5847c65354594797a9198d671b6c6844"><enum>(iv)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id483900a1d020449cb8b6c68c0e14e72f"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has served, is serving, or has enlisted in the Armed Forces; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f2f21eb53b54c2a8d983f253418c039" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an alien who has been discharged from the Armed Forces, has received an honorable discharge; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9409170D200640AC9CADAF45BA43E17B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the alien has sworn under penalty of perjury that the alien—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81e115ccb9a649eca6abc8c4c01044d7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has no unpaid applicable Federal tax liability, which is assessed and is not being disputed;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc9ab8e49d684ec6b8cf271114b0930a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has entered into an agreement to resolve any such assessed and undisputed Federal tax liability (via an installment agreement, an offer in compromise, or otherwise) which has been approved by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id411a7a180f9f4f189ead1d5bbedf67e0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has applied in good faith to enter into an agreement to resolve any such assessed and undisputed Federal tax liability, which has not been rejected by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id504a30cf844a4f56bf16be2bb02f3d88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>With respect to any benefit under this Act, the Secretary may waive the grounds of inadmissibility under paragraph (2), (6)(E), (6)(G), or (10)(D) of section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>) for humanitarian purposes or family unity or if the waiver is otherwise in the public interest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f462313d0fd417ab7b019eb9d36d12b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of expunged convictions</header><text>An expunged conviction shall not automatically be treated as an offense under paragraph (1). The Secretary shall evaluate expunged convictions on a case-by-case basis according to the nature and severity of the offense to determine whether, under the particular circumstances, the Secretary determines that the alien should be eligible for cancellation of removal, adjustment to permanent resident status on a conditional basis, or other adjustment of status.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id753BA8DD2F284FA899EB12E855A6CDC9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>DACA recipients</header><text>The Secretary shall cancel the removal of, and adjust to the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence on a conditional basis, an alien who was granted DACA unless the alien has engaged in conduct since the alien was granted DACA that would make the alien ineligible for DACA.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde5be65d398b424996879602f9b4339a"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application fee</header><subparagraph id="id5a6b2180c06b4ca692f123f4d702871b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may require an alien applying for permanent resident status on a conditional basis under this section to pay a reasonable fee that is commensurate with the cost of processing the application.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17c76c26df0740dd8912d3c3df71982f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>An applicant may be exempted from paying the fee required under subparagraph (A) if the alien—</text><clause id="id93d01a7c8a63453090ea429dce4c40f7"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id7C9E5CE338124FB7A09C2DCE531FFD3A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is younger than 18 years of age;</text></subclause><subclause id="id80a10844c13343288c0a92ef8328a6fb" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>received total income, during the 12-month period immediately preceding the date on which the alien files an application under this section, that is less than 150 percent of the poverty line; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id1fa45c32a4f74e21bf0ea58035f29ffc" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is in foster care or otherwise lacking any parental or other familial support;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idad6c22a9dfbf4960829a5bec4f03ebce"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is younger than 18 years of age and is homeless;</text></clause><clause id="idbaf08a115218479ba7ffbf95227399a1"><enum>(iii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id0E7998C4A43F4330A2D75575782D4F33"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cannot care for himself or herself because of a serious, chronic disability; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idae493b3cc17b4fa0936e4cc521162d80" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>received total income, during the 12-month period immediately preceding the date on which the alien files an application under this section, that is less than 150 percent of the poverty line; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3b614bf16b574a1c9f4612a9e5ad6879"><enum>(iv)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idEC6523148DB04926884A5976F3C1ACAC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>during the 12-month period immediately preceding the date on which the alien files an application under this section, accumulated $10,000 or more in debt as a result of unreimbursed medical expenses incurred by the alien or an immediate family member of the alien; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id2416f5b0a2294d399172d84da8d1ca2b" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>received total income, during the 12-month period immediately preceding the date on which the alien files an application under this section, that is less than 150 percent of the poverty line.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb500b5cbe3a4678bea3fbe7cce78d7a"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Submission of biometric and biographic data</header><text>The Secretary may not grant an alien permanent resident status on a conditional basis under this section unless the alien submits biometric and biographic data, in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary. The Secretary shall provide an alternative procedure for aliens who are unable to provide such biometric or biographic data because of a physical impairment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b6a1c6d1ceb44f387bd2e9345320853"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Background checks</header><subparagraph id="id6cb89ab70fee429b9f8b141d9f2dfd28"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement for background checks</header><text>The Secretary shall utilize biometric, biographic, and other data that the Secretary determines appropriate—</text><clause id="id621d703ba9bb45c5b5c74cb725a5f9be"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to conduct security and law enforcement background checks of an alien seeking permanent resident status on a conditional basis under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="id82ca71ea3cd6453692c2ddfd9eb6a32d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to determine whether there is any criminal, national security, or other factor that would render the alien ineligible for such status.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46ad567d8c664cfdb42fc2e177fbe6f9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Completion of background checks</header><text>The security and law enforcement background checks of an alien required under subparagraph (A) shall be completed, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, before the date on which the Secretary grants such alien permanent resident status on a conditional basis under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idccda7adc89ef44d386f9521bcfd1af25"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Medical examination</header><subparagraph id="idAC028E2AF4CC4A5FB0DFCAEB304252CC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>An alien applying for permanent resident status on a conditional basis under this section shall undergo a medical examination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3F9F804F5F7B4E83A54A66833082A622"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Policies and procedures</header><text>The Secretary, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall prescribe policies and procedures for the nature and timing of the examination required under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id40a1f17ff5f24ec183dd929d2f7303f9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Military selective service</header><text>An alien applying for permanent resident status on a conditional basis under this section shall establish that the alien has registered under the Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3801">50 U.S.C. 3801 et seq.</external-xref>), if the alien is subject to registration under such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id820d3d14d0934405b4eea686fdc12f41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of continuous presence</header><paragraph id="id668ec381f0b7492e9cedc2a19b3de751"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Termination of continuous period</header><text>Any period of continuous physical presence in the United States of an alien who applies for permanent resident status on a conditional basis under this section shall not terminate when the alien is served a notice to appear under section 239(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1229">8 U.S.C. 1229(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79815a27372c48d4a5dd6d8fd8bf63e8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of certain breaks in presence</header><subparagraph id="idd4863219b86941799e208f66b7584bf9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), an alien shall be considered to have failed to maintain continuous physical presence in the United States under subsection (b)(1)(A) if the alien has departed from the United States for any period exceeding 90 days or for any periods, in the aggregate, exceeding 180 days.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3020ced4279b4ad98230d25c4903bcf6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extensions for extenuating circumstances</header><text>The Secretary may extend the time periods described in subparagraph (A) for an alien who demonstrates that the failure to timely return to the United States was due to extenuating circumstances beyond the alien’s control, including the serious illness of the alien, or death or serious illness of a parent, grandparent, sibling, or child of the alien.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id97F6A912BA07445097A276EAC59C7653"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Travel authorized by the secretary</header><text>Any period of travel outside of the United States by an alien that was authorized by the Secretary may not be counted toward any period of departure from the United States under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id30629fcd21284042a487378bd756fc66"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on removal of certain aliens</header><paragraph id="id26afba3fb5b44525b3daba8fe39a6831"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary or the Attorney General may not remove an alien who appears prima facie eligible for relief under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF42671DE46F24EA0A30F70CD31D6810E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens subject to removal</header><text>The Secretary shall provide a reasonable opportunity to apply for relief under this section to any alien who requests such an opportunity or who appears prima facie eligible for relief under this section if the alien is in removal proceedings, is the subject of a final removal order, or is the subject of a voluntary departure order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9f5759e7e06e42eeb308989489348e69"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certain aliens enrolled in elementary or secondary school</header><subparagraph id="id9eabfb82b6fa4b2da5fe4f760d0e3ba7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Stay of removal</header><text>The Attorney General shall stay the removal proceedings of an alien who—</text><clause id="id4ec8e75708db493480aacf002f9ae258"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meets all the requirements under subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of subsection (b)(1), subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of such subsection;</text></clause><clause id="idbc8b4d9502c74906b90da71216ec38a2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is at least 5 years of age; and</text></clause><clause id="idee7a76edac6549b0865f7a30826b7b06"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is enrolled in an elementary school, a secondary school, or an early childhood education program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idddcefd41339e4ff3b6eb0afaf9efa04a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Commencement of removal proceedings</header><text>The Secretary may not commence removal proceedings for an alien described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5587e42fd9a043e5b95ff765f7d1d46c"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Employment</header><text>An alien whose removal is stayed pursuant to subparagraph (A) or who may not be placed in removal proceedings pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall, upon application to the Secretary, be granted an employment authorization document.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd33e69eeff1a41d1a40996a4a0327280"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Lift of stay</header><text>The Secretary or Attorney General may not lift the stay granted to an alien under subparagraph (A) unless the alien ceases to meet the requirements under such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb608932acaaa40ad8a4ea372333671f1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exemption from numerical limitations</header><text>Nothing in this section or in any other law may be construed to apply a numerical limitation on the number of aliens who may be granted permanent resident status on a conditional basis under this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id93a026ba97dd4abb921e5ba7f95e98ed"><enum>4.</enum><header>Terms of permanent resident status on a conditional basis</header><subsection id="id5b95c0f0a6c44ea9ab151c4109d686fb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Period of status</header><text>Permanent resident status on a conditional basis is—</text><paragraph id="id2253ba1f0a5e4558a536b98b5f7d8cf7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>valid for a period of 8 years, unless such period is extended by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59db6a2be7bd41539aa2e756785e6ba5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to termination under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id88208c582f78432da1776f43e901b2e9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice of requirements</header><text>At the time an alien obtains permanent resident status on a conditional basis, the Secretary shall provide notice to the alien regarding the provisions of this Act and the requirements to have the conditional basis of such status removed.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6b5a9b8b8e3947bb821589b410e41edc"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination of status</header><text>The Secretary may terminate the permanent resident status on a conditional basis of an alien only if the Secretary—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id6A12D307F3664890B237A507163F5FEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that the alien ceases to meet the requirements under paragraph (1)(C) of section 3(b), subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of that section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id03b59844ce4d4f25b60f940440abccdf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prior to the termination, provides the alien—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id6DA1AD2443364828827A8F3C5B4E589F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice of the proposed termination; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id619F546EE1814A10A4273A49F1DF5F2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the opportunity for a hearing to provide evidence that the alien meets such requirements or otherwise contest the termination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide2886568672e476bb2bc00ef274d2579"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Return to previous immigration status</header><paragraph id="id8326799b0c664c178816c21fe287d700"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an alien whose permanent resident status on a conditional basis expires under subsection (a)(1) or is terminated under subsection (c) or whose application for such status is denied shall return to the immigration status that the alien had immediately before receiving permanent resident status on a conditional basis or applying for such status, as appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5cac26fc80d5417a9208f0bafcbe4994"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for temporary protected status</header><text>An alien whose permanent resident status on a conditional basis expires under subsection (a)(1) or is terminated under subsection (c) or whose application for such status is denied and who had temporary protected status under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</external-xref>) immediately before receiving or applying for such permanent resident status on a conditional basis, as appropriate, may not return to such temporary protected status if—</text><subparagraph id="id14fa61546d534f01b2c463b791eef1a0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the relevant designation under section 244(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a(b)</external-xref>) has been terminated; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3c1bc83ab8db4f2595769d42a1485305"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the reason for terminating the permanent resident status on a conditional basis renders the alien ineligible for such temporary protected status.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4dde7f89b64a4a73bb0a1472003e093b"><enum>5.</enum><header>Removal of conditional basis of permanent resident status</header><subsection id="idabac7d4c0ca142a3a9420ecf101ec5d2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility for removal of conditional basis</header><paragraph id="idf74293660b5e499ca108f79992f3fc80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall remove the conditional basis of an alien’s permanent resident status granted under this Act and grant the alien status as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence if the alien—</text><subparagraph id="id793813906f1f4cfea33369ba27921730"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is described in paragraph (1)(C) of section 3(b), subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) of that section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f118db43713406587f9153cd61d3b0e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has not abandoned the alien’s residence in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77213244bd6044fa90a5ef938626bdfc"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idD8EE87BCE18D4133802D803B27859C1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has acquired a degree from an institution of higher education or has completed at least 2 years, in good standing, in a program for a bachelor’s degree or higher degree in the United States;</text></clause><clause id="idc536a8b04fb640d895ce99c1404c0534" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has served in the Armed Forces for at least 2 years and, if discharged, received an honorable discharge; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idD54859D85F7B4ACF80B584B151795728" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has been employed for periods totaling at least 3 years and at least 75 percent of the time that the alien has had a valid employment authorization, except that any period during which the alien is not employed while having a valid employment authorization and is enrolled in an institution of higher education, a secondary school, or an education program described in section 3(b)(1)(D)(iii), shall not count toward the time requirements under this clause.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida455e5e67ed144bd8a9c12036df43d11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hardship exception</header><text>The Secretary shall remove the conditional basis of an alien’s permanent resident status and grant the alien status as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence if the alien—</text><subparagraph id="id6704057fbece495babaa103fffeef0b4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>satisfies the requirements under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id02684010919a43839124378a9ee0c4f8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrates compelling circumstances for the inability to satisfy the requirements under subparagraph (C) of such paragraph; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id885998047b674c40b68a81abfd66afbf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrates that—</text><clause id="id98AF38C4353D4F26BEAFA99AA24AA58F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the alien has a disability;</text></clause><clause id="id9DEACF2007D64C1A982BD170984EF44F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the alien is a full-time caregiver of a minor child; or</text></clause><clause id="id26665E89D2C24441A12046393FD2F0C8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the removal of the alien from the United States would result in extreme hardship to the alien or the alien’s spouse, parent, or child who is a national of the United States or is lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3124915b581244fc87fcf53b97dc4fab"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Citizenship requirement</header><subparagraph id="id92d2f754a2994ff087e9944883b0249c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the conditional basis of an alien’s permanent resident status granted under this Act may not be removed unless the alien demonstrates that the alien satisfies the requirements under section 312(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1423">8 U.S.C. 1423(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c8388675f6d4909bd6eea5c676e62ee"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to an alien who is unable to meet the requirements under such section 312(a) due to disability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id37728af1302241f39ab5b02be689ef2e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application fee</header><subparagraph id="id83bbb5aa333b414780b305f34120622f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may require aliens applying for lawful permanent resident status under this section to pay a reasonable fee that is commensurate with the cost of processing the application.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida4a3c49e3e4a4ee194059398ca1b837c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>An applicant may be exempted from paying the fee required under subparagraph (A) if the alien—</text><clause id="idf84f2b2d670f4181aeec5a65d8777004"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id34C5B34943694C8C99A661C06280ADB0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is younger than 18 years of age;</text></subclause><subclause id="idc9dd6182dc5e4210b58945d94d517ca6" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>received total income, during the 12-month period immediately preceding the date on which the alien files an application under this section, that is less than 150 percent of the poverty line; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id131c809cb2ea4050875a3c787979956f" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is in foster care or otherwise lacking any parental or other familial support;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idd1a11b6914984827b8396f05b81d7ce7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is younger than 18 years of age and is homeless;</text></clause><clause id="id4ee0226f15ef466db3c29321c26a2342"><enum>(iii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9D51BDBB7632493DBF5A3EF1CF2EE692"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cannot care for himself or herself because of a serious, chronic disability; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id879fdf892f404f20850787e375989c22" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>received total income, during the 12-month period immediately preceding the date on which the alien files an application under this section, that is less than 150 percent of the poverty line; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id848b5f4c14a94f9799ed6232e7029ff6"><enum>(iv)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id74ADB855FA754022A9CD8FE8AD775F66"><enum>(I)</enum><text>during the 12-month period immediately preceding the date on which the alien files an application under this section, the alien accumulated $10,000 or more in debt as a result of unreimbursed medical expenses incurred by the alien or an immediate family member of the alien; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id09de587dc7164cdaa8a95e8725c863cd" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>received total income, during the 12-month period immediately preceding the date on which the alien files an application under this section, that is less than 150 percent of the poverty line.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id60ae44a3cb7848d08cef91e7163b4ca2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Submission of biometric and biographic data</header><text>The Secretary may not remove the conditional basis of an alien’s permanent resident status unless the alien submits biometric and biographic data, in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary. The Secretary shall provide an alternative procedure for applicants who are unable to provide such biometric data because of a physical impairment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id628f571ec22e468a9aee26d8c1b41267"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Background checks</header><subparagraph id="idd52792cb53e24ba2b62f0cc7c654631c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement for background checks</header><text>The Secretary shall utilize biometric, biographic, and other data that the Secretary determines appropriate—</text><clause id="iddb105ed87334447dbd8e70c1ed29608f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to conduct security and law enforcement background checks of an alien applying for removal of the conditional basis of the alien’s permanent resident status; and</text></clause><clause id="id4f7734391dac4bf288e8a54b959049fb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to determine whether there is any criminal, national security, or other factor that would render the alien ineligible for removal of such conditional basis.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbcfaffd47c1d4914bfe9390007dc4c7a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Completion of background checks</header><text>The security and law enforcement background checks of an alien required under subparagraph (A) shall be completed, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, before the date on which the Secretary removes the conditional basis of the alien’s permanent resident status.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1930aa192c7640f2b08fae3a709b0621"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment for purposes of naturalization</header><paragraph id="idbc26db45959f4090a10ef212c97af50b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of title III of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1401">8 U.S.C. 1401 et seq.</external-xref>), an alien granted permanent resident status on a conditional basis shall be considered to have been admitted to the United States, and be present in the United States, as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc7b4e2f89078486ca2a964d7b92f0f02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on application for naturalization</header><text>An alien may not apply for naturalization while the alien is in permanent resident status on a conditional basis.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7648BECBB4F2470EA4BBD4B850DD0C8C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Documentation requirements</header><subsection id="id3ca85210533c458fa282a9f99c4d9dfd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Documents establishing identity</header><text>An alien’s application for permanent resident status on a conditional basis may include, as proof of identity—</text><paragraph id="ide8fdfe87806c4f0da7aa402990959f8b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a passport or national identity document from the alien’s country of origin that includes the alien’s name and the alien’s photograph or fingerprint;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ff7ec0193644d4191de229462ffeacd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the alien’s birth certificate and an identity card that includes the alien’s name and photograph;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5dd88d5479ce46cbba2410058f69e956"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a school identification card that includes the alien’s name and photograph, and school records showing the alien’s name and that the alien is or was enrolled at the school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf748d37f3d044b1b8089d7a1064a81f5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a Uniformed Services identification card issued by the Department of Defense;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c3203720f0e431f8707b090d49f1e54"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any immigration or other document issued by the United States Government bearing the alien’s name and photograph; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE72666CBD7E84F028E37EB1199A1C1F8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a State-issued identification card bearing the alien's name and photograph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id41798b67f26847c6a56873823d538d5e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Documents establishing continuous physical presence in the United States</header><text>To establish that an alien has been continuously physically present in the United States, as required under section 3(b)(1)(A), or to establish that an alien has not abandoned residence in the United States, as required under section 5(a)(1)(B), the alien may submit documents to the Secretary, including—</text><paragraph id="idf3851bd0e27f48ae8e6a10762d8fabb9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>employment records that include the employer’s name and contact information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idffe0b84578104926880d4084a54930b0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>records from any educational institution the alien has attended in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id83e4522e6e894f9da0912472be61f1f8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>records of service from the Uniformed Services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e11eca1bffc4f2fbc3bbe0eb034ab67"><enum>(4)</enum><text>official records from a religious entity confirming the alien’s participation in a religious ceremony;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide1c5994b8aaf4192bf017741a016a217"><enum>(5)</enum><text>passport entries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb9488941d81c485280da04f0b5c833b2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a birth certificate for a child who was born in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf63b6339bed6427f9dc942fda8fa1dc4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>automobile license receipts or registration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc529650b0174bc09f634eeb750a62c6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>deeds, mortgages, or rental agreement contracts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a3ad7d4a9714f40ad11c2039ba9e6b7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>tax receipts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbfe7293a88df42ce94a7798f6a373cd6"><enum>(10)</enum><text>insurance policies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide5bb9bf93d9e4ebfbe53ec21ddbb5875"><enum>(11)</enum><text>remittance records;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida4f0ad819aad4db9a228dac2e79c0140"><enum>(12)</enum><text>rent receipts or utility bills bearing the alien’s name or the name of an immediate family member of the alien, and the alien’s address;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5b2406cf2c144b3a08fd1b0f2a841d4"><enum>(13)</enum><text>copies of money order receipts for money sent in or out of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c28c39b4b3c4af38ad48016c0791236"><enum>(14)</enum><text>dated bank transactions; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59438b65e5f6466c88eb2a78bfc9dc6d"><enum>(15)</enum><text>2 or more sworn affidavits from individuals who are not related to the alien who have direct knowledge of the alien’s continuous physical presence in the United States, that contain—</text><subparagraph id="ide8017d4cbf3844dcaf15712d8dade12b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name, address, and telephone number of the affiant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf66c01647e1848bf99828a526699850d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the nature and duration of the relationship between the affiant and the alien.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idaf38ab4cff1f423c893d56d61e18fbfd"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Documents establishing initial entry into the United States</header><text>To establish under section 3(b)(1)(B) that an alien was younger than 18 years of age on the date on which the alien initially entered the United States, an alien may submit documents to the Secretary, including—</text><paragraph id="ide058bee3f82d4205a1a6818cbec68e5e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an admission stamp on the alien’s passport;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e3d9c47425c430da7c7dca022cb9839"><enum>(2)</enum><text>records from any educational institution the alien has attended in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5854b73276b14d149c154c92a0a5a8a5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any document from the Department of Justice or the Department of Homeland Security stating the alien’s date of entry into the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9456e59c775e407c89a8f137e12a7fed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>hospital or medical records showing medical treatment or hospitalization, the name of the medical facility or physician, and the date of the treatment or hospitalization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9f0323f93bcd40e995268f95081cebd7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>rent receipts or utility bills bearing the alien’s name or the name of an immediate family member of the alien, and the alien’s address;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id69dc2e5472b8467d8b8f4b67c32b48f2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>employment records that include the employer’s name and contact information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id968a80ecfd0a4fbf87cd71fdab46533f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>official records from a religious entity confirming the alien’s participation in a religious ceremony;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id302135f86a514396a3d849a343a90662"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a birth certificate for a child who was born in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2bac83a478c4125b1515d0f29e48dac"><enum>(9)</enum><text>automobile license receipts or registration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8b9b174d48e4e7d96dce280e3e22617"><enum>(10)</enum><text>deeds, mortgages, or rental agreement contracts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ca7120db61f4b2b929c9a04a5bafd93"><enum>(11)</enum><text>tax receipts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id06ba2d4eb02142a696833704a6489a18"><enum>(12)</enum><text>travel records;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd303363b01ab4d55bd400486b5f6815e"><enum>(13)</enum><text>copies of money order receipts sent in or out of the country;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3574801a38b48d8880213c1478ff99a"><enum>(14)</enum><text>dated bank transactions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id77af974208d54318ae09198cc8de2053"><enum>(15)</enum><text>remittance records; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id83cf595b904546deaf1b22294979b52e"><enum>(16)</enum><text>insurance policies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5e98efb9b74c4d6284b974efde72a4b0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Documents establishing admission to an institution of higher education</header><text>To establish that an alien has been admitted to an institution of higher education, the alien shall submit to the Secretary a document from the institution of higher education certifying that the alien—</text><paragraph id="id6629E488817D413B862AE08B2A87AF72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has been admitted to the institution; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBAA88BE1AE6144D88FC56FA6A946C4FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is currently enrolled in the institution as a student.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcea030ae7f12479aba26f5b240931949"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Documents establishing receipt of a degree from an institution of higher education</header><text>To establish that an alien has acquired a degree from an institution of higher education in the United States, the alien shall submit to the Secretary a diploma or other document from the institution stating that the alien has received such a degree.</text></subsection><subsection id="idfc4a570670204aeda749a7bd6c911336"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Documents establishing receipt of high school diploma, general educational development certificate, or a recognized equivalent</header><text>To establish that an alien has earned a high school diploma or a commensurate alternative award from a public or private high school, or has obtained a general educational development certificate recognized under State law or a high school equivalency diploma in the United States, the alien shall submit to the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="id81af43e0a7ec4ad997b256c170f17096"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a high school diploma, certificate of completion, or other alternate award;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idadb85f060ca44368a8353a7e88e2a5c7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a high school equivalency diploma or certificate recognized under State law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd04ac2eb47b848aab19e0fe69d496a6b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evidence that the alien passed a State-authorized exam, including the general educational development exam, in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9b4e51d402e24494a6d739c547db23a4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Documents establishing enrollment in an educational program</header><text>To establish that an alien is enrolled in any school or education program described in section 3(b)(1)(D)(iii), 3(d)(3)(A)(iii), or 5(a)(1)(C), the alien shall submit school records from the United States school that the alien is currently attending that include—</text><paragraph id="id1294CC10AB97440ABB455A13C2AD2B4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the name of the school; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id65F71FA02FBF4B1F9A5BE311E18C5281"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the alien’s name, periods of attendance, and current grade or educational level.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc7aeb974298c46b6a0d4a4412f093483"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Documents establishing exemption from application fees</header><text>To establish that an alien is exempt from an application fee under section 3(b)(5)(B) or 5(a)(4)(B), the alien shall submit to the Secretary the following relevant documents:</text><paragraph id="id5899D796C94B45A9A76AFA1BB4767091"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Documents to establish age</header><text>To establish that an alien meets an age requirement, the alien shall provide proof of identity, as described in subsection (a), that establishes that the alien is younger than 18 years of age.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94793CD6175A4328AE56A20AD06946D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Documents to establish income</header><text>To establish the alien’s income, the alien shall provide—</text><subparagraph id="id7067f5190a69400a9112e9172f3551a6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employment records that have been maintained by the Social Security Administration, the Internal Revenue Service, or any other Federal, State, or local government agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9acecadc62bf43ba87b76a22dd993056"><enum>(B)</enum><text>bank records; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce59a3c39fc94f2e8b66a1d73094cae8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at least 2 sworn affidavits from individuals who are not related to the alien and who have direct knowledge of the alien’s work and income that contain—</text><clause id="id788d634c20b5442cb93ea3b1cfe7fc53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name, address, and telephone number of the affiant; and</text></clause><clause id="id3f5702c62a7d47ba9cf2ec6fed0b0b27"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the nature and duration of the relationship between the affiant and the alien.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id35F8D9442F0943619010E59301E5DA22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Documents to establish foster care, lack of familial support, homelessness, or serious, chronic disability</header><text>To establish that the alien was in foster care, lacks parental or familial support, is homeless, or has a serious, chronic disability, the alien shall provide at least 2 sworn affidavits from individuals who are not related to the alien and who have direct knowledge of the circumstances that contain—</text><subparagraph id="idfa2a0879833c4f20b397c563fdd445a9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement that the alien is in foster care, otherwise lacks any parental or other familiar support, is homeless, or has a serious, chronic disability, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE36AA303C2B641F680D4FF49B3C8CF7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name, address, and telephone number of the affiant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida90c7e38ce284736b2cc45ae7eaf9c1f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the nature and duration of the relationship between the affiant and the alien.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a0cba26c97846b89b14bffb070a90dc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Documents to establish unpaid medical expense</header><text>To establish that the alien has debt as a result of unreimbursed medical expenses, the alien shall provide receipts or other documentation from a medical provider that—</text><subparagraph id="id15800E55A11E440DAA9F90FEB81BD37E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>bear the provider’s name and address;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20B269ED56CC43E89649D391C04270B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>bear the name of the individual receiving treatment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCD704414D17641C7BC0592FA9C2C1015"><enum>(C)</enum><text>document that the alien has accumulated $10,000 or more in debt in the past 12 months as a result of unreimbursed medical expenses incurred by the alien or an immediate family member of the alien.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idacdb9de2e4394e3b9b9b36be5bbe795a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Documents establishing qualification for hardship exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To establish that an alien satisfies one of the criteria for the hardship exemption set forth in section 5(a)(2)(C), the alien shall submit to the Secretary at least 2 sworn affidavits from individuals who are not related to the alien and who have direct knowledge of the circumstances that warrant the exemption, that contain—</text><paragraph id="idd82ec320a546449890125069eb31868b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the name, address, and telephone number of the affiant; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f15b0cfe8d14e44a893e88cf3dafafc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the nature and duration of the relationship between the affiant and the alien.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2ce5364731484a36821c30bc170f7cbe"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Documents establishing service in the Armed Forces</header><text>To establish that an alien has served in the Armed Forces for at least 2 years and, if discharged, received an honorable discharge, the alien shall submit to the Secretary official service records showing the character of the alien's service.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide3ac05bee3d341eca8dcbc9c5225b9d9"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Documents establishing employment</header><paragraph id="id8df28a8473af4143bec5bb7d98bb5516"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien may satisfy the employment requirement under section 5(a)(1)(C)(iii) by submitting records that—</text><subparagraph id="idd7327093b5564c3dac205e745ffc5536"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish compliance with such employment requirement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3c6c33207694862b62162a9e2c71633"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have been maintained by the Social Security Administration, the Internal Revenue Service, or any other Federal, State, or local government agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id21df6c9570d84f7b9abc103a6ef20278"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other documents</header><text>An alien who is unable to submit the records described in paragraph (1) may satisfy the employment requirement by submitting at least 2 types of reliable documents that provide evidence of employment, including—</text><subparagraph id="id49f2e35ac9d5430290aaaa97a05da517"><enum>(A)</enum><text>bank records;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2088d4b22214b428251a928ddaa0300"><enum>(B)</enum><text>business records;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2bc816d6ce94b41bf223e1a4ad9cfd3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>employer records;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45bcc5fe24ec498fb6c51349f2e0a1e5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>records of a labor union, day labor center, or organization that assists workers in employment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf6f008298c7408ca501a87a600a1ff9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>sworn affidavits from individuals who are not related to the alien and who have direct knowledge of the alien’s work, that contain—</text><clause id="id5aedfef339a34a8f83e3cae6ea180388"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name, address, and telephone number of the affiant; and</text></clause><clause id="id2a3fb1c2c7f4469584777c7f21c71ebf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the nature and duration of the relationship between the affiant and the alien; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6a0cc7782e748f2b96ae90468721941"><enum>(F)</enum><text>remittance records.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id58558ae4a67c43378c1b2d2ed5839518"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Authority To prohibit use of certain documents</header><text>If the Secretary determines, after publication in the Federal Register and an opportunity for public comment, that any document or class of documents does not reliably establish identity or that permanent resident status on a conditional basis is being obtained fraudulently to an unacceptable degree, the Secretary may prohibit or restrict the use of such document or class of documents.</text></subsection></section><section id="id59ffeb886f6946bba312a98503b5cc69"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><subsection id="idc8ae594034434f99b57d1d27a2944cc5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial publication</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish regulations implementing this Act in the Federal Register. Such regulations shall allow eligible individuals to immediately apply affirmatively for the relief available under section 3 without being placed in removal proceedings.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4bc2c0c445dc4b57a789c9bbd259de90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim regulations</header><text>Notwithstanding section 553 of title 5, United States Code, the regulations published pursuant to subsection (a) shall be effective, on an interim basis, immediately upon publication in the Federal Register, but may be subject to change and revision after public notice and opportunity for a period of public comment.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2b650714ccb54e21b986e165930f1e0e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which interim regulations are published under this section, the Secretary shall publish final regulations implementing this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida2a461d333c44a0dbb80bc80f70f20d8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Paperwork Reduction Act</header><text>The requirements under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>), shall not apply to any action to implement this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id1541DAA67CF9426CAC6375E8E30EC4C2"><enum>8.</enum><header>Confidentiality of information</header><subsection id="ida49394f2b25c49048b5f3ee1ceba9acd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may not disclose or use information provided in applications filed under this Act or in requests for DACA for the purpose of immigration enforcement.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide28b2978b9a24828979fbd9c943f8fa8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Referrals prohibited</header><text>The Secretary may not refer any individual who has been granted permanent resident status on a conditional basis or who was granted DACA to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, or any designee of either such entity.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc16221fd6939491696709d1dec630b37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limited exception</header><text>Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), information provided in an application for permanent resident status on a conditional basis or a request for DACA may be shared with Federal security and law enforcement agencies—</text><paragraph id="idab301b37db2b4334a3b305c206c35e11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for assistance in the consideration of an application for permanent resident status on a conditional basis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4780a70661d41d1b45a5034707c1e9e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to identify or prevent fraudulent claims;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c361591e0db4b9a94d7857b7fd08756"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for national security purposes; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id426b90ec5ab444c091258d5269825f84"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for the investigation or prosecution of any felony not related to immigration status.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id145d91ce4f564007b5a5286e2d4f4b83"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any person who knowingly uses, publishes, or permits information to be examined in violation of this section shall be fined not more than $10,000.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

