<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA1344E458AF84F4EB3950B7B9BACBDAB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9196 IH: Helen Keller Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9196</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote and ensure delivery of high-quality special education and
            related services to children and youth who are deafblind, and for other
            purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBF27EE4F53184775B4D6CC932FC4CE9D" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC32A9E4BC7AD4529B15E2E8BA2F066D9"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; references; definition; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H3A7B48A12CDB45CD86D5011CEE319F0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helen Keller Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF9C6205BA17A446FBC86C423AC9728C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text>Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F7ECC7B9B2647538DB364B70ED6F34E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <quote>deafblind</quote>, when applied to an individual, means the individual has concomitant hearing and visual impairments, the combination of which—</text> <paragraph id="H68C6531385EE4111887D7BFA16606C6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevents access to information;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA6501AF60F0471D9E67EE0D8718F673"><enum>(2)</enum><text>causes severe communication challenges;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D436BD445214FB1A77D4220A4C2C316"><enum>(3)</enum><text>interferes with social and emotional well-being; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H063AEAAC935F46D09964413503F670F3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>impacts other developmental areas in a manner that adversely affect a child’s educational performance (including children who are deafblind with additional disabilities).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5BE09CF5B8AE413FA46D9A228D6946D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HC32A9E4BC7AD4529B15E2E8BA2F066D9" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; references; definition; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA30D1F2392A240BA8BFCF69C75DCF1B7" level="title">Title I—General Provisions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HAAB0DC97E0974A1DAF504BF0FD3E0608" level="section">Sec. 101. Identifying children and youth who are deafblind.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE3CF07B43CF541508FE13D68010D068D" level="section">Sec. 102. Related services.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H689765A1E5794CF19F6FE3FA674559FF" level="section">Sec. 103. State plans.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD603A87E481148A5BE4EB2369C98C7C3" level="section">Sec. 104. Evaluations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H39ADBD1FE0EA4E4283D29B69C29CB5E0" level="section">Sec. 105. Consideration of special factors.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H753897CCE6CB4C409246BBEA60C54FF1" level="section">Sec. 106. Technical assistance for parents and educators of children and youth who are deafblind.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9A61DF33689F4E8DA31770C55152F514" level="section">Sec. 107. Conforming regulations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4F17CAE0A4AE4000A92B76D769D61551" level="title">Title II—Improving the Effectiveness of Early Intervention for Infants and Toddlers Who Are Deafblind and Their Families</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCED7C82E1E7D45DEB7F8EBFFBABCE368" level="section">Sec. 201. Content of plan.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF89BD07144BA41ECB44EE8E825161B61" level="title">Title III—National Activities To Improve the Education of Children With Disabilities</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA562C362986A449DB1CBF84C2167B111" level="section">Sec. 301. Personnel development to improve services and results for children with disabilities; ensuring sufficient teachers of children who are deafblind, interveners, and early intervention specialists.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<title id="HA30D1F2392A240BA8BFCF69C75DCF1B7"><enum>I</enum><header>General Provisions</header> 
<section id="HAAB0DC97E0974A1DAF504BF0FD3E0608"><enum>101.</enum><header>Identifying children and youth who are deafblind</header> 
<subsection id="H10CC78C35CA846D180C1D51268EF7D9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Serving all children who are deafblind regardless of classification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 612(a)(3) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1412">20 U.S.C. 1412(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8D755041452443E0AE0CE918D7973EE7"> <subparagraph id="HC3524F9E761B4173BA4DF6CF089A5C6E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Serving children who are deafblind</header><text>When a State classifies children by disability, the State, in complying with subsection (a)—</text> 
<clause id="H2B1D77F300EA4AD89D1BF122ACC7F319"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifies, locates and evaluates children with concomitant vision and hearing losses who are, or may be, classified in a disability category other than deafblindness; and</text></clause> <clause id="H840A28F6693441458DEB0ECB824FFB06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides (without prejudice to such classification) special education and related services to such children, including the specific services determined appropriate based on proper evaluation as would be provided to children classified in the State as having deafblindness.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H0F0286CD09A44896B130DB0C1213E7A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data collection and reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 618 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1418">20 U.S.C. 1418</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H08400B2817B64D58B505B9DBEE04E5A4"> <subsection commented="no" id="HE8263F30C9D142A3B60BB2FAAD20DAFA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Accounting for children who are deafblind</header><text>In addition to the other data collection and reporting requirements of this section and subject to such provisions, the State and the Secretary of the Interior shall, with respect to children classified in a disability category other than deafblindness, include the number and percentage of such children in each disability category who are also deafblind.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC154CC88568247A5BF7775B302E51ACB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Child with a disability</header><text>Section 602(3)(A)(i) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401(3)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>deafblindness,</quote> before <quote>serious</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="HE3CF07B43CF541508FE13D68010D068D"><enum>102.</enum><header>Related services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 602(26)(A) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401(26)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, and intervener services, which are provided to children who are deafblind by a qualified intervener</quote> after <quote>for diagnostic and evaluation purposes only</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H689765A1E5794CF19F6FE3FA674559FF"><enum>103.</enum><header>State plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 612 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1412">20 U.S.C. 1412</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBCC44C61BF2F417390CAA2AC391480F5"> <subsection id="HD77E3F8CF40D49FD894FC02D8EADFF59"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Addendum concerning children who are deafblind</header> <paragraph id="H2F81B206ADAD45FA815F76B05FA65DF3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (c), a State shall not be determined to be in compliance with this section unless, not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of the Helen Keller Education Act, the State files with the Secretary a written addendum to the plan required by this section describing how the State ensures that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF93B4C35742544ADBD364E5FE279A5CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>children who are deafblind (regardless of the State’s use of disability categories or the extent to which children with deafblindness may be classified in disability categories other than deafblindness) are evaluated by qualified professionals, including teachers of the deafblind, using valid and reliable assessments, for such children’s need for instruction and services that meet their unique language and communication, literacy, academic, social and related learning needs, including instruction which may be needed by children without disabilities or with other disabilities but which must be specifically designed, modified, or delivered to meet the unique language and communication, academic, and related learning needs of children who are deafblind;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB3CF356A19C4B52ABE1ED13AD246796"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there is sufficient availability of personnel, including teachers of the deafblind and interveners, within the State qualified to provide the evaluation, instruction, and services described in subparagraph (A) to all children within the State requiring such instruction; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59FBF489637743DFB14ECF943B5E49FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all children who are deafblind within the State who need special education and related services, whether or not such children have other disabilities, receive such instruction and are not being served solely in accordance with section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09D476B708B64C7AB067079F14A5C8F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In preparing the addendum described in paragraph (1), the State shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H209174C650D54F07858ABFBCA2086051"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specifically address how the State meets the needs of children who are deafblind to support ongoing progress in language development and in the child’s preferred mode of communication, and including the provision of school-related opportunities for direct communications with peers and professional personnel in the child’s preferred mode of communication and opportunities for direct instruction in (but not limited to) concept development, functional skills for academic success, self-determination and advocacy, social-emotional skills, visual and auditory sensory efficiency skills, orientation and mobility, assistive technology proficiency, independent living skills, age-appropriate career education, and support for the student through family education; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H47EE1F96F7BA4FBFBE243B87D2F89E65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consult with individuals and organizations with expertise in the education of children who are deafblind, including parents, consumers, advocacy organizations, national and State organizations focused on deafblindness, and others the State may identify.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HD603A87E481148A5BE4EB2369C98C7C3"><enum>104.</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 614(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1414">20 U.S.C. 1414(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H370BED8911A74AFF8BEB518DE56473B6"> <paragraph id="H38A96569FF894080992D5F4D814113BB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Children who are deafblind</header> <subparagraph id="H7B4A1E6D88E64CCC925EEB369A42255D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In conducting the assessments prescribed in paragraph (3)(B), children who are deafblind (including children who may have additional disabilities) shall be evaluated on language and communication proficiency levels, including expressive, receptive, and pragmatic skills, and ability to access grade level content in the child’s preferred mode of communication, including non-symbolic and symbolic communication and tactile sign language. Qualified personnel trained in deafblindness, who communicate in the child’s preferred mode of communication, shall be actively involved in assessments and evaluations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E85EB1E3A05472F9711A4BF7EBD81C8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Content of evaluations</header><text>The evaluations described in subparagraph (A) shall, at a minimum, include evaluations assessing the need for services and supports to assist children who are deafblind in developing and maintaining language and communication skills in their preferred mode of communication, including non-symbolic and symbolic communication and tactile sign language.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section commented="no" id="H39ADBD1FE0EA4E4283D29B69C29CB5E0"><enum>105.</enum><header>Consideration of special factors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 614(d)(3)(B) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1414">20 U.S.C. 1414(d)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD1789FB36939495C9CB6284E6F2DCD8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF8CD60C2D2249C48E61FCD62320CD81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (v) as clause (vi); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11B88D8EC89346818DC5F314CBE62533"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iv) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6DF98D48AD254DDEA58CDB7A559E361C"> <clause commented="no" id="H3DB5CF23BA55456DA2940B3056BBC518"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a child who is deafblind, provide for the child’s language and communication needs, including tactile sign language, tactile and visual adaptations to sign and fingerspelling, and object and tangible symbol systems. The requirements included in clauses (iii) and (iv) shall also apply to children who are deafblind; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H753897CCE6CB4C409246BBEA60C54FF1"><enum>106.</enum><header>Technical assistance for parents and educators of children and youth who are deafblind</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 616 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1416">20 U.S.C. 1416</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE8755A9F024D4BFB8054462CA44C93E9"> <subsection id="H5C2EEF38020A438086D50F0FDE7ECF67"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Developing policy guidance for parents and educators of children who are deafblind</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Helen Keller Education Act, policy guidance concerning the provision of special education and related services to children who are deafblind is developed (and periodically thereafter but not less than once every 5 years, updated) with particular attention to explanation of relevant amendments to this Act or to its implementing regulations and is published in the Federal Register.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H9A61DF33689F4E8DA31770C55152F514"><enum>107.</enum><header>Conforming regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 617 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1417">20 U.S.C. 1417</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HADB6B462566547D1952F1B1A59326DA8"> <subsection id="H635935CC91B24C9A99481C8FA3EECF1B"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Helen Keller Education Act, the Secretary shall, after notice and comment, publish regulations that provide definitions for <quote>deafblindness</quote> and <quote>intervener services</quote>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title> 
<title id="H4F17CAE0A4AE4000A92B76D769D61551"><enum>II</enum><header>Improving the Effectiveness of Early Intervention for Infants and Toddlers Who Are Deafblind and Their Families</header> 
<section id="HCED7C82E1E7D45DEB7F8EBFFBABCE368"><enum>201.</enum><header>Content of plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 636(d) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1436">20 U.S.C. 1436(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1C59CD9FB6B04C91B1D07CE652222017"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FB54CB42708456DBC95623C3FC4616B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (8), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EBDE039F6214CD8BA58C028DFB4F63C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80132F094A9C498CBBE63532C8416870"> 
<paragraph id="HD0258F0B706B4345A9183542EA2F5CD2"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an infant or toddler who is deafblind, a statement of the ongoing language and communication assessment that will be provided to the child, language and communication development goals commensurate with the child’s cognitive abilities, the language and communication access that will be provided, including ongoing opportunities for direct language learning and communication access to peers, early intervention service providers, and other professional personnel trained in the child’s preferred mode of communication, and the support and instruction that will be provided to families to learn and support the child’s language and communication mode and the child’s full range of needs.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title> <title id="HF89BD07144BA41ECB44EE8E825161B61"><enum>III</enum><header>National Activities To Improve the Education of Children With Disabilities</header> <section id="HA562C362986A449DB1CBF84C2167B111"><enum>301.</enum><header>Personnel development to improve services and results for children with disabilities; ensuring sufficient teachers of children who are deafblind, interveners, and early intervention specialists</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 662(c)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1462">20 U.S.C. 1462(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H309F1BBB8D5A498189F0A795FC99AD33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (F) and (G) as subparagraphs (H) and (I), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19E012D02148468FA112098373E738CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H54C54FDCC39A45F6A861C6C683C28994"> 
<subparagraph id="H4D3DED89774D48D894A8271614539A52"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Preparing personnel to be qualified teachers of children who are deafblind and early intervention specialists, to assist children who are deafblind in schools and school-related activities, as well as toddlers and preschool children who are deafblind in early intervention and preschool programs, to develop communication and literacy skills, to be able to access, organize and utilize information about the environment, and to acquire concepts essential for learning.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F7DE08661CC4E08944C5FC2CA5FD98A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Preparing personnel to be qualified interveners as individualized supports to assist children who are deafblind in school and school-related activities, and infants and toddlers and preschool children who are deafblind in early intervention and preschool programs.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </title> 
</legis-body></bill>

