<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H392146F705E041BE98C05C770A59DC69" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1392 IH: Supporting the designation of a “National Learn to Swim Week” beginning on the 4th Sunday in June.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1392</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of a <quote>National Learn to Swim Week</quote> beginning on the 4th Sunday in June.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), drowning remains the leading cause of death among children ages 1 to 4, is the second-leading cause of unintentional injury death among children ages 5 to 14 in the United States, and is in the top 10 leading causes of unintentional injury death across all age groups;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas CDC data indicate that in recent years, an estimated 4,000 fatal unintentional drownings occur annually in the United States, including boating-related incidents, equivalent to 11 deaths per day;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas an additional 8,000 nonfatal drownings occur each year, often resulting in long-term neurological and cognitive disabilities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a study supported by the National Institutes of Health found that formal swimming lessons can reduce the risk of drowning among young children by 88 percent;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it is important to practice additional water safety precautions to help prevent drowning, such as—</text> <paragraph id="H89397A09AD5E4739A3F3E5B5BAADF3BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>close and active supervision;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H672DE83109A4461F8940394C753461A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preventing unsupervised access to water, including four-sided isolation fencing that fully encloses pool areas;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9150DD44AE99439CBDFD9AE0D8F9B331"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring that children, inexperienced swimmers, and all boaters wear Coast Guard-approved life jackets; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7850674B25E1437781BBCD006FE4EBDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>swimming in lifeguarded areas;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas lack of access to designated swimming areas, lack of available swim and water safety lessons, financial constraints, and limited instruction tailored to cultural and logistical needs contribute to disproportionate drowning risks among underserved communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the USA Swimming Foundation reports that 64 percent of African-American children, 45 percent of Hispanic and Latino children, and 40 percent of White children lack basic swimming skills, and if a parent does not know how to swim, there is only a 19-percent chance that a child in their household will learn to swim, which underscores the urgent need for expanded access to lessons for people of all ages;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas learning to swim not only reduces the risk of drownings but also promotes physical health, self-confidence, and inclusion in recreational and competitive aquatic activities for a lifetime; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas learning to swim is not just a life skill but a lifesaving skill: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H09FC0AA4CAB8454684847BED55569157"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7FC67CB13EB3445DB0D0AF1DAC521B3B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That—</text> 
<paragraph id="H76304A3498D04FB1A186A76CB5D6661C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the House of Representatives supports the designation of a <quote>National Learn to Swim Week</quote> to raise awareness of water safety and to encourage families and communities to take action; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10A890710E2A4404AA1D7115D290544E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3094308B16B9400C94F5A44C91C0D184"><enum>(A)</enum><text>learning to swim is a lifesaving skill that helps reduce the risk of drowning, and every child and adult in the United States should have the opportunity to learn;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFCB2A95A2AB84FBF82D52939022C7718"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal, State, and local governments should promote and support access to swimming lessons, including through public funding, education initiatives, and partnerships with community-based organizations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF5AE1BB34134056A5FAFBDE235B9904"><enum>(C)</enum><text>schools and youth-serving organizations should be encouraged to integrate water safety education into their curricula and extracurricular programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B8A193087F04F25A6C27B535A517EF4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Congress should support a national effort to reduce drowning deaths by supporting the United States National Water Safety Action Plan, whose mission is to prevent drowning in the United States through evidence-informed action; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD07883A3B3DA40658C7555A776F6B056"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Congress should support a national effort to reduce drowning deaths, through tracking of fatal and nonfatal drowning, expanded lifesaving swim instructions, public awareness campaigns, and infrastructure investment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

