<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25E66-HF1-WX-8N4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3440 IS: Temporary Family Visitation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3440</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a new nonimmigrant category for alien relatives of United States citizens and lawful permanent residents seeking to enter the United States temporarily for family purposes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H7E8B93EB42944280880722526C9873E5"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC3A98B998ED84B5DAC8D7EBE85374DAE"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Temporary Family Visitation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAFB957860FBC4FC386E6EB1DC22419AA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Family purpose nonimmigrant visas for relatives of United States citizens and lawful permanent residents seeking to enter the United States temporarily</header><subsection id="H12CF327513BD4ED6B13788AAF004608F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of new nonimmigrant visa category</header><text>Section 101(a)(15)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and who is visiting the United States temporarily for business or temporarily for pleasure;</quote> and inserting</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8B879F934C76476E9BADB49AEDA28DB3"><text>and who is visiting the United States temporarily for—</text><clause id="H6FBD49990E844043BDE3BBA65B87D91D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>business;</text></clause><clause id="H4FBAA45442634314AF463F5F04B5B0DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pleasure; or</text></clause><clause id="HB0FB79B9F8124FA1A856CDB9E1C51795"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>family purposes;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB8DCFAAC26D046AFBDC752F26C5BC344"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements applicable to family purpose visas</header><text>Section 214 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H35D3882CDF14478FB5051247F05A4A7F"><subsection id="H3D2E976538404D6795974BB716133E2A"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Requirements applicable to family purpose visas</header><paragraph id="H93F86BBD086F4C219FDF47916BA561AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection and section 101(a)(15)(B)(iii):</text><subparagraph id="H20D239C8BDB2496AB7E6B130C4FEA810"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Family purposes</header><text>The term <term>family purposes</term> means any visit by a relative for a social or occasional purpose, a major life event, a religious event, or for any other purpose.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE589E985712C49D6A254908A3C76CD08"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relative</header><text>The term <term>relative</term> means the spouse, child, son, daughter, grandchild, parent, grandparent, great-grandparent, sibling, uncle, aunt, niece, or nephew of a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1AAB7A2BB604AD389604F88D0444A78"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>A relative seeking admission pursuant to a visa issued under section 101(a)(15)(B)(iii) is inadmissible unless—</text><subparagraph id="H18088D474E9347F6A6BF8FC0403B88F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual petitioning for such admission, or an additional sponsor, has submitted to the Secretary of Homeland Security an undertaking under section 213 in the form of a declaration of financial support;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B28EE9BA6974DF2913C71004A7115A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such relative has obtained, for the duration of his or her stay in the United States, a short-term travel medical insurance policy or an existing health insurance policy that provides coverage for international medical expenses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42B95F3C69C54AD3B8FC3CB09FEFE1F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such relative expresses intent to leave the United States at the conclusion of the period of authorized admission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEA5C3F701164385BAA53F3933957BA3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Period of authorized admission</header><text>The period of authorized admission for a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(B)(iii) shall not exceed 90 days per calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H759D39FAE3AE42608621AC4BCEC6FC4C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Petitioner eligibility</header><subparagraph id="H4C3C4A9D6A2B4B148EFD86DB1F291879"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual may not petition for the admission of a relative as a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(B)(iii) if the individual previously petitioned for the admission of such a relative who—</text><clause id="H7D78B5CD959540D3B77B814BFB50628C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was admitted to the United States pursuant to a visa issued under that section as a result; and</text></clause><clause id="H05D6FBCFD89E4498A12A525E22EBDAE4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>overstayed his or her period of authorized admission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F4B2743C2CF43A4A1EF4AB0F2B02C4F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Previous petitioners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual filing a declaration of financial support for the admission of a relative as a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(B)(iii) who has previously provided a declaration of financial support for such a relative shall certify to the Secretary of Homeland Security that the relative whose admission the individual previously supported did not overstay his or her period of authorized admission or provide an explanation of why the relative’s overstay was due to extraordinary circumstances beyond the control of the relative. A certification under this subparagraph shall be subject to section 1001 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8C66CACCBD24999B73B243275F2E126"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may waive the application of section 212(a)(9)(B) in the case of a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(B)(iii) who overstayed his or her period of authorized admission due to extraordinary circumstances beyond the control of the nonimmigrant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H075959BF5B6E4A059A1674F46781BF39"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Restriction on change of status</header><text>Section 248(a)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1258">8 U.S.C. 1258(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9C1FBC6036ED4724BC375FA621C15AED"><paragraph id="HA2DF365A2D97487792AAECD45FA42329"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an alien classified as a nonimmigrant under subparagraph (B)(iii), (C), (D), (K), or (S) of section 101(a)(15),</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA35CDA7B146449BE836E446195FDCADF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Family purpose visa eligibility while awaiting immigrant visa</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a21546fa9cb4616a6e9744b13da4a82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 214(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(b)</external-xref>), a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(B)(iii) of that Act who has been classified as an immigrant under section 201 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>) and is awaiting the availability of an immigrant visa subject to the numerical limitations under section 203 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153</external-xref>) may be admitted pursuant to a family purpose visa, in accordance with section 214(s) of that Act, if the individual is otherwise eligible for admission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73cee5d3057644b0ae1d6de6f647118a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien admitted as a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(B)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act shall not be considered to have been admitted to the United States for purposes of section 245(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0D7931E059874911B804B3A11109C439"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdf6b247acb6479fbd35c1c53eb49f2f"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to limit the authority of immigration officers to refuse to admit to the United States an applicant under section 101(a)(15)(B)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act who fails to meet one or more of the criteria under section 214(s) of that Act, or who is inadmissible under section 212(a) of that Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41c77fa9875548bd8eedaff6f2846286" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to preclude the application of section 101(a)(15)(B)(ii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to family travel for pleasure in accordance with the policies and procedures in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

