<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MAZ26070-TJD-W1-7YP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3836 IS: Foreign Emissions and Nonattainment Clarification for Economic Stability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3836</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Clean Air Act to clarify standards for emissions emanating from outside of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6C36873B73AB45D8B25DE8865599F0BB"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD7B01755D4A44C6B93C08C78E2818BBB"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foreign Emissions and Nonattainment Clarification for Economic Stability Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FENCES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" id="H34E98C2FA9B342058DD797398C29F32A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Emissions beyond control</header><subsection id="HCD79345187FE4261A6230FD5417A3C52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification of emissions covered</header><text>Section 179B of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7509a">42 U.S.C. 7509a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4F5BFF5A1A0C40758F248CA4B56DEDD3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(regardless of whether such emissions result from human activity)</quote> after <quote>but for emissions emanating from outside of the United States</quote> each place it appears; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13F62C788DFE4B73B17B230CB54B4EE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by inserting <quote>(regardless of whether such emissions result from human activity)</quote> after <quote>but for emissions emanating from outside the United States</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDFC5766BBF040C28C61374997ADB425"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 179B of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7509a">42 U.S.C. 7509a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C56A2AF74394A95B7070F9A6ACA876E"><subsection id="H79FA730BC18549B588AF90BFAD96EB15"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Designations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an area within a State may not be designated as a nonattainment area with respect to any new or revised primary or secondary national ambient air quality standard for a pollutant if such State establishes to the satisfaction of the Administrator that such area would be in attainment with such national ambient air quality standard for such pollutant but for emissions emanating from outside of the United States (regardless of whether such emissions result from human activity).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1B56316A73154C049140D1D6F779A12E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability of sanctions and fees if emissions beyond control</header><text>Subpart 1 of part D of title I of the Clean Air Act is amended by inserting after section 179 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7509">42 U.S.C. 7509</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09C9909E56864F6BB8A7427BDFF2F1DE"><section commented="no" id="H923643B7A06A4E5599E2BB223BFE4D79"><enum>179A.</enum><header>Applicability of sanctions and fees if emissions beyond control</header><subsection commented="no" id="H41CF6B2FE14D4473BBC2695386C67B92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, with respect to any nonattainment area that is classified under section 181 as a Severe Area or an Extreme Area for ozone or under section 188 as a Serious Area for particulate matter, no sanction or fee under section 179 or 185 shall apply with respect to a State (or an area or source therein) on the basis of a deficiency described in section 179(a), or the failure to attain a national ambient air quality standard for ozone or particulate matter by the applicable attainment date, if the State demonstrates that the State would have avoided such deficiency, or such standard would have been attained, but for one or more of the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HC067910CA13D4156AC2E278EECD4AE91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Emissions emanating from outside the nonattainment area.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H23B382CF810E4F0EBF54D8D68F6B7ABE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Emissions from an exceptional event (as defined in section 319(b)(1)).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1E6A10034B87445AA0E05BCA864742D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Emissions from mobile sources to the extent the State demonstrates that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H98199F16969946608C01B7DE5348A2B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such emissions are beyond the control of the State to reduce or eliminate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H23818D2DD9CD4F9E8F3266B21FBC973D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State is fully implementing such measures as are within the authority of the State to control emissions from the mobile sources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF16553E2ED0D464B90BD40C77660DE09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No effect on underlying standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The inapplicability of sanctions or fees with respect to a State (or an area or source therein) pursuant to subsection (a) does not affect the obligation of a State, area, source, or other entity under other provisions of this Act to establish and implement measures to attain a national ambient air quality standard for ozone or particulate matter.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB72D351BDF7648A88A3D365C475A4895"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Periodic renewal of demonstration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For subsection (a) to continue to apply with respect to a State (or an area or source therein), the State involved shall renew the demonstration required by subsection (a) at least once every 5 years.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

