<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0C2397B4CDF64E1DAD6C4EA58C16B1A3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7519 IH: Army Corps Congressional Engagement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7519</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the District Commanders of the Corps of Engineers to provide to offices of Members of Congress annual briefings on projects funded or led by the Corps of Engineers in watersheds within such district, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H384F22A26C6C48068C53BBD1970F389C" style="OLC"><section id="H34BE102C4FA04947B1535B2F13522972" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be referred to as the <quote><short-title>Army Corps Congressional Engagement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2EFE25071E9B43979F7C37E38120A8E0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual briefings on Corps of Engineers projects within United States watersheds</header><subsection id="H2C30E928695144B3B59086AAC7108FB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each calendar year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, the District Commander of each district of the Corps of Engineers shall provide to each office of a Member of Congress for which the respective congressional district is located, fully or partially, in the district of the Corps of Engineers, an annual briefing, virtually or in-person at the discretion of the District Commander—</text><paragraph id="H00A58DE29BCE451CBBA81C6089C7F14B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>regarding each project that is—</text><subparagraph id="HEFA70F4DB3004FA1A60AA8C7A029F8D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located in the district of the Corps of Engineers and, fully or partially, in the respective congressional district;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B2924A77759408F85BCF4759C8678F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fully or partially located within a watershed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB60B8E52ABB14153B2266F342D653569"><enum>(C)</enum><text>funded, partially funded, led, or partially led by the Corps of Engineers, or on which the Corps of Engineers has consulted during the period covered by the report;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D2D8BC206694CC296428C8D2D9AE7E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conveying for each such project—</text><subparagraph id="H5D59444004E24750BA2B3B00C8F8543F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the location, including identification of any other congressional districts in which the project is being carried out;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53E77559E44243478A783578350120E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the status and progress towards project completion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC22FE94E02B845188F0FB39874674F98"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any delays, or potential delays, in the project timeline;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF45339A5FB29481ABBBBEE28016C9FE7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of funding expended by the Corps of Engineers, total and for the period covered by the report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA476946319A41D49EE65422D767F9EF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an estimation any additional funds required to complete the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFADD345659C1448A9FB627F48EC0CA2A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of project expenses for which funds were expended by the Corps of Engineers, since project inception and for the period covered by the report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30E31CAA167548F2A208BA478F97A52A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a summary of any environmental impacts of the project and any identifiable impacts of the project on the community local to the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9494C9D478314774B1F96D7AD2636446"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of any engagement between the Corps of Engineers and a non-Federal sponsor or the public with respect to the project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0FC644AC9E5415886E039C754EC313E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any opportunities identified by the District Commander for a related study or project authorization that may be carried out in the same congressional district in which the project is being carried out;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3246B20B408C4AEBBA63AAFCDBB27AA8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>detailing any request for additional appropriations for use in one or more such projects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF30DB705D4D94CF4A8898E7A189267B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that includes a period during which the Member of Congress and staff of the office may ask questions regarding any project being carried out in the congressional district of the Member.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A3A215C9E4443DDA35663A43236DCAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Failure to brief</header><paragraph id="H65D4CC14D901440A82FF42643EE8B1FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Written statement</header><text>For each calendar year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, if a District Commander has not provided an annual briefing required under subsection (a) by December 1 of the calendar year, the District Commander shall, prior to December 31 of the calendar year, submit to each office of a Member of Congress the District Commander has yet to brief as required under subsection (a) a written statement that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H50895894B2EE4FF7888564F0C097FBD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an explanation of why the briefing has not occurred;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0763898F82C44F9AB7AEDA5B767A6152"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indication of whether the District Commander has contacted the office about scheduling the briefing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4915651F9FE749DFA3230C7071589367"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the District Commander plans to ensure that the briefing is scheduled as soon as possible.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H089C539680BD4B5EA7B5989FFAE19A6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a District Commander fails to submit a written statement required under paragraph (1), not later than 30 day after the date on which the written statement was due, the Inspector General of the Army shall submit to each office of a Member of Congress the District Commander has yet to brief as required under subsection (a) and the relevant Congressional Committees a report containing—</text><subparagraph id="H1A67EB58AB1B4449949FC48A36C9F175"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of an investigation of the Inspector General as to why the briefing did not occur during the calendar year in which it was required; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51D06A37F8184848978BF8D7BE8C6439"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations of the Inspector General to facilitate and ensure the briefing takes place as soon as possible.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCBA5A9FE0A94820B820C407C2609597"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE98EDE8F75AF40EDB8CF72594726F02E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Member of Congress</term> includes a Delegate to Congress and a Resident Commissioner to Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB500458045904F2E885444C7025EDF30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relevant Congressional Committees</header><text>The term <term>relevant Congressional Committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H38A2CAD07BB04F948A45FDF8AAA0C40A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06647CE70D48409E81B0C9E0CE50199F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H784B71DD861D47EBB5F4F556C4927BC7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE75D5BBD63AB45789530353A38CC5D14"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

