<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6C942B64E06645E3BE12B0C0FAE105F0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7241 IH: Protect Veterans from the Theft of Health and Identifying Information in Electronic Forms Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7241</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from entering into a contract pursuant to which the contractor may sell sensitive personal information maintained by the Secretary and to ensure the protection of personal information in certain contracts of the Department.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H45280FB8FF8E41C48486707D07AF235D" style="OLC"><section id="H0C91ACC6CE4449EBB6B723BC29BE8D86" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Veterans from the Theft of Health and Identifying Information in Electronic Forms Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Protect Veterans from the THIEF Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4AE38D7D503B4B9A96D8ED8973DA242C" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition of the sale of sensitive personal information maintained by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5725 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HD9BDAB319AFA422290693B9D2769683B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H0CC95EECE26348449E091BF4C1CBD4FC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition of sale of sensitive personal information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not enter into a contract that permits the contractor to sell (or otherwise disclose for consideration) sensitive personal information to another entity.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H1B50F4DBFC274FCD9457BB6307F74B00" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protection of personal information in contracts of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="HAFBBD941AA614E28AB64A2223F10984F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph id="HE47E21288FF04D50946551D54779165A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that each covered contract includes, or is modified to include, a clause prohibiting covered information from being monetized, sold, or otherwise misused by any contractor, including any subcontractor or affiliate thereof, or other non-Department of Veterans Affairs entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5455461AAFD84CA3B232EC971B61FFB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue a directive or other policy providing guidance to employees and contractors of the Department on how to identify the monetization, sale, or misuse of covered information in order to ensure contractors are in compliance with clauses in covered contracts included pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H026C5D3A473E48938D74EDCB8D47F5B8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="HC3DB27CDDCD348CFB350E550BD04887B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a copy of the contract clause required by subsection (a)(1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67E9A31D8ABB4D18B54EC04E5FDAF35A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the guidance required by subsection (a)(2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEE09B8E8D914FF7A565E9DBF474EE97"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a summary of any other actions taken to comply with subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F2D0373C52F487CA8BD362F5C739E5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB98EFD94E75D400FA974E4A383B58E2F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H777FE7624615496989C931CDB5F8FB2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered contract</term> means a contract of the Department of Veterans Affairs that provides for the handling of covered information and is entered into—</text><subparagraph id="H367F78E11BAA4776A99143E257246880"><enum>(A)</enum><text>after the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0016258C8A1049BA978213E9DB6410AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>before the date of the enactment of this Act and does not expire before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H997F3734E462414EA0BE6E96A64F944D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>covered information</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H4A48F7276BBD4B52B691E470A43F96DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means protected health information or personally identifiable information, including such information that has been anonymized; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD093FE946D58496CB38EFF6558B5CDA8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes information protected under—</text><clause id="H7A9D8AD1715E4FC28129F3F094C494B2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 552a of title 5, United States Code;</text></clause><clause id="HA0959C27DF3F427AB5DEDE41967FD93D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 5701 or 7332 of title 38 United States Code;</text></clause><clause id="H44480B30E1704A45B027A95E6DE6ACE8" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>parts 160, 161, and 164 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></clause><clause id="HE38219826E7342319A6D10B45B1CA63D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other provision of law, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

