<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26990-41G-TT-GST"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4501 IS: Barring American Citizenship by Keeping Out Foreign Fraudsters</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4501</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To bar aliens from admission to the United States to give birth on United States soil or remaining in the United States to undermine the sovereignty of the United States through birth tourism.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Barring American Citizenship by Keeping Out Foreign Fraudsters</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BACK OFF Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc921d9e81b5b447a8b078aa7850ea0f9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grounds for inadmissibility to, and removal from the United States for engaging in birth tourism</header><subsection id="idea296684cdf24292a34e6a74c66ed051"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grounds of inadmissibility</header><text>Section 212(a)(2)(F) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(2)(F)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd81ceb0668444512b7f05eda934b3b08"><subparagraph id="ida9aaa755e7d5401fa15f3814d723a5ba"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Aliens undermining the sovereignty of United States through birth tourism</header><clause id="id7c6c970f873241c2bfc513aa8133dba1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any alien convicted of, who admits to having committed, or who admits committing acts which constitute the essential elements of, an offense described in section 274E, 274F, or 275(e) or an offense described in section 1546A of title 18, United States Code, is inadmissible.</text></clause><clause id="id04c92bca55194fcb956e01693f5d9eb8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Birth tourism</header><text>An alien is inadmissible if such alien—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6cf2fa6d8df043b29aa294a405af132c"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idc80f6869b23547b39a912872f16bb9f4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not lawfully admitted to the United States as a permanent resident; or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3443cced507444595262c8d8ce03b4a" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not lawfully maintained lawful permanent resident status (such status not having been abandoned, rescinded, or terminated); and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id1e931e15348046b0bb181a5f7f583a33"><enum>(II)</enum><text>based on the reasonable judgment of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, or a consular officer—</text><item id="id6cb561f33bc24a52965c2f2b01604e30"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is seeking to enter or reenter the United States to engage in birth tourism and undermine the sovereignty of the United States or its territories or outlying possessions by giving birth to a child on United States soil; or</text></item><item id="id5cad2ebf953048bb800c4c4ebf69b3d7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is likely to give birth to a child within 10 months of entry if such alien is admitted to, or while in the United States or its territories or outlying possessions and, as a result, obtain United States citizenship for such child based on the child’s birth on United States soil; or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id7d3b3a23eaaa4ce79608a7ac86f501cb"><enum>(III)</enum><text>as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b9d29b501374f5f9fb566c7ff4b9fc8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has engaged in birth tourism; or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id444000c599a94fc28b5dcff0c4232464"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">while physically present in the United States or its territories or outlying possessions, is likely to give birth to a child and, as a result, obtain United States citizenship for such child based on the child’s birth on United States soil.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idb87a0b844e924a8e9df8b0881a898142"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Waiver not authorized</header><text>The grounds of inadmissibility specified in this subparagraph may not be waived.</text></clause><clause id="id2ea342c4fe354d90824c839171d47bf4"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Ineligibility for parole</header><text>An alien who is inadmissible under this subparagraph is not be eligible for parole into the United States under section 212(d)(5) or for conditional parole under section 236.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="ide1c1e4941f25474c91b5878878215b9b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grounds of deportability</header><text>Section 237(a)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda32710fa20b4ab0a01ab913c86ed115"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraph (F) as subparagraph (G); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7e29b80a31e40688906bb2c11cfd4ea"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id143f286c143d4c29b818e26c00d93f9d"><subparagraph id="id249cedb7264347c7875759723bfffbf9"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Aliens undermining the sovereignty of United States through birth tourism</header><clause id="iddf5e331bb32e4e42ace789645796615c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien is deportable if such alien—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2edc5e43e8054f739aa3b93d4ac27997"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id570ce0c772bd45cd9203331f8a5bff13"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not lawfully admitted to the United States as a permanent resident; or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9595c5eff90487386e1710a65661c2a" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not lawfully maintaining lawful permanent resident status (such status not having been abandoned, rescinded, or terminated); and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id1524cd7f7a4f4b808606efea676e6900"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has been convicted of an offense under section 274E, 274F, or 275(e) or under section 1546A of title 18, United States Code; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id2c1056f825c0473a82f99e5f0f0a5ec3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is described in section 212(a)(2)(F).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idd3ffa6ece53b46b3af3bc17b650b0f0b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Waiver not authorized</header><text>The grounds of deportability specified in clause (i) may not be waived.</text></clause><clause id="id3897905036a5408383cc8aec7fce43f1"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Ineligibility for parole</header><text>An alien who is deportable under clause (i) is not be eligible for parole into the United States under section 212(d)(5) or for conditional parole under section 236.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idd27b41548f42414eb28f39cdff1bb323"><enum>3.</enum><header>Mandatory detention for criminal aliens inadmissible or subject to deportation for birth tourism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 236(c)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">8 U.S.C. 1226(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id16320c5e6bdb41b7a924c4ed4f432a72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at the end of each of subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), by striking the comma at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07ea181b35ac4959b163df245089a8fd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>, or</quote> at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf5e69fba83db4410bd031c8cb2982636"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E)(ii), by striking the comma at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e3b86be990b4977a8c22f0e1fa2d9d0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E)(ii) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb18aa9345eaa48ffa0fbc712e5eb0a10"><subparagraph id="idb0fa8bb2515c4099b0946e8616334a03"><enum>(F)</enum><text>is inadmissible under section 212(a)(2)(F) or deportable under section 237(a)(2)(F) by reason of having been convicted of, admitting to having committed, or admitting committing acts that are the essential elements of, an offense under sections 274E, 274F, or 275(e), or of section 1546A of title 18, United States Code,</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="ide28482c8682748d79b3a42bc64dabe4c"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expedited removal for aliens engaged in birth tourism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 235 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf2030fa35a549ceb10342399b9df344"><subsection id="id3bd0bd203a974057958ee29cc736d3c1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Removal of aliens based on birth tourism</header><paragraph id="id97a565d36f614a2caa83fb628baca143" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Removal without further hearing</header><text>An immigration officer who determines an alien is inadmissible under section 212(a)(2)(F) or deportable under section 237(a)(2)(F)—</text><subparagraph id="ide435f8d899ef45f28126068fa95ea6bd" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall order the alien removed, subject to review in accordance with paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddae3b3546a5a4e3e8ec18674c8cca5ab" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall report the order of removal to the immigration court as expeditiously as possible, but in no case later than 7 days after the date of such determination; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8b3a6b3ee60f4d668260dd26220ff3ea" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may not conduct any further inquiry or hearing or execute the order of removal until ordered by the immigration judge pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ba3139403a94e308e2e1704b73ab511"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of order by immigration judge</header><subparagraph id="id2bf6768cbb37482399cc986dda0d00f3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An immigration judge shall review each administrative removal order issued pursuant to paragraph (1) not later than 7 days after such order is referred to the court by the immigration officer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1284c4219dd84a99bea3eff1aa0d0f57"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal order</header><text>If an immigration judge determines that an alien referred to the immigration court is inadmissible under section 212(a)(2)(F) or deportable under 237(a)(2)(F), the immigration judge shall order the alien removed without further inquiry or hearing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8243b18cfe0e48a5ab2506f84410c5ea"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>The alien shall bear the burden of proof to establish that he or she—</text><subparagraph id="ide05917826f61411b93803a65c66d4f40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a lawful permanent resident (such status not having been abandoned, rescinded, or terminated); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e59230ea5434f288ec912aedaa6789f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not described in section 212(a)(2)(F) or section 237(a)(4)(F).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8e8dadbaaf14d6da02b713374207f43"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Conduct of proceedings</header><text>In proceedings before the immigration judge under this section, the Attorney General shall provide the alien—</text><subparagraph id="idc74b56758d914694bfaef5ee06a29643"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reasonable notice of the proceeding and of the opportunity described in subparagraph (C);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfcd7d747132941c5bc59f766eaf01683"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the privilege of being represented (at no expense to the Government) by a licensed attorney at law or an accredited representative of the alien’s choice who is authorized to practice before the immigration court in accordance with section 292; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b1ddd14bc4947db9bed39eef6604483"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an opportunity to inspect the evidence and submit any additional evidence to support the alien’s case prior to the review of the order by the immigration judge.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3243e08651fc4675bb26a4dd2dba30ed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of aliens arriving from contiguous territory</header><text>If an alien who is arriving on land (whether or not at a designated port of entry) from a foreign contiguous territory to the United States is determined by an immigration officer to be inadmissible under section 212(a)(2)(F) or deportable under section 237(a)(2)(F), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall return such alien to such territory pending a final decision under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1201baa56193424d8435d200e65fac70"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment of aliens arriving in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands or Guam</header><text>If an alien who is arriving in the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas or Guam from any foreign port of embarkation or foreign country (whether or not at a designated port of entry) is determined by an immigration officer to be inadmissible under section 212(a)(2)(F) or deportable under section 237(a)(2)(F), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall immediately return such alien to such foreign port of embarkation or foreign country pending a final decision under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4bf9159381a940d7858b1b8bccdd61b2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Prohibition on judicial review</header><text>Notwithstanding section 242 of this title, any other provision of law (statutory or nonstatutory), including section 2241 of the title 28, United States Code, or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title, there shall be no judicial review of any findings (factual or legal), decisions, or actions taken by the Secretary, immigration officer, or immigration judge, pursuant to the proceedings under subsection (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="id5075e5455cec4d2e86d1cab572d59765"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Recalcitrant countries</header><paragraph id="idb2e3ac1a0267499eae44afc13ccea082"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Automatic suspension of visa issuance and bar to admission</header><text>Notwithstanding section 243(d) or any other provision of law, if the country of birth, nationality, citizenship, or last habitual residence of an alien subject to removal under subsection (e) refuses to accept such alien within 14 days of receiving notification from the Secretary of Homeland Security of such removal order, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1916f92fb11a49a0a00b7a6266f97e7d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">direct the Secretary of State to immediately pause the issuance of visas for all citizens, nationals, subjects, and habitual residents of such country for the following 180 days; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89af378721d1456bad97af919bc5155c"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immediately suspend admission of all citizens, nationals, subjects, and habitual residents of such country until the country accepts the return of the removed alien.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6071e205c6564d20a8a80a88a2856409"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for national security or foreign policy</header><subparagraph id="id665f5c95d5df4adda6dade94f081c8ac"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security may jointly determine, based on the specific circumstances of an individual alien’s case, that it is in the national security or foreign policy interests of the United States to issue a visa or other travel document to an individual alien before the expiration of the 180-day period of suspension referred to in paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7814811bf0be440a8733136fce4389ed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The authority under this subsection—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f599079dde04c47b458cae1a422d7e8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not subject to delegation below the Deputy Secretary of Homeland Security or the Deputy Secretary of State;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96da00dcbe134fc98983c99830aec91e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be used to allow categories or groups of aliens of any nationality or citizenship into the United States; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f20c17bc00d4ef1a09c9518e254f592"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be exercised for not more than 50 aliens in any fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="ide481aa9ad2dc4e168ae14c1672c4fcd6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Mandatory medical examinations for aliens seeking visas, admission to the United States, and physically present in the United States</header><subsection id="id3a7fdcdab2994ed9b3d1f96425d62e72"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 221(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id1da6286e84ee4200b673611e3602b02a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>(d)</quote> the following: “<header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">Physical and mental examinations</header-in-text>.—</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2a99e99ca754d859c9fc16f3b2d864f"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf03d4defc7f84cc09d597bc8f29f7699"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Immigrant visas</header></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id20d95aed9010413cb1ffc24afccbc297"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>Prior to</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f1ff54f10a44ac0bee4295540149605"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc0f5597abe0472da7c927c8370a420d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonimmigrant visas</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebfa655d90884a9aa809c55e0c045866"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), prior to</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f99c77898384793baba7fadfecd4b19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f10b70747b04fbb864fff2940001512"><subparagraph id="id654539e8e2cf4111b8c4b60f30741968"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mandatory examinations</header><clause id="ide82ef19b8a07476eb2efd6ebdfca42d3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Medical examination</header><text>Prior to the issuance of a nonimmigrant visa for business or pleasure pursuant to section 101(a)(15)(B), the Secretary of State or consular officer shall require an alien who is a biological female of childbearing age to submit to a medical examination by a medical officer of the United States Public Health Service to determine if the alien is likely to give birth in the United States or its territories or outlying possessions during the alien's stay, which will make such alien inadmissible under section 212(a)(2)(F).</text></clause><clause id="idc8870f329b1646d6b192662dc0cacd3b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Medical certification</header><text>A medical officer of the United States Public Health Service shall conduct the examination of an alien described in clause (i) and submit a certification to the Secretary of State or consular officer on whether the alien is likely to give birth during the alien’s stay in the United States or its territories or outlying possessions.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7514556510c34d8ba4e9ed2aa6f0c539"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Birth tourism assessment and nonimmigrant visa decisions</header><text>If, based on the medical certification under subparagraph (B), the Secretary of State or consular officer suspects the alien is likely to give birth within 10 months in the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, the Secretary of State or consular officer may—</text><clause id="id6e7566066b0643a2bc65d499de0a9c68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deny the nonimmigrant visa; or</text></clause><clause id="idfdbfcb63a46c4444916ba3b51038f7d3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>withhold visa issuance until such date as the consular officer determines the alien is no longer inadmissible under section 212(a)(2)(F)(ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf30a8726ee9c4a3e98173d1c7fe38984"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Detention for physical and mental examinations</header><text>Section 232 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1222">8 U.S.C. 1222</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id4796525c478445dd8c1cde90183f4824" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="id9b015f736e034dbfa8e155661c4577f2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Detention and medical certifications for aliens subject to inadmissibility or deportability due to birth tourism</header><paragraph id="id99234b0d5703469f99416a061cd7ec64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Detention</header><text>If an immigration officer suspects an alien who is a biological female of child bearing age is inadmissible under section 212(a)(2)(F) or deportable under section 237(a)(2)(F), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall temporarily detain such alien for a sufficient period to enable a medical officer of the United States Public Health Service to determine if the alien is likely to give birth in the United States or its territories or outlying possessions during the alien’s stay.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb6d27c081f504315a41b0ff6521483ff" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medical examination and certification</header><text>A medical officer of the United States Public Health Service shall conduct a physical examination, administer necessary medical tests, and certify the resulting findings for the immigration officer or immigration judge regarding whether an alien described in paragraph (1) is likely to give birth in the United States or its territories or outlying possessions during the alien’s stay.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id56bbaa978ed04f18baabfe001e3566a6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Criminal penalties for facilitating birth tourism</header><subsection id="id81f22d3fba5644a08db670b5886c537b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 8 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1321">8 U.S.C. 1321 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7fd0aafab7046d49e6e084d11cdd6bf"><section id="id04713f3583024758bf4b4c54f339f669"><enum>274E.</enum><header>Criminal penalties for facilitating birth tourism</header><subsection id="id47cb993476ed451d9202d29f34609786"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Activities prohibited</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly—</text><paragraph id="idde70f44cbb01476bb4e4c538a58b12c0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>forge, counterfeit, alter, falsely make, or attempt to forge, counterfeit, alter, falsely make any document;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida22b45c8b8a046309826501625758037"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide an alien any forged, counterfeit, altered, or falsely made document; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b6c5a9d7bd14164907cf1b8ec206726"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prepare, file, or assist an alien with an application for a visa, travel document or other immigration benefit under this title; or</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ideec9b467692d40f1b1d971309598613e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criminal penalties</header><text>Any individual described in subsection (a), shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not less than 10 years, or both.</text></subsection></section><section id="id23e3ec8353504f63bd3cee236bf75361"><enum>274F.</enum><header>Criminal penalties for health care matters related to birth tourism</header><subsection id="id32d7046931144ab39f14d11eb7ad4445"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Healthcare theft or embezzlement through birth tourism</header><text>Any person, who knowingly—</text><paragraph id="ida0925342a8624237aba6f1bca4c8eb46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>embezzles, steals, or otherwise without authority converts to the use of any person other than the rightful owner; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a548bdd292d4ed8b9bfdf3cad7dcbaf" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>misapplies any of the moneys, funds, securities, premiums, credits, property, or other assets of a Federal health care program, to facilitate, engage in, encourage, solicit, or advertise to an alien any services related to birth tourism (regardless of whether such services, or a portion of such services, were initiated inside or outside the United States), to allow such alien to enter or remain in the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, solely to give birth to a child on United States soil in order to obtain United States citizenship for a child, shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, and imprisoned for not less than 10 years, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id813bf3ea26cc48779b667a69932f5dd9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Healthcare fraud through birth tourism</header><text>Whoever knowingly executes, or attempts to execute, a scheme or artifice to—</text><paragraph id="id9dacb635f52f47fdb9079bcae50684a9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to defraud any Federal healthcare program; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1da2b5feab9b42e5aa7ee708bf18d216"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to obtain, by means of false or fraudulent pretenses, representations, or promises, any of the money or property owned by, or under the custody or control of, any Federal healthcare program, in connection with the delivery of or payment for health care benefits, items, or services, for the purpose of allowing an alien to give birth to a child on United States soil in order to obtain United States citizenship for such child, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8ea045841ab447b7b5a0357db03e8a88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>As used in this section, the term <term>Federal healthcare program</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1302a–7b(f) of title 42, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idec623ae878aa4cab9c8850f7a7ddbfc1"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Section 275 of the Immigration and Nationality Act, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1325">8 U.S.C. 1325</external-xref>, is amended by—</text><paragraph id="id9df673054b7d4ffb82e1b1d2ef658432"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revising the title of the section to read: <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="section">Improper entry by alien; fraud and evasion of immigration laws</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0526d782cfea4300ac3eaa92e0a6649d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adding a new subsection (e) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb010eae6959348d8adb8a4ab1575cb75"><subsection id="idd4a33da1d137478e8b824896e1db591c"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Birth tourism fraud</header><text>Any individual who—</text><paragraph id="idce1bc9b4ffd046c2bd979035aa3bf987"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commits any act that the individual knows or reasonably should have known provides an alien with housing, transportation, food, medical care, or travel via any mode to the United States, its territories or outlying possessions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0a1f493d2c24df0b9387e61249f986d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commits any act that the individual knows or reasonably should have known allows an alien to receive any financial support, including expenses associated with food, medical care, housing, and transportation, that will allow the alien to enter the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, or attempt to enter the United States, its territories or outlying possessions; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id985f9be6c7ae4059be8bf2127c9a172f" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conspires to assist an alien to enter the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, under false pretenses, through fraud, or material misrepresentations in a visa application or other entry document, to obtain United States citizenship for the alien’s child, shall be fined imprisoned for not less than 10 years and not more than 25 years, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf2c2235856ee4ea9a7fd7ea2edbd4237"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Title 18 of the United States Code is further amended by adding a new section 1546A to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63a58c47c5114fe3ab830cbf1f7da064"><section id="ida317cc038f254ebe874d8165b8ad5b58"><enum>1546A.</enum><header>Fraud, conspiracy, and other acts associated with undermining United States sovereignty through birth tourism</header><subsection id="id084f4509adff4e27aa2fbe02d42bc082"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Any person who knowingly—</text><paragraph id="ida28d7d5614584fd4ae702a02c5aaaf90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>aids or assist any alien to enter the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, or to physically remain in the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, regardless of the alien’s manner of entry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide8f94688ca934a67aac090b4ad4d9406"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conspires or connives, or attempts to conspire or connive to aid or assist any alien to enter the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, or to physically remain in the United States, its territories or outlying possessions; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c81d32be3574284b2967d880f81a0cf" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conspires or connives, or attempts to conspire or connive with any other person or persons to aid or assist any alien to enter the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, or remain in the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, for the purpose of giving birth to a child in the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, so that such child can obtain United States citizenship at birth, shall be imprisoned for a minimum of 10 years and fined $100,000 for each alien such person aided or assisted.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="id4ff95119fdb248ada768b4f7b82beaf6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Birth tourism taskforce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II, Chapter 9 of the Immigration and Nationality Act is amended to add a new section 295 to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84b55e6e97d445a18365d45a1f6c2b8c"><section id="id0267dee562854551a8fb5e7e058e7d01"><enum>295.</enum><header>Taskforce on birth tourism</header><subsection id="id752e550baf084243a5c261d3646779d0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a Taskforce (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Taskforce</quote>) within the Department of Homeland Security, that shall include U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, Homeland Security Investigations, and U.S. Customs and Border Protection, that shall:</text><paragraph id="id3ec11d308f664900a5e6ea98675aee40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>investigate individuals, organizations and entities that create schemes and run operations to facilitate in and enforce laws to prevent an alien from seeking to undermine the sovereignty of the United States by attempting to enter, entering, or remaining physically in the United States, its territories or outlying possessions, for the purpose of giving birth to a child on United States soil; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9040db002f664f9e9a5acba83b220b48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>refer cases to the Department of Justice for criminal prosecutions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1bda890706334e5e82b2ae6a6216719a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training materials</header><text>The Taskforce shall produce training materials for local law enforcement on the investigation and detection of criminal offenses described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="id804e3d615c8f4df8a3f7ca19d820998f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Taskforce shall coordinate with the Department of Agriculture, the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Agriculture, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the United States Marshals Service, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and other agencies, as appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="iddb9ad9f9cf4948529e84e1ad782295c6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>On the date that is one year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Taskforce shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, a report on, for the previous year—</text><paragraph id="id5d24c5daf5574f9ea202cb54be1081ce"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of charges that were filed for violations of laws described in subsection (a), disaggregated by the law alleged to have been violated, the State in which the violation was alleged to have occurred, and the number of convictions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide57d12bb7b9e46bcb3d3df52eb93ca8c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of investigations of violations of laws described in subsection (a) for which charges were not filed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id332d72c879a04f588a21a889556bc971"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate committees defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>appropriate committees</term> includes—</text><paragraph id="idbfaaf77555004d02b6695a30ac4fb68f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Senate Committee on the Judiciary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe740e90997243b1960cfa1707922470"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the House Committee on the Judiciary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idda4db2ced8d840348c8ae209a55dc05d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01e1a954678c43e783936aee6321799a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the House Committee on Homeland Security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id678cd7105390408888ae0a1d73788c96"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the House Foreign Affairs Committee;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id400ffc2641e54dfc94c4849f6fda7cdc"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Senate Foreign Relations Committee; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f844495bed74e15ab4555c3196f7b77"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the House Oversight and Government Reform Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id3f7f072a502e4ea28c0cc9e963f7f032"><enum>8.</enum><header>Exemption from Paperwork Reduction Act and the Administrative Procedure Act</header><subsection id="id6b3272579ebb43cb92fd446a3ea52eed"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Paperwork Reduction Act</header> <text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to require the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of State, or the Attorney General to comply with the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>), if the department head involved determines that compliance would impede the immediate implementation of this Act or the amendments made by this Act.</text>
            </subsection><subsection id="id9fa1f7e3ecde44d08b01672c5bdd6a7d">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Administrative Procedure Act</header>
 <text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to require the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of State, or the Attorney General to promulgate regulations under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>), if the department head involved determines that compliance would impede the immediate implementation of this Act or the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="idf5ba9152fec64e0f97e85e5c3f520fbe"><enum>9.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

