<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7BBD4956D24A40F2B1883C1A66E051C7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9070 IH: Oversight, Protection, and Enforcement Notification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9070</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve immigration enforcement transparency, preserve civil rights, and improve the accountability of immigration enforcement personnel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4D346C759F774C489C288362F3011AD1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H35352541E3C44C62B8633EE518C04C3B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Oversight, Protection, and Enforcement Notification Act</short-title></quote> and <quote><short-title>OPEN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA41D657172D64BDCA5169D3F5A7D13B5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03714CDF112F49FCA2A1EE22645D82E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chokehold or carotid hold</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>chokehold or carotid hold</term> means the application of any pressure to the throat or windpipe, the use of maneuvers that restrict blood or oxygen flow to the brain, or carotid artery restraints that prevent or hinder breathing or reduce intake of air of an individual.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75EEB174F7714B77B5231CCCA3283E07"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conduct exceeding authorized authority</header><text>The term <term>conduct exceeding authorized authority</term> means any action taken without legal authorization, outside the scope of assigned duties, or in violation of Federal law, regulation, or Department of Homeland Security policy, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC555F2FD1EF245158F3A304D51D8AD58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducting a stop, search, entry, arrest, or detention without legal authority, a valid warrant, or required supervisory approval;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06FCCEF1D5214CB498547C9FE27BCE7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>misrepresenting identity, authority, or purpose to gain compliance or entry;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD9AA62F3789040C4ABF3C1E063ACBDA0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conducting enforcement activity outside an assigned geographic area, mission scope, or operational plan;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9606FDC7F6084A83BA2A1A8EF863DEB8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>using unapproved tactics, equipment, or vehicles, including failure to comply with identification or uniform requirements;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5B068CDCD5144C0BA265AB284501D7AA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>acting in violation of constitutional protections, civil rights laws, or court orders; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC90B86AA2E094FCF9D8AC8E3894E7309"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any action involving sexual violence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H187E62734C194D8888E1F83330BE7DAE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Excessive force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>excessive force</term> means the use of physical force or weapons beyond what is objectively reasonable and necessary, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H73151F0E16D849DC8F812A6373CB0D70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>discharging or brandishing a firearm at any individual or vehicle;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8749E9F2908A429B9ABD9B8128B6897B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>using a chemical agent, a conducted energy device, a baton, or an impact weapon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD7D976FD1C794FC58A5EA4881551A7F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any action involving a physical takedown, a chokehold, or the placement of an individual on the ground;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H99D96B37E16C4200B2787AD96C300E08" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>using restraints or force resulting in bodily injury, hospitalization, or death; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15E8132E30D846EE9D3584DDCCB28017" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using deadly force to incapacitate a subject.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H246788C9152B4E1C8A09DB732A23F31E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Member of congress</header><text>The term <term>Member of Congress</term> includes any Senator, Representative, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner of the United States Congress.</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70F3FC38187543AF94994A726D625943"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improving immigration enforcement transparency</header> <subsection id="H4E975E85F02B449DABE90AFCB79AC2D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access to immigration detention facilities</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD12616CE2F34831AF5F4E4004C7DD07"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that all Members of Congress are given unrestricted access, without advance notice, to all immigration detention facilities used or operated by the Department of Homeland Security, including facilities operated by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or U.S. Customs and Border Protection, regional processing centers, field offices, State-run facilities, and privately operated or contracted facilities, regardless of the source of funding for such facilities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H86550A74E3E1407EA670C80D0B8E9A99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of access</header><text>Access to immigration detention facilities required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA99A7458780541DFA0EB2E4FAE87D5F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access to all of the areas in such facilities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13BD22422A6A4318B1BB519B1BEEFA61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ability to speak privately with detained individuals and facility personnel on the same day as the visit and without prior authorization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H22171994CE7144FA8477828CD546D56B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability to observe conditions of confinement and compliance with applicable Federal law, regulations, and standards; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1374229794954056887F8108FEF1830B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of a Member of Congress, a State or local elected official, or a representative of a local health and safety agency to be accompanied by congressional staff and, at the discretion of the Member, official, or representative, subject matter experts, including medical professionals, legal experts, interpreters, and other individuals who such Member, official, or representative considers necessary to assist in evaluating facility conditions and compliance with applicable laws and standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0C388014F0341D89DB2F319B22590C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Access for legal counsel, faith leaders, and family members</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that detained individuals have timely and reasonable access to legal counsel, faith leaders, and family members, including the ability to communicate privately and in person whenever practicable, subject only to narrowly tailored limitations that are necessary to protect the safety and security of the facility in which such individuals are detained.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H09A71FDF35C54983B25B03F61B6A82C3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition on delay or denial</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A1A0C26E8F4431E8D29EB06E788BC1D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The operator of an immigration detention facility may not delay, condition, restrict, or deny access to such facility to a Member of Congress on the basis of staffing limitations, operational considerations, contractual arrangements, or facility designation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C0DCEFAC8D343A69CE3FB05F0C776F8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 72 hours after discovering that a Member of Congress' access to an immigration detention facility was delayed or denied for any reason, the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall submit a detailed report identifying the reasons for such delay and denial and describing the steps that will be taken to prevent future delays or denials to—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EEA71B4D49A47008EC3DA0CE6B45DBF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAD06A0CCA494036B376E9B4E9EB6123"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B895660C200425DBDA65EBEF8F3D59C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BDFC1730A614F4A8D940F225EA4C8EA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE56AD98E03924D79A1AEC08D71EB81F9"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91D9E2BDFAB74C82AECF3E02F215C5DA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61DA52819488452EA360674BF672FC59"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H012FFEFEE8D1415EB7AE4A0324A19D7D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consequences for repeated noncompliance</header> <subparagraph id="H74F1E6AE5EB141FA81233BBBD1A9ED4B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If access to an immigration detention facility is delayed or denied to 2 or more Members of Congress in violation of this subsection during any fiscal year, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that any officer, employee, or contractor of the Department of Homeland Security who knowingly delays, restricts, or denies access to such a facility in violation of this subsection is subject to appropriate administrative or contractual disciplinary action.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H60B27CA6C38F434FB650F74058258995"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary shall notify the committees listed in paragraph (4)(B) not later than 48 hours after determining a violation described in subparagraph (A) has occurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB0232A90C9A4547AE7C149D3E533208"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit the authority of Congress to impose additional requirements or restrictions through appropriations Acts or other legislation.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDD7BC356042449CBAE5AF9D5742C3776"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public reporting requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall track and publicly report, on an aggregated basis without including personally identifiable information of those involved, all allegations and incidents in which immigration enforcement officers or agents, during an immigration enforcement operation or while an individual is detained by the Department of Homeland Security—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44FCB9A699294D2CAB9B3EAB777C34F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">used excessive force to carry out their objective;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A122E4A5609473EB624D4F5DA41F9B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaged in conduct exceeding authorized authority;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE210469849B94B64A34FA5BF0ADE2817"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>detained a United States citizen;</text>
                </paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB613D5D4E364EA98354EE243D787929"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mistakenly detained or arrested an individual who should not have been detained or arrested;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FE3ED79208942429878CE2893E35AE6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>perpetrated sexual assault, abuse, or harassment; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEB4B02DD384D4375851A2B7722D0AE16"><enum>(6)</enum><text>engaged in other misconduct.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCC7274301C940BFB51532EE4D0D0E24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Detention accountability and grievance procedures</header> <paragraph id="H3BFAE751D74B4F8FB95BF61B75F14702"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grievance process</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that each immigration detention facility used or operated by the Department of Homeland Security or its contractors maintains a confidential and accessible grievance process through which detained individuals may report grievances regarding—</text>
<subparagraph id="H861123529D0A4CD3A70DC58E24C2BDA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of excessive force;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31ACAC494B2545CDB981E67268C0AFD4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>violations of Federal law, detention standards, or Department policy;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7AC4220F500E4962B0D3C878937C4098"><enum>(C)</enum><text>threats, intimidation, retaliation, or abuse by facility personnel; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H144B01336EBF4AC4B1F4C5165CCBCAE7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>sexual assault, abuse, or harassment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H52A2312F115946EABE1B33BA6822CE6F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accessibility requirements</header><text>The grievance process required under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HA4DA79C2EAA342D9920498D098490080"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be available in all languages commonly spoken by detained individuals;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5F53FEFB78EF49E7BEC4AEB69D81194A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>permit grievances to be filed orally or in writing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB596FB5BDD1B4BFE9C47BB2946275F14"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allow detained individuals to submit grievances without interference or retaliation; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDF5B8EA173C648F1A97FAD39D37E93C7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide timely review and resolution of such grievances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42E078271A9541FABF06FB26C28BB0A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Accountability for excessive force or misconduct</header><text>If an investigation conducted by the Department of Homeland Security, the Office of Inspector General of the Department, the Office of Professional Responsibility of the Department, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, a local field office, or any other authorized investigative entity determines that an officer, employee, or contractor used excessive force against a detained individual, the head of the agency with jurisdiction over the facility shall ensure that such individual—</text>
<subparagraph id="H03FD09962EE84DC882B1F70537C41675"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is immediately removed from duties involving the supervision, custody, or transport of detained individuals at the facility at which the incident occurred; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C4C8904501D41DB875A2E4EA86FEFFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not permitted to return to perform such duties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C4ACCF9B30A4759AA471A650B0242F8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sexual abuse and assault prevention and intervention program</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall publish facility-specific information for each immigration detention facility regarding each facility's compliance with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement's Sexual Abuse and Assault Prevention and Intervention Program, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HB9C3EB727FC642D0A34215A4F9B7FC2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of allegations of sexual abuse or harassment reported at such facility;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDCCE21168AD940E68226ACA8290CCF59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the status and outcome of investigations into such allegations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABB26E26E8214FA1AA993D78FD11794E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the facility was found compliant with applicable standards under the Sexual Abuse and Assault Prevention and Intervention Program; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE1E7523F724D4A91B59A9F2649F0FD6E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any corrective actions required and the status of such actions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2910B1A03B644ACA6FB28BD75BB9984"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preserving civil rights</header> <subsection id="H83E85655AD074E8F8DD2DFEFD94137BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of force</header><text>In carrying out immigration enforcement operations, immigration enforcement officers and agents may not use excessive force.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF713D973B60A49F49B1F43E4B26CA529"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Detainee rights</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure, after an immigration enforcement officer or agent detains any individual—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC40398B405B047EBB2CAE23BA6A80917"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a member of such individual's immediate family, as determined by the detained individual, is notified of such detention by the Department of Homeland Security not later than 5 hours after the commencement of such detention;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBA6F557B63CF487BBFE44EDB5148DE2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such individual is guaranteed access to at least 1 phone call within 5 hours after the commencement of the detention;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BE7159D24B8496EA0208917E1C6A94A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual is guaranteed reasonable access to legal counsel and a faith leader not later than 12 hours after the commencement of the detention and periodically thereafter, either in person or through telephonic communication; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2EA0BA4F45F34EC2AC017ED6C2749B8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such individual is guaranteed reasonable accommodations to facilitate the signing of any necessary legal documentation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5A1EC81BFC249A3831C8AF3AF5BC847"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Medical and mental health services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7AF66CDE49D14CC9B621B55963882DDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after an immigration enforcement officer or agent detains any individual, such individual is provided timely medical and mental health services, including access to emergency care and chronic condition management, in accordance with the standards established under the National Detention Standards and the Performance-Based National Detention Standards;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7269210F21145258EE7662FFFED679F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any individual in detention with care provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs should have access to health care services provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3793E72233114E20BF77DFB49A016847"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if an individual described in paragraph (1) is transferred to a hospital or emergency room—</text> <subparagraph id="H45F1F2D7F8BC416DB104CB45DBB3176D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual's legal counsel or designated representative is immediately notified; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H195889AA99ED41F2BFBABAB40C5D37F6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>family members or a designated emergency contact are notified of the location of such hospital or emergency room as soon as practicable; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H377229D4922A479EB345B53200F9674A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>procedures are implemented to allow family members or legal representatives of such individuals to drop off valid prescription medications and necessary medical devices for use in detention facilities, including CPAP machines, mobility aids, and glucose monitors, for the individual’s use after such items are cleared through standard security and medical review.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2FAD5C1B7AF749D2A558221728C0C5BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transportation and transfers</header>
<paragraph id="H822112F20A2C451C8CBDD4AF8DA85667"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of transfer</header><text>Not later than 24 hours after any detained individual is transferred to another detention facility, the head of the facility housing the individual shall notify the individual’s legal counsel, designated representative, and next of kin, as applicable, of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB97744B17A5C42AF8C402A3E00FF00D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the specific name and address of the facility to which the individual has been transferred; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDD04EED06C4648E09451837E9DB5A8D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the direct contact information for such facility, including a primary phone number and a point of contact for inquiries from the family and legal representative of such individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H065C8F10CF5A4B3CAD96FA883702EA79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Justification for transfer</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5374E4FE123D4F8ABBAB14FDA065F01D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before any transfer described in paragraph (1), the Director of the facility or the field office shall provide a written justification to the detained individual and such individual's legal counsel detailing the specific administrative or safety reason for such transfer, such as medical necessity, facility capacity, or specialized housing requirements.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D7BC1CF32884DE1A427111C5E7D62F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Medical transfer summaries</header><text>The Director of the facility from which a detained individual is being transferred shall provide a medical transfer summary with respect to such individual to the receiving facility.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98158766581647D9BDE57446B0922CBD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Observations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Officers involved in the transfer of detained individuals between detention facilities shall share with the receiving facility any observations suggesting the detained individual—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04143148443B45B0AAF1D84B93B3D3E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has engaged in self-injurious behavior; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98E979D0EFD94A489EE63D5DFFDFA322"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has expressed a desire to harm himself or herself during such transfer.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE4F3B4DDA9E74A35B33D54B0D307DC64"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Specialty care</header><text>A detained individual in need of specialty care may not be transferred to a detention facility that lacks the resources to provide such care unless such resources may be easily procured from a nearby hospital, clinic, or doctors' office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H285C385360DF44A8BCE4F5BEE37A9ED1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Bed availability and facility standards</header><text>A transfer described in paragraph (1) may not occur unless the Director of both the originating and receiving detention facilities attest that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD20AE3145AFF49B28C7561C78B76B457"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a dedicated bed and appropriate housing space are available at the destination facility to which the individual is being transferred; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDAFCD72548944678288A061D7535ACC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such destination facility meets all applicable Federal detention standards, including having the medical and mental health resources to maintain the individual's continuity of care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4E81D31569340E28B407859EA135209"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional detention standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All transfers of detained individuals shall comply with all applicable standards established by the Secretary of Transportation, including—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB11E58AB18E34EAD9F2EB5410AC17FB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">minimum protections during transport, including—</text>
<clause id="H9FD05CEDD1C1453B8B6240506AD1D2B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use of seatbelts or secure seating for all individuals during vehicle movement;</text></clause> <clause id="HFB9F92BE649341F686D25469D2AA9D01"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>prohibition on transport in overcrowded conditions or standing-room configurations;</text>
                        </clause>
<clause id="HDC5C353E8BA547C68B244FDB6558095D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>access to adequate ventilation, temperature control, food, drinking water, and necessary medications; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4BF239C29304A26A939439CDE1214E1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for individuals who are restrained or shackled—</text>
<subclause id="H7A4019838A454C5D93A553024DF731E4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the application or adjustment of such restraints shall allow the individual the physical range of motion necessary to safely drink water and consume food without assistance; or</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8568F3F25F644E499C541A0D842F6F1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the security level of the restraint prevents the individual from self-feeding or self-drinking, the provision of direct, safe assistance to ensure the individual is able to eat and drink fully and comfortably;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EDE9987AC414255900A260FE5B1E7B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regular bathroom breaks, including—</text> <clause id="HBE3F69FC7BF14926B4C1DFE557EC58FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>access to restroom facilities not less frequently than once every 2 hours during transport;</text></clause>
<clause id="HEA1FAAD5E0E54EFA9085D9A4AE39C5AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reasonable accommodations for children, elderly individuals, pregnant women, and individuals with medical conditions; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD4185BED6F0F4C3DA32E682FC1662A7A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>mandatory reasonable accommodations for individuals with physical, sensory, intellectual, or mental health disabilities, including the provision of vehicles and communication assistance in full compliance with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H590B8919FFD247058E3A42B41A5413B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">safety protocols, including—</text> <clause id="H04674B8C953B49EA82A875F2028A31BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>medical screening before transport to identify health risks, disabilities, or special needs;</text></clause>
<clause id="H2883A9B5A5E4413F9172B939F0AE9226"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>continuous monitoring of individuals during transport by trained personnel;</text></clause> <clause id="H3E48B572AE5E4453B69090F5BCC9BF8B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prohibiting the use of restraint methods that impede breathing, circulation, or safe seating during transport;</text></clause>
<clause id="H2C088824C70141FC8C87D6E61B90E913"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>maintaining written transport logs documenting the duration, conditions, stops, and personnel involved;</text></clause> <clause id="HA5E4D6AEAA5C4DA5B01EF2CB19F60506"><enum>(v)</enum><text>operating audio or video recording equipment, where available, for the duration of transport; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BA5A0D3C82D4820B46E1B7FE0DD8D04"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>protecting mobility and medical devices by ensuring such items are transported with the individual and are not separated or damaged during the transfer process;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H024D6EE3AF9A497884B76EF3DDF0D275"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Documentation and reporting</header><text>Not later than 24 hours after each incident involving a violation by a transporting officer or agent of any standard described in paragraph (4), such incident shall be—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H608D21BBCF6A4A85A3D53727DD5A233E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">documented by the supervisor of such officer or agent, which documentation shall include—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28FC0926398047A1B036B4F06DC3CF44"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the nature of the violation;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED73C7D793124357B2A2EAFF321FE85E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the duration of the transport during which such violation occurred;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB5DE3DAFAD44DCBB654AA2D101AB2AC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individuals affected by such violation;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C79E7664EFF41EC9994E35946B3613B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any corrective actions taken to prevent future violations; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4D40353F0B547EBB3DBD70CE2F55141"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any disciplinary or remedial measures imposed on the violator; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF72E5A883BB4D68A3766C855FEC9A9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reported to—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H351CA1D003BD418DBDA9FF44765D75B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC505646FF0284BDBB98F085BCB015E42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BA64F5CFF8C49FEA11E64A528A703CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appropriate congressional committees.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0C6F050960F4114A575263C90425B0A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF72CF803CCA34B89907216F5277C641C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reconstitute the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D0DD2552D7743DAB8E42EBD9C20D9E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure such Office has an independent reporting structure, including direct reporting authority to the Secretary of Homeland Security, for purposes of investigating, reviewing, and reporting on civil rights and civil liberties violations related to immigration enforcement or detention.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD291DADC0CA4497388601841434BD341"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitations on conversions of existing buildings into immigrant detention centers</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CFCDFB187434E3D98BD1FEE7EBDCC0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or U.S. Customs and Border Protection may not acquire and repurpose any warehouse, State-run facility, or correctional facility as a detention center for individuals who are awaiting removal proceedings or are in Federal custody absent full compliance with the requirements set forth in subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE33B8AA34E6747E297DF8A73D087CC4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for conversion of existing facilities</header>
<paragraph id="H5D3C0A7C3F6F47ABA762D78B9EA71790"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compliance and financial accountability</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78C83415FDC343BA93665AE5BAA556D8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The new immigrant detention center shall be operated in full compliance with all applicable Federal detention and safety standards.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H77B25C05E1FC42FB90D2516D3842564D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contractual penalties</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure all contracts for the operation of immigration detention centers include enforceable financial clawbacks and liquidated damages provisions to be triggered by a persistent or systemic failure to adhere to all applicable Federal detention and safety standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2D17D5C3572544FFB9BBAE07FC931A48"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guaranteed access</header><text>All individuals housed at any immigration detention center shall be guaranteed regular access to legal counsel, faith leaders, and family members, either in person or through telephonic communication, in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 3(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99C85ADE919540EAAA0BA3D5926E1DD8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Independent inspections and timeline</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA3DCF00B40C444FA008EE5A757D97A1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each immigration detention center shall be subject to a rigorous inspection schedule.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA316010118F041E2849C9006459A2301"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pre-operational audit</header><text>An independent inspection of each new immigration detention facility shall be completed and published not later than 30 days before any contract is executed for the operation of such facility.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FEAD234FBD34AF38640B7FB2C3DADD0"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Recurring access</header> <text>State attorneys general, the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security, and a court-appointed independent monitor shall have unrestricted, unannounced access to each immigration detention facility at any time.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H660756EB5AAD48E9B211EB08F05148D2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 14 days after conducting an inspection of an immigration detention facility, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report containing the results of such inspection to—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4258CBC4E0444CD38D53D702DA1A8784"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appropriate congressional committees; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA727CEAA48B42A19F1319533FA15164"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Governor of the State in which such facility is located.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66B0242407784EC6A57C39E5EA3C2E7C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Commencement of operations</header><text>A new immigration detention center may not commence operations without full transparency and oversight in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB84A16BE73FA4D28B5F5C932264532F4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notice; briefings</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide advance written notice and ongoing coordination to the Governor, State attorney general, and appropriate local government officials in the jurisdiction in which any new immigration detention center is located, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H8B10CECF840448F78418E3927D34C09A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice of the intent to establish, expand, or materially modify operations at the facility; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2D56ED55822D4FC7B43E3A1C632D726D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regular briefings regarding population levels, medical capacity, emergency protocols, and public safety impacts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7329F3C8CE0B472795733B4D2765056E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Intergovernmental consultation</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC4F4A90DCE44F8396BBF21A7019AE4A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish procedures for consulting with appropriate State and local government officials regarding any new immigration detention center’s impact on local infrastructure.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5639014BC11545328FA0D44E1BF76D7E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certification requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall certify that each new immigration detention center adheres to all applicable State health and safety standards unless such standards directly conflict with the execution of Federal immigration law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CC9CB097363415AB61BC1AF9610E7BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to waive the supremacy of Federal law.</text></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63E18F80DAF04CFE980E0F52AD20F576"><enum>6.</enum><header>Warrant requirements</header>
<subsection id="H0B3E7D74E3E34AA9A8BCEB49629A972B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Judicial warrants</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) and any regulation or policy issued by the Department of Homeland Security, an officer or agent of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or U.S. Customs and Border Protection may not arrest or detain an individual without a judicially enforceable warrant issued by a magistrate judge or a judge appointed under article III of the Constitution of the United States who has been duly confirmed by the Senate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE131D8F054C044FF922E1DB53408630D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative warrants</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57D807523DE946F192FE5DD0A689E476"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), an administrative warrant, including a warrant of arrest or removal issued by an officer or employee of the Department of Homeland Security, may not—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5949DBC4A6244561826329620C018221"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorize entry into a private residence or dwelling; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7718A239DF004046BD9E70D6B72450C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be used to justify forced entry, coercive entry, or entry without consent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0044F4C0FD294D168114B4977793508C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The restrictions set forth in paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to an individual who is determined to be a flight risk or a danger to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3FA8B349AAB948D49F3993D7DB88E214"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Remedies for violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an immigration enforcement action is conducted in violation of this section—</text>
<paragraph id="HAEDBC2415D6843F28DF447E4E36388A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any information obtained as a result of such action shall be prohibited from being entered into the record or received into evidence in a removal proceeding for purposes of establishing alienage or chargeability; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FE83A3DFF454A8591E081960CBF76A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the noncitizen who is the subject of such removal proceedings may file a motion to enforce the prohibition described in paragraph (1), including through a motion to terminate such proceedings.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

