<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA3120A0A03DA4B4099EB7075097C610F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6770 IH: Scam Defense Strategy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6770</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Commander of the United States Cyber Command to submit to Congress a report regarding recommended actions in cyberspace to defend the United States against transnational organized crime networks linked to the Chinese Communist Party that operate digital scams.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD3315D6BFC544D1D93E66216FA26C589" style="OLC"><section id="H48ACF24DF0314EDA87B2DC209B9B0D6B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Scam Defense Strategy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6EA51A74AAA04E17A10525FF0D7E8177" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transnational organized crime networks</header><subsection id="H111D53FE21B746DE93B36D9FAA95E877"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HF89E4C4106D24786A88EBA8F1F02AF1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to estimates from the United States Institutes of Peace, China-linked transnational organized crime groups that operate <quote>fraud farms</quote> in Southeast Asia steal nearly $43,800,000,000 annually through digital scams.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2EC5200B1E54F6E8D47781DA844B7DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such scams increasingly affect Americans and disproportionately target vulnerable populations such as the elderly and socially isolated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C8F297A77874E6EB7BA26DD1361370A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the Federal Trade Commission, in 2024 alone—</text><subparagraph id="HF15D12ED59CA4E9990FB77363131CECC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>246,783 scam text messages were reported, resulting in $469,000,000 in losses to Americans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B004AA7263549768DB490A3CCC27B33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>371,664 scam emails were reported, resulting in $502,000,000 in losses to Americans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71727FC57E9E42EFB6F4D0C1D43EBA8B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>284,651 scam phone calls were reported, resulting in $948,000,000 in losses to Americans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H82E868F5B51E44319860BB6C97616146"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Transnational organized crime groups maintain documented ties to the Chinese Communist Party. Chinese officials and state-owned enterprises have provided direct support for the construction and operation of facilities linked to transnational organized crime, raising serious concerns about a coordinated campaign of foreign interference and sabotage.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85DEA586B2EA4FE2866F1618259011C7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The involvement of the Chinese Communist Party in transnational organized crime networks presents an urgent national security threat. These networks funnel financial assets and sensitive personal information of United States citizens to a hostile foreign power, undermining American economic security and individual privacy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBF3F5C8A14C4209887034B7CDD9DCE7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Such transnational organized crime networks have deeply imbedded themselves into Southeast Asian economies, exerting destabilizing influence across the region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9ADB228B1834C7F920333DA32FE8B15"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Proceeds from scams operated by these transnational crime networks are used to fund warlords and ongoing civil conflicts, compounding regional instability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80D02884CCBE4D3D9AC5A9DA1BA297A0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Transnational organized crime networks have trafficked an estimated 300,000 individuals into cyber scam operations across Southeast Asia. Victims, including United States citizens, are forced to work under conditions that the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission compares to modern slavery. The United Nations has warned that human trafficking tied to these scam centers has reached the level of a humanitarian and human rights crisis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF62BE0A9BE84167A55CD3D93131D769"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The U.S.-China Economic and Security Review has acknowledged credible reports linking scam facilities in the Philippines to Chinese espionage activity. These facilities are being constructed near air bases strategically important to United States operations, including Clark Air Base and Basa Air Base, a key site under the Enhanced Defense Cooperative Agreement. Philippine intelligence has provided compelling evidence that these compounds have been used for surveillance and cyber intrusions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCD3C448C13C469287ACF30C3D197F1F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Chinese government has used the presence of Chinese transnational organized crime networks in Southeast Asia to pressure regional governments to allow a greater role for Chinese security forces, which threatens national sovereignty and regional stability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21ED06F35F3544A0A0A3AF7F7AF5CFD5"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Transnational organized crime networks endanger American defense priorities as well as democracy, good governance, and stability worldwide by co-opting local elites, undermining law enforcement, weakening state authority, and threatening the strategic interests of the United States in building a free and open Indo-Pacific.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0119C1FC927746158CE07672CCBB8B46"><enum>(12)</enum><text>An effective response by the United States Government will require a coordinated, whole-of-government effort drawing on the competencies of Federal agencies in information collection, financial enforcement, diplomatic engagement, defense and intelligence preparedness, and law enforcement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92918D9259DC498FB61F432BF6A59044"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commander of the United States Cyber Command shall submit to Congress a report regarding recommended actions for the Secretary of Defense to take in cyberspace to defend the United States and United States citizens, assets, and interests against transnational organized crime networks linked to the Chinese Communist Party that operate digital scams. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

