<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN26686-SFK-JT-07X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4708 IS: Arctic Security and Diplomacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4708</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve the security of the Arctic, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Arctic Security and Diplomacy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idfe5904c94abf4ef891fb2f03425a184b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id81bfd355f7894beabb0a83d66d8296c4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Arctic is a critical domain for the security and sovereignty of the United States and faces elevated risks related to the threats of territorial expansion and violation, influence operations, sabotage of critical undersea infrastructure, and espionage by foreign adversaries, particularly the People’s Republic of China and the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb432c2e8c8344b6ebe340a74dddb1def"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Russian Federation holds a significant portion of the Arctic, accounting for approximately 53 percent of the Arctic Ocean coastline, and has significantly expanded its military basing infrastructure and capabilities in the region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b73984a96034eb9850c5d9d87316b70"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2018, the People’s Republic of China declared that it is a <quote>Near-Arctic State</quote> with significant interests in the Arctic and is attempting to become a <quote>polar great power</quote> through economic expansion, scientific investments, and dual-use civilian and military infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idff38e291a3a04281aa0b5ca1f474e284"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Russian Federation is cooperating with the People’s Republic of China to establish a <quote>Polar Silk Road</quote> in the Arctic, and the two countries are working together to strengthen cooperation in polar shipbuilding and ship technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id88b57830df6748808af86181537b59ad"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China has made multiple attempts to gain strategic footholds in the Arctic, has research stations in Norway’s Svalbard archipelago and in Iceland, and consistently attempts to co-opt and manipulate civilian science and research activities, university partnerships, and multilateral science and research initiatives throughout the Arctic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98db260240cf416e9fc83e9e57574ed1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China has observer status on the Arctic Council, has significantly increased diplomatic engagement with Nordic countries, and uses investments in cooperative marine scientific research as a form of soft power in the Arctic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida1c45d9599214301add80a5170901a97"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China engages in extensive marine surveying, much of which has dual-use risk for military applications, including seabed mapping, NATO asset monitoring, and other espionage-related activity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id136c23cd82084ddebb9c02c61567e10d"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In 2022, the Danish Security and Intelligence Service reported several attempts at espionage by the People’s Republic of China against Denmark, Greenland, and the Faroe Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0784babb5a824769af4822f412719dba"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In 2024, the Canadian Security Intelligence Service warned of espionage activity by the People’s Republic of China and the Russian Federation, and the Canadian military discovered and removed buoys in the Arctic owned by the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id862631c7532a4c848735da4f1e21a964"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In 2025, the head of the National Police Commission in Iceland warned that the China-Iceland Arctic Science Observatory poses dual-use risks and may be used for espionage.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb998b86ac6774f22a6233c20cf710a6a"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The 2026 Annual Threat Assessment by the intelligence community describes the Russian Federation as <quote>our primary challenge in the Arctic … Moscow is seeking to expand and deepen its presence in the Arctic through increased maritime trade, natural resource extraction, and military activity,</quote> while warning that the People's Republic of China <quote>seeks to expand its Arctic presence using scientific research, investments, and commercial ventures along the Northern Sea Route.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0d2ad207fd0b41e5920b7390ef6c7cc0"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 2025 NATO Maritime Strategy highlighted the Russian Federation's military build-up in the Arctic and use of hybrid threats like sabotage against critical undersea infrastructure, while warning that the People's Republic of China <quote>is pursuing a military build-up, including rapidly expanding its naval capabilities, increasing its use of dual-use military-scientific vessels and surging its presence in the High North and the Arctic, while remaining opaque about its intentions.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3d56ea2b9c04e0bb03c7d3cd802dc6c"><enum>(13)</enum><text>According to the Department of Homeland Security, an unprecedented number of military and research vessels of the People’s Republic of China are operating in or near United States Arctic waters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id61f1c9eb126a431c850ea257c5b6b7e8"><enum>(14)</enum><text>It is in the interests of Arctic countries to cooperatively limit the ability of the People’s Republic of China to conduct further espionage in the Arctic.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id3f1d9e40496c45019d722deb3481e047"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1998566e65004f4f810dbb68666ebfeb"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>Executive agency</quote> in section 105 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ee1089bdd7c46feaac838a2e6fb2214"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idc0b636e8cb20429493d70edad4b1c158"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8d487055eb64aa0ba3a4eaf9fd4c88b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Homeland Security, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6e7ec276fd944b49fc1054b1b871a27"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Arctic</header><text>The term <term>Arctic</term> has the meaning given that term in section 112 of the Arctic Research and Policy Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4111">15 U.S.C. 4111</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f1f1423cd844419879cd9cf87d834d6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered activities</header><text>The term <term>covered activities</term> means marine surveys that may pose dual-use risks for civilian and military applications, including—</text><subparagraph id="id082ce74a504a42fa8e9524a3f536279d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exploration of natural resources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88c194461e6848bf918308de0522d711"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seabed mapping, hydrographic surveys, and oceanographic surveys;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f8cb47a14064e2bb39559d9e59fc60d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>data collection related to subsea assets and infrastructure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a000633013248d5b0ea1dfc6fbdbcc2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>operation of unmanned maritime systems; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19f555c7926a492d94d2f9956456b53b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other activity designated by the Secretary of State as posing a risk to national security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id199adce8ee53424b867032edef191f89"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered vessel</header><text>The term <term>covered vessel</term> means a foreign vessel that—</text><subparagraph id="id768c46e2e1534afa87154010eadd4820"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a vessel of a foreign adversary; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7843889bd2584440b0ece8a154f89065"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of State reasonably believes to be associated with a foreign adversary in a manner that threatens the security of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id63edf2158cc442dd94c59338ec7eab17"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exclusive economic zone</header><text>The term <term>exclusive economic zone</term> means, with respect to the United States, including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and any other territory or possession over which the United States exercises sovereignty, the zone seaward of and adjacent to the territorial sea, including the contiguous zone, and extending 200 nautical miles from the territorial sea baseline (except where otherwise limited by treaty or other agreement recognized by the United States) in which the United States has sovereign rights and jurisdiction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf23eb920a3d14ae18730b7c06fa2ded8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Foreign adversary</header><text>The term <term>foreign adversary</term> means any foreign government or foreign nongovernment person engaged in a long-term pattern or serious instances of conduct significantly adverse to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons, including—</text><subparagraph id="id966f908cf3b94367a5dff27c915dd5b7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Democratic People's Republic of Korea;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id360f7ce967af488a87263e5b4c1dc769"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Islamic Republic of Iran;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde29fd4ef48d4cc183b0f8d11208489a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id384616a63f2c4ffca227e010fab0952a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Russian Federation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4cd346c40656461fb7bf43743c4a966c"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Foreign vessel</header><text>The term <term>foreign vessel</term> means any vessel that is—</text><subparagraph id="ide73b1240a34f4b4da5dfb41d1cb1575f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>owned, operated, or chartered by a foreign government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3dc95b17cf4040ba9c3d2a0b0a9c99d2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>owned or controlled by an entity organized under the laws of, headquartered in, or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of a foreign country; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8349eb17a484a9c8c25dee7449cdbf5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>registered under the flag of a foreign country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id17f72307313c483a990cab137d137655"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id880e5a6ad4df44ba947e631ee79899a7"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Marine scientific research</header><text>The term <term>marine scientific research</term> means any activity that is—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6911acfa11724ee687d8b3ae660ab42d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">undertaken in the ocean to expand knowledge of the marine environment and its processes, including data collection activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee30d106a0244485b8bf7fb31783a926"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regulated by the United States under the Presidential Proclamation on Revision to United States Marine Scientific Research Policy of September 2020.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide28c6019597442999fab032cd4d16a19"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Territorial sea</header><text>The term <term>territorial sea</term> means the waters extending to 12 nautical miles from the baselines of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ad47b3df7b84a2582bc70e62a444161"><enum>(12)</enum><header>United States waters</header><text>The term <term>United States waters</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idd440445eb142415f98ea5f6d74caa35b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the territorial sea of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idac93e89d0f5f4c949cf7f267d97d4578"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the exclusive economic zone of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7b5605820fa44c4b6e0b1e1666a1097"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the continental shelf of the United States, as it pertains to marine scientific research and other activities on the seabed or subsoil.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idfed45521cf114f51af19a76a47c96168"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="id0cd24d3f98c745eea03e47fffca49a16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to limit espionage and influence operations by foreign adversaries in the Arctic and in United States waters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1358c55346504b83bdc32749eb57bccb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to inform allied countries with a presence in the Arctic about the espionage and influence operations of foreign adversaries in the Arctic, including espionage through covered activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35f6a046dca64b71b00ff207f76ad406"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to condition support from the Federal Government for marine surveys on cooperation with counterespionage in the Arctic and in United States waters, including limitations on information sharing of data obtained through covered activities in the Arctic and in United States waters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id32092dd690434ef393766fed05c199b3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to leverage all appropriate diplomatic means available to ensure the security of the Arctic and the sovereignty of United States waters through the enforcement of section 6, including through—</text><subparagraph id="idbacdd12cfbde4a7aade3ee4d2cdbd6a1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demarches;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb9c65d12ebbb4a008e6b228634e8d414"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public condemnations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6bb6c22e6bc14ca59b78476e3db0ddbd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>diplomatic sanctions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00be7e70ba06403e938441aa1e012be1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>coordination of multilateral diplomatic pressure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3cd55062f974475586bcf3c92cb7ac7f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>motions to remove an offending country from Arctic-related multilateral bodies and cooperatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d442a0fb653447f9baa3715e4f0d262"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other diplomatic means authorized by law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id60808624e27e47ad9a6168299082c250"><enum>5.</enum><header>Strategy</header><subsection id="id2e56a934974e4379b0711284b28fc383" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall produce a strategy to identify and combat espionage and influence operations by foreign adversaries in the Arctic.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2e542cd458ab478b9f27637f9b269206" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required by paragraph (1) shall include—</text><paragraph id="id2d7d298bdc5c441591566d3ba09b2983" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying and countering espionage activities in the Arctic;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideff6f8e147914801b0c5abb1ce716e6b" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>diplomatic methods to enforce section 6; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ab2d1bf24634e2b8343f5510f1aa5e6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as appropriate, enlistment of and coordination with allied countries that have a presence in the Arctic to combat espionage by foreign adversaries.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb404d4e4a5a349d7b13b29395fbf74e7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Marine scientific research in United States waters</header><subsection id="ide1fe6a20e5e64c9c805558f1b326723b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No foreign scientist may conduct a maritime scientific research project in United States waters without prior consent from the United States Government provided in accordance with this section and with appropriate international customs as determined by the Secretary of State.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb2586b8fcfbc4103b497177463328e9b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements; applications</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbddc6acc2bff4c69854cddf56180bf9b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require foreign vessels to obtain prior consent to conduct maritime scientific research in United States waters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide5217ddb8c31417698292f1fc08aa13f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement a process for reviewing applications for such consent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide4b8bf0044914f17ab299a0357f662d4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text>To facilitate the process for reviewing applications to conduct maritime scientific research under this section, the head of each agency shall share information related to such maritime scientific research with the Department of State unless otherwise prohibited by law.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4ae9f6ba30404234a1d9ef321c20d57b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on covered vessels</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (e), the Secretary of State shall not approve any application submitted under this section for any covered vessel.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34a51322bec744118fa9066567bffb9e"><enum>(e)</enum><header>National interest waiver</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id776985bbc9b84df797c7e4119f3e3be4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may waive the prohibition in subsection (d) on an individual basis if the Secretary determines that doing so is the national interest of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22064547fb6e4541abbe5860ebb6565d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice required</header><text>Not later than 5 days after any issuance of a waiver under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress written notice describing the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1eee7d21111845c184b3b1a036ffa2fd"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date of any violation of subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall notify the appropriate committees of Congress of such violation, including—</text><paragraph id="id512256c0ce8843f89885d0ad11d3eaaa"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the country affiliation of the foreign scientist;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id27509b99c5f14bbabbcaa00fd1b9bda9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the nature of the violation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2dc91f58059746ca9f37df4037ee276d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>subsequent action by the Federal Government to address the violation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ideb0c8311987d4843af13c2cdd084c4ee"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="id6ac5c505fd3b4df7aa7f4b726668a1c8" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on espionage and influence operations by foreign adversaries in the Arctic and in United States waters.</text></subsection><subsection id="id676194be8e6548cdb0d4727790142ab0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="ide51131d56c514c838c26a8d172885a57" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the extent to which covered activities support espionage and influence operations by foreign adversaries in the Arctic and in United States waters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc70e8b12e65b42dd90b66b8cfaaa77af" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of United States Government support for covered activities in the Arctic that involve foreign adversaries, including—</text><subparagraph id="idc6664f9b2f6143719c10c625e2b01a05" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>funding;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3eaad33de9ce4b18a9ced093f00d6741" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public-private partnerships;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc2217a4921ca4a05a6237178ccea40c0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maritime security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57f086a6ddfb41c783132e1e4c6e3a34" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>technical assistance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbd21d9632ac7435fa578a9c3db1a713a" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>information sharing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc40c72a041f64c2983fe5504f8d8412d" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other form of material or technical support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a3ae20d90b04343b0d18de21b65b01a" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of efforts by the Secretary of State to enlist allied countries with a presence in the Arctic to combat espionage in the Arctic by foreign adversaries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id245b01bcff7a454eb003703bf4250552" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations for combating such espionage.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2790b45a41894626bb554b738e72ed4b" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9ed70147530b45ddb1e87b66cc7d58cf" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be made available on request to any Member of Congress.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

