<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9E0C56A0EBBC46AD9F65EF8E4CA1F9B0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8113 IH: To direct the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a feasibility study on a selective water withdrawal system at Glen Canyon Dam, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8113</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a feasibility study on a selective water withdrawal system at Glen Canyon Dam, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H47FBE250AA324269B6F0438F56451546" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H168A5974D8604D28BB9885088018476C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Glen Canyon Dam selective water withdrawal system feasibility study</header> 
<subsection id="H9AAE74CBAACF4BE2AB06C7C542163222"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior (acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation) (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and Colorado River Storage Project power contractors, shall carry out a feasibility study (including all hydrological modeling) on a selective water withdrawal system at Glen Canyon Dam to optimize hydropower generation when releasing cold water from Glen Canyon Dam, while also preventing entrainment of invasive species, pursuant to the 2016 Long-Term Experimental and Management Plan Record of Decision and the 2024 Long-Term Experimental and Management Plan Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement and Record of Decision.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2AFA1BA559224B6B903FCC5F9E3A9CD2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Feasibility determination</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a selective water withdrawal system alternative studied under subsection (a) is feasible under the reclamation laws, the Secretary may, if the Colorado River Storage Project power contractors concur with the alternative chosen, begin compliance with, and construction of, the chosen alternative.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H60179ED32AF44A399F0C9778101F2074"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Feasibility study deadline</header><text>The Secretary shall complete the feasibility study required under subsection (a) not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A4CDA2CB1314E36BA6A0EC5A42604BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED5014AE2BE94953B0FAA9413D8F5793"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The costs of the feasibility study under subsection (a) shall be paid for by the Secretary using appropriated funds.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H772BCADABB7441DB9F16A783A1C6B4FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Federal funds made available to carry out this section shall be nonreimbursable and nonreturnable to the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA612669FB564F5D9A0665084ADF5D50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Identification of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and Colorado River Storage Project power contractors, shall identify sources of available funds to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H546231A4FCC14670B8FD70F0CBF617C6" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the post-2026 Colorado River reservoir operations guidelines and strategies for Lake Powell and Lake Mead in effect before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

