<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM26404-VN2-NW-WN5"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4332 IS: Medication Competition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4332</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260416" legis-day="20260414">April 16 (legislative day, April 14), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make determinations of the exclusivity periods for which licensed biological products are eligible.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medication Competition Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb19a70f3e9294bc1a0392f59bb78ac02"><enum>2.</enum><header>Determination of reference product exclusivity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 351(k)(9)(A)(iv) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(k)(9)(A)(iv)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b14d630048f4adab43556cbecd4cd93"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>determine any applicable exclusivity period under paragraph (6) or (7), and shall</quote> after <quote>the Secretary shall</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc78f757587274e3f800457866939ce8b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, as follows:</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4a06f2cdf02479bbebf2dc34ba8efc5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2227d3ae886f44e6a525ce1c97fce2d4"><subclause id="ida90f10fa81f942339279585d5063e7e1"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Exclusivity for first interchangeable biological products</header><item id="id2504936fb46a4565abe51a09476f03a6"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Products licensed on or after the date of enactment</header><text>With respect to a biological product licensed under this subsection on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medication Competition Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall include on the list published under this subparagraph any applicable exclusivity period under paragraph (6), not later than 30 days after the earliest date on which an expiration date of such an exclusivity period can be known pursuant to paragraph (6).</text></item><item id="ida072f89ef6de4b219a22a3459eee6e70"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Products licensed before the date of enactment</header><text>With respect to a biological product licensed under this subsection before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medication Competition Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall include on the list published under this subparagraph any applicable exclusivity period under paragraph (6), not later than 30 days after the later of such date of enactment or the earliest date on which an expiration date of such an exclusivity period can be known pursuant to paragraph (6).</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idea5b1a44c87242ac9ae3c9ab9073b558"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exclusivity for reference products</header><item id="id07b8e8af62bb48a5968ef4435db0e37f"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Products licensed on or after the date of enactment</header><text>With respect to a biological product licensed under subsection (a) on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medication Competition Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall include on the list published under this subparagraph the expiration date of any exclusivity period under paragraph (7), not later than 30 days after licensure of the biological product.</text></item><item id="id19317d3bda5d4af2a336011cd8f1d748"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Products licensed before the date of enactment</header><text>With respect to any biological product licensed under subsection (a) before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medication Competition Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall include on the list published under this subparagraph the expiration date of any exclusivity period under paragraph (7), not later than 2 years after such date of enactment.</text></item></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

