<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H25D22E3DC1D544329A9DCC0BC94832C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9490 IH: Bank Failure Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9490</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To defer part of the compensation of senior employees of large financial institutions (and their subsidiaries), to use such deferred amounts to pay any civil or criminal fines that may be levied on the institution (or subsidiary), and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8C661EC9AB954B4494848AC2E3D67481" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H44C420A99EF64689B873ECC67A5B7C5F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bank Failure Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H02AC8746DAF347A29D0E592E12564A96" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3DA346E2D90B41CF9E8AA324481BB945"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Going back at least to the Wall Street crash of 1929, improper pay structures have contributed to financial crises in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4F87642E5AD4DEFBC436AB6D8F6E2D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Widespread financial misconduct led to the 2008 financial crisis, which caused the Great Recession. Compensation structures incentivized executives and employees to pursue short-term profits without regard for long-term risks to their firms or the broader financial system. While culpable employees and executives continued to receive extraordinary pay, homeowners, workers, and communities paid the price for their greed and recklessness.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BC827EAE5EA4ABDAD5DEF3F60218EEA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As seen in the 2023 banking failures, misaligned incentives within the financial sector continue to fail to hold executives and their senior employees accountable for their actions. Silicon Valley Bank CEO Greg Becker enjoyed millions of dollars in incentive-based bonuses, while his bank mismanaged risks and failed to respond to regulator’s warnings. In the hours before the failure of Silicon Valley Bank, managers paid themselves millions of dollars for what they deemed to be superior performance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85619FAA38604127AE96758CC07A53E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employees in the financial sector continue to walk away with generous bonuses while their firms break the law and undermine the stability of the financial system. Compensation incentives that promote inappropriate risk-taking are a threat to economic security.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H53F97A6702F54C86B1AFFF6D73361683"><enum>3.</enum><header>Deferment of senior employee compensation</header> 
<subsection id="H91D289ECA90949DDB887D62FF5B17017"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deferment fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered financial institution and each subsidiary of a covered financial institution shall establish a deferment fund, which shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3DD090AFECB14096A92751A649CED52D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>only contain compensation deferred under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBC7BB14931A4AA8BD94DD0D16A199B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>only be used as permitted by this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H77D37D3D507841839013E07AFE5E437F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deferment of compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered financial institution and each subsidiary of a covered financial institution shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC883E0642CDF4373AF9FE475673B5607"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each year, defer the compensation of each senior employee of the covered financial institution or subsidiary in an amount equal to at least 50 percent of the amount that the employee’s total compensation for the year exceeds 7 times the compensation of the median paid employee of the consolidated financial institution for the year;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF67BAEE6DFB64D71A7DE3F0FA83E027C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">place all compensation deferred under paragraph (1) into the deferment fund of the covered financial institution or subsidiary; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97188B1759B54BA88DA1F012B8C0C25E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after the end of the covered deferment period, if sufficient funds remain in the deferment fund, pay the senior employee the amount of compensation deferred and for which the covered deferment period ended.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF0A792A123A54515AE9E64EF5F99BE4C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of deferment fund</header> <paragraph id="H1A1BC1AFBD6D4C028E1C3434AA4BBB59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of fund to pay fines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a covered financial institution or subsidiary of a covered financial institution is subject to a civil or criminal fine, the covered financial institution or subsidiary shall first pay such fine out of amounts contained in the deferment fund of the covered financial institution or subsidiary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0BFB826E90B64951B688B0FB54E11D67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds to make depositors whole</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a covered financial institution is a depository institution or a credit union and the depository institution or credit union fails, the depository institution or credit union shall use amounts in the deferment fund of the depository institution or credit union to ensure depositors do not lose any of their deposits. All amounts in the deferment fund shall be used before any amounts are paid from the Deposit Insurance Fund or the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund, as applicable, for such purpose.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD710A12D58C64CBE969F9E9900D65914"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cancellation of compensation that cannot be paid from deferment fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered financial institution or subsidiary shall have in place a policy that cancels any compensation deferred under subsection (b) that cannot be repaid as described under subsection (b)(3), due to the deferment fund lacking sufficient funds.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7ADFBCABE716496787BC699E714A7A23"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment of deferred compensation of ex-Employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an individual that has compensation deferred pursuant to subsection (b), but is no longer employed by the applicable covered financial institution or subsidiary, if the covered financial institution or subsidiary is required to pay a fine from its deferment fund for misconduct that occurred after the individual was no longer employed by the covered financial institution or subsidiary, the covered financial institution or subsidiary shall segregate the individual’s deferred compensation from other amounts in the deferment fund and shall not use such segregated amounts for any purpose other than repaying the individual pursuant to subsection (b)(3) or for the payment of another fine for misconduct that occurred while the individual was still employed by the covered financial institution or subsidiary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD561737FFB084EAB8DD0761E0133A705"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Securities and Exchange Commission may each issue such rules as may be necessary to carry out this section with respect to covered financial institutions and subsidiaries subject to supervision by the agency.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1D7951AA5ABC41FEAB635FBBF2C85F45"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H7BB045E0D440464199AB0AA666DFA179"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate Federal regulator</header><text>The term <term>appropriate Federal regulator</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H686EFD1BB631472E9C1A9FB651408BC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the appropriate Federal banking agency, as defined under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8D16B3A4A2A4942807D6A2262A1DBED"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Housing Finance Agency, in the case of the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4057FFEB613A4F4F83A0E1F7E84815BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Credit Union Administration, in the case of a credit union described under paragraph (6)(C); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29C4C280A0874DE8B5F376A3EB1903AE"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>the Securities and Exchange Commission, in the case of a person described under subparagraph (B) or (D) of paragraph (6).</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3A891BB30964234AD9085F7F6023BCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>With respect to an employee, the term <term>compensation</term> means any financial remuneration, including salary, bonuses, incentives, benefits, severance, deferred compensation, or golden parachute benefits, and any profits that would be realized from the sale of the securities of the company employing the employee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE3E6B9570554F71A5D7339F282D249D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consolidated financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a financial institution, the term <term>consolidated financial institution</term> means the financial institution and all subsidiaries of the financial institution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8325E180546848A08BFE21F4244DE8B3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered deferment period</header><text>The term <term>covered deferment period</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF9408A596C44C71A593054B52399798"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a covered financial institution with less than $10,000,000,000 in consolidated assets, a number of years, to be determined by the appropriate Federal regulator if determined necessary by such appropriate Federal regulator, beginning on the date the compensation is deferred;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H66CF50FDF49A480DBCD6EFE133D309E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a covered financial institution with $10,000,000,000 or more, but less than $50,000,000,000, in consolidated assets, 2 years beginning on the date the compensation is deferred;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7B4772E670D46C58F1FB3E22EADE6EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a covered financial institution with $50,000,000,000 or more, but less than $250,000,000,000, in consolidated assets, 6 years beginning on the date the compensation is deferred; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B37274A173B41DFA6D12BD934717787"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a covered financial institution with $250,000,000,000 or more in consolidated assets, 8 years beginning on the date the compensation is deferred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H155F30AF6D334E979A8711024225F098"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered financial institution</term> means a financial institution with more than $1,000,000,000 in consolidated assets.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HABE54B224E4B4F9BBDEAC2ECB0C1EB70"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <term>financial institution</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H791869598CE24E3E869759A509E264E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a depository institution or depository institution holding company, as such terms are defined, respectively, in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5DB1323EB304696B4F96CC3A494350C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a broker or a dealer registered under section 15 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H94690F8FF56A47CB9851181002DCA633"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a credit union, as described in section 19(b)(1)(A)(iv) of the Federal Reserve Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3D78DBDD85B24F4B93CA24769D9206A7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an investment adviser, as defined in section 202(a) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-2">15 U.S.C. 80b–2(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF1745BAD57E4D90935D7DF64B9282EA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Federal National Mortgage Association; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H36E9A6858FE54D27AD1D3744A50DF51E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBB1E96BD04F4D089B5A9D7CC965F754"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Senior employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>senior employee</term> means an employee of a covered financial institution or a subsidiary of the covered financial institution who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE1937B4212114649838B260DE461A0C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a senior executive officer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78E0866C3D3743A2A4DA62D6A53E1F32"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has total annual compensation of more than $1,000,000;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H37B25105455A49618ECBFEAFB99B8684"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a covered financial institution with $50,000,000,000 or more, but less than $250,000,000,000, in consolidated assets—</text> <clause id="H36A6977626254FB49D5AF0114E77C180"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in the top 2 percent of the most highly compensated employees in the consolidated financial institution; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H12BF7C447A8D43629241617FD5F3750C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the authority to commit or expose 0.5 percent or more of the capital of the consolidated financial institution; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F672027F39647A4BCC26DD35690974F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a covered financial institution with $250,000,000,000 or more in consolidated assets—</text> 
<clause id="HA89D7B67B70D4BF8BB23D3C03D0A1448"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in the top 5 percent of the most highly compensated employees in the consolidated financial institution; or</text></clause> <clause id="H741FCCF4C0934AC8855810A32566C4E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the authority to commit or expose 0.5 percent or more of the capital of the consolidated financial institution.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

