<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H64C1C3E8BB664C538A832490FF646354" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6809 IH: Alyssa’s Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6809</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to reduce losses of life through better school safety standards and responses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6E94962E0C1E42E280F66E83234874DB" style="OLC"><section id="H6379659335B3414A89011EE880E513F2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Alyssa’s Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8997AC4BC5E941F6A5A32DFB8D57947F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of the Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Evidence-based Practices</header><subsection id="H839E2906255C46CEBE88430D5B68C935"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/665k">6 U.S.C. 665k</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1C736E66D98F406BB55C12158CB472AD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H746E8CD5B99748228B5C5F410537DF7E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Public education efforts</header><paragraph id="HF0FBB86FC6074F599E0BD2B196274534"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As part of the Clearinghouse, the Secretary may take any step necessary to carry out public education efforts regarding tools and processes necessary to avoid and address school emergencies (including school shootings), including with respect to prevention and response.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E99494FFA3942D4B425F4FA35101ED1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Programs</header><text>The public education efforts referred to in paragraph (1) shall include programs to provide specialized information to States and school administrators to help identify, address, and prevent school emergencies (including school shootings) to protect life as quickly and efficiently as possible.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E36D046A50D474F89FAA378DD18033A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Means</header><text>The Secretary shall sponsor and encourage research, testing, and experimentation to determine the most effective means to implement the tools and processes referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H477E5CD70A8649C1927AB9FB8C02F1CD" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Training and technical assistance</header><text>As part of the Clearinghouse, the Secretary shall provide to the individuals and entities referred to in subsection (a)(2) training and technical assistance with respect to the following:</text><paragraph id="H89650878773C48E089EABDFB9A8E5236" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The evidence-based practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H415FF7CF9EEE441DB1F44659BFE931F0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Individualized consulting with schools, to determine for each school the best way to implement such practices and recommendations, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1F1FBA8B76F48048ED472310043399B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Subject matter experts</header><text>As part of the Clearinghouse, the Secretary shall hire personnel and contractors with expertise in school safety and school administration to provide additional subject matter expertise in implementing evidence-based programming in schools.</text></subsection><subsection id="H331E2C99324C49EAB0176DB1B4CE09E9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Panic alarm technology</header><paragraph id="HE3DD2EA325F447C2B677EEF423AC4EA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Technology development program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the Clearinghouse, the Secretary shall carry out a program of development, testing, and evaluation of panic alarm technology for utilization by first responders and local educational agencies to improve response times, recovery, and loss mitigation in the event of school emergencies (including school shootings), including with respect to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H026148D473EC4D59BDC21BECC165AA91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Safe and reliable auxiliary equipment for utilization in school shooting response, detection, and control, including visual strobes and audio communications equipment and mobile equipment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H623D1423629C4DD781118D9DA995EAC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Related equipment with high sensitivity and reliability that are relatively inexpensive to purchase, install, and maintain to ensure wide acceptance and utilization in schools.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4EA9DDB612744258FEF105FDF46079D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Methods of testing such technology on a non-interference basis.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF56E66C013664241B80EE3EF8FE34811"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Specifications, standards, and acceptance and validation test procedures for all such equipment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9F7BF6034B445C6B72763B1DF266DFE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Operation tests, demonstration projects, and alert investigations in support of the matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55C125B4BD3B44B8BE13B1F41B26C111" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary may not manufacture or sell any equipment developed pursuant to paragraph (1), except to the extent the Secretary determines necessary to develop, test, or evaluate such equipment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3754E9E3DFAD4D19B7BFA028A0138FAC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management studies</header><subparagraph id="H52F4F13E576442B3A674B7C69F38087F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Panic alarm technology</header><clause id="HC54263A3AA804161A61CC8DBDD499B5D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Studies permitted</header><text>The Secretary may conduct studies of the operations and management aspects of panic alarm technology through quantitative techniques, including operations research, management economics, cost effectiveness studies, and other techniques and methods as may be applicable and useful.</text></clause><clause id="H047D243C99B64F26BAB3D3838BD580BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The studies under clause (i) shall include consideration of the following:</text><subclause id="HF850E43A03C642ABB8FECF14C5A0C872"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The allocation of resources.</text></subclause><subclause id="H2D4F27568B8C40CAAEF0C5BC609F3180"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The optimum panic alarm technology.</text></subclause><subclause id="HA1194153016A45A0BF2CE7BD87BFF90C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The optimum geographical area for panic alarm technology.</text></subclause><subclause id="H34A35E8E6C4B4D55A42E51F5F384D822"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The manner of responding to such technology.</text></subclause><subclause id="H6F9C1BEA3FAF4F34BC4E36A779B67BEA"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The operation of citywide and regional public safety answering points.</text></subclause><subclause id="H6F5B83D8290249898C2FAC23F2AD2E36"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The effectiveness, frequency, and methods of inspecting such technology.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68578CBCAF544B9E8A79A81D7E14D102"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The Secretary may conduct research on the following:</text><clause id="H141E523595F5413294DB2B97662CAE99"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The productivity and efficiency of panic alarm technology.</text></clause><clause id="H11C371FA98E14309A8A0160426479EFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The reduction of injuries caused by such technology.</text></clause><clause id="H0214C9A5574D425CAC93F307C5E15933"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The most effective types of such technology.</text></clause><clause id="H36F503AC3F794F8B8139895013FC3431"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Procedures and techniques for accurately measuring and analyzing the matters described in clauses (i) through (iii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30C5E24DBF5E4544A84773E02EAFCB38"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>The Secretary may assist first responders and local educational agencies in measuring and evaluating, on a cost-benefit basis, the effectiveness of programs and activities related to panic alarm technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4989F49D86504691BCCB77B31757CCBA"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the Clearinghouse, the Secretary may conduct development, testing, and demonstration projects to introduce to and encourage utilization by local educational agencies new technology, standards, operating methods, command techniques, and management systems.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEA7D6D6F8001494C91FFEB4DACD9377C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Rural assistance</header><text>As part of the Clearinghouse, the Secretary may assist first responders and local educational agencies in sponsoring and encouraging research into approaches, techniques, systems, and equipment to improve school emergency prevention and response in rural and remote areas.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1B603DA4125442E97A924443AF9D9EA"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall ensure that, as relevant technological and practical developments occur, the Clearinghouse’s guidance regarding school emergencies (including school shootings) is as aligned as practicable with the related guidance of other Federal agencies (including the Department of Education and the Department of Health and Human Services), State and local governments, public sector entities, and private sector entities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEBDFDE8A72034608BB33CA745823D96E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(m)</enum><header>National School Safety Data Center</header><paragraph id="HC5CE535A97A14566AC48FDEEADC73249"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As part of the Clearinghouse, not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish through SchoolSafety.gov an integrated, comprehensive National School Safety Data Center (in this section referred to as the <quote>Data Center</quote>) for the selection, analysis, publication, and dissemination of information related to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H239227F3B8E749CEB1FEE5494189601F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The prevention, occurrence, and control of school emergencies (including school shootings).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C71D0FDCB224C72B7C2E839DC33DC71" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Results with respect to any effort to address school safety.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73075E4C818442728DFA171712C56F51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Other school safety resources, including with respect to hardening measures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6284FE2E45ED488FA1EDBB7BF6F26A52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Secretary with respect to the Data Center are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H34F2016871824699A86F9607D14364DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Provide an accurate nationwide analysis of issues related to school safety.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F9AC494ACAA4BC0AB154DAF91B9A8F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identify major problems regarding school safety.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96B2DF833317444E92758EA03E99194B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Assist States, local educational agencies, and law enforcement agencies in setting priorities regarding school safety.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65E489002A8C40A0B911833C0E9D5C38"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Determine possible solutions to such problems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9BD375555AB4A168D4E03217A5C3A78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data</header><text>In carrying out the duties under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall gather and analyze data with respect to the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFCD59AD52D094FBAB32C1666E7C4FF83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The frequency, causes, trends, and responses with respect to school emergencies (including school shootings).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H915A991C65DF441BAFF5729D09ECC210"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of injuries and deaths resulting from school violence, including information on the specific causes and nature of such injuries and deaths.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07A673B57D594AAA932C0946F6D8F54B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The property losses resulting from school violence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F71A10FE7E744958F8C80A9898F41D9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The behavioral hazards faced by school staff, including the causes of staff injuries and deaths resulting from school violence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5427DAC48A4141CA819F5DAC47BC9335"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The types of school safety plans utilized by schools, including with respect to inspection and updating reporting practices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD19D2D15D3D0458DA3344952D676AA6B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The school safety prevention and response laws, systems, methods, techniques, and administrative structures utilized in States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H689EB7506E6842ED9E4AD8EC18A4775F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The causes of, behaviors relating to, and best methods to control other types of school safety issues, including classroom outbursts, physical altercations, truancy, and elopement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD62F57B52C3C44799B801012A71A785B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Any other matter as the Data Center determines useful and applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H075F5613F656409AB4F951AA752E2C2E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other duties</header><text>In carrying out the duties under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H733CC1FC369D44FA9288CBFD514983DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Develop standardized data reporting methods with respect to the data described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ADFC0BBAF1741258F992BEFC2797BD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Encourage and assist States, local educational agencies, and law enforcement agencies in developing and reporting such data.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6052B8AE4D154D68A8815FEF31F08D5C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Utilize data gathering and analysis organizations, both public and private.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBCCBC56A5864BADBFBE42D065DB3A49"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA9280E3C1D764D4E9A93E7B36D92064A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure, to the maximum extent possible, dissemination to States, local educational agencies, and law enforcement agencies of the school safety data collected and developed with respect to the Data Center.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F58766F9247436CB66216FCC0D2C27F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Publish through SchoolSafety.gov such data for utilization by Federal agencies (including the Department of Education and the Department of Health and Human Services), State and local governments, public sector entities, and private sector entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFED5CB851A3A4C1FA576ECB5D5600F20"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph id="H1FC8B8D4AC9E4F8B999EE860B4C31866" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 30 of the year following the date of the enactment of this subsection and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report on any activity relating to the Clearinghouse during the preceding year to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H12A8B919296F491BA07C18F2B53BDC10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1A8DBF0ABA54456AD752D29012536ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF81EDA0AECE43FC944C43F413A7C0C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD56B48CE1C614D1BA41B793EB9FCBEB9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C9D06C31F4F4D7989F033117F436EDE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEDD0F4443BD4693A88E036D01B802A7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C763238B23D4F788F009DD850F0909E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H232ACB6CBA2B4095BF794C5B624D2D27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include information relating to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H80F19819FAC643278B82F912B163FE85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An appraisal, including statistical analyses, estimates, and long-term projections, of the human and economic losses due to school shootings.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96DCF2D0B7AE44459A6A9880CADCDDC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A survey and summary of any activity relating to the research and technology efforts carried out under the Clearinghouse.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H742909ECD49B496D92D04551D46B8B24"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A comparative analysis of actions recommended in school safety plans described in subsection (m)(3)(E).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF171BB145BE349ACBCEF8AC5F30F4DE2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of the effectiveness of the Clearinghouse in assisting schools to develop and implement master plans as a means to avert violence, and policy recommendations for improved effectiveness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD77A3E533C2441A79EE0043B8DF1761C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A summary of the activities taken to assist first responders and local educational agencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE11E9A58896D4E15A00021DB03D27574"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A summary of the public education efforts carried out under the Clearinghouse.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA947243E630463BAB2926AEFB2F3025"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A summary of outstanding problems with respect to the Clearinghouse, in order of priority.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA19F595CEA664A16B01404AEFDEB7067"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A description of evidence-based recommendations for additional legislation as the Secretary determines appropriate with respect to school safety.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF654CB204490421794FD96DBE88302C9"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD84BAD8B83214084BC83E2F52CF4E0A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DDA674FE88444DEA5014A7FCB14718F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Panic alarm technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>panic alarm technology</term> means a wearable device that allows for immediate contact with emergency services or emergency services agencies, law enforcement agencies, health departments, and fire departments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FDB3EEA9D724F51AB205D7C58AACD9D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public safety answering point</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public safety answering point</term> has the meaning given such term in section 222 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/222">47 U.S.C. 222</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8C06733705334A02AB9D03F735576FD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Directors</header><paragraph id="H409651EE07614F64AF7C57539B63E9BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clearinghouse</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/665k">6 U.S.C. 665k</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H1066527C0034495082D61204F2BFEEF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)—</text><clause id="H029AA74B336347CEB6C663581794A5C6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as subparagraphs (B) and (C), respectively; and</text></clause><clause id="HE62616B963124CF4B824B0F4E11C5C2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting before subparagraph (B), as so redesignated, the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H62A52C7B677C48549AA8ED8AA643E308" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HDD4F625F6107413CBD7F2EA7E3F1F7F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Director</header><clause id="HE6B8676721AD4403871E11364B1F1190"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this clause, the Secretary shall designate from among the personnel of the Department a Director of the Clearinghouse (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>).</text></clause><clause id="H1EF223089DD045FE9EECCDB082E648B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Discharge</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall act through the Director.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97BE25C27A7C45D69981AE4511FF7852"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="HE8535CF877B044DB8FE36BA8F1857E50"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B)(iii), by striking <quote>subsection (a)(3)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(3)(C)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H692682D3BDF74AF8B4839ECA6FAF9EDE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>subsection (a)(3)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(3)(C)</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08D10C37F34F4825855973D02BCEC3EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States Secret Service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/665k">6 U.S.C. 665k</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H92132DA38DC241429BB83C2B87853876"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by inserting <quote>the Director of the United States Secret Service,</quote> after <quote>with</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3B99DC0D0134CDE9E4E8BE88DFC3450"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text><clause id="H51973B5F013A446EAC7AF4B504C1EFA9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>for</quote> and inserting <quote>of</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H9DCF26E62EF14395821DB340F14466F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="HD6446F25F175466BAE4EC377F3609158"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subclause id="HA3A1DDA2D72344C7A9F77A668E7C768A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>evidence-based practices published by the Clearinghouse</quote> and inserting <quote>such practices</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAADD1A5FFA7140FD9FC7F6DB64BF5A23"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD7C6C87E944F4A47A128153686415E43"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6A85F95DE2B641709097CC2F6785A05D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H9FE92EB9A6904819B6A1163BAB500145"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the Director of the United States Secret Service to ensure that such practices and recommendations are aligned with the evidence-based support of the National Threat Assessment Center.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8E0A3CDEB2640D4B8C0C5F0578628D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>the Director of the United States Secret Service,</quote> after <quote>with</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9840BD4B9044D879E711A1D372E8D24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>External advisory board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d)(2)(B) of section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/665k">6 U.S.C. 665k</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB8364E8D5CF34E4796FFE4D049223FB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>establish an external advisory board, which shall be comprised</quote> and inserting <quote>notwithstanding subsection (a)(2) of section 1013 of title 5, United States Code, maintain an external advisory board composed</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE91AB9A059E44AB985E9A6E9F394AF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>representative</quote> and inserting <quote>representatives</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6E06273BCBAD453D92E48C225B9B2F3D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Funding prohibition and strategy for emergency response maps</header><subsection id="HCB51A46E227344158945871E7872FBB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding prohibition</header><paragraph id="H84F88284475B48C9BF706FDA82CCB176"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds made available for fiscal year 2026 or any fiscal year thereafter may be used to procure an emergency response map that does not meet the requirements described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H377362C135424886AD76095F3FB3E2D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The requirements for an emergency response map described in paragraph (1) are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H209B86C054B544C2B3A2E432A63F71F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Be in a digital geospatial format—</text><clause id="H6FDFE492EC4B432DBD0A326C4CC39566"><enum>(i)</enum><text>accessible on a laptop computer, tablet computer, smartphone, or other mobile platform; and</text></clause><clause id="H485AD8EE49344A33901C164DEF424603"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">capable of being—</text><subclause id="HCB14EF382FAD47389B48A7A1477AC6DF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>printed and shared electronically; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H97CD2812CE614D5DBAF8BA9F2BA12CD1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>updated in real time.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB06BF99BB664B9685AE96043CBA1A0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Be interoperable with emergency response systems using commonly accepted standards and capable of being digitally integrated into other mapping, emergency response, or public safety applications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C4186949F774427BCE8EA927F4BBF07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Have symbology in accordance with guidelines of the National Association of Public Safety GIS.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3908F0FFC1949C897BFA8C6E2137B35"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Have data owned by the owner of the site for which such map is procured with the right to copy, display, distribute, transmit, and adapt such map for any lawful purpose, including sharing such map with the governmental or private entities that provide or support emergency services at such site.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10BF6120464D467595D73A070593F8D4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Have data shared only via a secured and authenticated application programming interface.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E67B4EE8D58476F9ED393A6471BDC01"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Not be stored in a data center located outside of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AFE558574624B32B01A1365512478DC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Be in a format that can be oriented true north and on a coordinate grid.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6E31DDB4E8F40268BB140B579DE3A59"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Be in a format that can display any floor of the site (or the portion of the site) for which such map is procured through overlaid, aerial imagery.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77003DFF97C244BDA868780C6A246E99"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Be for a site (or a portion of a site) that is verified annually by the local educational agency for accuracy by a walk through inspection of such site or such portion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE3F33E980A444DEA9C671F8F97D0FE3"><enum>(J)</enum><text>After any funds to procure such map are expended, be made available to the following without restriction:</text><clause id="H15997BA3D6524300B9329CCB6574D62A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The procurer of such map.</text></clause><clause id="H22CA1EFBE4BF4AA5810EFD99D0A303A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Each covered public safety agency that serves the site for which such map is procured.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57FC151613C7436A866F0FB5346D65F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy</header><paragraph id="H021B5ABE45414C37AE86A65159D06037"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy for the Federal Government to carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="HE6592361F2F943ADA5216A7C90C772D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Procure an emergency response map that satisfies the requirements described in subsection (a)(2) for any site that is owned or leased by the Federal Government and determined to be critical by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FAEA94254C047938CB3C3B6F8BF8D23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Distribute such map to each covered public safety agency that serves such site.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF9695A44F04DF5A72886B0C0AD5A09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the strategy pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on such strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H636F97F482484DB3B5C3D725E048C031"><enum>4.</enum><header>Master plans</header><subsection id="H739603EBE1AC4D398339521453BCEA41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the establishment and effectiveness of master plans throughout the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2D8C6B5080EB4273A1D21FD413D99DE9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H1896740ABA9746888E2B5489B26CDEF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A summary of the extent and quality of master planning activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C108D4BAD6543C990EC013EED12B0C8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A summary and evaluation of master plans prepared by States and political subdivisions of States that considers with respect to each such plan the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8A7D22C031DC4D3194C5E0D06713353E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The characteristics of the jurisdiction adopting such plan, including the following:</text><clause id="HA0F39F3EC81C49C29ECB8907FC3A4294"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Density and distribution of population.</text></clause><clause id="H100FE27B0B0E40F1933F585832A2CCE8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Geographic location.</text></clause><clause id="HBC0DF488B6614AFCB566CB5A299D2847"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Per capita rate of—</text><subclause id="H1852BAB3D78A490EB0792569372C4787"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shootings; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF9951B1E31A24FD0BF4F9277D6F61626"><enum>(II)</enum><text>injuries and deaths caused by such shootings.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCA1EC360F2BE4DD09E0092868AAB5FCB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Size and characteristics of political subdivisions of such State or of such subdivision.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4196FE8C8B684DEB9FF272F63B222F30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The approach to developing and implementing such plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87B73730194344F5BF45867EB88EF305"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of the best approach to the development and implementation of master plans, such as central planning by a State department of education and department of public safety, regionalized planning within a State coordinated by a State agency, or local planning supplemented and coordinated by a State agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF69B097028094C51AA4C58ACA13954F4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of the costs and benefits of master plans.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HADF22EF6E9B045D5BF2133E88A6EACFC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction on rulemaking authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to grant any rulemaking or other regulatory authority to the Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Evidence-based Practices under section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/665k">6 U.S.C. 665k</external-xref>).</text></section><section id="HECC93A515EFF40C092876BAC03226E68"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HA5BAFF457D49463B8B43B12942605E96" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="H56C0B347840A44B89437385D96EE7921"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DAB24BA8B694A389C17FDB71D912AAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA187BDAB8E7C4FA394A116E0850AF0F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H417F67311F32479285187230B261DA6B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE53B1E4E7B44848BB174C492A9352D9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H913F335324F74B93951873AF030D7324"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37BA8B5496F94D8E8479C8D366A1C581"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF687A6A89BFE4487A845443879285665"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered public safety agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered public safety agency</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H2570B6B51407442DBEE53CEBEA6FC76D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal, State, or local agency that provides emergency response services; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DAE8B596D2B4DA2BBEB6D98F8C0950B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a SLTT entity (as defined in section 2200 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/650">6 U.S.C. 650</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86CED0D836404F36B6BABC4FCE382EA6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Emergency response map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>emergency response map</term> means a map of a site (or a portion of a site) to be used by a covered public safety agency in responding to an emergency at such site (or such portion of such site).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1077127C0C8341A9BB4EE959518BFC4C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E9AE95B74E04A2E802BD090FE5E1B1B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Master plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>master plan</term> means a plan that results in the planning and implementation in the area involved of a general program of action for school shooting prevention and response and that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2AD08DBDD6D349EA92DC16439A77B948" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A survey of the resources and personnel of school safety services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAD9FC1162C34755A1628AC8DFD17129"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of the effectiveness of the school safety standards and codes in such area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C8FACDA252C457F8B9B3496612D7F60"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An analysis of short- and long-term school shooting prevention and response needs in such area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H846B7F2AD84E4655B94BAAC106041688"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A plan to meet the school shooting prevention and response needs in such area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35493363CB8B4D8EA7F891B5E874BF45"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An estimate of cost and realistic plans for financing the implementation of the plan and operation on a continuing basis.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC13ED3C596B49E59A73914703FC994E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A summary of problems that are anticipated in implementing such plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E39CE62E9AC4639881DF569338E3174"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of the Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Evidence-based Practices under section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/665k">6 U.S.C. 665k</external-xref>) (as amended by section 2(b)(1) of this Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H512299B6A28B4FE899B9773377502552"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Site</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>site</term> means a building, campus, or facility of a school.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E4070C15477486FBC58C90C95861C79"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

