<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6777271E5A724390B183B98F2F786A22" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7579 IH: Empowering Rural Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7579</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260213">February 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve access to Department of Agriculture Rural Development discretionary grant programs by establishing a technical assistance set-aside to support low-capacity rural communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4B779CC0F4A84B18B7AB20DAB78C1195" style="OLC"><section id="H4DACC20DC9AE455F907B6AA7C2F9206E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Empowering Rural Communities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8B33F3D16C344BD4876C69FB3F4EF1EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Technical assistance set-aside for Rural Development discretionary grant programs</header><subsection id="H96BF5A25093E479C9657E69B30625593"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Set-Aside established</header> <text>The Secretary shall reserve not less than 2.5 percent of the total amount made available in appropriations Acts for each Rural Development discretionary grant program, to support technical assistance activities under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7CD0FB22F7394E7289673CB527C18BA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The Secretary shall use funds reserved under subsection (a) for—</text><paragraph id="HFF54CB7CDA4F4EC9BFAFEDD3AE9FD40A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>technical assistance, including training, project scoping, application development support, pre-award planning, post-award compliance assistance, and long-term administrative capacity-building;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B27ED28072F443B85D8040666AFE7B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pre-development support, including engineering, environmental review preparation, and financial feasibility analysis necessary to prepare complete applications;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8DEB10552AB483D8DE8ED46DA373128"><enum>(3)</enum><text>outreach activities, including workshops, webinars, and direct community engagement; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H376E455FA4C24CA9869F257C8F962B76"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the development of project-ready grant applications for broadband, water and wastewater systems, community facilities, housing, business development, and other rural development priorities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDC5F76906DE438BBF4E37CABB0DC3B6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Method of delivery</header><text>The Secretary may carry out this section through—</text><paragraph id="HE8FD0AEE951C46B5B78BF0CD1799E89A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>cooperative agreements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89169B49C8CD4B5C9402BD0A9443980D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>grants or subgrants; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H145CD6F93D794A92A32DDED9F5D79DDE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>contracts with eligible entities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H067D773FF2CE4DFA99E88DFDFE1A1938"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority for assistance</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall give priority to an entity serving a community that—</text><paragraph id="HADF35866ED03428DADED8FE45B901B6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lacks full-time grant writing or administrative staff;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F2428F49F5B450B880CACC244C975A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has historically low participation rates in Rural Development discretionary grant programs; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7545F62FFDA4BB2BCFEECD7FD6F460C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is located in a persistent poverty, underserved, or high-need rural area.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0982E4B5E35447F1829998EBD7B29AAA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination with State offices</header><text>Each State office of Rural Development shall—</text><paragraph id="H67AD55605DB44DB29E20A7C578D9B6A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify high-need communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A873B6C17284EA4A11F1CFB31C9B29B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate with technical assistance providers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE5DCF814D4343B383098554878F0F03"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure services are delivered in a geographically balanced and equitable manner.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8708FA253A524B57AEE1947F8CF585DC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative expense limitation</header><text>Funds reserved under subsection (a) shall not be taken into account in applying a statutory limitation on administrative expenses applicable to a Rural Development program.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4D3F5E7E25494A039814AFE493009A66"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual report</header><subsection id="HCEE8465B5A7A4E6692D191576E87F3AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing—</text><paragraph id="H1B1DC7694B0445079C4BBB00B21AFEEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amounts reserved and expended under this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87C8A4883CFE4DBEAEBCCA651D58203B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number, type, and geographic distribution of communities assisted under this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H397C0BAD1F1147319081DCF5522685A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measurable outcomes, including increased application completion rates and award success, of measures taken under this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F145594C85A4F639348076D1DEC58C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any recommendations for improving the framework for delivery of technical assistance activities under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAA2E31EB3D5404DA2222115291F7EF3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the report publicly available on the Department of Agriculture website.</text></subsection></section><section id="H927129FC7FFA42F19D06C7E93B21E5EC"><enum>4.</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may use amounts otherwise appropriated to carry out this Act. This Act shall not be interpreted to authorize or require an additional appropriation.</text></section><section id="HAEEC8740173E4B3091DD3D12D2AFC641"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H8AC3822E87984330830E3E147661B76D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Discretionary grant program</header><text>The term <term>discretionary grant program</term> means any grant program for which funds are made available in an appropriations Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA579267E6E824C838AD3498AA1B0B221"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HE0DBEB354DC3457DAA5411215179AE82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a unit of local government, parish, or Tribal government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A01211CDC594A18ACAD2C57E7E48C55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A9345E282874E53AAF8CA36D7056911"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a rural electric or telephone cooperative;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF33302D74354729AFC0800174448560"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EE8B7BAAF394486AFF2EE20624A7A8D"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a private-sector firm with demonstrated experience in planning, financing, developing, administering, or implementing rural development or infrastructure projects, including broadband, water and wastewater systems, housing, energy, transportation, or community facilities, as evidenced by prior project delivery, grants, or contracts; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43B3BA6019F847E7A9035212CBDE9AC6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a State or territory cooperative extension service authorized under the Smith-Lever Act, including such a service operated by a land-grant institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H159EC4B995924814A621EA74DCD9D5E4"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>High-need area</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>high-need area</term> means an area that demonstrates economic distress or limited local capacity, including 1 or more of the following, as determined by the Secretary:</text>
        <subparagraph id="H54FB3C1230EA451E9759F6C7F918F535">
          <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>High poverty or unemployment rates.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B05DF85ABE24B1E92437BF93B8F4668"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>Population loss or long-term economic decline.</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H2358F35DBABA4DEAADEF7EE747350B52">
          <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>Inadequate access to basic infrastructure or essential services.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC46D520F4C4440796139EECEA0AD537"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>Limited staffing or administrative capacity to compete for Federal assistance.</text>
        </subparagraph>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49111BBD05834EECB49D88F78E0FCBF0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-need community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>high-need community</term> means a community experiencing economic distress, limited administrative capacity, or significant infrastructure deficiencies, as determined by the Secretary, consistent with criteria used by Rural Development and the Economic Development Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53CE15BF3FCE47BC9FC8D91562914DBA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Land-grant institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>land-grant institution</term> means land-grant colleges and universities (as defined in section 1404 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BA3E05E3EAB45E4862013D18D4E255D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Low-capacity community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>low-capacity community</term> means a community in a rural area, that—</text><subparagraph id="H9E03CBDDAF64451CB1C37AB868B9C38A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a population of not more than 20,000 individuals; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD1A57035E2C473EB81472AD48F92BE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lacks full-time grant writing or administrative staff, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE65CE3A3E5D244ED9B3DF2BC30393745"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Persistent poverty area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>persistent poverty area</term> means a county or equivalent jurisdiction in which 20 percent or more of the population has lived in poverty for a period of at least 30 years, as measured by the decennial census and other data sources used by the Office of Management and Budget, the Census Bureau, or the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55C2901A8EC84F79B3547ECC8143805A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text>The term <term>rural area</term> has the meaning set forth in section 343(a)(13)(A) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, without regard to section 343(a)(13)(I) of such Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75559807FD2043A48A8E21C6E656A0A4"> <enum>(9)</enum> <header>Rural development</header> <text>The term <term>Rural Development</term> means the mission area of the Department of Agriculture that includes the Rural Utilities Service, the Rural Business–Cooperative Service, and the Rural Housing Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A1779D4E7E842818BF6020A68FD176C"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E5EC9BB8F674B8F9B5F61CE69845246"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Underserved area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>underserved area</term> means a community that has historically experienced barriers to accessing Federal programs, funding, or technical assistance, including due to geographic isolation, limited administrative capacity, insufficient local resources, or historic underinvestment, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

