<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC2A93228AEF4E42BA3D9FDC92F8033B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8196 IH: Workforce Data Quality Initiative Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8196</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260406">April 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to add the Workforce data quality initiative.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAA0DD6C600924309ABF32F0CD2293067" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8B869ACA3B3548A3B8B09EB42C525A09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workforce Data Quality Initiative Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HA3937337F9894C0DBE3BB30B94A829E4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Workforce data quality initiative</header> 
<subsection id="H0BEC4FF02A904C00BB7E8E43CD609894"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservations of funds for workforce data quality initiative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 132(a)(2)(A) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3172">29 U.S.C. 3172(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by—</text> <paragraph id="H270439A4B6B94948B5557B61E06054ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>striking <quote>, 169(c) (relating to dislocated worker projects),</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H763CBEC3E9B341B1B3732DC8C559B6C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and under subsections (c) (relating to dislocated worker projects) and (d) (relating to workforce data quality initiatives) of section 169</quote> before <quote>; and</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3DE76CE04218403DAD446C9F97E7903C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Workforce data quality initiative</header><text>Section 169 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3224">29 U.S.C. 3224</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H65CF645086A741A99D8F6B56A0D07247" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H5BBC06994E184DC08947BFD5D514A36E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Workforce data quality initiative</header> 
<paragraph id="H1AE713D8B38545D3B2AB130841DAF034"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text>Of amount made available pursuant to section 132(a)(2)(A) for any program year, the Secretary shall use not less than 5 percent and not more than 10 percent of such amount, and may also use funds appropriated under section 172(d) for purposes of carrying out this section, to award grants to eligible entities to create workforce longitudinal data systems and associated resources for the purposes of strengthening program quality, building State capacity to produce evidence for decision-making, meeting performance reporting requirements, protecting privacy, and improving transparency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49791C4204C14E10B8ADD74957608957"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, which shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB8E14B8656A24B3E8EA5F6B1AA80A83F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the proposed activities that will be conducted by the eligible entity, including a description of the need for such activities and a detailed budget for such activities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H304935FD498448ADB82EBD660BBA4B13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the expected outcomes and outputs (such as systems or products) that will result from the proposed activities and the proposed uses of such outputs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF2FEA600AFE9407D846EBBA23FCC93BB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how the proposed activities will—</text> <clause id="HF3A368C7E5CE49FB9BB83F7FBE759CE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>support the reporting of performance data, including employment and earnings outcomes, for the performance accountability requirements under section 116, including outcomes for eligible providers of training services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9E8DE222A4674DED96D812E239DC1CDD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improve workforce data standardization across programs in the State; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF81868198B2747B5A2958642D2E219D6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improve the collection, accuracy, timeliness, and usability of real-time, economy-wide data on new and emerging skills and in-demand occupational roles;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9A74DCE3A5B4EC5B545F8777FC10C4B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the methods and procedures the eligible entity will use to ensure the security and privacy of the collection, storage, and use of all data involved in the systems and resources supported through the grant, including compliance with State and Federal privacy and confidentiality statutes and regulations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H10687212B80745C1B1760E32AD2C0ADC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a plan for how the eligible entity will continue the activities or sustain the use of the outputs created with the grant funds after the grant period ends.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8F378B83BD441289899606F234E463F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under the subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to—</text> <subparagraph id="H9ECFB399E7AC4658A6ACA77B510174B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eligible entities that are—</text> 
<clause id="HD8146D35598C417DB85B03F48E6BFF1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State agency of a State that has not previously received a grant from the Secretary for the purposes of this subsection and demonstrates a substantial need to improve its data infrastructure; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0226081D238C4E2CABBD03ED132BB2BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a consortium of State agencies that is comprised of State agencies from multiple States and includes at least one State agency described in clause (i) and has the capacity to make significant contributions toward building interoperable, cross-State data infrastructure; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE492DFE7687A40789FFD4740EE797D2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eligible entities that will use grant funds to—</text> <clause id="H6B868DC47E5845F19F7A2823499226DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expand the adoption and use of linked, open, and interoperable data on credentials, including through the development of a credential registry or other tools and services designed to help learners and workers make informed decisions, such as a credential navigation feature that allows participants and the public to search a list of recognized post-secondary credentials offered by eligible providers of training services under section 122;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H179927274F8C42EBB84769271687F80F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>participate in and contribute data to a multistate data collaborative, including data that provide participating States the ability to better understand—</text> <subclause id="HC9A8227C581E4E7BA4A53EE5DD311A57"><enum>(I)</enum><text>earnings and employment outcomes of individuals who work out-of-State; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H29620F677EFC4CC588A57BB3B4D5272B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>cross-State earnings and employment trends;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE9760FA517DD4C35A6290DDAFB4CCA41"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>enhance collaboration with private sector workforce and labor market data entities and the end-users of workforce and labor market data, including individuals, employers, economic development agencies, and workforce development providers;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE7F590D5D1324C2E8DAC07048F20727A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>leverage the use of non-Federal contributions to improve workforce data infrastructure, including staff capacity building; or</text></clause> <clause id="HD719F5B38BF64605A97D3ED3747DAE98"><enum>(v)</enum><text>expand existing statewide integrated longitudinal data systems, including such systems receiving assistance under section 208 of the Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9607">20 U.S.C. 9607</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H512EF95A45144FFBA65A0164D02FCD93"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>In addition to the activities described in paragraph (3)(B), an eligible entity awarded a grant under this subsection may use funds to carry out any of the following activities:</text> <subparagraph id="H580F300ADB514C7B9D859BEFA4D46F6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Developing or enhancing a State’s workforce longitudinal data system, including by participating and contributing data to the State’s data system, if applicable, that links with elementary and secondary school and post-secondary data.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H365B713FEED34A46859A1397B80CB5FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Accelerating the replication and adoption of data systems, projects, products, or practices already in use in one or more States to other States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H96901DC170144498807CC54EFDAF1196"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Research and labor market data improvement activities to improve the timeliness, relevance, and accessibility of such data through pilot projects that are developed locally but designed to scale to other regions or States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1C5B6F506E04FDCB131EAD46FFA998B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Establishing, enhancing, or connecting to a system of interoperable learning and employment records that provides individuals who choose to participate in such system ownership of a verified and secure record of their skills and achievements and the ability to share such record with employers and education providers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79FE6005176D4AA6BF8F830E6A31BE26"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Developing policies, guidelines, and security measures for data collection, storing, and sharing to ensure compliance with relevant Federal and State privacy laws and regulations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C14A9D425F24AF7A9653EB41E885AF8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Increasing local board access to and integration with the State’s workforce longitudinal data system in a secure manner.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EC7821D568E4B1C8C03C9F4DFD40B7D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Creating or participating in a data exchange for collecting and using standards-based jobs and employment data including, at a minimum, job titles or occupation codes.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FEF65B959464CF29518ED14913C215B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Improving State and local staff capacity to understand, use, and analyze data to improve decision-making and improve participant outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EE09B3EC233437584C7D2890377DB49"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administration</header> <subparagraph id="HA4AC6AD285CA49168064DB4043F159A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant awarded under this subsection may be for a period of up to 3 years.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD11C7097C5FE4962BCA9C13A71F886F6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Funds made available under this subsection shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other Federal, State, or local funds used for development of State data systems.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCCFD8092B1841758B92B4504FA8B081"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subsection shall submit a report to the Secretary not later than 180 days after the conclusion of the grant period on the activities supported through the grant and improvements in the use of workforce and labor market information that have resulted from such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE78698658194C62B8335ED1458F8191"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible entity defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State agency or consortium of State agencies, including a multistate data collaborative, that is or includes the State agencies responsible for—</text> <subparagraph id="H8CA4C67E7E3E4C6A9DBFF50B2439891E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State employer wage records used by the State’s unemployment insurance programs in labor market information reporting and analysis and for fulfilling the reporting requirements of this Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC06A2F7B76B848A4887B1299D4C0F251"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the production of labor market information; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6C4B6CB8D8C440A80D7563B37461020"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the direct administration of one or more of the core programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

