<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H11B3010EF6D84B1E9B6A99BB50B84559" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7600 IH: Postal Supervisors, Managers, and Postmasters Fairness Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7600</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260217">February 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 39, United States Code, to modify procedures for negotiating pay and benefits of supervisory and other managerial personnel of the United States Postal Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H430BE76E8DB442B5A0410106D501B7FF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4AD944FEA72F498384A35971133580E1" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Postal Supervisors, Managers, and Postmasters Fairness Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H95885308D9A54CFA8DDD29A602909359"><enum>2.</enum><header>Negotiation of pay and benefits programs for Postal Service supervisory and managerial personnel positions</header> <subsection id="H7E1A745E8C95489C94C0977D13AD9BD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (e) of section 1004 of title 39, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H9443AD7B1DBA431B9CCE4AF12816EEA8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H577CDBDD3F4549C39BB059E895B605C1"><enum>(e)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0E966E2E8FCA4DF6AE0D73DEE246075D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days before the date on which a Postal Service pay decision under this section regarding pay policies and schedules and fringe benefit programs is scheduled to expire, the Postal Service shall provide a written proposal to the supervisors’ organization and the postmasters’ organization for any changes in pay policies and schedules and fringe benefit programs for members represented by the supervisors’ organization and the postmasters’ organization for a covered period.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B3B40C4D7594D2C8D848CFA174924B8" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date an agreement is reached on a collective bargaining agreement between the Postal Service and a bargaining representative recognized under section 1203 of this title that affects any matter (including the supervisory differential) concerning supervisor, manager, and postmaster pay policies and schedules and fringe benefit programs, the Postal Service shall provide a written proposal regarding the matters so affected to the supervisors’ organization and the postmasters’ organization for any changes in pay policies and schedules and fringe benefit programs covering members represented by the supervisors’ organization and the postmasters’ organization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD72993D7C90E4909A355339D7A4BCCFC" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service, the supervisors’ organization, and the postmasters’ organization shall strive to resolve any differences concerning the proposal described in paragraph (1) or (2) under the procedures provided for, or adopted under, subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HAE98FCA1CD904FB8A10BFC2E932DADF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of dispute resolution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (5) of section 1004(f) of title 39, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H9F2B02D5A6D4473588ABDF699312F0B3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H373B719FFD1C485DABC55EEE0AEDF475" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 15 days after the panel has made its recommendation and considered input from the Postal Service, the supervisors’ organization, and the postmasters’ organization pursuant to paragraph (4), the panel shall issue its final determination for pay policies and schedules and fringe benefit programs. Such final determination shall be binding upon the Postal Service, the supervisors’ organization, and the postmasters’ organization.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

