<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA7B40B735B314CBC8FB0FD87CE35367D" public-private="public" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print" key="H">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 135 IH: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to limit the pardon power of the President.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 135</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</sponsor> (for himself and
                    <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) submitted the following
                joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United
            States to limit the pardon power of the President.</official-title>
    </form>
    <resolution-body style="constitutional-amendment" id="H37125B31E73744249F1C62F500327F19">
        <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H6D2B3F3AEEE941AB98D0772E785E62E1">
 <text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States:</text>
            <quoted-block style="traditional" id="H7DCA3EA5112D490999C7B5A825C79163" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <constitution-article id="H1234">
                    <enum> —</enum>
                    <section id="HECB3E8A5D29A401FB494105401AA485D" section-type="section-one">
                        <enum>1.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall transmit a notification of a grant of a Reprieve or Pardon within 3 days to the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. Upon receipt of such notification, Congress may, within 30 days, introduce a Bill to nullify the Reprieve or Pardon. Upon introduction of a Bill to nullify, Congress may pass, within 60 days, the Bill by two-thirds vote of both Houses. If a Bill to nullify a Reprieve or Pardon is not passed by Congress, the Reprieve or Pardon shall become effective on the date that is 90 days after the date in which the President notifies the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives of a Reprieve or Pardon.</text>
                    </section>
                    <section id="H6E5C8C9ED4BF4EF99A622367BCA1B4F3" section-type="section-one">
                        <enum>2.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Bill to nullify a Reprieve or Pardon that is signed by 20 Representatives or 5 Senators shall be voted on.</text>
                    </section>
                    <section id="H60D3133C107E47A79A2393DA11AAD0DD" section-type="section-one">
                        <enum>3.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President fails to notify the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives of a grant of a Reprieve or Pardon within 3 days, the Reprieve or Pardon shall have no force or effect. </text>
                    </section>
                    <section id="HEEA35E49D9DA49D79089F760AE884803" section-type="section-one">
                        <enum>4.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not grant a reprieve or pardon of an offense against the United States that was previously nullified by Congress.</text>
                    </section>
                    <section id="H63F69E2184AC464F828307A7B440DB93" section-type="section-one">
                        <enum>5.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress shall have power to enforce, by appropriate legislation, the provisions of this article.</text>
                    </section>
                </constitution-article>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

