<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H66A2A13CA7104926B709DABC51699CA9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8444 IH: Motor Vehicle Flammability Standards Study Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8444</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to conduct a study with respect to motor vehicle flammability hazards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H67B00BCA18E94FCA9710FE6793DE3B37" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9F169FF289D04B529D5BBCF5159FEDFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Motor Vehicle Flammability Standards Study Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB72B9938870A410FABD2CF69C1D9BADC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on motor vehicle flammability hazards</header> <subsection id="H4189D183F75C4E5B865F98C590ED6D34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Administrator shall conduct a study—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB6330AE2E9834107A6EC4D264DFF187E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to identify—</text> <subparagraph id="H0E01ED0146AD49AB9E4A486107EFFB0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the safety risks to motor vehicle occupants and first responders related to the flammability of materials used in the occupant compartments of motor vehicles;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F1CC02C5D2145AB9336EDFE9D453494"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the chemicals, materials, and technologies used by manufacturers to comply with Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 302; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F59CD700BA94EC4AF68EFD119ED165F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the likely human health and environmental hazards to motor vehicle occupants and first responders associated with exposure to chemicals, materials, and technologies identified, relevant to their use in motor vehicles under subparagraph (B) including for susceptible subpopulations within the general motor vehicle occupants and first responders population identified by the Administrator who, due to either greater susceptibility or greater exposure, may be at greater risk than the general population of adverse health effects from exposure to such chemicals, materials, or technologies, such as infants, children, pregnant women, or the elderly; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H038625380E5D47D3801AC333B7EB5803"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to analyze—</text> <subparagraph id="H6B72AE92AF414A8B844315743E0CC804"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to risks identified under paragraph (1)(A), methods for mitigating such risks, including the extent to which Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 302 mitigates such risks; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AA78205288B45CB8E1CE46DEFD9AA9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any hazards identified under paragraph (1)(C), methods for mitigating such hazards, including alternative methods of compliance with respect to Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 302.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE7D1F3C225E84AFB930C94D26B58DC45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall coordinate, as determined appropriate by the Administrator, with—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7E27316449314CB3A1B3B8948E03DD3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD85A6AF5ABE4531BDCA07D15AC4BF61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Chair of the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5AAF8D31696148B186B736DC891CFB44"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public comment period</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall provide a period for public comment on the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2FB83927C1F441A59C82CD2FC721C712"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and publish on the website of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, a report on the results of the study.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5C3F95A173B9432D82C94E54F498D129"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H3AC0F7734C8147769C76CDE55BC50EF6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2489A9EF01C4466D83AF5CC581962298"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. <enum-in-header>302</enum-in-header></header><text>The term <quote>Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard No. 302</quote> means the Federal motor vehicle safety standard described in section 571.302 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

