<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H16A896BF75694EBCAB6B350D38BC3CB5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8441 IH: Military Voters Overseas Technical Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8441</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to
      require States to accept the official post card form prescribed by the Secretary of Defense
      under such Act when submitted by electronic means, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFF012F31F31C4774812E6812E272E201" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0EB70A24E19C439FBC3DC7C1CE7E5674" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Voters Overseas Technical Enhancement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Military VOTE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF7914A031F3C47479904315EE926A347"> <enum>2.</enum> <header>Promoting timely and accurate delivery of post card form and absentee ballots</header> <subsection id="HACD3978BDAFE4CC59C56A5724E599B0B"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Acceptance of post card form transmitted electronically</header> <paragraph id="H93E8954622634F86989974E33771DBDF"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Requiring acceptance</header> <text>Section 102(a)(4) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20302">52 U.S.C. 20302(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H90E260BB2CC4433EA77A3B1B345CE58D"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <paragraph id="HAD08BDCEED1F458982E7CDB75B0A761E">
              <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use the official post card form prescribed under section 101 for simultaneous voter registration application and absentee ballot application, and accept such post card form when submitted by electronic means (defined as submission by electronic mail or submission through an online portal) or physical means;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8E25DB5D0F0C48C68D122E2E56DE3AF6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Grants to States to assist in meeting requirement</header>
          <subparagraph id="HD91E566ED0A74EB4B1CCD0092B80E202">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Grants</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Presidential designee under section 101(a) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20301">52 U.S.C. 20301(a)</external-xref>) shall make a grant to a State to assist the State in complying with the requirement under section 102(a)(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20302">52 U.S.C. 20302(a)(4)</external-xref>), as amended by paragraph (1), to accept the official post card form prescribed under section 101 of such Act when the form is submitted by electronic mail or through an online portal.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H18B4B822A4F34FEFA3E74C6464620D7D">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Requirements for States</header>
 <text>The Presidential designee shall make a grant to a State under this paragraph only if the State provides to the Secretary the following information and assurances:</text>
            <clause id="H61B90BC7383243AE820274E00554721E">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>A certification that the State is unable to comply with the requirement described in subparagraph (A).</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H6FEF9DBF0F5E453EAEB5CE20A8FC7310">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the State’s existing process for receiving the official post card form described in subparagraph (A).</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H22D0A2204D69450589B46D50D9C737E9">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>The State’s plan to implement the means necessary to comply with such requirement, including a detailed breakdown of the costs the State will incur.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HEF8E280610CC40E5ABAEF5BB472678C6">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>Any further relevant information that the Secretary may request.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF3AF13180914EC1B0FD74261E9014AD"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <text>There are authorized to be appropriated $40,000,000 to carry out this paragraph.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H54E5FB8897F94E55BAE84623A33D037C">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <header>State defined</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>State</term> means each State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H24BE14A7C83E490CBFEEA1040B1DF93C">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Electronic transmission of absentee ballots</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 102(f)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20302">52 U.S.C. 20302(f)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
        <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H191A4D21A91344779FF5C13D7E0343C7"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <paragraph id="H00345930E2A14B5A8CD5E6312AAA8094">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Transmission if no preference indicated</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an absent uniformed services voter or overseas voter does not designate a preference under paragraph (1)(B)—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H3EFC2CB87FA24578BF311A40A8BF6935">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State shall transmit the ballot electronically; or</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H53195E17EC8D44FD98121AEB7D79350F">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>if the State lacks sufficient information to transmit the ballot electronically, the State shall transmit the ballot by any delivery method allowable in accordance with applicable State law.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H012DF447FC8D425E91D3294D9902B135">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Effective date</header>
 <text>This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2026 and each succeeding election for Federal office.</text>
      </subsection>
    </section>
<section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H4AE628AC7A2947669756A4A68E5F9618"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of single absentee ballot application for subsequent elections</header>
<subsection id="HC4B1E63AA06C47E1B96719FAD87635BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 104 of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20306">52 U.S.C. 20306</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD483F68DB2445CDB6AADBAE05671EDD"> <section id="H3F51517C28754BC48F743D6A292381DB"><enum>104.</enum><header>Treatment of ballot requests</header> <subsection id="H29B4435FA6074AEFB4BA49E97583F175"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of application by absent uniformed services and overseas voters for subsequent elections</header> <paragraph id="HCFC5BFDA2D27405E97159760263196EF"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>If a State accepts and processes an official post card form (prescribed under section 101) submitted by an absent uniformed services voter or overseas voter for simultaneous voter registration and absentee ballot application (in accordance with section 102(a)(4)) and the voter requests that the application be considered an application for an absentee ballot for each subsequent election for Federal office held in the State, the State shall provide an absentee ballot to the voter—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H3E67C4AFCAD2490CAE3ED7E838B954F1">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a voter who requests the ballot in paper form, for not fewer than the next 2 such subsequent elections; or</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H1A9C21E28CC14BE3926BB71517B41F91">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a voter who receives the ballot in electronic form, for each such subsequent election.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H88667E92E22147C7881AB26A464A168C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a voter if—</text> <subparagraph id="H7AF14E4E106A438F83D75F36914D509C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the voter’s registration is cancelled by the State;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDDE24548BCDF414482D9D023416713B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State obtains evidence that the voter is no longer eligible to register to vote or vote as an absent uniformed services voter or overseas voter; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB54737B6A7994A0B900B6CCBF80C2BE9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the voter requests that the State no longer provide the voter with an absentee ballot under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3325476221AE48909EE21098D0DC7D84">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Prohibition of refusal of application on grounds of early submission</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may not refuse to accept or to process, with respect to any election for Federal office, any otherwise valid voter registration application or absentee ballot application (including the post card form prescribed under section 101) submitted by an absent uniformed services voter or overseas voter on the grounds that the voter submitted the application before the first date on which the State otherwise accepts or processes such applications for that election which are submitted by absentee voters who are not members of the uniformed services or overseas citizens.</text>
            </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HFB105F0119864258885C4AC37F0DFBFF">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Conforming revision to post card form</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20301">52 U.S.C. 20301</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="HA0075DE86AF5464EBCCFCB1BA4D1F478">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (b)(2), by striking the semicolon and inserting <quote>, in accordance with subsection (c);</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HABD4A9F00D754451B347F9B8B900C2C6">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (c) and (d); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H89C120D7E7764809BAE9FBB40A426986"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text>
          <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H579AEAABB79340FDBA7C8CF2BC59612F"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <subsection id="HCEFDE7C991CC481896E0558E1B991C38">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Use of official post card form for registration for subsequent
                elections</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Presidential designee shall ensure that the official post card form prescribed under subsection (b)(2) enables a voter using the form to request an absentee ballot for subsequent elections for Federal office held in a State, as provided under section 104.</text>
            </subsection>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HD0003A6E0C8B4F71B29751E572B62B08"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply with respect to voter registration and absentee ballot applications which are submitted to a State or local election official on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7F67B0C5BB094E158832026F5DC05790"><enum>4.</enum><header>Evaluation of accuracy and timeliness of voter registration information provided to absent uniformed services voters upon transfer to new duty station</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 105A of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20308">52 U.S.C. 20308</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H1A07436AD5034DEEA0E62C00031AAAED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H375D90FB1AD64B598A60F66D876ED206"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA01BAFB1CFD141A5A723E29BDB357EAF" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="H6537D0D892384D8EBE3ABA5EBD7C63C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Adequacy of voter registration information provided to members upon transfer to new duty station</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Presidential designee shall submit to the President and the relevant congressional committees an evaluation of whether the information on voter registration which is included in the change of base packet provided to absent uniformed services voters who are transferred to new duty stations provides timely and accurate information on how such voters may register to vote in elections for Federal office.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="HA06E620C50A2468382D0CE5073690D02"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study and report on feasibility of automatic voter registration</header> <subsection id="H6257017614D646A692D01982C2DD6637"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall conduct a study of the feasibility of the creation of a system of automatic voter registration for members of the uniformed services upon enlistment or receiving commission, as well as the creation of a system to automatically update the address of absent members of the uniformed services for voter registration purposes upon any change of address for such member, including an assessment of the feasibility and costs of—</text>
<paragraph id="H5CB4A4A2B0054FFEBC9F3BAFC989307C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using information already collected as part of the enlistment or commission process for purposes of voter registration, including whether such information is sufficient for States to register an individual to vote, and if not, what other information would need to be collected as part of the enlistment and commission process to enable this process;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB12C97DEA3514010A0F50C93A38BF255"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using information already collected as part of the enlistment or commission process for purposes of updating voter registration information for existing registrants, including whether such information is sufficient for States to update an existing registration, and if not, what other information would need to be collected as part of the enlistment or commission process to enable this process; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA388157DFE974D24BF164831440D44DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>electronically transmitting such voter registration information to chief State election officials.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB8653B4D36264F5F93343EE469FAEB65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives, and make publicly available, a report on the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HB0C85E61BAE742109A2271594CF7B36A"><enum>6.</enum><header>No effect on ability to register or revise registration information directly</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or any amendment made by this Act shall be construed to limit the ability of a member of the Armed Forces to register to vote in elections for Federal office directly with a State election official, or to revise the member’s voter registration information, including the member’s place of residence, directly with a State election official.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

