<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MDM26709-NFX-81-NXH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 662 IS: Honoring the life and service of United States Marine Corps veteran Nicholas Douglas Quets, expressing condolences to his family, and condemning cartel violence.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 662</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and service of United States Marine Corps veteran Nicholas Douglas Quets, expressing condolences to his family, and condemning cartel violence.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Nicholas Douglas Quets was born on March 31, 1993, in Panama, where his father was serving in the United States Army;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Nicholas Quets grew up in Tucson, Arizona and graduated from Empire High School;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Nicholas Quets honorably served the United States as a member of the United States Marine Corps, where he deployed overseas, demonstrating courage, dedication, and patriotism in defense of the Nation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Nicholas Quets was known by family and friends for his generous spirit and strong desire to help others, reflecting the same sense of service that defined his time in the United States Marine Corps;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Nicholas Quets possessed a deep passion for craftsmanship, including welding and fabrication, and took pride in creating and building through skilled trades;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after being honorably discharged from military service, Nicholas Quets earned several degrees from Pima Community College and became a certified welder;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Nicholas Quets was working on water reclamation projects for Pima County, Arizona at the time of his death, and his community mourns his loss;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas, on October 18, 2024, Nicholas Quets was driving through the Mexican state of Sonora along the Altar-Caborca highway, en route to the coast town of Puerto Peñasco;</text>
 </whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas Nicholas Quets encountered armed criminals associated with the Sinaloa Cartel at an unauthorized cartel-controlled highway checkpoint;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas reports indicate that Nicholas Quets fled from initial gunfire, but the attackers caught up with him and fired at his vehicle, causing it to crash;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the attackers shot 31-year-old Nicholas Quets and fatally wounded him;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the brutal murder of Nicholas Quets reflects the ongoing threat posed by transnational criminal organizations and cartel violence in the region;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas violent criminal organizations, including factions associated with the Sinaloa Cartel, have engaged in ongoing conflicts to gain control of narcotics and smuggling routes in northern Mexico, which has contributed to increased violence along Mexican highways and in border regions frequented by American visitors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the violence perpetrated by transnational criminal organizations endangers innocent civilians, undermines the rule of law, and threatens the safety of United States citizens traveling abroad; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate mourns the tragic loss of Nicholas Quets and honors the service he rendered to the United States as a member of the Armed Forces: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idc808e9ba11224bd18c8afc2d37ba7d6d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the life, service, and memory of United States Marine Corps veteran Nicholas Douglas Quets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id814210c1771c46e7891e6c6219ec080d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses its deepest condolences to the family, friends, and loved ones of Nicholas Quets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc7dc88ddf7474d6bad00a235de56f2e4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>condemns the violent actions of the Sinaloa Cartel and other transnational criminal organizations responsible for acts of brutality that endanger innocent lives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id71c067b0920b45bdb9d9e620c248a2d6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the broader threat posed by cartel violence to regional stability and the safety of United States citizens; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id857491f589a045a4bb67300452dc7fd2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reaffirms the commitment of the United States to pursuing justice and combating transnational criminal organizations that threaten peace, security, and the rule of law.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

