<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H23F77AD0002642FFA70706D6B2B6DF3A" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1240 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of May 8 through May 17, 2026, as “National American Birding Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1240</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000829">Mr. Wied</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of May 8 through May 17, 2026, as <quote>National American Birding Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas approximately 3,500,000,000 songbirds, raptors, shore birds, and waterfowl representing over 350 species migrate north through the United States to breeding grounds every spring from wintering grounds in the southern United States, Mexico, and the tropics;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas populations of many migratory bird species are in decline due to habitat loss, predation, and collisions with buildings, utility infrastructure, and vehicles;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas an estimated 96,000,000 American birders spend almost $107,000,000,000 annually on birdwatching activities, creating 1,400,000 jobs and billions in employment income and Federal and State tax revenue; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas annual birding events, such as the <quote>Biggest Week in American Birding</quote>, sponsored by the Black Swamp Bird Observatory in Oak Harbor, Ohio, in collaboration with the Ottawa National Wildlife Refuge, the Magee Marsh State Wildlife Area, and a coalition of public, nonprofit, and private partners, leverage government, nonprofit, and private resources to promote conservation of migratory bird populations and economic development through a multifaceted approach that combines research, education, and outreach: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H9E9A7ABBEC50417D86BFCA88BABA735B"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0ADD28252F5442DE9C60D58F4E77330C"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H928CDC3DB44E4680845243459C051B4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National American Birding Week</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H12FD1EE19EAF4FED84B772B14DBFF7FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that birding is a pastime that generates billions in economic benefits annually;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48DB5516208143B1AF9E416BF2EBBF6C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>understands that migratory bird populations face an array of natural and human-caused threats to their survival;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEB7B5F01D948469990FF68504225051F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>applauds coordinated efforts by Federal, State, and local governments, conservation organizations, and businesses to promote conservation of migratory birds and economic development through birding; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBD4D198ADA8412A9ABE3D4BE86B910D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages birders and the public at large to attend events such as the <quote>Biggest Week in American Birding</quote> to learn about bird migration and to support efforts by governments, conservation organizations, and businesses to preserve migratory bird populations.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

