<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H94F4F5E818F34059A7F61ABB15D67712" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6309 IH: Cyber Deterrence and Response Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6309</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251125">November 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to designated critical cyber threat actors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H03DC9D2C44A84277A0268677647C24B3" style="OLC"><section id="H92459CD74BD2447785CE43A7AE93DA0F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cyber Deterrence and Response Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0E4E412E76704D6F9139B8D33689E248"><enum>2.</enum><header>Actions to address state-sponsored cyber activities against the United States</header><subsection id="H5575A9A67C844D89BB53739323A3E07A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation as a critical cyber threat actor</header><paragraph id="H3DF8AB2ED3924B2DBE6ABC9381D626AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the National Cyber Director, and in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall designate pursuant to the National Attribution Framework under paragraph (2) as a critical cyber threat actor—</text><subparagraph id="H1FE9DC687F3848B0AE710EABD070165C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each foreign person and each agency or instrumentality of a foreign state that the President determines to be knowingly responsible for or complicit in, or have engaged in, directly or indirectly, state-sponsored cyber activities originating from, or directed by persons located, in whole or in substantial part, outside the United States that are reasonably likely to result in, or have contributed to, a significant threat to the national security, foreign policy, or economic health or financial stability of the United States and that have the purpose or effect of—</text><clause id="HE98370A8C3A8422AA6E71C795085835A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>causing a significant disruption to the availability of a computer or network of computers;</text></clause><clause id="H4D31398F82D24862BDF007713268C9D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>harming, or otherwise significantly compromising the provision of service by, a computer or network of computers that support one or more entities in a critical infrastructure sector;</text></clause><clause id="HD28AF4EE574040FD81EFF3A0B0BD95A0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>significantly compromising the provision of services by one or more entities in a critical infrastructure sector;</text></clause><clause id="H25D11B9E6FD04259A428091A14D368F0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>causing a significant misappropriation of funds or economic resources, trade secrets, personal identifiers, health or financial information for commercial or competitive advantage or private financial gain;</text></clause><clause id="H24BF45213A594B6AB1E768C0812F5626"><enum>(v)</enum><text>destabilizing the financial sector of the United States by tampering with, altering, or causing a misappropriation of data;</text></clause><clause id="HDFAA2A3B86C44146A3150CA6652EB8AD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>causing a significant disruption to the energy sector of the United States by tampering with or altering data or equipment necessary for the operation of the energy sector in the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="H07EDEDE263F64BC89EEBDB604DE49F7C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>interfering with or undermining election processes or government institutions by tampering with, altering, or causing misappropriation of data;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FB8797F65B84E738D4B4FF25886F05C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each foreign person that the President has determined to have knowingly, significantly, and materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, any activities described in subparagraph (A) by a foreign person or agency or instrumentality of a foreign state designated as a critical cyber threat actor under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DBF6B0821EF4ECD98F7A1EF977989B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>each agency or instrumentality of a foreign state that the President has determined to have significantly and materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, any activities described in subparagraph (A) by a foreign person or agency or instrumentality of a foreign state designated as a critical cyber threat actor under subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H367B6C9AE9034D2E8A2270E27DABAE62"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any person determined by the President to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have engaged in, the receipt or use for commercial or competitive advantage or private financial gain, or by a commercial entity, outside the United States of data or information, including trade secrets, misappropriated through cyber-enabled means, knowing they have been misappropriated, where the misappropriation of such trade secrets is reasonably likely to result in, or has materially contributed to, a significant threat to the national security, foreign policy, or economic health or financial stability of the United States or personal safety of American citizens.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H82218B5C3A614DF1A62F721063BB3BF0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Attribution Framework</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Defense, the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, and the head of any other Federal agency the Director determines appropriate, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a framework, to be known as the <quote>National Attribution Framework</quote> to carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB9FAD17FECF14ABDAB023E18D27C5A77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Establish a uniform, criteria-based process for evaluating and determining attribution of state-sponsored cyber activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98ABB150825347B48B26D422E80E0B99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Define technical, operational, and strategic evidentiary standards, including thresholds for reliability, corroboration, and technical verification, that must be satisfied for such an attribution determination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB683F42E74E946698D87CDFF8D167D49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Require assessments based on the quality of available evidence to assign a confidence level with respect to such an attribution determination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE228B1BE2A642638F4CD8296ABCCDFD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Provide for the consideration of private sector threat intelligence if such intelligence satisfies such evidentiary standards.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C5E3E107E6949F7B50C96A9462773CF"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establish procedures for coordination with allied and partner countries, including regarding processes for information sharing, validation of evidence, and efforts to develop consistent public attribution statements to enhance international consensus relating to determining attribution of state-sponsored cyber activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28BFDDA4D02848B2A0E6C80BBD04FD61"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Establish timelines and reporting thresholds to ensure that attribution determinations are conducted promptly after the detection of any state-sponsored cyber activity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB55ED524734B4655B34412E3C9518984" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Ensure the National Attribution Framework is consistent with the National Cyber Incident Response Plan under section 2210 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/660">6 U.S.C. 660</external-xref>) and other relevant policies governing cyber attribution and response processes of the following:</text><clause id="HE8582FFCDD8B4BAB980C0CB437DC2E06" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Homeland Security.</text></clause><clause id="H1F7348C1725F4BCE9C2F4DD36581F4D2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Office of the National Cyber Director.</text></clause><clause id="H7E9BEA169995425F8AB78AD2C0B12F92" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Department of Defense.</text></clause><clause id="H214C63794ECF4227A29DBC7A9F3B3CC7" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Department of State.</text></clause><clause id="HD3F3679949A1418A97EB431D4B84CD5F" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any other appropriate Federal department or agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8590AFD83874333AB963CAF4B86000D" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure attribution determinations account for exemptions, waivers, and removals described in subsection (g), including mandatory exemptions for United States intelligence activities and case-by-case waivers granted in the national interest of the United States, for law enforcement purposes, or for humanitarian reasons.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F4F2890ACBF4EEE9F791500ED9810AE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Establish procedures for the designation of a foreign person and each agency or instrumentality of a foreign state as a critical cyber threat actor under paragraph (1) to provide for a reassignment of such designation if the original designee is subject to an exception described in subsection (g)(4) to the next operationally responsible foreign person and each agency or instrumentality of a foreign state materially involved in the state-sponsored cyber activity at issue.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FCAB6D50BD8463AB763F26BC8E630BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transmission to Congress</header><text>Not later than seven calendar days after designating a foreign person or agency or instrumentality of a foreign state as a critical cyber threat actor under paragraph (1), the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees in classified or unclassified form a report identifying the designee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE79F45CEE9D4D8D86DE3BF993F06614"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Non-Travel-Related sanctions</header> <paragraph id="HD1F8ED6D4B9F4439AC3FF0DD166F7362"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The President shall impose one or more of the applicable sanctions described in paragraph (2) with respect to each foreign person and each agency or instrumentality of a foreign state designated as a critical cyber threat actor under subsection (a).</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE5B97AEB1C6441D09F1C648FCE916786">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Sanctions described</header>
 <text>The sanctions described in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H51A6E97843DE481CBA323F29C92939C2"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>The President may provide for the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of non-humanitarian United States development assistance under chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H74BD1F3925AB47459F38E006DF640FF2">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The President may provide for the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States security assistance under part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2301">22 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB3C1FE57E2D64087AB4239340ECDFBD2">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>The President may direct the United States executive director to each international financial institution to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any loan from the international financial institution that would benefit the designated foreign person or the designated agency or instrumentality of a foreign state.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HCC2C54DE8B9C4AA2AD9CEBCAA4D43144">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>The President may direct the United States International Development Finance Corporation, or any other United States Government agency not to approve the issuance of any (or a specified number of) guarantees, insurance, extensions of credit, or participation in the extension of credit.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H694D498C37BE4C13BD4E37762D002536">
            <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>The President may, pursuant to such regulations or guidelines as the President may prescribe, prohibit any United States person from purchasing or selling any publicly traded securities, or any publicly traded securities that are derivative of such securities or are designed to provide investment exposure to such securities or investing in or purchasing significant amounts of equity or debt instruments of the designated foreign person.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7450459017934EAC80558927AE791CE9">
            <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>The President may, pursuant to procedures the President shall prescribe, which shall include the opportunity to appeal actions under this subparagraph, prohibit any United States agency or instrumentality from procuring, or entering into any contract for the procurement of, any goods, technology, or services, or classes of goods, technology, or services, from the designated foreign person or the designated agency or instrumentality of a foreign state.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H62343C2C21FB454295488D5333D10823">
            <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>The President may terminate—</text> <clause id="H5FCF31865E1240CA88F8900B0A210695"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>sales to that country under the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>) of any defense articles, defense services, or design and construction services; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HEC02FD3DE08E4A5098F16F52A0BFDF15">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sales to that country of any item on the United States Munitions List maintained pursuant to part 121 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HC9C46BF37F104EE2A76B0EC3B00F4AEE">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>The President may prohibit the entity and, when acting for or on the entity’s behalf, its successors, assigns, directors, officers, employees, representatives, or agents, from directly or indirectly participating in transactions involving any commodity, software, or technology subject to United States jurisdiction under the Export Administration Regulations (<quote>EAR</quote>) or any other activity subject to the EAR, including—</text>
            <clause id="HCDA73ED00D004BBFB883A1F6DA7EA212">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>applying for, obtaining, or using any license, license exception, or export control document;</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HFF19EA239F78436CAE6EA5561AFC88A5">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>carrying out negotiations concerning, ordering, buying, receiving, using, selling, delivering, storing, disposing of, forwarding, transporting, financing, or servicing in any way any item exported or to be exported from the United States that is subject to the EAR; and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H4CDD7370547942FDB1E211723B7CBE96">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>benefitting in any way from any transaction involving any item exported or to be exported from the United States that is subject to the EAR.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H7764DFE807394CF3ABC09063CDF461E7">
            <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>The President may prohibit any person, whether a United States or non-United States person, from engaging in the following activities, either directly or indirectly, with the entity:</text>
            <clause id="H5DB5D0D29B97434A9A525AAC1C6C3631">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>Exporting or reexporting to or on behalf of the entity any item subject to the EAR.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H22F9208485E64B3BB7E3839D97A87879">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>Facilitating the acquisition or attempted acquisition by the entity of the ownership, possession, or control of any item subject to the EAR that has been or will be exported from the United States, including financing or other support activities related to a transaction whereby the entity acquires or attempts to acquire such ownership, possession or control.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H742F1753BE044F37AC97CECAA00E4691">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Acquiring from or facilitating the acquisition or attempted acquisition from the entity or any item subject to the EAR that has been exported from the United States.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HAF137DA8BEA34261BD3B41BC01DC8D1C">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>Obtaining from the entity in the United States any item subject to the EAR with knowledge or reason to know that the item will be, or is intended to be, exported from the United States.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H92D54CCDFA8C4CE19EB40EFD3CFED88E">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>Engaging in any transaction to service any item subject to the EAR that has been or will be exported from the United States and which is owned, possessed, or controlled by the entity if such service involves the use of any item subject to the EAR that has been or will be exported from the United States (for purposes of this paragraph <quote>service</quote> means installation, maintenance, repair, modification, or testing).</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H2EFA5041C0F54E64B9F5C4476ACD72CE">
            <enum>(J)</enum>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline"
              id="HAC3DDE235DD6468AA36CAEDF411F321A">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>The President may exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the designated foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H4996B4C470E347D28A0AF7A7AF72BA88" indent="up1">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations prescribed under clause (i) to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of such section 206.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H21BD37043E8749C49FE9A86448EC25FA">
            <enum>(K)</enum>
 <text>The President may, pursuant to such regulations as the President may prescribe, prohibit any transfers of credit or payments between one or more financial institutions or by, through, or to any financial institution, to the extent that such transfers or payments are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and involve any interest of the designated foreign person.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection><subsection id="H6F11B0F3511E40B4BF06F047D8116270">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Travel-Related sanctions</header>
        <paragraph id="H64A1E4A31B8847D39189235A55E26C40">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header>
 <text>An alien who is designated as a critical cyber threat actor under subsection (a) is—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HFB794113327842599B72C134028619BC">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>inadmissible to the United States;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H62FCA650E5A84C57B65155FAD23AD715"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HCC251A9DB7324AFB9E7AECCA9C078354">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC3F2699CD3014567AF74F5F0CD80D230">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Current visas revoked</header>
 <text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of either such Secretaries) shall revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to the foreign person designated as a critical cyber threat actor under subsection (a) regardless of when issued. A revocation under this clause shall take effect immediately and shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of such foreign person.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="H49A1F5639C5647EA84BD6E4C0064E808"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional sanctions with respect to foreign countries</header><paragraph id="HA8E1D08670E745F4812E911443CCBFA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may impose any of the sanctions described in paragraph (2) with respect to the government of each country that the President has determined aided, abetted, or directed a foreign person or agency or instrumentality of a foreign state designated as a critical cyber threat actor under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3923E53B93164E63A31DC0DB652F48C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8DAEE5CC64F14ED39AA87AE2FCB0703F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may provide for the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of non-humanitarian or non-trade-related assistance United States development assistance under chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29C023C47D914545A5911DC5B4534CD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may provide for the withdrawal, limitation, or suspension of United States security assistance under part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2301">22 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB12F567502254AC5896BABBBC0D8FB1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The President may instruct the United States Executive Director to each appropriate international financial institution to oppose, and vote against the extension by such institution of any loan or financial assistance to the government of the country.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6ADD2287A0B9451EA4079F93D397878A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No item on the United States Munitions List (maintained pursuant to part 121 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations) or the Commerce Control List set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, may be exported to the government of the country or any entity under its influence, control, or ownership.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8D077BE295D4F5097D1F2DC918A28A6"><enum>(E)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5A363A27C0BC4DF6B8A7FE078FED0CCE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>No intrusion software or IP network communications surveillance systems or related items that are subject to the Export Administration Regulations, whether or not enumerated on the Commerce Control List, may be exported, reexported, or transferred, directly or indirectly, to the government of the country or any entity under its influence, control, or ownership.</text></clause><clause id="HC42E582EDEE8401AA15CA1EE10163AC3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the terms <term>intrusion software</term> and <term>IP network communications</term> mean any—</text><subclause id="HA77B0959DFA7403AAAB64A2330C015FE" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>systems, equipment, or components specially designed for the generation, operation or delivery of, or communication with, with intrusion software;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0E322CE03EC444FD9B46ADD859CC8DA4" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>software specially designed or modified for the development or production of such systems, equipment or components;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC4FE9288E521492794763CBF96648691" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>software specially designed for the generation, operation or delivery of, or communication with, intrusion software; technology required for the development of intrusion software; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA9E99ABE3112437DA738E1AB5923DB47" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>internet protocol network communications surveillance systems or equipment and test, inspection, production equipment, specially designed components therefor, and development and production software and technology therefor.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6F91E87A7864967998BEB5186495091"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2586917EFE8C48BEA944F42E4974D74B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>To the extent practicable—</text><paragraph id="HD39F238B83434F3EAA8C3180C12E5801"><enum>(1)</enum><text>actions taken by the President pursuant to this section should be coordinated with United States allies and partners; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2793C3E15B7640679BF250DD9E121A00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of State should work with United States allies and partners, on a voluntary basis, to lead an international diplomatic initiative to—</text><subparagraph id="H1609778A92B64BFD87A69B6A95A44AC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deter critical cyber threat actors and state-sponsored cyber activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCE50AD0DF4D4BB6BF050722F7551D80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide mutual support to such allies and partners participating in such initiative to respond to such state-sponsored cyber activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7788755506844D69E076B89371726F4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exemptions, waivers, and removals of sanctions and designations</header><paragraph id="HD6794BD983A84EC497180F93CF3F039F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory exemptions</header><text>Activities subject to the reporting requirements of title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/413">50 U.S.C. 413 et seq.</external-xref>), and any authorized intelligence activities of the United States, shall be exempt from the imposition of sanctions under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA99853F0C4F54C3CB8CF627BA5CACA06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive, on a case-by-case basis, the imposition of sanctions described in this section for a period of not more than one year, and may renew such waiver for additional periods of not more than one year, if the President transmits to the appropriate congressional committees a written determination that such waiver meets one or more of the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="HF062E2782023465C9C97ADE26B1C3CC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Such waiver is in the national interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CB2DFD0E9BB41149C952A7A62298E1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such waiver will further the enforcement of this Act or is for an important law enforcement purpose.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54B613245BAF4559AB4718FDDA561BD8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such waiver is for an important humanitarian purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5C517D0B7A74AAB9992D278EEDDEFBA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removals of sanctions and designations</header><text>The President may prescribe rules and regulations for the removal of sanctions under subsections (b), (c), and (d) and the removal of designations under subsection (a) if the President determines that a foreign person, agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, or government of a country subject to such sanctions or such designations, as the case may be, has verifiably ceased its participation in any of the conduct with respect to which such foreign person, agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, or government was subject to such sanctions or designation, as the case may be, under this section, and has given assurances that such foreign person, agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, or government, as the case may be, will no longer participate in such conduct.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC3F1633582145F58026ADEF6B009618"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception to comply with United Nations Headquarters Agreement</header><text>Sanctions under subsection (c) shall not apply to a foreign person if admitting such foreign person into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C6BE63F9E7248C485E9B9E38867A7CA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other provision of law to impose sanctions to address critical cyber threat actors and malicious state-sponsored cyber activities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H973049CBF43D41A08A08A76CB6952C44"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H86B81AF53A40448181E7309735E3E8F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEBBC69D7ED2442FB1111096C6B84A0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HEA0C31B4C55A4B25B5F94CA325B9E367"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H884768499A7946B4A6E9EFEEE6089D2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85B1676592734B6ABC61B4847936B0FE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agency or instrumentality of a foreign state</header><text>The term <term>agency or instrumentality of a foreign state</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1603(b) of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC107F50015A4271B8A8783BB93D8EE4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure sector</header><text>The term <term>critical infrastructure sector</term> means any of the designated critical infrastructure sectors identified in the Presidential Policy Directive entitled <quote>Critical Infrastructure Security and Resilience</quote>, numbered 21, and dated February 12, 2013.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BB49EDCC5DA409991F7D9F7C0CDA8F8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the National Cyber Director.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A6566198D454D5A9837EF8AC5A658F0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAA33A9994BA4250830A6E4C2F7EEF42"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Foreign state</header><text>The term <term>foreign state</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1603(a) of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H334EC2F44DEF45028E07D3D4FEF7C372"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85BD4BE6848C463080E25DA64D26F787"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Misappropriation</header><text>The term <term>misappropriation</term> means taking or obtaining by improper means, without permission or consent, or under false pretenses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DED5B49F2854DC482E9211CB0116931"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State-sponsored cyber activities</header><text>The term <term>state-sponsored cyber activities</term> means any malicious cyber-enabled activities that—</text><subparagraph id="H4EE69B20BE23474792AAFE48F5E28E98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are carried out by a government of a foreign country or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB0FECDB04064FA6B1D8BA2A86648CA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are carried out by a foreign person that is aided, abetted, or directed by a government of a foreign country or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H645AA60772B24DD59042A5F4B859CF1D"><enum>(11)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H758DC3B147D54B63961B68E29D31B2F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA349E4EB20C445D09B7F36D0F6EDE80B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

