<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC9611CF0BEEF4207ABE58322BA301BA1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9039 IH: Preserving Accountability for National Assets Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9039</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260526">May 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Venezuela Restoration Fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE6533EB00C284F3DA8D5C97187EF7234" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H130B884FEFFB4D57B32CDAFDB70C7083"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving Accountability for National Assets Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PANA Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB0F15EC2CBD64B33836ACF09B7C9EF6A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Venezuela Restoration Fund</header> <subsection id="H0D0F587856D240DFA797846BD607B25E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the <quote>Venezuela Restoration Fund</quote>, which shall consist of amounts deposited in such fund under subsection (c).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4C5881841BD64F0896A0B4FEE8F896CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Venezuela Restoration Fund—</text> <paragraph id="HB186A87BCE13458899ECB7352EFAF5F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be available to the Secretary of State for the purposes described in paragraph (2) without fiscal year limitation or need for subsequent appropriation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECCC8CF8EB4B454B810B98FB8773DADC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be used for the purposes of—</text> <subparagraph id="HE1B9C87276894A73BE2F0D8D1D97C06C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strengthening democratic governance and institutions in Venezuela;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBAD5F706EE0848699EB92391FF3DC73E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>defending internationally recognized human rights for the people of Venezuela, including support for efforts to document crimes against humanity and abuses of human rights in Venezuela;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3AEBDD365BDE4B5C8F35687C0792DCAB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting the efforts of independent media outlets to broadcast, distribute, and share information in Venezuela; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H42EB4AEF0EE6422EB5384ABDB3193426"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">combating corruption and improving the transparency and accountability of governing institutions and state-owned enterprises in Venezuela;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4220CC131676409FB05B6FD5B6A76B49"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may be used to support governmental and nongovernmental entities in advancing the purposes described in paragraph (2); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4C475D629454E1C963178A487EC0B0B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall be allocated in a manner complementary to existing United States foreign policy, diplomacy, and anti-corruption activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H85CDB11ED6394252A8036D2D06ECAF22" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of any funds or assets forfeited to the United States on or after the date of the enactment of this Act by an individual or entity who has acted or purported to act directly or indirectly for or on behalf of, the regimes of Hugo Chávez or Nicolás Maduro in Venezuela, the funds or assets will be deposited in the Venezuela Restoration Fund established under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H068E00C2D167473FB6120F5F111BABA6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H27100FF064C24A0FA26CAD7952EEBD08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an accounting of the amount and sources of funds that have been deposited into the Venezuela Restoration Fund; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H194A6A574F74453E8D783FC7E06BA4C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of the obligation, amounts, and expenditure of such funds.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEE96D15CAD7E4318B1D0F70597688C4D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2734F20297284DDE895821E8E9D77956"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE773297F294C4FAF9DAAEBEA3A6BF756"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A9E5DD553274480A3DF6F3BF47D15CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EE185C0EF444949A4218CB63B282AC9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

