<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H79BA8F05EE194273894ACF642F008C35" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8331 IH: Maverick Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8331</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001220">Mr. Strong</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the conveyance by the Secretary of the Navy to the U.S. Space and Rocket Center Commission in Huntsville, Alabama, of certain F&#8211;14D Tomcat aircraft, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF180E6AFE39D41628B7292DBAC97AB7A" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H56ACDD9EADA843BEB0D2C71FE597BA62"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maverick Act</short-title> of 2026</quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H71EA3C748993428FB338640AC7908888"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conveyance of certain F–14D Tomcat aircraft to U.S. Space and Rocket Center Commission in Huntsville, Alabama</header> <subsection id="HB0E6F00DA145480398C8E6C876E5B227"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Navy may convey, without consideration, to the U.S. Space and Rocket Center Commission in Huntsville, Alabama (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>), all right, title, and interest of the United States in the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9E5833970D594C448B14C1E307A17535"><enum>(1)</enum><text>F–14D Tomcat aircraft (Bureau Number 163283).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA84CB1B56AA944228B9281DBFA91E18D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">F–14D Tomcat aircraft (Bureau Number 164602).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA2D562D38274E51BAC00BFED3522CE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">F–14D Tomcat aircraft (Bureau Number 159437).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H11C9E2E1526A42E7BADF7EA6808DFA71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gift</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any conveyance under subsection (a) shall be made by means of a conditional deed of gift. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H94FEF07989A147F0A75111B45894BBCC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conveyance at no cost to the United States</header><text>Any conveyance under subsection (a) shall be made at no cost to the United States. Any costs associated with such conveyance, costs of determining compliance with terms of the conveyance, and costs of operation and maintenance of the aircraft conveyed shall be borne by the Commission.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H070BDD9BF5BA42F386C50768657C21AC" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Condition of aircraft to be conveyed</header> <paragraph id="HF47E82366C1749E984D4B8E3B3BD3399" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>As-is condition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not be required to repair or alter the condition of any aircraft prior to conveying such aircraft under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H899A86F6CB384D4895C06E9C542FBCDC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manuals; certain spare parts and equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary elects to convey to the Commission the aircraft under subsection (a), the Secretary shall, prior to such conveyance, provide to the Commission—</text> <subparagraph id="H150C0E79C9C64739BF37658A05B220E3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any operations manuals of the Department of Defense or the Navy specific to the F–14D Tomcat aircraft; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDED992E180874C008663A081AA5D98AF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such excess spare parts or equipment from stocks of the Navy as the Secretary determines necessary to restore such aircraft, or operate or display such aircraft once restored, for a use specified in subsection (e)(2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD8D7837B4D14705B9B432E47AD6951E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No obligation to provide other support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not be required to provide any spare part, equipment, manual, or other form of support not specified in paragraph (2)(B) as a result of or in connection with a conveyance authorized under subsection (a).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB2B94C8433641AD9109594FB48E4606" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Agreements for restoration and operation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may authorize the Commission to enter into one or more agreements with a qualified nonprofit organization for the purpose of restoring the aircraft conveyed under subsection (a) for a use specified in subsection (e)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD8BB1ABBE4AF4EC48ACBED745E2C793A" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require that any conveyance of aircraft under subsection (a) be carried out by means of an instrument of conveyance that includes, at a minimum, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H93836F0ED8EB4AF4A6465B158A1E778E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition that such aircraft do not possess any capability for use as a platform for launching or releasing munitions or any other combat capability, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE873FE7FAEB14148975A91E0A6232B95"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition that the Commission may only use such aircraft for display or operation in a public static display, an airshow, or a commemorative event to preserve United States naval aviation heritage.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC03FD76C9BB644449570C0D7D63FBB50"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition that the Commission shall operate and maintain such aircraft in compliance with all applicable limitations and maintenance requirements imposed by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27A33778A5304BC6A4CF371233417840"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A condition that, if the Secretary determines at any time that the Commission has conveyed an ownership interest in, or transferred possession of, such aircraft to any party without the prior approval of the Secretary or has violated a condition specified in paragraph (2) or (3), all right, title, and interest in and to the aircraft, including any repair or alteration of the aircraft, shall revert to the United States, and the United States shall have the right of immediate possession of the aircraft. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8379383A70BA44ACB3E18ED8A29D5FC1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other terms and conditions as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States, which may include requirements for demilitarization and indemnification and may restrict further disposition or use.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H504209D8BCB74D91A7BAA839CD8DFF32"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Clarification of liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, upon the conveyance to the Commission of interests in the aircraft under subsection (a), the United States may not be liable for any death, injury, loss, or damage that results from any use of such aircraft by any person other than the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6B75EC3587E041AF9B266370FA262654" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The conveyance of an aircraft under subsection (a), and the use of such aircraft following such conveyance, shall be subject to all applicable Federal and State laws and regulations, including the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>), the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>), <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Espionage Act</quote>), the regulations set forth in subchapter M of chapter I of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations (commonly referred to as the <quote>International Traffic in Arms Regulations</quote>), subchapter C of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (commonly referred to as the <quote>Export Administration Regulations</quote>), and chapter V of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (commonly referred to as the <quote>Foreign Assets Control Regulations</quote>).</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

