<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H931545BD35C544928C3FA7DF9CAA1872" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8548 IH: One Stop Shop Community Reentry Program Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8548</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize implementation grants to community-based nonprofits to operate one-stop reentry centers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE39D6DC4A954406685310B376FBF2E40" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HEAB5DAAF4554437ABE87E2D7C3EB93C1" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>One Stop Shop Community Reentry Program Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1AB4DCE20DD44EE7956CC09D7E26D011" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Community reentry center grant program</header> <subsection id="HFFA61D67ED2A4287973E86DFEAAC4B37" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General is authorized to carry out a grant program to make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of creating community reentry centers.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF4A60D8C5A6E4E778D8AED8C6ED5FCE9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application requirements</header><text>Each application for a grant under this section shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HAB37F24874E44C7AA98B4F08C9802F3A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate a plan to work with community stakeholders who interact with formerly incarcerated people or individuals with a conviction record and their families to—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H7DE1226F27C94A55B41C7F297AA901D8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify specific strategies and approaches to providing reentry services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H85D4F47DDFF745AFB7B4D0BFB95DB718" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop a needs assessment tool to survey or conduct focus groups with community members in order to identify—</text> 
<clause commented="no" id="H0C653340C9F04F5AA3D40BEC5F84A2AC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the needs of individuals after conviction or incarceration, and the barriers such individuals face; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HE3CE658848AE4894B87E694C9EB89F2E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the needs of the families and communities to which such individuals belong; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H7B6AD014262241778F9C414494A2BF37" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use the information gathered pursuant to subparagraph (B) to determine the reentry services to be provided by the community reentry center;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC93ABF233CA48A5A4FF5F89E24522F4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify the institutions from which individuals who are released from incarceration are likely to reenter the community served by the community reentry center, and develop a plan, if feasible, to provide transportation for such released individuals to the community reentry center, to the individual’s residence, or to a location where the individual is ordered by a court to report;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE4A2666B20949199A10416C34A24DDB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>demonstrate a plan to provide accessible notice of the location of the reentry intake and coordination center and the services that it will provide (either directly or on a referral basis), including, where feasible, within and outside of institutions identified under paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDEDF62384A0345E69B640D0276C64783" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>demonstrate a plan to provide intake and reentry needs assessment that is trauma-informed and gender-responsive after an individual is released from an institution, or, in the case of an individual who is convicted of an offense and not sentenced to a term of imprisonment, after such conviction, and where feasible, before release, to ensure that the individuals served by the center are referred to appropriate reentry services based on the individual’s needs immediately upon release from an institution or after conviction, and continuously thereafter as needed;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A717535A0DB4560A680D610A17E5A3C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate a plan to provide the reentry services identified in paragraph (1)(C);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H096F79B8A17342EF9755EF4098FD21C6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text>demonstrate a plan to continue to provide services (including through referral) for individuals served by the center who move to a different geographic area to ensure appropriate case management, case planning, and access to continuous or new services, where necessary, and based on consistent reevaluation of needs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H416463C3AE9C46A9A22E955C8B7D699C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify specific methods that the community reentry center will employ to achieve performance objectives among the individuals served by the center, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H19CBB8D51A694E7BBD66E4416AC46AE2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increased access to and participation in reentry services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8957FF6F431D4EF7823A9A0E6A136BA0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduction in recidivism rates;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A09013BB9464CF2980C36C73A6AFF4D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increased numbers of individuals obtaining and retaining employment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC48004AEC5C24321B0FB7AE91CB17237" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increased enrollment in and degrees earned from educational programs, including high school or the equivalent thereof, and institutions of higher education, and receipt of professional or occupational licenses;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1AD0B3FEB63549A19295E781E535FC19"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increased enrollment in vocational rehabilitation, technical schools, or vocational training;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC877FE24DC74E92ADA6D99EF341E17F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text>increased numbers of individuals obtaining and maintaining permanent and stable housing; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF351494D73E84D858C11C65CD584C8EA" changed="not-changed"><enum>(G)</enum><text>increased self-reports of successful community living, including stability of living situation and positive family relationships; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph changed="not-changed" id="H317E53FBAB384E42A25CCDAFB2216534"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, identify State, local, and private funds available to supplement the funds received under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFF74E51C953E46F384B42C9C170DED5E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall give preference to applicants that demonstrate that they seek to employ individuals who have been convicted of an offense, or served a term of imprisonment and have completed any court-ordered supervision, or that, to the extent allowable by law, employ such formerly incarcerated individuals in positions of responsibility.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE76CD8BFBD96485C9EB85D20051FC8A5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation and report</header> 
<paragraph id="H2B2F7839D05D4439AC447FDE4529E798" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Attorney General shall enter into an agreement with a nonprofit organization with expertise in analyzing data related to reentry services and recidivism to monitor and evaluate each recipient of funds under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D03564108314E6BA4983DF0B919651E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date on which grants are initially made under this section, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report on the program, which shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4E36644D85D1429C8E2F5E788BF52607" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of grants made, the number of eligible entities receiving such grants, and the amount of funding distributed to each eligible entity pursuant to this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF2F6738FC6FF40E494F2C35F93DD8E10" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the location of each eligible entity receiving such a grant, and the population served by the community reentry center;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97ED4538942F445D939E24B56B729D9A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of persons who have participated in reentry services offered by a community reentry center, disaggregated by type of services, and success rates of participants in each service to the extent possible;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE01AD999105F44F6AF8B90613825A29B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of persons who have participated in reentry services for which they received a referral from a community reentry center, disaggregated by type of services, and success rates of participants in each service;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3BC5A03FADF43CFB56E3A0EB0FAA6BD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recidivism rates within the population served by each community reentry center, both before and after receiving a grant under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H57EA5D8C8E974B84AAA57064ECA50313" changed="not-changed"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the numbers of individuals obtaining and retaining employment within the population served by each community reentry center, both before and after receiving a grant under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA518A6A7DEEE4D7E8943E937E0921977" changed="not-changed"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals obtaining and maintaining housing within the population served by each community reentry center, both before and after receiving a grant under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4D079E13CEE411C96D309AE407B45A2"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals enrolled in an educational program, including high school, or the equivalent thereof, and institutions of higher education, both before and after receiving a grant under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06C7046E8F7F4469A607D6EDCA21E3AC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of individuals enrolled in vocational rehabilitation, technical schools, or vocational training, both before and after receiving a grant under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1A426FA32C1543078AE347866382E7E0"><enum>(J)</enum><text>for each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section, the number of individuals employed who have been convicted of an offense, or served a term of imprisonment and have completed any court-ordered supervision, to include the number of formerly incarcerated individuals in positions of responsibility; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H453CCC83964C446E80F8C5B9DA7E4720"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other relevant information, which may include recommendations, if any, to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of the grant program under this section, and to address barriers faced by individuals receiving reentry services from community reentry centers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0758808CF8574D809CBE060F6251D809" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3051EE37F7814D2AB4111E5378706566" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community stakeholder</header><text>The term <term>community stakeholder</term>—</text> <subparagraph changed="not-changed" id="H76B1F414D9BC4491A8675775111C98AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an individual who serves the community; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph changed="not-changed" id="HFFE0223749A74534B4220C09009050C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text> <clause id="H6749AE05E85A47E6A2F2EE80C166A498" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a school official;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAB813A1E2CFF44E5AA1A0CB60D58670C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a faith leader;</text></clause> <clause id="H999A708CC3BA4BD2B5177D346C547290" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a social service provider;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H67914A12D0274690A2073B3D8B4D6E5F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a leader of a neighborhood association;</text></clause> <clause id="HFEABE37822AB4F6599598AD9D6F66F9F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a public safety representative;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1016F38866524C6C904E63EE4E03869F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employee of an organization that provides reentry services;</text></clause> <clause id="H80534DC0DA74402184CA6C27A83017A9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a member of a civic or volunteer group related to the provision of reentry services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE061111B43104F6D84B87E12112F2BDB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a health care professional; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D161C8761BE481CACC978C2ED6106F0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>an employee of a State, local, or tribal government agency with expertise in the provision of reentry services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC233CB274BE246729858D7DF8D1E3756" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community reentry center</header><text>The term <term>community reentry center</term> means a center that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD2A364F70FC4488FB13DED72609D73CB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offers intake, reentry needs assessments, case management, and case planning for reentry services for individuals after conviction or incarceration;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A99B0CB389747FCAE3362569DFF4701" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides the reentry services identified under subsection (b)(1)(C) at a single location; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H990A900F4A6E475DA22C0FA92C8406A4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides referrals to appropriate service providers based on the assessment of needs of the individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DEEF48A565C4F64B5576AE9CA4213B8" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a community-based nonprofit organization that—</text> <subparagraph id="HA08768AE0ED74542BD03C220F67B4CD6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has expertise in the provision of reentry services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8EC9ED55899D4C9D96F6C2CDBBECBA8D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located in a geographic area that has disproportionately high numbers of residents, when compared to the local community, who—</text> <clause id="H7311832B01D64FB6AC17D3E367F749E2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have been arrested;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0A94336FCD6B431FB0FB8A5342BEDEBD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have been convicted of a criminal offense; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H10C30E1F10744E0BB3C60D5156E9CD82" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>return to such geographic area after incarceration.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF409D76FA52E44F4A06997F92C48247A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reentry services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reentry services</term>—</text> <subparagraph changed="not-changed" id="H412A978ECA554C73B46DCC1F6F82BB56"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means comprehensive and holistic services that improve outcomes for individuals after conviction or incarceration; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph changed="not-changed" id="HC5D2D7BA234B4DBEABCB16F6AC4D3D0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text> <clause id="H16A05804863148CC9989990FFC169D7C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seeking and maintaining employment, including—</text> 
<subclause id="H3068DC0FFDD046F285F4CF73D324C872"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance with drafting resumes, establishing emails accounts, locating job solicitations, submitting of job applications, and preparing for interviews; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBE4D9776A25849D983C9DCAC735878D8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">securing any licenses, certifications, government-issued identifications, or other documentation necessary to obtain employment;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HE7F10BED298E4D76933FEFD0B99425CD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>placement in job placement programs that partner with private employers;</text></clause> <clause id="H51D6B31A5BBD4D90A2B06DD638B70129" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>obtaining free and low-cost job skills classes, including computer skills, technical skills, vocational skills, and any other job-related or other necessary skills;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF9E7FFA3F68F46F4B5A3D23EDD0FCFCF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting preparation for postsecondary education, including academic counseling, peer mentoring, and community support;</text></clause> <clause id="H71978CF46DF54239B9BA8D9EE300DDD0"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">locating and maintaining housing, which may include housing counseling, assisting with finding and securing affordable housing including in areas of opportunity, assisting with applications for subsidized housing and housing-related benefits, locating and identifying temporary shelter when housing cannot be found immediately, and applying for home energy and utility assistance programs;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBEF2294ADCD1441AB674E2704AB9DB19" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>obtaining identification cards, driver’s licenses, replacement Social Security cards, birth certificates, and citizenship or immigration documentation;</text></clause> <clause id="H3093463402844A98915F8750F0A8877D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>registering to vote, and applying for voting rights to be restored, where permitted by law;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H942B8324C9E4485DBD093C4AE4191F9C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>applying for or accessing high school equivalency classes, vocational rehabilitation, or technical courses;</text></clause> <clause id="HC99292F2845E43E1ABAB9EBF55F89C3E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>applying for loans for and admission to institutions of higher education;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDBD40B12996B458AB03CB7CD83E7A41C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(x)</enum><text>financial counseling planning, empowerment, or coaching;</text></clause> <clause id="H6587F391078A40919814992240A7DBD0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>legal assistance or referrals for record sealing or expungement, forfeiture of property or assets, family law and custody matters, legal aid services (including other civil legal aid services), and relevant civil matters including housing and other issues;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF4E4026C04CD4809B8B27E38F736FD43" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>retrieving property or funds retained by the arresting agency or facility of incarceration, or retrieving property or funds obtained while incarcerated;</text></clause> <clause id="HDF1FCE477C0B4CEB896CC6B51D7D6F98" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>transportation, including through provision of transit fare;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H368159C2A477476FB487916E16609453" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>individual and familial counseling;</text></clause> <clause id="HE274015F67E040B78255B3D14F7A2A69" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>problem-solving, in coordination with counsel where necessary, any difficulties in compliance with court-ordered supervision requirements, including restrictions on living with certain family members, contact with certain friends, bond requirements, location and residency restrictions, electronic monitoring compliance, court-ordered substance use disorder treatment, and other court-ordered requirements;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB9770D96FDA14753AD3A15E9253245B2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>communication needs, including providing a mobile phone, mobile phone service or access, or internet access;</text></clause> <clause id="H8B79043791484001A5480F0B738629F0" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(xvii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applying for State or Federal Government benefits, where eligible, and assisting in locating free or reduced cost food and sustenance benefits;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="H5013B3B562804ABFA160215116C16887" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>life skills assistance;</text></clause> <clause id="HF0C07B1D10604148A3B99D7566878E2E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xix)</enum><text>mentorship;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB86D6596D61F4875AE7577288E565E39" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xx)</enum><text>medical and mental health services, and cognitive-behavioral programming;</text></clause> <clause id="H9552168E6E184E6AB2BA69D16957CE50" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xxi)</enum><text>substance use disorder treatment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7B2B8AF64F584D4D8C2F56694452A4FA" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xxii)</enum><text>reactivation, application for, and maintenance of professional or other licenses;</text></clause> <clause id="HC11A76589C864A468E8AC8A9F10BA888" changed="not-changed"><enum>(xxiii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing case management services, in connection with court-ordered terms of release, or other local publicly supported social work case management;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB27491FFBA6848E7B3D015E528047FBF"><enum>(xxiv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">safety planning with victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, stalking, and human trafficking; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE67CBBCC36CC42F5A75C7E0908BDC2AE"><enum>(xxv)</enum><text>applying for State Vocational Rehabilitation services for individuals with disabilities that may qualify or conduct an evaluation to determine whether they may be eligible or potentially eligible for vocational rehabilitation services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D1395F2B23F41839C9999D2F40BA90D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Success rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>success rate</term> means the rate of recidivism (as measured by a subsequent conviction or return to prison), job placement, permanent housing placement, or completion of certification, trade, or other education program.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A357C2176D54AA288E447FF25F594C9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <paragraph id="HF272BF28C8AF48E8988E5861A0744452" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68A18179C9A44DBE933F5B5C0B8E1CFB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Equitable distribution</header><text>The Attorney General shall ensure that grants awarded under this section are equitably distributed among the geographical regions and between urban and rural populations, including Indian Tribes, consistent with the objective of reducing recidivism.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA4C2747C181D425E93EDB321560D609A" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants for reentry services assistance hotlines</header> <subsection id="HE2A3B148757146578C4C0FE21BA0A36E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header> <paragraph id="H7DB84A7D0DD044C8B56CE93319ADC683" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General is authorized to make grants to States, Indian Tribes, and units of local government to operate reentry services assistance hotlines that are toll-free and operate 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D2088FC95FF4FA39404AD2B1536B4F1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>A grant made under paragraph (1) shall be for a period of not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEC3FD3720F044479B57DC1D48D8ED983" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hotline requirements</header><text>A grant recipient shall ensure, with respect to a hotline funded by a grant under subsection (a), that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE3156383130C4A09BD2D6C281730D76C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the hotline directs individuals to local reentry services (as such term is defined in section 2(e));</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE59DC0087E8E405A9DBAE7AEF5B38FEB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any personally identifiable information that an individual provides to an agency of the State or Indian Tribe through the hotline is not directly or indirectly disclosed, without the consent of the individual, to any other agency or entity, or person;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33A5B7574B3B4A23B743803ECA617F36" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the staff members who operate the hotline are trained to be knowledgeable about—</text> <subparagraph id="HCD0AD87780C240EF9F281BF0C8A6C5F4" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>applicable Federal, State, Tribal, and local reentry services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FFC4D6E65E942E6B92A03655ADFF04C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the unique barriers to successful reentry into the community after a person has been convicted or incarcerated;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD814382B9A0D4521963496381F4C361A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the hotline is accessible to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF23B9B18E34F48339807024839F55279" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals with limited English proficiency, consistent with applicable law; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B9A4727A16E4B2F894E05048BF2A998" changed="not-changed"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>individuals with disabilities; and</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H662F21B204D3458EB8AECD2FCA13F3AC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the hotline has the capability to engage with individuals using text messages.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H55AA46B56B7545E593283754F84FD658" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Attorney General shall issue guidance to grant recipients on best practices for implementing the requirements of subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA4EA4670491E4BF5BEDAA7041E8D018A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall give preference to applicants that demonstrate that they seek to employ individuals to operate the hotline who have been convicted of an offense, or have served a term of imprisonment and have completed any court-ordered supervision.</text></subsection> <subsection changed="not-changed" id="HC8ECEC11EBA84C74B4DC444136A84792"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" id="HD551ED1736F14ABEBF14EDA21CCED98C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph changed="not-changed" id="H36134D76529240C1861111B68C71C13F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF9E3550943194FC1B18C07B9072382E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CDE9F3640CD40F4BF270E7679ADD938"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48ED0BA2686E40C0BD951F9A0AFB845D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBA300F9CD7234F449E9294657B94C6AA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6ACB7754AECD4B0894FA0392CD166AAD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

