<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3B7706D2B5814450AA7FE8829C0D6524" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5984 IH: American Manufacturers over Argentine Bailouts Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5984</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to provide financial relief for small and medium sized manufacturers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD81BBEA1C784D508CB072C7FBC5C81D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H129A53B58F894CA4A1E700084EC9B3D7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Manufacturers over Argentine Bailouts Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDF1DA1D7DEAF4410B0C38E5674CC3C41"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of exchange stabilization fund for Argentina</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary, pursuant to the direction of the President, shall not provide direct or indirect financial support to the country of Argentina under funds designated for such purpose under section 5302 of title 31, United States Code.</text> </section> 
<section id="H657DF2FB481C4993B83C9CE3000EFA7B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Small and medium sized manufacturers tariff relief</header> 
<subsection id="HFC692EB2439D49E3AFA9ADB8C57CA177">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
 <text>Of funds made available to carry out section 5302 of title 31, United States Code, the Secretary shall establish a financial relief program for eligible manufacturers to offset negative financial impacts related to any tariffs applied by the President on foreign imports between January 20, 2025 to January 20, 2029.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HEBA39A20A2B14BB0BF9445E763B298BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disbursement</header> 
<paragraph id="H35AE9B497B3B4DBC948EACA0BEC18F38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an appropriate administrative process for eligible manufacturers to submit an application and to receive financial support described in subsection (a). The Secretary may issue any guidance or regulation necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD707355498414C65A777C9C906EFBA47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The application submitted by small and medium sized manufacturers required by the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H59C8115E3BA645658CAE1FF7EF97BEF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the good produced by the eligible manufacturer in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1247E0D43385475C80F60BDE97AE710C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of any foreign imports subject to a tariff that are production inputs of the good described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC97D32B258C48588C204C37878A99C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the negative financial impact experienced by the eligible manufacturer due to any tariff imposed by the President, including any tariff described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA54C682FB26649F2B5D6F8C88204F2DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relief amount</header><text>The Secretary shall provide direct or indirect financial support in an amount equal to the financial harm imposed by any applicable tariff experienced by an eligible manufacturer described in the application submitted pursuant to paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B673651E6F74305B049DE68385F3E92"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorizations</header><text>To carry out this section, the Secretary is authorized to provide no less than $20,000,000,000 in financial assistance to eligible manufacturers from any available funds available in the stabilization fund described in section 5302 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H567B06D27661452993511CB1B0650866"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph id="HB578B5E82E73455CA9495F4AD9651691"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible manufacturer</header><text>The term <quote>eligible manufacturer</quote> means a small and medium sized manufacturer domiciled in the United States that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB07BE3C4C9974142ACFEAC3BE881DE8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employs less than 500 individuals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E56D126EEA748D5B35F6432B6EC4645"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>sources at least 50 percent of any steel or aluminum inputs domestically; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD4E4156F94E84665A3E4C61D6BB722DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not source any production inputs from a foreign entity of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0F5B87785AF4DD3B2F04E4BF2765B93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

