<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H74E8A73DC4334AB9B08CD7714E71D0A7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6077 IH: Healthcare Education in AI Literacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6077</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to ensure that medical students, medical residents, and medical faculty receive education and training in the deployment of artificial intelligence in the medical profession, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H20EF60BCEE0C4DECB4E0E37346C59F1D" style="OLC"><section id="HEF30D14D1FFE44C89780A491988B4881" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healthcare Education in AI Literacy Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HEAL-AI Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H636EC83AFD964D9F92AA2610B0817F64"><enum>2.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence medical education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/293k">42 U.S.C. 293k et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC941EC6FBE3E4DA5A09F61B8F301E43D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subpart id="HAF66B525BB454C6BBDAC2290310A3D78"><enum>III</enum><header>Artificial intelligence medical education</header><section id="H1D51A23DEC794482819A011ACF1706DE"><enum>749C.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this subpart is to create a program of grants to be administered by the Health Resources and Services Administration for the education and training of medical students, medical residents, and medical faculty in the deployment of artificial intelligence in the medical profession.</text></section><section id="H1BDA5BE49B9347F192D62E4C1AC209F4"><enum>749D.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subpart:</text><paragraph id="HBDEE2F233E55485BA603AEAA27B0EACD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence or AI</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> or <term>AI</term> means, with respect to the medical profession, a machine-based system—</text><subparagraph id="HD08F35228F094EDB8D74BCB32D57374B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>capable of generating predictions, recommendations, or decisions that influence real medical profession environments, as aligned with a set of objectives defined by humans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBFC1CC564CF48D5939058A82C549216"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that employs inputs derived from both machine and human sources to perceive and process data from real or virtual environments to provide information or facilitate actions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D8664923F3E4EB09E5A368F8C283B75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Education and training</header><text>The term <term>education and training</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HDA90709308784DF89811174FF7C509BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means, with respect to the medical profession, competency-based medical education and training for skill-building and decisionmaking to improve health outcomes and patient care; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE3A0EB8D5C14D859CB361CDF919D4DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text><clause id="HDBD914B3F30D457394455F4C9AD0F823"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use of data and data analysis;</text></clause><clause id="H1DEA10E4D9794F8A96C77C0D29CA0F20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>training such as virtual simulation and case studies; and</text></clause><clause id="H8C02105825594E209BAC67FCC8942041"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>student assessment to provide—</text><subclause id="H2EB11CC39A374EC099DE8A1912D3E946"><enum>(I)</enum><text>feedback and personalize learning; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H46EA736EB9CC4CC78D45B35B0C3C9B41"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the latest updates to health care.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B4E4FA2776548DD97594810D2EEEE0E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Medical resident</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>medical resident</term> means a graduate from an accredited medical school who is participating in a postgraduate medical residency training program at a residency sponsoring institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H152232AA8EAD49F9B9411E3999B5176E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Medical student</header><text>The term <term>medical student</term> means a student who attends a qualified medical school.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32115753962A4806968B377EDE0E31DD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified medical school</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified medical school</term> means an accredited school of medicine or accredited school of osteopathic medicine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB503246930644FC8A4450DAF22D87153" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Residency sponsoring institution</header><text>The term <term>residency sponsoring institution</term> means an institution that sponsors a postgraduate medical residency training program accredited by the Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA7358C6071B41BB957E50FB9C9B3A22"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H10199D9837C0493CB1F6B8090AF81B19"><enum>749E.</enum><header>Grant program to support artificial intelligence literacy for medical students, residents, and faculty</header><subsection id="H12BECB0297A94FA49A3DF477049AA407"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and carry out a program under which the Secretary makes grants, on a competitive basis, to qualified medical schools or residency sponsoring institutions for the education and training of medical students, medical residents, and medical faculty of such schools or institutions in the deployment of artificial intelligence in the medical profession.</text></subsection><subsection id="H56622BA0C4884F968C28D0014540E001"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><paragraph id="H513D5A961C734053B61E6067CA1C79A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a qualified medical school or residency sponsoring institution shall include in the application submitted under section 796, in addition to any information required by such section—</text><subparagraph id="HD3D80E4DE21D41C7989617DBE942D560"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the desired grant amount, not to exceed $100,000; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76CA59A73BDC47669BA919F0D58547CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the assurances described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1B0CDCA1EE745F18C81291DC72E9D0A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required assurances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assurances described in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H4A8CFBC06EE5499DAAB960653D4D06F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assurance that the school or institution will comply with the reporting requirements under section 749F.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD749C22872EB4AB5A553948FAF4EF794"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assurance that the school or institution will provide a description of the need for medical students, medical residents, or medical faculty of such school or institution, as appropriate, to become literate in artificial intelligence and to indicate how the grant would facilitate—</text><clause id="H8D92065B2C244099934A7720419FC27B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>bringing interdisciplinary expertise to the development and provision of the AI curriculum;</text></clause><clause id="H9580F7422D734A1986E82D6FB6E27015"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>completing formal program evaluation regarding effectiveness of the local implementation of AI; and</text></clause><clause id="H65FF03FD76B548B48C5E36ABBB41032C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sharing tools and learning with the broader education community to support relationship building and continued education within the medical education community.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A8A7DA5B4C54725A7FAB7E369BDCE9D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="H903464762F7F427DAC6EB2CABA2A70CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this section may only be used for the education and training of medical students, medical residents, and medical faculty in the deployment of artificial intelligence to understand the immediate effectiveness of training in competencies of the technology, including—</text><subparagraph id="H4CE6A066F49F4427B0FA55F8F9F06C49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>utilizing AI for medical diagnostics, treatment recommendations, and predictive analytics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15D43E5AF4AE4C72BED19DB0FEFF813B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integrating AI tools into clinical support and decision-making processes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4436E1A526A4BF88B4EB55CC2409C03"><enum>(C)</enum><text>understanding the ethical implications of AI in health care, such as bias, patient data privacy, and algorithm transparency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DBDDE5756A8463BAE2D7EA0CB4EFDA7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>studying the impact of artificial intelligence in medical ethics use cases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H177206AEA48F45CD8A07D84CF881B326"><enum>(E)</enum><text>conducting practical educational demonstrations or laboratories to exhibit the variety of use cases artificial intelligence may be deployed in a health profession field.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB95748414E740BBB74859A5EB22088B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on use for administrative costs</header><text>Not more than 10 percent of the amount of a grant under this section may be used for administrative costs, including the preparation of the annual reports required under section 749F.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7101E1B5AC4D4BC0A2F875E5F6DB0BB1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on publishing in predatory journals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this section may not be used to support the publication of any piece in a predatory journal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77BD707E4200481E961F3C4EAEA9004A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>A qualified medical school or residency sponsoring institution that receives a grant under this section may apply for renewal of such grant for one or more additional grant periods.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDAC4F29E1CFA475A8960D7C028780BC1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Access; Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H5BBF11005B4B4EA0BDB63E44C721159F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote access to emerging technologies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CA0D9E7A85F4FD999AAB58910B1F0D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">give priority to schools or institutions that provide care to medically underserved communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA4340A6AC6E4D169D5ADBB049F4AC28"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Collaborating with outside entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the activities described in subsection (c)(1), a qualified medical school or residency sponsoring institution may—</text><paragraph id="H468DB2B0EA734FB2B32E225BAFF48643"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborate with academic, nonprofit, and government entities, including other educational departments within the university or college of the qualified medical school, such as departments of computer science, computer engineering, software engineering, data science, computer programming, scientific computing, or any other related field as the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2CFC6072D4B413D94213F9234954AAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with—</text><subparagraph id="H2A3D9466B7674B63AC5FD7DAC182F4B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any of the academic, nonprofit, or government entities described in paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H960323E658774321B8D1E98CA05549E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a for-profit entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0D4FADC95F54D54A9F7831C6237AF02"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Geographic diversity</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall ensure that, to the extent practicable, grants are distributed among qualified medical schools and residency sponsoring institutions that serve geographically diverse areas, including urban, suburban, and rural areas across the United States. The Secretary may award grants under this section to not more than two qualified medical schools or residency sponsoring institutions located within the same 2020 United States Census Division.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE44E35E78250425D9D0E039E86C6ECBE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Yearly funding limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualified medical school or residency sponsoring institution may not receive more than $100,000 in funding under this section in any fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4F4084CB4B39450A867959FC285A6BA8"><enum>749F.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><subsection id="H8545636DD73B4A2B91FFD0B33D2DA925"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after receiving a grant under section 749E, and annually thereafter for the duration of the grant period, a qualified medical school or residency sponsoring institution that receives such grant shall submit to the Secretary a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="HAC6536B0C09D4F0A854C64EB8C279269"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the educational program goals and objectives and related evidence to support academic progress or advancements made under such grant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D80A2C164CF47B7980942A6C76F5ECE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of grant funds expended by such school or institution for artificial intelligence education and training;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EE97017BFB34D8DA703DF0685AB3CD6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how education and training was integrated into existing curricula, or used to create new curricula including the strategy, approach, and methods to begin development of the resources or curricula;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02FB8C0D81424D10A66E93AF08998A46"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of learners that enrolled in and successfully completed at least one course funded by such grant, to become knowledgeable in artificial intelligence literacy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE266DC94AAE547EE8DA16F802F7F02A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a list of any entity with which the school or institution collaborated or consulted under section 749E(f).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD24A94D28C249DFAA4486E8D036C5FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To make educational material publicly available</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after submitting a report under subsection (a), the qualified medical school or residency sponsoring institution submitting such report shall make publicly available any educational materials funded by the grant with respect to which such report was submitted—</text><paragraph id="H4BC7CB3D150D41D4AE482F97D9E5E088"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the website of the school or institution; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H232DD178432E417EB0439F8BEF227FE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on an online academic research portal.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC772F1DB22374793B96BA801E2A31B5B"><enum>749G.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subpart $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

