<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG26640-35S-D6-98G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4341 IS: Faster Department of Veterans Affairs Construction Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4341</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260416" legis-day="20260414">April 16 (legislative day, April 14), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to use commercial codes and standards instead of or in addition to Federal codes and standards in the construction or alteration of facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Faster Department of Veterans Affairs Construction Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id387a54e25a264b8e8a6a6506221292c9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs use of commercial construction and facilities code and standards</header><subsection id="idb91938ec58074077992e117a8a8e1d89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall use commercial codes and standards instead of or in addition to Federal codes and standards in the construction or alteration of facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, where such commercial codes and standards do not conflict with statutory and regulatory requirements.</text></subsection><subsection id="idabf2e36083fb47d0a880b938811acd86"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot projects</header><text>The Secretary shall undertake not fewer than three pilot projects during each of fiscal years 2027, 2028, 2029, 2030, and 2031 utilizing commercial codes and standards instead of Federal codes and standards to lease or construct facilities of the Department for major construction, minor construction, or major lease projects.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8f1c8b436cea48c18742a3e2d61bac7b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives not later than 90 days after the end of each of fiscal years 2027, 2028, 2029, 2030, and 2031 detailing the use by the Secretary of the authority provided by subsection (a) and conduct of each pilot project required by subsection (b) that was initiated, ongoing, or completed during the fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb29430e10e094d1bb800bf0a5969eda9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idf66eda2c6809434e9f8c0c51f6bf0c15"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commercial codes and standards</header><text>The term <term>commercial codes and standards</term> means building codes or standards of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id5529168219e84737b62fa0d590f3a0cf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The National Fire Protection Association.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60575cd47abd46f1bd519a08e3d53372"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The International Code Council.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb91535c28d3149d2a4a2091fa6e2be4d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The American Society for Testing and Materials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1c6cda4e28744468bd31dff04f9c210f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The American Society of Civil Engineers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad6f564df6c54946b85430999889095f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other building code or standard, other than those described in paragraph (2), determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id259738dea0264df09f9654bc79cd50e9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal codes and standards</header><text>The term <term>Federal codes and standards</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="id8a7f1ef92a6c466daba2ffa84001c0ab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Building codes or standards specific to one or more Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f5896a46ccb4ef8b96ea6f36cc05691"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Building codes or standards specific to the Department, including the Technical Information Library.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id939309a6f3b142509f93a68994efde20"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Standards of the Federal Guidelines Institute.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

