<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2EEBAA2EC732464E992438BB4CB165BE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6618 IH: Wildfire Aerial Response Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6618</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to conduct a study on drone incursions on wildfire suppression, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE1E6655ECF074446B754892312DF4F76" style="OLC"><section id="H5DC98432C29C4EBB8CF54DF2414F7B14" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Aerial Response Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEBDD758B3B2E44359CDEDE04A6DD363D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on drone incursions on wildfire suppression</header><subsection id="HBB03287BB19D45C2BA244ABA12E95688"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE0D721BBA80945C5BB9B07A7EB38E210"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Drone</header><text>The term <term>drone</term> means an unmanned aircraft system owned by a private individual or entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5D87102C8904DDCBBB6DC292A44C9EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Drone incursion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>drone incursion</term> means the operation of a drone within any airspace for which the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration has issued a temporary flight restriction because of a wildfire.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9033BAFCD9AB4820A328A3B84C3D849D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>unmanned aircraft system</quote> means an unmanned aircraft and associated elements (including, if applicable, communication links and the components that control the unmanned aircraft) that are required for the operator to operate safely and efficiently.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23944CC70ABB48E1B0BB171E000637F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall conduct a study on the effects of drone incursions on wildfire suppression with respect to land managed by the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9125DD22C220488798F49610666D20F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Study contents</header><text>In conducting the study required under subsection (b), the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H0595DB594ECB49448D8DFCB11FBFA4B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine, for each of the 5 most recent calendar years—</text><subparagraph id="H94319D563BA7465BBC6830CC9B690C2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of occurrences in which a drone incursion interfered with wildfire suppression; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C8D3E5B0DC847A3B18DF50AD5CA9F23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the estimated effect of each occurrence described in subparagraph (A) on—</text><clause id="HE48B6420934845859F214DE6E07E6AAD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the length of time required to achieve complete suppression;</text></clause><clause id="H1821C68C46814966BC17C79897DD8B22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any associated delay in the fielding of aerial firefighting response units; and</text></clause><clause id="H1C72C2E202814D93BD9D6236F06EC613"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amounts expended by the Federal Government; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8CA2F6BFD5F4B8C804DEB0920E6F07A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate the feasibility and effectiveness of various actions to prevent drone incursions, including—</text><subparagraph id="H58F25E5E971D46E09E404814296D7E89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of counter-drone radio towers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AB284F915EB4FD6B3F622A451DDBF9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of reasonable force to disable, damage, or destroy a drone;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3309ED6F7EE8428D9528454B2C72A7FE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the seizure of a drone, including seizure with a net device; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6F36B70B75642C795985BC760A5BBCA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the dissemination of educational materials relating to the effects of drone incursions on wildfire suppression.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2649A1E7A893467BA84C5A59A575BC33"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report describing—</text><paragraph id="H4CF85F99F2B24FDF83E1A5D51BC35880"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the study required under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA75AA7996B29423680B0D9435D61CA65"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendations relating to those findings.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

