<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H8B6C04EECC7842459FC6CA8D66D9C59D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7618 RH: American Battlefield Protection Program Amendments Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 578</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7618</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–664]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 20, 2026</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 54, United States Code, to modify certain cost-sharing requirements for grant programs under the American Battlefield Protection Program, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H8C6109C1CFAB4B47919156C1416B9E92"><section id="HB013FE8FF1C140208393C52496A718C6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Battlefield Protection Program Amendments Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H711253B6B62E4ED1ACC61F4099C82B1C"><enum>2.</enum><header>American battlefield protection program grant programs</header><subsection id="HDF84C253086D49549EF6E033635E8261"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reauthorization of battlefield acquisition grant program</header><text>Section 308103(f) of title 54, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>2028</quote> and inserting <quote>2036</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H97B97B72479D43BA97DB3B11C65AD121"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Battlefield interpretation modernization grant program</header><text>Section 308104 of title 54, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="H98D9DA6639724DC9AC3F4A3515233144"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Battlefield restoration grant program</header><text>Section 308105 of title 54, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (e) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H26E2FCF1F8374B42B8C9D2369CE7605E" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="HEEABF0D0AD22481B90DFE520626166E4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to provide grants under section 308104 and this section $2,000,000 for each fiscal year through fiscal year 2036.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HE10338A2635A46A6B1C5C836709034B3"><enum>3.</enum><header>French and Indian war and Mexican-American War sites studies</header><subsection id="H0853889C09C44D6CAFC52E796FA01EDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations made in advance for such purpose, the Secretary of the Interior (acting through the Director of the National Park Service) (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall prepare or certify, pursuant to subsection (b), studies of sites and structures located in the United States that are thematically tied with nationally significant events that occurred during—</text><paragraph id="H1F6F14A8D649433DB391A6F7389759D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the French and Indian War from 1754–1763; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F68E536CDED463A9A64F968B7709569"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Mexican-American War from 1846–1848.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13C18EF1EF9B49A9A45EF7E0ED0F7017"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preparation</header><paragraph id="H54783E79A95E4FDA9AA30258BE0B647E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The studies under subsection (a) may be carried out—</text><subparagraph id="HAAB43F7F4F8246618D3DA92BB0481E31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by the Secretary, in consultation with affected States, Indian Tribes, local governments, the American Battlefield Trust, historic preservation organizations, and any other interested individuals or entities, as determined by the Secretary; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13E35058B2B4460D8E46C408B479B531"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by interested individuals or entities, if the Secretary certifies that the completed study meets the requirements of subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98BBCA52ADFC4240826DD481C41B8058"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Not later than 1 year after receiving a study carried out by interested individuals or entities under subsection (b)(1)(B), the Secretary shall review and certify whether the study meets the requirements of subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA755B19CC1A1436B9D2E2C15F0277D09"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The studies prepared under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="HD76FADEF5D25439C9E339F000D52259F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify French and Indian War and Mexican-American War sites, respectively, located within the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F11A51C6DFF4008854E833D302B30DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the relative significance of the identified sites;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H677AB419B796453D9EEAE4BCD9463360"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess short- and long-term threats to the integrity of the identified sites; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14EFEDCA40DC4B92A9523A5418141AA4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide alternatives for the preservation and interpretation of the identified sites by the Federal Government, State, local, and Tribal governments, or other public or private entities, including potential designation of the identified sites as units of the National Park System, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA56879B4F87B42059EEC4C130004A038"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration of previous studies and reports</header><text>In preparing the studies under subsection (b)(1), the Secretary shall consider and may include information from previous studies and reports relating to French and Indian War or Mexican-American War historic sites prepared by the National Park Service, the American Battlefield Trust, or other historic preservation organizations, as appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA4045DEDDD0D4E5AB0C69DF2BEC1ADF9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><paragraph id="H5C3B429C258B4090AEFFD58867B3491F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Studies carried out by the secretary</header><text>With respect to studies carried out by the Secretary in accordance with subsection (b)(1)(A), the Secretary shall submit such studies to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate not later than 2 years after the date on which funds are made available to carry out such studies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H260F62996F2B4F248F6C8F0EBE74E5F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Studies carried out by other interested parties</header><text>With respect to studies carried out by interested individuals or entities in accordance with subsection (b)(1)(B), the Secretary shall submit such studies to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary certifies under subsection (b)(2) that the studies meet the requirements of subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

