<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RYA26387-6S7-0F-39J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>112 S4469 IS: Prediction Market Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4469</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Commodity Exchange Act to modify provisions relating to event contracts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prediction Market Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id616bb15daa2c4a8a80d54b10565286ba"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special rules relating to event contracts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5c of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7a-2">7 U.S.C. 7a–2</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id17f688d9d713401e8414c525265caf76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(5)(C)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9951f69c6668404fac5e7d9b9a4c35bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subparagraph">event contracts and</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69a5dd8108724a89bf2b7071ee1640ff"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking clauses (i), (ii), and (iv);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78f0faff6d414cc9ae7803b39e47cb10"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the clause designation and heading and all that follows through <quote>In connection</quote> in subclause (I) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1629681547b344f7ad6b9852b4a6494a"><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2b1d2cd0e924cc083bee3a612a4adde"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In connection</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5557bb960907483c91d70203e7d59c25"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating subclause (II) as clause (ii) and indenting appropriately; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id541a4dd62d364ba68af23e3cf4fb4ce8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in clause (ii) (as so redesignated), by redesignating items (aa) and (bb) as subclauses (I) and (II), respectively, and indenting appropriately; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3779187526e4ae9b528d1a0e458ff75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id938fe949640e47a7b0531307ab54a6f7"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78ae7f983efd4cda8c9859dfe3c03031"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rules relating to event contracts</header><paragraph id="id4306a536af394d0c9f89a13c59b9288b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="idb509d83b93a04a5e8a96c05660c65647"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Contingency</header><text>The term <term>contingency</term> means an event or circumstance that may happen, but is not certain to occur, including the outcome of another event or circumstance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c388212aa5a4dcdb32abc774ee342e3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Event contract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>event contract</term> means a contract for the sale of a commodity for future delivery, option on such a contract, or swap based on one or more excluded commodities that is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb24c12dcaeb04a349e32ffbdad871873"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based upon an occurrence, extent of an occurrence, or contingency (other than a change in the price, rate, value, or levels of a commodity described in section 1a(19)(i)); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a1acee8b17e489db71cd733bc63b5a4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">listed by a designated contract market or swap execution facility.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5c0fd2dfcb34800aeb2572c77cff88c"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Occurrence</header><text>The term <term>occurrence</term> means something that happens, such as an event, including the outcome of another event.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b67c84209124668910979b752d34c5e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review or approval of event contracts</header><subparagraph id="idc7ba7321b9e3463f81b27c3fd6cf9372"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In connection with the listing of event contracts by a designated contract market or swap execution facility, the Commission, on a case-by-case basis, may determine that an event contract is contrary to the public interest if the event contract is based on an occurrence, extent of an occurrence, or contingency involving—</text><clause id="idb089771c8f9c423d8f4aa413cecac044"><enum>(i)</enum><text>activity that is unlawful under any Federal or State law;</text></clause><clause id="idca358236799d4feca89423cc570b2c1e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>terrorism;</text></clause><clause id="id9eacc5cf92964d64a3d03938e7f4d90d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assassination;</text></clause><clause id="ide67477253a2740a1b890e302b277bf4e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>war;</text></clause><clause id="id8c7b7c406ef2470496a632420bd59a1d"><enum>(v)</enum><text>violence;</text></clause><clause id="idb45d81a3575549e992c18f9c03213a96"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>gaming; or</text></clause><clause id="idcdba93134f6f4473aa8d4dec59886e3c"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>other similar activity determined by the Commission to be contrary to the public interest.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2630d4d13014d4ea6627acd10fc53a0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No event contract determined by the Commission to be contrary to the public interest under subparagraph (A) may be listed or made available for clearing or trading on or through a registered entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id12c53fbe79434d209e687106bab376e1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public interest criteria</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id935f9603e3ec43909d9304db85e70a44"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall promulgate such rules and regulations as the Commission determines appropriate to specify the criteria for determining that event contracts based on the activities described in clauses (i) through (vii) of subparagraph (A) are contrary to the public interest.</text></clause><clause id="id0c446ea6895a4c99841e7ec814198788"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Public interest</header><text>In the rules and regulations promulgated under clause (i), the Commission shall provide that an event contract is likely to be contrary to the public interest if the event contract materially encourages violence or similar unlawful activity.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4dc93589702f473c923e73d2fdc47459"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>In promulgating rules and regulations under clause (i), the Commission shall provide not less than a 60-day public comment period.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0067506bb3f54a8baf77e82eeed969e6"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Enhanced certification</header><clause id="id597c6927bea44d06b3fcd0f475a7f9c6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Format of submissions</header><text>The Commission shall prescribe by rule or regulation standardized requirements, as determined by the Commission, in addition to the requirements of subsection (c), for the format of written certifications of designated contract markets and swap execution facilities for new event contracts pursuant to subsection (c)(1) and for voluntary requests for prior approval for new event contracts pursuant to subsection (c)(4).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida653b82eee2e485299a8f35ce56b1ed9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Disclosure requirements</header><text>The Commission shall prescribe by rule or regulation disclosure requirements relating to the material terms and conditions of event contracts that are reasonably designed to promote retail customer readability.</text></clause><clause id="idb74168f6dab9438e8694e328395ba00c"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Financial penalty</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f51f2df7cd64b51ab805d311d95564b"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may prescribe by rule or regulation a financial penalty for a violation of clause (i).</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida68c7054909a47a5b16d054582cb974e"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining the amount of a financial penalty assessed under subclause (I), the Commission shall consider—</text><item id="idb54342144f4c4fb6a79d573907e6aa4e"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the gravity of the violation; and</text></item><item id="id970ad3a70e8948768286370ed589aab7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>similar previous violations committed by the designated contract market or swap execution facility.</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc826dfaa9c3f4593aabb8cc93ed288af"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commission prescribes a financial penalty under subclause (I), the Commission shall establish a procedure for appealing such penalties, including in Federal courts.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7339dc48153d4fbd82152a44e56b98d1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Communications with the public</header><subparagraph id="id10a56ef1c3294cb0b6085ebc153729e8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In connection with the offer of an event contract to a person that is not an eligible contract participant, a derivatives clearing organization shall not use any promotional material that—</text><clause id="id600457dd075447c49e1b307efcbad459"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is likely to deceive the public;</text></clause><clause id="id4ae89bf0701544f1b0006b846871da4e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contains any material misstatement or omission that makes the promotional material misleading;</text></clause><clause id="id2fa09fb674ce45aba591dcc1c72c1c14"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>mentions the possibility of profit unless accompanied by an equally prominent discussion of the risk of loss;</text></clause><clause id="id739b31db1cc842c48b703cba7ad7aab4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>includes any reference to actual past trading profits without mentioning that past results are not necessarily indicative of future results;</text></clause><clause id="id3b4eab979d904b93b3442d2d7faa3aaa"><enum>(v)</enum><text>includes any specific numerical or statistical information about the past performance of any actual account, unless permitted by the Commission by rule or regulation; or</text></clause><clause id="id2e74ff343ec14e1eb39c1c46eea019c0"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>includes a testimonial that—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide30ad0b29fae4565bb00336fbc6091a3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not representative of all reasonably comparable investors;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id676bfc2b78ee4bab81b3df3b87904d04"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not prominently state that the testimonial is not indicative of future performance or success; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04e45f1049b74309869b93ca6669d18e"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if applicable, does not prominently state that it is a paid testimonial.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6bb4dcd4f6e5457895277f1983b4dd5e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Commission shall promulgate such rules or regulations as the Commission determines to be appropriate to carry out subparagraph (A), consistent with applicable standards for futures commission merchants, including—</text><clause id="ide1000d7fc95c4a07927e2c3b3d878953"><enum>(i)</enum><text>relating to records to be made available for examination by the Commission; and</text></clause><clause id="idaa291b14f9514d8e8da67c2616951425" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>applicable disciplinary actions or penalties for noncompliance with this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id51244666d4e24fed93c0f16b7fd52008"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Know your customer application</header><subparagraph id="id898eff9eef0946c29aebaf8f9511519e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Anti-money laundering compliance program</header><text>In connection with the offer of an event contract to a person that is not an eligible contract participant, a derivatives clearing organization shall have an anti-money laundering compliance program in place in accordance with section 5318(h) of title 31, United States Code, which shall include—</text><clause id="idbb2463cd498e424889672d033f0ce542"><enum>(i)</enum><text>internal policies, procedures, and controls reasonably designed to achieve compliance with subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, and chapter 2 of title I of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/508">Public Law 91–508</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1951">12 U.S.C. 1951 et seq.</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>Bank Secrecy Act</quote>) (including regulations promulgated under that subchapter and chapter);</text></clause><clause id="id081f1ca1a0704f1fb3dcda483a3516d1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appointment of one or more individuals responsible for implementing and monitoring the program's day-to-day operations;</text></clause><clause id="id232f7bf7e307499d8a04f81dc8db2666"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an ongoing training program;</text></clause><clause id="id95780ee57b654314aea9e5eed0075392"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>independent testing;</text></clause><clause id="id73454ce462234eb29faf30f4f4e0c37e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>appropriate risk-based procedures for conducting customer due diligence, including—</text><subclause id="id08de335a42e84f428d532494bb0c9e0f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>understanding the nature and the purpose of developing a customer risk profile; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ida54eb383b99841c0945f1888a0897ea8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>conducting ongoing monitoring to detect and report suspicious transactions and on a risk basis to maintain and update customer information, including identifying and verifying beneficial owners; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id1cd204c2acdf448387b46292ec0bab00"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>appropriate procedures to verify that individual customers have attained the age of 18 years.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa9695b7bab146dc8482827eddf62ef9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Commission shall promulgate such rules or regulations, with consideration of the application of the applicable core principles described in this Act, as the Commission determines to be appropriate to carry out subparagraph (A), including—</text><clause id="id02f2628b75ec4c3ba4dcd1fbe20e2295"><enum>(i)</enum><text>relating to records to be made available for examination by the Commission; and</text></clause><clause id="id0283f56ea4394964a422a9ff3a392b2a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>applicable disciplinary actions or penalties for noncompliance with this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id675168bde53a4492a3b38738c23d8aba"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Funds</header><subparagraph id="id323b115a9e86447aa7e8480fbdfc92fd"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Segregation required</header><text>In connection with the offer of an event contract to a person that is not an eligible contract participant and accessing a derivatives clearing organization as a direct clearing member, the Commission shall promulgate such rules or regulations as the Commission determines to be appropriate regarding the segregation of member funds from the derivatives clearing organization’s own funds.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0b45189dda4042d9b9b9bb4d9bd1f756"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Customer communication</header><text>A futures commission merchant, designated contract market, or swap execution facility shall disclose to event contract customers the relevant risks of loss or potential delay in access to the funds and assets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd11812064b4476e866e3abcfe24bce8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Default fund</header><text>For default management purposes, a derivatives clearing organization shall treat funds held for members and customers solely trading fully collateralized contracts separately from funds held for members and customers trading leveraged contracts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id90a1c062213a430381cd2b2094c3f68c"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Commission shall promulgate such rules or regulations as the Commission determines to be appropriate to carry out subparagraphs (B) and (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa9e52742e1e41799cca6fcbca7441d7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Advisory Council on Consumer Protection</header><subparagraph id="id210da00329c34faba414939046c8383f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Prediction Market Act of 2026</short-title>, the Chairman of the Commission shall establish the Advisory Council on Consumer Protection (referred to in this paragraph as the <term>Advisory Council</term>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f922f3576e04158ac75ebd71671a099"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Chair and Vice-Chair</header><text>The Chairman of the Commission shall appoint a Chair and Vice-Chair of the Advisory Council from among the members of the Advisory Council.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddb42422dfdda42d8b1078b827fab7f50"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mission</header><text>The mission of the Advisory Council shall be—</text><clause id="ide7a5bb3465524b18ae98b26221127ec9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to provide a forum for regular communication and analysis related to retail investor participation in derivatives markets;</text></clause><clause id="idf705fb9474084a5fb474ce46095ef308"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to encourage discussions relating to consumer protection regarding event contract markets and related markets; and</text></clause><clause id="id9ec37bd228fe4714a3462db47224853f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to develop recommendations to ensure that markets promote customer protection, market integrity, and responsible participation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee39cdf265ab4632a4a8c6a47620e75c"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Advisory Council shall be composed of 15 members, who shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Commission and shall include—</text><clause id="id1ee6aef428fe42feaa7aeda20804dba9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Retail Advocate described in paragraph (7)(C);</text></clause><clause id="id04e312bbc2d84bc4bb4d8b6cf7a4f795"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not fewer than 3 State attorneys general;</text></clause><clause id="id15cf6e9bfb144f129fb6cb2c29bd81a7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>subject matter experts in behavioral science and health, financial risk, and consumer finance; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b9a2eba66ec4250923dc45c94733028"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives of—</text><subclause id="idda421f1fa1ce4e16af25d0b2ce8b166d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Office of Customer Education and Outreach;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd4186e6d95d2423aa514075757cf1163"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text></subclause><subclause id="id158ac5babb464978b23eaca684459f08"><enum>(III)</enum><text>State and local law enforcement;</text></subclause><subclause id="idc1e4b1cff3ba40eb97bdc34885e1a239"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>State and local regulatory agencies, as appropriate;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6b8878da14b043d1bf893184f13cfd61"><enum>(V)</enum><text>market operators; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idc63060d735684893ad152ba85ff123c6"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>market participants.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9562e17fb6c1401e9fcd8deb3e032e61"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Advisory Council shall include—</text><clause id="id9c62d124b34147c1a1746d3f189dc06f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meeting not less frequently than once every 120 days, in a manner to be determined by the Chairman of the Commission, to provide independent advice and recommendations to the Commission and Congress;</text></clause><clause id="id6f0c0221864b4c8bafed303ff98c062f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifying policies to promote retail customer protection and specific gaps in investor protections for retail customers;</text></clause><clause id="ide813a44408324ddaaa717fd50af89011"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assessing the viability of a self-exclusion program, which would allow a customer to be voluntarily prohibited from entering into an event contract;</text></clause><clause id="id63647ceb909f4255a5762b89d4d986cf"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>assessing the viability of a program to implement voluntary deposit and trade limits;</text></clause><clause id="id6d0094349e4144afbd5c5509ea4f95e5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>reviewing the considerations of the retail customer profile, including age, income, and behavioral vulnerabilities, when assessing investor protection;</text></clause><clause id="id87bbcffef56a4a22976e8bc4f6835d01"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>studying behavioral prompts and marketing features designed to engage customers in connection with the offer of an event contract;</text></clause><clause id="idc5185719fc6a40bbbcf6e92e442675d8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>reviewing the effectiveness of existing legal or regulatory recommendations to improve customer protections in connection with the offer of an event contract; and</text></clause><clause id="id5f639dbfc28e4fb9bfdb180ad5ae17ce"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>evaluating the design, accessibility, and use of mobile applications, smartphones, and other personal electronic devices in connection with the offer of event contracts.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98a27c1500644aa09166082d3a5cae16"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Advisory Council shall—</text><clause id="id11fd87a1ca7f49c9a35b418f5d9ff552"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Prediction Market Act of 2026</short-title>, submit to Congress an initial report with analysis and recommendations regarding matters studied under subparagraph (E), which shall include consumer protection, market integrity, investor profile, marketing features, and other related topics; and</text></clause><clause id="id887a44316da74e749cb15109fffb8945"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>twice each year thereafter, submit to Congress a report containing findings, and recommendations for legislation, regulations, and oversight, relating to the matters studied under subparagraph (E).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc24fa8b2be5f4890bac552350f008a66"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Review by Commission</header><text>The Commission shall—</text><clause id="idc6e8435338bc4740a4f239f9fbffa28e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review the findings and recommendations of the Advisory Council; and</text></clause><clause id="ide32ced5f74e5419dbf78f677c128a140"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make publicly available a report containing an assessment by the Commission of any findings and recommendations of the Advisory Council.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7061abf363b24cde9fe203e3d5673456"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Office of the Retail Advocate</header><subparagraph id="id4fa4e501a5ba4a79a8b7e80a767f8ce2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2fd8b1b60266402ebb81a3f2756564d0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Chairman</header><text>The term <term>Chairman</term> means the Chairman of the Commission.</text></clause><clause id="id38639fec2cd5448db27170ef42ca4f61"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of the Retail Advocate established by subparagraph (B).</text></clause><clause id="id4130fd242b2c4186a38b7ce5b12f84d9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Retail participant</header><text>The term <term>retail participant</term> means a person that—</text><subclause id="id1ef12aafec4f4e478c81306d0683bb49"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is not an eligible contract participant; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idd5f0c5e14aea4aae92f16d90033f5f98"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is participating in a designated contract market.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id434b6a0b97914fd285d3c001b6354690"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Office established</header><text>There is established within the Commission the Office of the Retail Advocate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9db6ea0e03134956bd45d94e6c00b8ac"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Retail Advocate</header><clause id="idc282945286bc4371b32574944f78af52"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Retail Advocate shall—</text><subclause id="id085dc59b2b9a402f851c6d59a54e5c2d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>report directly to the Commission; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id7e1065c94806444cbd745a556b5e5d38"><enum>(II)</enum><text>be appointed by the Chairman from among individuals with experience in advocating for the interests of retail participants.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idca94383d2c1f48e3acbd9ba6c8744f69"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The annual rate of pay for the Retail Advocate shall be equal to the highest rate of annual pay for other senior executives who report to the Chairman.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id734a1ead9ebe4ad88d35a4453a9074d8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Functions of the Retail Advocate</header><text>The Retail Advocate shall—</text><clause id="id8c8da9162a474b4f8c942b3203ca7635"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assist retail participants in resolving significant problems relating to transactions;</text></clause><clause id="id0e80bc5ff07c4edf860b32c6ec93e746"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>analyze the potential impact on retail participants of proposed regulations of the Commission;</text></clause><clause id="id1995d8822be34987a7ca6d7ac79a06af"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, propose to the Commission changes in the regulations or orders of the Commission that may be appropriate to promote the interests of retail participants;</text></clause><clause id="id9771b47ea4834512afb4286e3b0c072a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>conduct research to identify and understand issues that affect retail participants; and</text></clause><clause id="id1f4a06d098a6426b8f398de09bacbc9b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>operate with and provide assistance to the Office of Customer Education and Outreach to conduct initiatives and outreach for retail participants.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2fe397b40af40a28476e5512fa564a5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Access to documents</header><clause id="id6c887166c8bb4c9fa08ef20e7a04c3ba"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At the discretion of the Chairman, the Retail Advocate shall have full access to the documents of the Commission as necessary to carry out the functions of the Office.</text></clause><clause id="id8609410318dc4cad99fe0c3510eb0b40"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph authorizes the Retail Advocate, or staff of the Office, to have access to, or to release publicly or internally within the Commission, proprietary or sensitive market data, including data and information that would separately disclose the business transactions or market positions of any person and trade secrets or names of customers, consistent with section 8.</text></clause><clause id="idaff123547ac2408bba961fa009c43115"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Policies and procedures</header><text>The Office shall establish and make public on the website of the Commission policies and procedures to safeguard the confidentiality of any documents the Retail Advocate or staff of the Office has access to.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id783ac54563ba40a694dd2b2c479fec0e"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Annual report on objectives and activities</header><clause id="id1ecd90eff2e54f428becee4389b30ada"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than September 30 of each year, the Retail Advocate shall submit to Congress a report describing the objectives and activities of the Retail Advocate for the following fiscal year.</text></clause><clause id="id92a66aaa9ce644659f41293a422017cf"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required under clause (i) shall include—</text><subclause id="id2fcd93cd0692474198083af4a5e777ae"><enum>(I)</enum><text>appropriate statistical information and full and substantive analysis;</text></subclause><subclause id="id4741aa6079a64268bbbff5c7b801a1c3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>information on steps that the Retail Advocate has taken during the reporting period to improve—</text><item id="id967d151df0794f1aab5c2aa5cdb0844b"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>services to and communication with retail participants; and</text></item><item id="id797f09baf9d347efa24a29aef8aed563"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the responsiveness of the Commission;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id1d3e121b125f4afd8082c690a4e63386"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a summary of the most serious problems reported to the Office or the Commission by retail participants during the reporting period;</text></subclause><subclause id="idce33cd7aa4d4405eaa8f7caaefd58f6b"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an inventory of the items described in subclause (III) that includes—</text><item id="id1f8e335c209043079e8b63f8a01f3d6b"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>identification of any action taken by the Commission and the result of that action;</text></item><item id="idaaa39937df1945cab32166c9be15006d"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the period of time that each item has remained on the inventory; and</text></item><item id="idb46516ca7f9c4bd3bcbd7065e2dec2f4"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>for items with respect to which no action has been taken, the reasons for inaction, and an identification of any official who is responsible for the action;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idd6cfd378d1074c18b656f84ada77e1f6"><enum>(V)</enum><text>recommendations for such administrative and legislative actions as may be appropriate to resolve problems encountered by retail participants; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id7f830dad24f2411c88be9940ecbaf6d2"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>any other information, as determined appropriate by the Retail Advocate.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idf4136a4938e043b999a0e8e74bb7fda2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>No report required under clause (i) may contain confidential information.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d9d8f334b2a4ddca82026c4f3d01ca5"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Ombudsman</header><clause id="id7608896554e84b18b56a312ad98dc10f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the first Retail Advocate is appointed under subparagraph (C)(i)(II), the Retail Advocate shall appoint an Ombudsman, who shall report directly to the Retail Advocate.</text></clause><clause id="id3ab3f3e8958742a18dde891c84843e31"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Ombudsman appointed under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="id48cb3e23d31c45958c1e5602d43505e1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>act as a liaison between the Commission and any retail participant in resolving problems the retail participant may have with the Commission;</text></subclause><subclause id="id2ec0947776934e4bb902325a2e19a4fb"><enum>(II)</enum><text>review and make recommendations regarding policies and procedures to encourage persons to present questions to the Retail Advocate regarding compliance with this Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id3f0d870859374614bf93fd17310b281d"><enum>(III)</enum><text>establish safeguards to maintain the confidentiality of communications between the persons described in subclause (II) and the Ombudsman.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3b16f6621fcc4a29bef25d5b1d5ce6b0"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><subclause id="id6be45051d846434bb6377699f0f8e83e"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text>In carrying out the duties of the Ombudsman under clause (ii), the Ombudsman shall utilize personnel of the Commission, to the extent practicable.</text></subclause><subclause id="id4599525642e44137b08b3ddf8d13c952"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this clause shall be construed as replacing, altering, or diminishing the activities of any ombudsman or similar office of any other agency.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idbc7619439f9049108f87630d07bd6e59"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Report on activities</header><subclause id="id42eb8786b2664916af1b26c1a1f7cfdf"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Ombudsman shall submit to the Retail Advocate an annual report that describes the activities and evaluates the effectiveness of the Ombudsman during the preceding 1-year period.</text></subclause><subclause id="id682bf15ce49441c6a72127ecb867520d" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The Retail Advocate shall include the report required under subclause (I) in the reports required to be submitted by the Retail Advocate under subparagraph (F).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a17e835db394c01984f0351a32f8a25"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to affect—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3bc2540efe4149b2914a271079c5e65d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ability of a State to investigate and bring enforcement actions under this Act, including pursuant to section 6d; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44fdb7bfe2e44b739c93cc7b14a2b232"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the jurisdiction of the Commission described in section 2(a)(1)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="idd0972ba5fac640ddb9ea0dbdab5de6eb"><enum>3.</enum><header>Insider trading and manipulation</header><subsection id="id34ab91b35c314418886de80488322913"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on Members of Congress trading event contracts</header><text>Section 4c(a)(3) of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/6c">7 U.S.C. 6c(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id1ec0ff23f65e4413ae5d5ae43357d1f4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>under section 2 of the STOCK Act)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>in section 2 of the STOCK Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/13101">5 U.S.C. 13101</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/105">Public Law 112–105</external-xref>))</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99790227acbb42ed8e0535286a2187e7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (C) as clauses (i) through (iii), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb3178e52b814c338f3af8c85c0891e1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>It shall</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5230d20a824c491e8c9b09078a4ef5e0"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id566f56223a604a469fd26fffb909c7ab"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1f59c7816264923bd65bbca26c40b59"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb59b1cdbf9914c3e87493716ccbf22dc"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb275499ab6c9447a8034c9b0198f674d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition on Members of Congress and executive branch officials trading event contracts</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any Member of Congress (as defined in section 2 of the STOCK Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/13101">5 U.S.C. 13101</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/105">Public Law 112–105</external-xref>)), the President, the Vice President, or any officer or employee described in sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5, United States Code, to enter into an event contract (as defined in section 5c(d)(1)).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id87a2d10bf7e240b2a00b002ccbe70daa"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules or regulations</header><text>The Commodity Futures Trading Commission (referred to in this section as the <term>Commission</term>) shall promulgate such rules or regulations as the Commission determines to be appropriate to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="idf2bcce1a198147d89e25198c99999d2c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of insider trading</header><text>The Commission shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84d2f3b832c049598f8a6bf784e489d3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether the rules and regulations of the Commission relating to insider trading should be revised or updated to require designated contract markets, swap execution facilities, and futures commission merchants to establish enhanced measures reasonably designed to detect and deter insider trading involving event contracts (as defined in subsection (d)(1) of section 5c of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7a-2">7 U.S.C. 7a–2</external-xref>)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07c27e9292d04adba921ffbf3a2c36e8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement any relevant revisions or updates resulting from the determination under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id91b923811ada48cf80e87bb4ba69a42c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Financial literacy</header><text>The Commission shall conduct, through the Office of Customer Education and Outreach, financial literacy and customer education activities specific to retail investor activity related to event contracts (as defined in subsection (d)(1) of section 5c of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7a-2">7 U.S.C. 7a–2</external-xref>)).</text></subsection></section><section id="idd3882f4605744634a84e1d73fcfb08d5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Innovation Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(a) of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2">7 U.S.C. 2(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id625c65196aca4d5fa8e8801647b77c33"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2a2cf0f2ba04f6c9e42273ed1fd6495"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Innovation Advisory Committee</header><subparagraph id="id1101f6a94902463e8d4e96170d5914d8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established the Innovation Advisory Committee (referred to in this paragraph as the <term>Committee</term>)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ac7e7bc5e73488c9ec0de3321f26186"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to facilitate discussion and communication on matters of concern to exchanges, firms, end-users, and regulators regarding innovation in the derivatives and commodity market and the regulation of those markets by the Commission; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idadc28f4ce3024b6e87ca321bc370c96d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to advise the Commission on the matters described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0517ed0ed57c44b683cdf5b59acb465b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Commission shall appoint members to the Committee with a wide diversity of opinions relating to the matters described in subparagraph (A)(i) and who represent a broad spectrum of interests, including—</text><clause id="id45f0c673a897478db84161e50414f538"><enum>(i)</enum><text>market makers;</text></clause><clause id="id94814a340de4411a9c8cf3d996b16f53"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>derivative end-users;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96a042800eea445393044dcca098b6fe"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">futures commission merchants; and</text></clause><clause id="iddf90f848592d40a2853662a455192a1d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>market operators.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca95023929aa4d4ca6fbb840d4fdfd51"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The Committee shall—</text><clause id="id622bfa3baa364456b3feeba5c0eaab11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct public meetings at such intervals as are necessary to carry out the functions of the Committee, but not less frequently than 2 times per year;</text></clause><clause id="id90a4e79d3eaf4c9aa031337f192ae2d7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit reports and recommendations to the Commission; and</text></clause><clause id="id203245eed2084d59a5f6e0914848fefe"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise facilitate discussion and communication on the matters described in subparagraph (A)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59fe4be03d5b40d7a09dd4aa57edddc0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>Members of the Committee shall be appointed to 3-year terms, but may be removed for cause by vote of the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a5d81af105d44ee99642213e5910010" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Reimbursements</header><text>A member of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida45162556b8747b589ce0e01c4002dc1" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Chapter 10 of title 5, United States Code</header><text>The Committee shall not be subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2b7586f9b2c49628f8b6a86ad63be4e"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may terminate the Committee if the Commission determines that such termination is appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id71d623508064475eaf00143562c3f448"><enum>5.</enum><header>Studies</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e542e5960cf440ea4fff5925e06ea71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9210f861bfb40e182753f17ba1ccd37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Commodity Futures Trading Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7cdde20bb2a494f929955036784729c" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Event contract</header><text>The term <term>event contract</term> has the meaning given the term in subsection (d)(1) of section 5c of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7a-2">7 U.S.C. 7a–2</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id943715f453cf4c2e9df07fe56eb48789"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study on event contracts</header><paragraph id="idb41c96248c6d45e282549b275b6ddbca"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Commission shall conduct a study on event contracts that includes—</text><subparagraph id="idf83ba9901845420dbdb59a321a02557a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the size and structure of event contract markets;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id442a7cf8b4ba4970b465e6e8b717b70b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the growth of event contract listings by contract markets designated under the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1">7 U.S.C. 1 et seq.</external-xref>) and swap execution facilities (as defined in section 1a of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb398e62609bd4981b3ab844a8bbb1ad8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the characteristics of the market structure and liquidity formation in event contracts related to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8549fefd7bf47b4800fcaf17b711e2f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">weather;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69e3894b266149578d321f93d92b95bd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>technology;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6087623c3e9540a2b704ae73967bee0d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>science;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7fbb33bea99b434880deaddf66db2a50"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>economics;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id479fdd0b3bcb4d2ea7447d85fca3d75c"><enum>(v)</enum><text>government data;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03ff1963bc5d472bbb03badb776718d1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>cultural events;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3a60968ff884cb1a7a1a5906c14b487"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>political events;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id630494fff8a64102bfdc96eec5df5d97"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>sports; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3c3ea40222243d78a1e0e8ed7bf851f"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>a particular word or phrase to be potentially mentioned by one or more persons in an oral or written statement, speech, briefing, address, or other form of communication;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8cf7d139e7145158ecd61390777609e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the types of trader or intermediary conduct unique to event contracts and markets that should be closely monitored or given special consideration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf06b0f30da574e4fa267fd15659a6983"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the provisions of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1">7 U.S.C. 1 et seq.</external-xref>) that prohibit fraud, manipulation, disruptive trading, or other similar conduct and apply to activities outside the United States related to event contracts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4893e61b54c43d88cf857d58b3f5745"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to Congress and publish on a publicly available website of the Commission a report on the findings of the study required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7db59873d7434dc383179a926cbd1181"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Joint Securities and Exchange Commission and Commodity Futures Trading Commission study</header><paragraph id="id8a239ff6b2f1477f90c8ff06ddedd78d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Securities and Exchange Commission and the Commission shall conduct a joint study on event contracts that includes—</text><subparagraph id="idafc2fe5455424a8b9c39ffa6d041609e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the nature of event contracts that could be in the jurisdiction of the Securities and Exchange Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63aa0c9db686479e9f8642424bda336e"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the harmonization efforts of the Securities and Exchange Commission and the Commission relevant to event contracts; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ba1a1c177b649549bcc510083bf0f94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the nature, size, role, and use of decentralized blockchain applications to offer event contracts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide67af65c417b4aae82ce6693dc52a6cb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 15 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to Congress and publish on a publicly available website of the Commission a report on the findings of the study required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id1b926fcd83c5472888ed3d0194420e04"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations; funding for event contract oversight</header><subsection id="id6fc6818d415d4373a7d8d730502b0a52"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commodity Futures Trading Commission $30,000,000 for each fiscal year of 2027 through 2031, to remain available until expended, for the purposes of—</text>
                <paragraph id="id5d27fa8076d54a3faab83a4a9517f0f9">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>implementing this Act and the amendments made by this Act; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id601671c7636148329d83469577ebb73b"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>developing policies, rules, and guidance relating to event contracts.</text>
                </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="id56a1967919fb4dd4a8dc881823a530d8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts made available pursuant to subsection (a) may be used for—</text><paragraph id="id4dd40e5ec7be4187b0dd01f7d51d0e28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>oversight, supervision, and enforcement of event contract markets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id496dd558a2e94c32bc0da60894e0788e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>rulemakings, reviews, and determinations required under subsection (d) of section 5c of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7a-2">7 U.S.C. 7a–2</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id73aaf7e7bc4b4767aac38d064de533e2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the studies and reports required under section 5;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0429cfbe10f46cc9bdf99c4d3926cee"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the establishment and operation of the Office of the Retail Advocate under subsection (d)(6) of section 5c of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7a-2">7 U.S.C. 7a–2</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id85eda72b8fae43bfbd3986a42f522aa3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the development of technological, surveillance, and data analysis capabilities of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66379941e216488ba92382edfd382929"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of event contract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>event contract</term> has the meaning given the term in subsection (d)(1) of section 5c of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7a-2">7 U.S.C. 7a–2</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

