<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H651F39B69F8F457591D0856C6B6B97B1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6962 IH: Families First Housing Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6962</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen and standardize <quote>first look</quote> protections for covered properties to ensure families and communities have priority access to foreclosed homes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H943DC0378188441386542FF04E90EEA0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H79795527F3794D0FBBD37C8B4FD3F505" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Families First Housing Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFB3BA8F7A9E24CF5AE3BDFF86965528A"><enum>2.</enum><header>First look protections</header> <subsection id="H111C09611A064863AADE160F73760B4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered entity shall ensure, when selling an eligible property, that the eligible property is only available for purchase by qualified first look buyers during the 180 day period beginning on the date that the eligible property is listed for sale.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H221FB58CE1174453BB24F21E71DF5E2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pricing of eligible properties</header> 
<paragraph id="HBD62ADC58191473DA842503CE3A37E3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 180 day period beginning on the date that the eligible property is listed for sale during which an eligible property is only available for purchase by qualified first look buyers the eligible property shall be offered by the covered entity at a price that is the fair market value of the property as determined by an independent third-party appraisal or broker price opinion not more than 60 days before the date on which the property was listed for sale.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79E566C0FCB041BBA6D56B9E7F2184DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the covered entity selling the eligible property determines that the fair market value of the property can not be determined by an independent third-party appraisal or broker price opinion not more than 60 days before the date on which the property was listed for sale the covered entity may offer the covered property at a price based on a standardized valuation model used by the covered entity if the covered entity publically discloses the methodology used by such standardized valuation model.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6736A6EB5E8742EE8910D63264CB9EAB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Listing on public website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 180-day period beginning on the date that the eligible property is listed for sale during which an eligible property is only available for purchase by qualified first look buyers the eligible property shall be listed on a publically accessible website by the covered entity in a manner that identifies the eligible property as only available for purchase by qualified first look buyers and indicates how many days remain in the 180-day period during which the eligible property is only available for purchase by qualified first look buyers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H78D445DE78B64640BEEF4B21F64CBE13"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Prohibition on bundling</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may not bundle eligible properties during the 180 day period beginning on the date that the eligible property is listed for sale by the eligible entity.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1288A5BF397D4A739BA3E2C55EEC58E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication of information</header><text>Each covered entity shall, each quarter, publish on a website of the covered entity, information about—</text> <paragraph id="H6DBDDBF5D7294F1BBA4F37A463E23E9D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of covered properties sold during the prior quarter;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42386C53475A46008AD3BA16C8DC1B32"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of covered properties sold to qualified first look buyers during the prior quarter;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38617C8605B1477EBFE58F6233790FFD"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>the number of covered properties sold to institutional investors during the prior quarter;</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H51322BC033954C429AA971C97B8421CD" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>the pricing methodology used by the covered entity when selling covered properties; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F5A5495B31E4A28A5A697B0A6FBB7C1">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each covered property sold during the prior quarter, the ratio of the sale price to the fair market value of the covered property as determined by an independent third-party appraisal, broker price opinion, or standardized valuation model.</text>
                </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H8EF52790F67C426E8E5FF8614A6B4D10"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header> 
<paragraph id="H997B2241DA9B4D1DA69221CBAAF8DB04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Inspectors General of each covered entity shall, each year, review all sales of covered properties by the covered entity in the prior year and determine whether any provisions of this section were violated during such sale.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE142EE95D5ED46799482BC5F7958FD31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspectors General of each covered entity shall submit a report to the Congress each year that includes the results of the review conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0574A1C6B594B6C9DE40C894EBEE1A3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspectors General of each covered entity shall publish the report submitted under paragraph (2) on a publically accessible website of the covered entity.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1E37CF79EC46491D902E1B02E37A8790" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Violations</header><text>If the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development determines that a covered entity has violated this section, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDFCFB141D438409BBA0A4BCB487B227E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require the covered entity to publically disclose the violation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19236DDA97554A5F9F2DB6A70971F3C3" commented="no"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>impose a civil penalty of the greater of $100,000 or <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the price for which the covered property was sold on each employee of the covered entity involved in the violating transaction; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB20552AA876A4AB1B8BF1B0F70A00371" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require the covered entity, if practicable without breaching contracts, to reverse or unwind the transaction associated with the violation.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD910BCFE2745486FBA1F91B55B07E470"> <enum>(h)</enum> <header>Rulemaking</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered entity shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, issue such rules are necessary to carry out this section and such rules shall include a process to verify the eligibility of qualified first look buyers.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F563EE39DE34DE4AD65587B7BA8FEC7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCEEB38AD358546D49F87EA3E8F4A35CD"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF892D90AA1CB4B82AC8A01ADED99806B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered property</header><text>The term <term>covered property</term> means any single-family residential property made up of 1 to 4 units, owned, foreclosed upon, or under disposition by a covered entity.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BD8601E03DB4D10863F1D9A3AEEA1BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <quote>covered entity</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H365BD0FD82B74EBCB03C4D45C349A3FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Housing Administration;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H772997C295E147FB967DAA5413386563" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Housing Finance Agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02612C557C594556ABF817BAE7ECD188"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal National Mortgage Association;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64A1F99DE9584B9EB6E47380CF35E7D6"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E1C00DF790C4C36AEC56C87EB92B065"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE72A99B030D4A36B9DC35DD38BE3C06"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Institutional Investor</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institutional investor</term> means any entity that purchases properties for rental, resale, or investment purposes, including trusts, corporations, real estate investment trusts, limited liability companies, and partnerships.</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9DABABAF68143F8B4551FE50A4FAC3B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified First Look Buyer</header><text>The term <term>qualified first look buyer</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H40115B221D8A42FEA22C98CFDCB22A1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a natural person intending to occupy the property as their primary residence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD2660B2D566422393CF8EA419499F2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nonprofit housing organization which is an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C59ADC4892D4DF0BA5FE303BB7280AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a unit of local government; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCEDE26390C7F4860BA6CBC28A729F223"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a community land trust.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

