<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MDM25K50-75K-KD-0CG">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 463 ATS: Expressing condemnation of the Chinese Communist Party's persecution of religious minority groups, including Christians, Muslims, and Buddhists and the detention of Pastor “Ezra” Jin Mingri and leaders of the Zion Church, and reaffirming the United States' global commitment to promote religious freedom and tolerance.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. RES. 463</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251023">October 23, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc>Committee discharged; considered, amended, and agreed to with an amended preamble</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Expressing condemnation of the Chinese Communist Party's persecution of religious minority groups, including Christians, Muslims, and Buddhists and the detention of Pastor <quote>Ezra</quote> Jin Mingri and leaders of the Zion Church, and reaffirming the United States' global commitment to promote religious freedom and tolerance.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble commented="no">
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, on October 10, 2025, international news outlets reported that the Chinese Communist Party (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>CCP</quote>) detained Pastor <quote>Ezra</quote> Jin Mingri, who is the founder of Zion Church, from his home in Guangxi Province, China;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas CCP authorities also arrested nearly 30 other pastors and church members from Zion Church;</text></whereas>
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas 23 members of Zion Church remain in detention centers, while other members have been released on bail, and still others are being harassed and intimidated by Chinese authorities;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the CCP’s actions mark the largest coordinated, nationwide crackdown against an unregistered Christian house church network in more than 40 years;</text></whereas>
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas thousands of Zion Church members and millions of Christians and other religious adherents who reside in the People’s Republic of China seek to peacefully worship God and care for their neighbors without the threat or fear of persecution;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the imprisonment of Pastor Jin is the latest instance of CCP persecution of a large number of religious minorities, including Christians, Muslim Uyghurs, Hui Muslims, and Tibetan Buddhists;</text></whereas>
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, since coming to power in 2012, CCP General Secretary Xi Jinping has escalated a campaign to <quote>sinicize</quote> religion in China by—</text> <paragraph id="H39822AF8088842BDA79D9CCC25DE34D3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allowing authorities to burn bibles, imprison believers, and tear down Christian crosses; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3DA45EBEDB124792BF3ED28BF8FDDAB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">forcing religious organizations and adherents to conform to the ideology of the CCP;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, under the policy of sinicizing religion, the Government of China has—</text>
<paragraph id="H0D785C02EA3B43D9A1F8DC727203A306" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ordered the removal of crosses from Catholic and Protestant churches;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H256BEE237BBC4CE1BBADC6ED9AFFD407"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">censored religious texts;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6970C0C39CB14D6183E15AE791E46B42"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">imposed CCP-approved religious materials;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEC458FA6A5440A79E626A6F822E8F39"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">replaced images of Jesus Christ or the Virgin Mary with pictures of Xi Jinping; and </text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B2805CDBC684EB59E1F9F88BDD2F560"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instructed clergy to preach CCP ideology;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, in 2021, the Trump administration determined the CCP—</text>
<paragraph id="H4D40EA32F5A34A518C86BCE957B94B88" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">had committed crimes against humanity and genocide against predominantly Muslim Uyghurs and members of other ethnic and religious minority groups, including ethnic Kazakhs and ethnic Kyrgyz; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8C2DB6EBD104C1EBD614BFCACD1C77B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has continued to subject religious minority groups in China to restrictions on religious practices and freedom of expression, arbitrary imprisonment, forced sterilization torture, and forced labor;</text></paragraph></whereas>
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the CCP has made consistent efforts to erode the religious, linguistic, and cultural identity of Tibetans, including by— </text> <paragraph id="H80AF642791B646DD81B7878844BE7C3D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">closing Buddhist monasteries and limiting entry or practitioners;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71D14A6C47A64D56B3371D535C9FBB2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">forcibly disappearing and arbitrarily detaining Tibetans for practicing their religious beliefs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCC79F80E98E472E88081542D0A06683"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">censoring religious content online; and </text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5ADD27E0BE954B4F8CC0B0D621DB9713"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanding the use of boarding schools to indoctrinate children in CCP-approved curricula and Mandarin Chinese;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Congress unanimously passed the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/292">Public Law 105–292</external-xref>), which established, as the official policy of the United States—</text>
<paragraph id="H4821C39406C34C0F8E1EE90A1911B122" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to condemn violations of religious freedom;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H602EC18FB637485BBE819010F9F3161A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to promote, and assist other governments in the promotion of, the fundamental right to freedom of religion;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CD581459CF44C7C874FD0F1D7D3831E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to stand for liberty and with the persecuted;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6527E53B41A45599F3A48864311B829"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to use and implement appropriate tools in the United States foreign policy apparatus, including diplomatic, political, commercial, charitable, educational, and cultural channels; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H201932CE7C67414DA9B280844F24018D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to promote respect for religious freedom by all governments and peoples;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, under the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998, the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom has designated the People's Republic of China as a <quote>country of particular concern for religious freedom</quote> every year since 1999;</text></whereas>
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Congress unanimously passed the Frank R. Wolf International Religious Freedom Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/281">Public Law 114–281</external-xref>) in 2016 to enhance the capabilities of the United States to advance religious liberty globally through diplomacy, training, counterterrorism, and foreign assistance;</text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>), enacted by Congress in 2016, gives the President the authority to impose targeted sanctions on individuals responsible for committing human rights violations;</text></whereas>
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the People's Republic of China is a signatory to the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, adopted in Paris on December 10, 1948, and the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, adopted in New York on December 19, 1966, which recognize freedom of religion as an internationally-recognized human right; </text></whereas> <whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Article 36 of the Constitution of the People’s Republic of China explicitly states that citizens of the People’s Republic of China enjoy freedom of religious belief; and</text></whereas>
<whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the United States must show strong international leadership when it comes to the advancement of religious freedoms, liberties, and protections: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body style="OLC" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause" id="HED74D3D0348343618B78980059E8ED6F"> <section id="H2E7FB554994B4AEDA79AC33D8A6C1C4A" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Senate—</text>
<paragraph id="H2647CE2E009B4F55A3AAD6C20688AC85" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strongly condemns the Chinese Communist Party’s persecution of religious minority groups, including Pastor <quote>Ezra</quote> Jin Mingri and other leaders and members of Zion Church and other faith communities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1913385B49F430C9560F62FC390E979" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms the commitment of the United States to promote religious freedom and tolerance around the world and to help provide protection and relief to religious minorities facing persecution and violence;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBB412E404C8D44568B7C72EE0767224C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls for the immediate and unconditional release of all detained members of Zion Church, including Pastor Jin, and all other wrongfully detained religious practioners in China;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0321C6A0C0E34B309B10F585FC6B2BFF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls for the Government of the People’s Republic of China to cease its harassment and intimidation of the relatives of Zion Church members and their relatives, including tactics of transnational repression overseas;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9061DFC4A483453B9D46750332DFFAE2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on the Government of the People’s Republic of China to release all other arbitrarily detained religious believers, including Uyghur Muslims, Tibetan Buddhists, and other Christians; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HADB740787DAF4D7399F682A3F155A3DC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demands that the Government of the People’s Republic of China—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B993AD7B4584081B79381DE6B6F0B12"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">respect the internationally recognized human right to freedom of religion or belief; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D44B4B1E31E4106B4857B9C07286AA6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">end all forms of violence and discrimination against religious minority groups and entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
</resolution-body>
</resolution> 


