<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H25C34B8FBF664FBE98C213578CD71C92" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8126 IH: Congressional Accountability Act Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8126</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to require Members of Congress to reimburse the Treasury for amounts paid as settlements and awards under such Act in all cases of employment discrimination acts committed personally by Members, to permit individuals who file claims under such Act to file an amended claim if the preliminary review of the individual’s claim by a hearing officer includes the determination that the individual filing the claim is not a covered employee under such Act or has not stated a claim for which relief may be granted under title IV of such Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H179F44FFB3D044CA8126E6A33959EE81" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H87C203B1F28E4E669D18C888CB4A8468" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Accountability Act Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE80B9B5A6D044FD0B1A8FFBA1B6E39C4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Revision of rules requiring reimbursement for amounts paid as settlements and awards under Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 in cases of employment discrimination</header> <subsection id="H829C4B72FC7C4C5B85A046612D0A43E1"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Requiring Members of Congress To reimburse Treasury for amounts paid as settlements and awards in all cases of employment discrimination acts by Members</header> <paragraph id="H9B30DDB2088442ED91570DD3E16610DA"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Requiring reimbursement</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (i) of section 415(d)(1)(C) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1415">2 U.S.C. 1415(d)(1)(C)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDD37E112F53A41FA83FFC4BB6A62FCF8"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <clause id="H2186DD2515CB45E7BECBC9DCEF50D3AA">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a violation of section 201(a) or section 206(a); or</text>
            </clause>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAB7F895E0F6E4C2F8D5D22BBB3A77A61">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Conforming amendment relating to notification of possibility of
            reimbursement</header>
 <text>Clause (i) of section 402(b)(2)(B) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1402">2 U.S.C. 1402(b)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
          <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC421D2CB055B49FABE15D33E524E38B9"
            display-inline="no-display-inline">
            <clause id="H443034086D5D4804BE6A62CDE31BD309">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a violation of section 201(a) or section 206(a); or</text>
            </clause>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF06985180134FBDA22BD69A2BB9F3A1">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Requiring other employing offices To reimburse Treasury for amounts paid in claims
          involving retaliation for filing employment discrimination claim</header>
 <text>Section 415(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1415">2 U.S.C. 1415(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE17EB06266294CCABCB9C778FA818DAB"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>a violation of section 201(a) or 206(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>a violation described in paragraph (4)</quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H20F868C779974D4DB0F26EA8D0BE986C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H228EAB4A7884436C842D49B413064987" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HF13B3F4CD00E41B98911403245FE451F"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Violations described</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation described in this paragraph is—</text>
              <subparagraph id="HAAEC2F013E3C4D4CA34B9077CA3C3C99">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a violation of section 201(a) or 206(a); or</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="HCB7989EF8ABB44788FBB3AB1DE312241">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intimidation, reprisal, or discrimination that is unlawful under section 207 and is taken against a covered employee because of a claim alleging a violation described in subparagraph (A).</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC955B3C789EF47D39D0A3D4F89C8FE83"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to claims under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 which are made on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7836B6BE0AB84F40BF7257D5BD3C2C65"><enum>3.</enum><header>Permitting individuals filing claims under Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to file amended claims if preliminary review includes determination of failure to state claim for which relief may be granted</header> <subsection id="H73A502A46FFD4492903529FFF1A7ECAE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permitting filing of amended claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 403(d) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1402a">2 U.S.C. 1402a(d)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFC9D6E8524C043B88A2CA4A7E43F13C7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H83067B27559547769997813F409A1BFF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect of Determination of Failure To State Claim for Which Relief May Be Granted</header> 
<paragraph id="H63E3DD6F44774D01ADB78AA28B13E3CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permitting filing of amended version of claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the hearing officer’s report on the preliminary review of a claim under subsection (c) includes the determination that the individual filing the claim is not a covered employee or has not stated a claim for which relief may be granted under this title—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE7F2B999A464612826A1E6A82EEC07A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual may file an amended version of the claim under this section; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H889E6007AFFB4498BE67E6C2658DD21A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amended claim shall be subject to a preliminary review under this section in the same manner as the original version of the claim.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H473F6CE41B9747F0BF00643678D54805"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the individual does not file an amended claim under paragraph (1)(A) prior to the expiration of the 10-day period which begins on the date the hearing officer submits the report on the preliminary review of the individual’s original version of the claim under subsection (c), or if the hearing officer’s report on the amended version of the claim includes the determination that the individual filing the claim is not a covered employee or has not stated a claim for which relief may be granted under this title—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H84FF5BA259DE45BF891590ADDC6CA6B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual (including an individual who is a Library claimant, as defined in section 401(d)(1)) may not obtain a formal hearing with respect to the claim as provided under section 405; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE517AF223D8444B828EE26D7DBB507C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the hearing officer shall provide the individual and the Executive Director with a written notice that the individual may file a civil action with respect to the claim in accordance with section 408.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8943FF920C8247E49806F3FBD6B0EE22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to claims under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 which are made on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H020F0F6046524DB7A7906A1C7B238AB8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Permitting Office of Employee Advocacy to provide assistance to covered employees in connection with civil actions</header> <subsection id="H5C390EB11B2D4D3698C5673A3BA99BEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 724(c) of House Resolution 724, One Hundred Fifteenth Congress, if a covered employee of the House of Representatives under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 files a civil action with respect to an alleged violation of such Act, as provided in section 408 of such Act, the Office of Employee Advocacy may provide assistance to the employee with respect to investigations or proceedings under such Act in connection with such alleged violation at any time, including after the employee files such action.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H042ED0EB3D314FD79441C874F0D523A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exercise of rulemaking authority</header><text>This section is enacted by Congress—</text> <paragraph id="H85881E74EAEF42BDA88B5D2BC827BB2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the House of Representatives, and as such it is deemed a part of the rules of the House of Representatives, and it supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0009A500DC284C3A8D6065BBC8B55C12"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with full recognition of the constitutional right of the House of Representatives to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of the House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of the House.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

