<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE8921D39CD8A48CA88CB7D2DC7CC2FB5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7876 IH: Secret Service-Local Law Enforcement Partnership Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7876</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260309">March 9, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To establish within the Department of Homeland Security the Extraordinary Protection Reimbursement Program.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H547260DCD6DA4A7D80012879B41A5DB2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H449541596A284C0197AC7DE3F0FA20CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secret Service-Local Law Enforcement Partnership Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H145176CE80F24F6FB07A40F0471393F6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extraordinary Protection Reimbursement Program established</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a program to be known as the Extraordinary Protection Reimbursement Program to provide grants to reimburse State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments for protection activities directly and demonstrably associated with the non-governmental properties as designated in the Presidential Protection Assistance Act of 1976 of persons protected pursuant to paragraphs (1), (3), (7), and (8) of section 3056 of title 18, United States Code.</text></section> 
<section id="H04D9BC49E55E478F8DD581BD5A325BC2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under the program, an applicant shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC5BA79E2CCAD4F41970D21F76C3D47D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be a State, local, Tribal, or territorial law enforcement agency; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1A14E4CDB2A4DD39A9175573B242822"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify that the grant will be used only for costs incurred in excess of typical law enforcement operation costs that are directly attributable to the provision of protection as described in section 4.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H59B4CE953E7C4FC58E112AD204C43EE7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Grants distributed under this section on a reimbursable basis may be used only in accordance with the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H585BF93F475F4A1DA7BA026393137C95"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of amounts expended on costs pertaining to personnel, grant amounts may only be expended for man-hours spent directly on protection of a non-governmental property, including patrols dedicated to the area immediately surrounding the residence or office and officers otherwise posted to protection of the property.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2BED765974E4AEEB57BF2D22003E939"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of amounts expended on equipment, grant amounts may only be expended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H93E0859DBED84438BF7713F062DAE830"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the explicit purpose of protection of a property; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF24E36F772554368B4B3E596525F3531"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the United States Secret Service shall ensure the need for the grantee to acquire equipment for the protection of the property and travel to and from the property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41085319591F4DBC9A58524A23249FD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Grant amounts may only be expended on protection provided while the protected person is physically present at, or traveling to or from, the property.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H3ACC9167CFC447EEBF6DAE7D8846AFD3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation on obligation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report to Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate a report on the implementation of the recommendations included in the report of the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security, dated July 28, 2023. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall thereafter ensure future implementation of each such recommendation.</text></section> 
<section id="H64B4CC78A8684DC686380EC9E3A572C2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Accountability</header> 
<subsection id="HBE9CAC679B9B4464AE6A7331A30675B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inspector General audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall carry out an audit of the program under this section each fiscal year and may carry out such other inspections of the program as the Inspector General determines appropriate. The Inspector General shall submit a report on such audit by not later than 90 days after the first date of the following fiscal year to the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE41136E0860243D89800C30E1FCA2FD4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report for each fiscal year grants are made to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H89CD865C171640F68BC9AED7F132E56D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total amount of grants disbursed that fiscal year; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5FB2F3472FF4D738EE4459FBB1469DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each grantee—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB5D767AB53A14E2696FFFD5A0938885F"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the identity of the grantee;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCFB655CDD26D409C8A4858F1C3FBBDD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of the grant;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H681D6AA92E1C48EDB7EA329401AA67A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total man-hours spent on protection of a property by the grantee; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF49027A5A2A848D3894DDD38C45FAC6C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an itemized list of all equipment acquired using the grant, including the certification referred to in section 4(2)(B) for that equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H66EF6104343845C9B94EC6ED89025861"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>non-governmental property</quote>—</text> <paragraph id="H35757D4F1BD04F38B157738B3659BCA3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means any non-governmental, owned or leased, property designated for protection by the United States Secret Service; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0836FCDF58047919A2FCE318693F252"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include any hotel or other place of temporary accommodation of less than 30 days.</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="H015AF6B64F6A462984FA8346BFC8B096"> <enum>8.</enum> <header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $61,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026, 2027, and 2028. Administration of these funds shall be executed by the Department’s Management Directorate or Federal Emergency Management Agency, as directed by the Secretary, in coordination with the Secret Service as appropriate.</text> </section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


