<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2738553E5D6246FF8C22C11E04A5E9F2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6680 IH: Tech Wellness for Men Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6680</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to assess the economic, mental health, and social consequences of screen addiction among adult men, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA502AA46893F4919BC047D54F0AAB4FF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD7E5F5054F384092AE1D6A8A72CF5EF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tech Wellness for Men Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEC9CEB0F890F4AE69BDB2713D1BBCBD2"><enum>2.</enum><header>National study on screen addiction in adult men</header> <subsection id="HA87B5193079843C5A29B77DBB9688AFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health, shall conduct a comprehensive study on the social, economic, and health impacts of screen addiction among men in the United States aged 25 to 64.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2229B071D3F041CDB8D1E3D535469707"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In conducting the study, the Secretary shall examine—</text> <paragraph id="H79A90CAB66FA4C348F4D65241E294024"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the association between screen overuse and increased rates of depression, anxiety, substance misuse, loneliness, and sleep disorders;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB60AA3D7F214409898F1CF02A93EA173"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the impact of screen addiction on workforce participation, productivity, and economic disengagement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A6AD3092B3F43FF96115B34430AE67A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>social isolation and declining participation in family life, marriage, parenting, and civic organizations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA70F6F69990744F3A6D8236E72D80129"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the role of screen overuse in contributing to male withdrawal from education, employment, and interpersonal relationships; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05D49628CDD84D10867D88AB63410889"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the cost of screen-related health burdens on Federal and State healthcare systems.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H73FD58D35CA148E88197D5FF7BED2C65"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Focus populations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the Secretary may include as a part of the study an assessment of—</text> <paragraph id="H8BA432E2BC084CA6A1E64D46C6E0573A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">screen addiction among veterans, unemployed men, and formerly incarcerated individuals; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFAC0B7F41A484732A034BDB439664AF2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>geographic breakdowns of screen addiction among adult men, including urban, suburban, and rural differences.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF26C4EB177D3428389E09B79A40DF050"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Publication</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish on the public internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services a summary of the findings of the Secretary based on the study, including an identification of mental health resources relating to screen addiction among adult men.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

