<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-LAN25258-94X-JN-C76"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 546 ATS: Designating November 2025 as “National Hospice and Palliative Care Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 546</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating November 2025 as <quote>National Hospice and Palliative Care Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas palliative care and hospice services—</text><paragraph id="id1D9826F288AB4439838FCE7AF90498D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>can empower individuals to live as fully as possible, surrounded and supported by family and loved ones, despite serious illnesses or injuries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id830A51E79630426F8A817A0E190F9195"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are critical parts of the continuum of supports and services that individuals with serious illness and their families need;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ensuring access to palliative care and hospice for all individuals in the United States who are in need, regardless of age, race, ethnicity, or socioeconomic status, is important;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas palliative care and hospice aims to bring patients and family caregivers high-quality care delivered by an interdisciplinary team of skilled health care professionals, including—</text><paragraph id="idF1A2554C33374ED597BFF12325A7C214"><enum>(1)</enum><text>physicians;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id918389C639AF4C89A72D5FB55B3152DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>nurses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id09705C09D4794B319A78BEB8FEE22120"><enum>(3)</enum><text>social workers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0D89F2D0B05949FE90EC408A8A3A29CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>therapists;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBE3739C5EEFA48D18F36AEB02DE2D041"><enum>(5)</enum><text>counselors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id51A352501AE64A8CBCADD09DCE65E8CC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>health aides;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA2BF31061EBE4D2F86B5B3A677CD2B00"><enum>(7)</enum><text>spiritual care providers; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id24B42C09F86442A18A1A9AF9928F87BD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>other health care professionals;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is a need to increase training opportunities for health care professionals to receive interdisciplinary team-based training in palliative care and hospice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas hospice focuses on quality of life through pain management and symptom control, caregiver assistance, and emotional and spiritual support, with the goal of allowing patients to live fully until the end of life, surrounded and supported by loved ones, friends, and caregivers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas trained palliative care and hospice professionals, during a time of trauma and loss, can provide grief and bereavement support services to individuals with a serious illness or injury, the family members of those individuals, and others;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas palliative care is a patient and family-centered approach to care that—</text><paragraph id="idA200CB911C3A46FB9BBC588F0E364041"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides relief from symptoms and stress;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id098359A51DD94A29981102F4BD00DE51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>can be complementary to curative treatments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0C27B8CDF8734A94BD4740887E9D74CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improves the quality of life of patients and their families;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, more than 1,720,000 individuals in the United States living with a serious illness or injury, and the families of those individuals, received care and support from more than 6,535 hospice providers in communities across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas volunteers continue to play a vital role in supporting hospice care and operations; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas palliative care and hospice providers encourage all patients to learn more about their options for care and to share their preferences with family, loved ones, and health care professionals: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id41339e51cba649ea8763c9ca0c6943d2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates November 2025 as <quote>National Hospice and Palliative Care Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0981d74b8cb340458229c002f86a3aa6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States— </text><subparagraph id="idC95CF6B0BED34316AEF56B62F454EAC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to increase their understanding and awareness of—</text><clause id="id66abce5346804bd69def46d45c43c725"><enum>(i)</enum><text>care for hospice patients with a serious illness or injury; </text></clause><clause id="id6edc3eb7435f4521a78262562e2acb8c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the benefits of integrating palliative care early into the treatment plans for patients with a serious illness or injury; and</text></clause><clause id="id95bcc537d32347a489df0abeb0dece3b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the importance of grief support for caregivers and loved ones during hospice care and after death; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35d930aaf0c547ddb842a6c196e46e4d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to recognize the care and dedication of—</text><clause id="idE728DB9EC2C942BCAB7C1F624663A53B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>millions of family caregivers; and </text></clause><clause id="idA51501A44B11433DB8BE886078E1866E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>tens of thousands of palliative care and hospice staff and volunteers; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida44dff4c25e44b6a85b6db0eb6e8a155"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to observe <quote>National Hospice and Palliative Care Month</quote> with appropriate activities and programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

