<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0E0BABD003154BA086AE76D4C35036CD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6876 IH: Protecting Children from Foreign Mutilation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6876</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the imposition of visa sanctions with respect to each foreign person the President determines has performed or otherwise facilitated chemical or surgical mutilations of United States minors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2A83014E664D4BB592207B79788ECE78" style="OLC"><section id="HC110C836E4744B989D56925C80947CC8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Children from Foreign Mutilation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7BC398663D974BD4AFD159420B436F6F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><subsection id="HE125E55966D649A4AD0EAAB6157D0E95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall impose the sanction described in subsection (b) with respect to each person the President determines, including through information submitted in accordance with subsection (d), is a foreign person who—</text><paragraph id="H11ECA45C3DC04E8281445D9C4CE25C95"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a member of the World Professional Association for Transgender Health;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90C0CDB115DE46578640408DEF9889E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has, in the capacity of such individual as a duly licensed physician, in any way performed, prescribed, or otherwise facilitated chemical or surgical mutilations of United States persons; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6444617932F4D9087C25779814D9439"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owns or operates a clinic, hospital, pharmacy, or other medical institution that performs, prescribes, or otherwise facilitates chemical or surgical mutilations of United States persons.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEC91AD89A6394E85833ADA030C62672F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Visa sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanction described in this subsection is the following:</text><paragraph id="H889F4A7B8B434290A4E215813E037482"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>A foreign person described in subsection (a) is—</text><subparagraph id="HF0401DC6C7724B529E3A05F87FF7F3A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H866EA3CC45F54B30BB287D93E7047E62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H388C4E0F4E474C3697E4961B32AECC08"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA013065650C4CD9B6E2B8863843F1AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subparagraph id="HF75F30A53D8E4C0FA427C2899834720D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A foreign person described in subsection (a) shall be subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58CAC33D696C424FBF6E331B85101C00"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under subparagraph (A) shall take effect immediately and automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0E16E0329794B158FC84E46D7AD7D9F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information submitted to Secretary of State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall establish procedures to enable individuals to submit to the Secretary information relating to foreign persons that may qualify for the imposition of sanctions under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7BAE1F1327F0419480919719EE384C33"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception; waiver</header><paragraph id="H5ED7D81AB74C4F9CB9A213FCA099899E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with—</text><subparagraph id="HBC16EAEAC5614E8988F6B3F32E2E0B6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DCF41BE96DE4555B21D6B1F7C825294"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other applicable international obligations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E163EBD39974593ABDC3FC00D179322"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception with respect to whistleblowers</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not be imposed with respect to a foreign person described in subsection (a)(2) if the Secretary of State determines that such foreign person—</text><subparagraph id="HD6C7AF3ECF56496688B6B39ECDF7CE1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no longer works for an entity performing any of the acts described in subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CFB129DE5EB45B7BE9A20515D09F9D5"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF3B57E6624ED452B9D2F57E7EAE28B47"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has provided information to the Secretary of State sufficient to identify at least one other foreign person meeting the criteria for the imposition of sanctions under this section; or</text></clause><clause id="H312404C90FD8402090C46DC7F445EC1C" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has provided information to any other Federal official relating to a violation of law or regulation in the practices of the entity described in subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56269DE7575C47058845CB3BFE2A1F2E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person if the President determines that such a waiver is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF08245295CEF4AFF9525C79152DD6BB0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H06A46E88436543F0BD0AA08B6BC8CF62"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the actions taken to carry out this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18DC23C8405C48B9B84429E77B74C499"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of people who have been sanctioned pursuant to the authorities provided by this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0FD162286284DB0896B7AD20C84DBCA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any additional measures the Secretary would recommend to be taken to discourage foreign persons from providing gender transitions to United States persons.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CBE4C67E8944EC5BCBB3DC3B1BE4823"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H506823A37EBD4C938134BB0C0106CB3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admission; admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admission</term>, <term>admitted</term>, and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB765B8E2D91946259D1E0982588E819A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chemical or surgical mutilation</header><subparagraph id="H327303CC0C054863AFD855876247569A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>chemical or surgical mutilation</term> means engaging in any one or more of the following for the purpose of intentionally halting the natural development of the individual’s body so that it no longer corresponds to the individual’s sex or intentionally changing the individual’s body, including the individual’s external appearance or biological functions, to no longer correspond to the individual’s sex:</text><clause id="HF728263FC0B54C788D8D1ADBD1F7C672"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The use of puberty blockers, including gonadotropin releasing hormone agonists and other interventions, to delay the onset or progression of normally timed puberty in an individual.</text></clause><clause id="H978650AB112241C0AD6ADB6C835A9F65"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The use of sex hormones, such as androgen blockers, estrogen, progesterone, or testosterone.</text></clause><clause id="H750A9F5B008A4EF2804B0680139CA105"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Surgical procedures that attempt to transform an individual’s physical appearance or that attempt to alter or remove an individual’s sexual organs.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC159C62029AB43029D74913758542112"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Such term does not include any of the following:</text><clause id="HE51E5C7193F34C8E8165FDC41BA33FD8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Appropriate and medically necessary procedures to treat a verifiable disorder of sexual development, including an individual born with 46 XX chromosomes with virilization, with 46 XY chromosomes with undervirilization, or having both ovarian and testicular tissue.</text></clause><clause id="H9E2BA062B93941F8A578C4C96004583A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The treatment of any infection, injury, disease, or disorder that has been caused or exacerbated by the performance of an intervention described in subparagraph (A) without regard to whether the intervention was performed in accordance with State or Federal law or whether the intervention is covered by the private right of action under section 4.</text></clause><clause id="H7ED28D1E9FD04536B3611867EC4D4646"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any intervention undertaken because the individual suffers from any diagnosed and verifiable condition of the body’s organ systems, including the following:</text><subclause id="HAFDDF2C2EB92476EBD6D43FC9B065AC2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Traumatic bodily injuries (such as fractures, organ rupture, or penetrating trauma).</text></subclause><subclause id="H06233BEE3BE84538B0FFAB1E33B8A703"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Congenital structural anomalies of major organs or systems, including the cardiovascular, respiratory, renal, hepatic, neurological, or musculoskeletal systems.</text></subclause><subclause id="H437AFDCF6E054AAC9E61B2E895DAB06A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Acute illnesses with a high probability of rapid mortality.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H149D945809554A0A843A5CE5AE24EC33"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Detransition treatment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H609D8BFF4DF64ADABCA0A51D208E0A0D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Detransition treatment</header><text>The term <term>detransition treatment</term> means any treatment, including a mental health treatment, medical intervention, or surgery, that does either or both of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2230484F268146E9A5E87E8ABCFC7E74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Stops or reverses the effects of a prior chemical or surgical mutilation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H322F404279BD451A80666C6B4CAAFA85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Helps an individual cope with the effects of a prior chemical or surgical mutilation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD90ABB3AD9714A63AF5A8726CA2CFEB9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means an individual who is not a citizen or national of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF559A5FC3414C3DBB5E53980848E2E7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sex</header><text>The term <term>sex</term> means a person’s immutable biological classification, determined at the moment of conception, as either male or female.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64C9F95E8C5C42D78E626E657AA8EB75"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H9270744F70FB403899C6EAAB25B7A08E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a United States citizen or national, or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BD164A79B794652BF5EA5AEC6214E9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not attained the age of 18 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCBB7561D81994B3091E6AD78C7AB2C7B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person, entity, government, or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, or the application of such provision to all other persons, entities, governments, or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

