<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5C91B1722CE148BAB35402738BDB9FE6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6038 IH: Improving Veteran Access to Care Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6038</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251112">November 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish an integrated project team to improve the process for scheduling appointments for health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H44653FF505144D128C2C8D4DEFEA88C0" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB99D6096617E44408E8983600EACB606"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Veteran Access to Care Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H27AF958E582844FAA9DF9969CD2AF079" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Implementation of and report on efforts of Department of Veterans Affairs to improve health care appointment scheduling</header> <subsection id="H6941BF870C0B46E5A33FFD062B12D4BF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a plan to improve the process for scheduling appointments for health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs, including improvements for both patients and employees of the Department responsible for scheduling such appointments.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA2436BE6EA4485DB5D8C93DEF25080A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements of plan</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE85991E73CAB4E1AA29D358CE540CDA7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan required by subsection (a) shall include—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H035AF55CE17D4E61BC2828ACEF5408FE" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such actions, resources, technology, and process improvements as the Secretary determines necessary to ensure the Department achieves, in a timely manner, improved delivery of health care, access to health care, customer experience and service relating to the receipt of health care, and efficiency with respect to the delivery of health care; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17622BC125994C4C8B7A625FA8F09581" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a proposed schedule and timeline to carry out such plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB4F9086D890419C85A4418E859C3A5F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C17B12E2FCD4C6B8F5357C3FBF1ECCC" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the plan required by subsection (a) addresses the following objectives:</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30C5ED9494F344B0800E8B641DB64CE6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>To develop or continue the development of a scheduling system that enables both personnel and patients of the Department to view available appointments for care furnished by the Department, including primary care, mental health care, and all forms of specialty care.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B921BDB68854E57AEFF156D59C4C744" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>To develop or continue the development of a self-service scheduling platform, available for use by all patients of the Department, which shall—</text>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAF2D2DD6EA646B793EB1788908B271F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enable such patients to view available appointments and, subject to the method provided under subclause (II), fully schedule appointments for all care furnished by the Department;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B2073C062C54F69A024D80905A39F9A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if a referral is required for an appointment, provide a method for the patient to request a referral and subsequently book an appointment if the referral is approved; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58A956FF7F6A41DEA871C65D448BB750" changed="not-changed"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide such patients with the ability to cancel or reschedule appointments.</text></subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H922C398DB75447459AC3743BEE56DA1A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>To create a process through which all patients of the Department can telephonically speak with a scheduler who can assist the patient to determine appointment availability and can fully schedule appointments on behalf of the patient for all care furnished by the Department.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8DEB009D9B24131BE2431A4AB06CEC9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>To carry out such other functions, oversight, metric development and tracking, change management, cross-Department coordination, and other related matters, including improvements to employee-facing information technology, training, and processes, as the Secretary determines appropriate as it relates to scheduling tools, functions, and operations with respect to health care appointments furnished by the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D18BDFBD281467190390C090F4F4CD1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Explanation of inability to implement certain objectives, features, or services</header><text>If the Secretary determines that an objective under subparagraph (A), or any feature or service in connection with that objective, cannot be implemented or otherwise incorporated into a final product pursuant to the plan required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall include with the plan submitted under such subsection a report containing—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16C3F97B8FCB492F9F0EDBB823F42AAF" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation as to why that objective, feature, or service cannot be implemented or incorporated, as the case may be; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H816E2BD8093E4C209DE3A6DBD980F159" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for implementing the plan required by subsection (a) without that objective, feature, or service.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3E23469331644AE7ABF536529A2472BD" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than two years after submitting to the appropriate committees of Congress the plan required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall fully implement the plan.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCA2A4CCE83B24A8D972FD585AC71B67F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination with Electronic Health Record Modernization Program</header><text>In developing the plan required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure that the elements and objectives of such plan set forth under subsection (b) are developed in consideration of the deployment schedule and capabilities of the Electronic Health Record Modernization Program of the Department to ensure a smooth transition to using the tools and features under such plan as relevant and appropriate.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H81B33B970E0A4143BD9F3E47B0388E7F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation reports</header><text>Not later than each of one year and two years after the date on which the Secretary submits the plan required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the progress of the Secretary in implementing such plan, including—</text> <paragraph id="HD94EAD86F7704F5D8264922F34D77772" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the costs incurred to implement the plan as of the date of the report;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2FF7369A4B424544AB25857AB4078876" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the expected costs to complete implementation of the plan (including costs for management and technology);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0485E16B22004CACBB21CB0639637B00" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the schedule for deployment of any capabilities developed pursuant to the plan; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4364D1E408F248F99F10C2785B8A5968" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the goals and metrics achieved, challenges, and lessons learned in implementing the plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H77283544B27E4004B95C08BA3D73BBB7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the Secretary to include in the plan required by subsection (a) any technology or process that would preclude or impede the ability of a veteran to contact or schedule an appointment directly with a facility or provider through a non-online scheduling process, should the veteran choose to do so.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H052C5A36869346B799A111A5614C706B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC2507C15C35F47948387EFAB1CA9FCA7" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD1F5FB3ED81049A1A325D3F07394D404" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fully schedule</header><text>The term <term>fully schedule</term>, with respect to an appointment for health care, means that the appointment booking is completed, rather than simply requested.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

