<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1C35FF5E20284830AB9907312D8A9CF3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7470 IH: Keep ICE Out of Washington County, Maryland Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7470</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260210">February 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Department of Homeland Security, including U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, from establishing or operating an immigration detention or holding facility in Washington County, Maryland, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H594772FC7935419883284A19B65CF24E" style="OLC"><section id="H63095BE5480447A0800FB9DE60592961" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keep ICE Out of Washington County, Maryland Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCD9250ECEE14459F8C69D6F7DD3F7144"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HE24FE25E76334B17BE3C3D1C8B8FBB25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Immigration detention and holding facilities have significant and lasting impacts on surrounding communities, including effects on public health, housing, infrastructure, and local services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBA0E07EA3894861B8A2A648390B17B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement has detained thousands of citizens and noncitizens without regard for due process or the rule of law, undermining key constitutional protections afforded to all people, regardless of status.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43D9CDC23CA1453CB85D75103B17B4C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Detention conditions in U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement facilities across the country are inhumane and fall far short of our values as Americans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFE209BBDEF547ADAF862672B49B95A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Detained noncitizens are routinely denied medical care, access to counsel, and family visitation while in Immigration and Customs Enforcement custody.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1C7850A731F4949B4BCA70E1266A4ED"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Land-use planning and community development are traditionally matters of local concern, and Federal actions should respect community input and local priorities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8655DCB789504487AAFA4DBEE93CE5D4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Residents and local officials in historic Washington County, Maryland, have raised substantial concerns regarding the siting of a Federal immigration detention or holding facility in their community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98276F2C19924FA593DE41942D27ED23"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Congress has authority to condition and prohibit the use of Federal funds and facilities.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA0CDDC19525843879E27558007BD9987"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on certain detention and holding facilities in Washington County, Maryland</header><subsection id="H6FB0DEC2B40745BD967839668F3B8B82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="HF5384DED8E914CE89E87B7BE3A06B545"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no covered agency may—</text><subparagraph id="H19EAF0C3CC464F1C9FA7580565BAD82D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish a detention or holding facility in Washington County, Maryland; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ADF039272BB4CD383D85866F9138683"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operate, expand, or reopen any detention or holding facility in Washington County.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55E198058F394AB7AB13A610E9461F2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds prohibited</header><text>No funds appropriated or otherwise made available to any covered agency may be obligated or expended for any purpose described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA432964C871A41C5BB97D0392BFC03DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H3D751453CC324F239EC8D9A6550C18EA"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Judicial review</header> <text>Any resident of Washington County, Maryland, the government of Washington, County, a Member of Congress, or the State of Maryland shall have standing to bring an action in the United States District Court for the District of Maryland to enforce this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B773ADC1B9F4DB99AA9585653F47CFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action brought under paragraph (1), the court may grant declaratory and injunctive relief, including an order prohibiting any activity in violation of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H189D8BA6AF67452EB496C090359E2EAD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4EBFD0809E034DE587127E5B9206711A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text>The term <quote>covered agency</quote> means the Department of Homeland Security and any of its components, including U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H410E37ABC4124823BA119071401AE969"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Detention or holding facility</header><text>The term <quote>detention or holding facility</quote> means any facility used primarily for the civil detention or holding of noncitizens, including facilities operated directly by the Federal Government or through contracts, intergovernmental service agreements, or private entities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

