<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B4A87D7946F4DBAB4A96B670F716C1C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5979 IH: Immigration Document Delivery Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5979</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require that any document pertaining to the immigration status of an individual that, in the determination of the Secretary, is to be carried or delivered by mail, by the United States Postal Service, shall include a trackable accountability measure.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H619BE191251E4C62AF5DD70E463BF1FC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H64B43FB153B046DC83A0CC71447CBEE2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Immigration Document Delivery Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0766544DCA1E4C3EA7CFB9AD5E123BFA"><enum>2.</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, by rule, require that any document pertaining to the immigration status of an individual that, in the determination of the Secretary, is to be carried or delivered by mail, by the United States Postal Service, shall include a trackable accountability measure that is—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA537EA20EEDC4737958B2D23DC7E3760"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Postal Service barcode (or successive service or marking) that enables tracking of each individual document mailed. This accountability measure could be either a tracking number or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0239C8A9D685404882A86DDBB9DF76D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a requirement for a signature of the recipient on any mail including such document sent from any United States Citizenship and Immigration Services facility.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">This section does not apply in the case of a document presented to an individual in person.</continuation-text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

