<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE0E04594F64844D1BAF678256219B6A3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7607 IH: Modernizing EIA Tracking and Reporting to Increase Consistency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7607</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To study and modernize the measurement and reporting of United States energy use, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA15402D08F5F49F5BC2C2693A7D8EE5F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H76D614578E3D45C99F28A8DA263CD51C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing EIA Tracking and Reporting to Increase Consistency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>METRIC Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB93FBF27F1B54628AED822ED76E42937"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose and findings</header> <subsection id="H7FDCBD7340DE4DE8A956368B89362EBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to improve the energy performance, transparency, and decision-making of the United States by modernizing how the United States measures and accounts for gross amount of energy input into the national energy system.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1DF1F65148BD4561AC7AED900E25B1E1" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="H1B81EB4A1F1B4235B792AB9C413D0619" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>historical measures of primary energy were developed for economies dominated by combustion-based fuels and do not accurately capture the efficiency or system value of noncombustion energy sources;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9AC7176D26E44E1EB0DF3CBDE73DC32C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>differences in how primary energy are measured across fuel and renewable systems obscure trends in electrification, decarbonization, and energy productivity, hindering effective policymaking and misinforming researchers, market participants, and the public; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAE2A1DE4405472085C9DA4101DC8DF2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enhancing national energy accounting through improved data collection, modeling, and transparency will strengthen evidence-based policymaking, support market efficiency, and better align United States statistics with the energy transition.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H11496D6DF06145D3906D975785A392E7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modernizing energy metrics</header> 
<subsection id="H27BE4177ABAE4B29B8AE193E4D65BD56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study on primary energy indicators</header> 
<paragraph id="H18F016956E59420FB6EFC80C1C6DB1E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required study</header><text>The Secretary of Energy, with support from the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration and relevant offices within the Department of Energy, shall conduct a comprehensive study on the validity, limitations, and potential alternatives to the use of the indicators for primary energy in national energy accounting.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H519571D0CE5A457C926A223AC6EDE67F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of study</header><text>The study shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB0313432950C40E9A0A87DC89DB6CACD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the conceptual basis and historical rationale for the current indicator for primary energy calculated and reported by the Energy Information Administration;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF1E3538E6684FF2B89A06B2272099A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the limitations of primary energy accounting in accurately reflecting energy efficiency, energy transitions, and the value and comparability of combustible and noncombustible energy sources;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8941A92DD48141E5AACB79B17116D5E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an analysis of alternative indicators and their suitability for integration into national energy statistics;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44FBBF27A81A40E4BC98E45370806222"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a review of international best practices for energy accounting, including methodologies used by the International Energy Agency and peer nations; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F2589E528884C7BBC2A44DE72FF306A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommendations for improvements or replacements to the primary energy indicator that better align with national goals for energy efficiency, electrification, decarbonization, and economic productivity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CFDFE7CC8454D519D35C2F5FB82DF71"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report containing the findings and recommendations of the study required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1D96B29FA47F41C3A98F5CF3655E79F9" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Complementary incident energy statistics</header><text>Section 205 of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7135">42 U.S.C. 7135</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H083DC07E0D9F4B40B451620CD5C8C8F4" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H39E6F57AE1E34FF3B6B842FCAC1EA36D" commented="no"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Incident energy statistics</header> <paragraph id="H055FB6BEC91645B1809D77A0EFD60326"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Administrator shall develop, collect, analyze, and report on incident energy.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FFA1E01E72E4F3CA473EDC76CB8F9B5" commented="no">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Measurement and estimation</header>
                            <subparagraph id="H8C3E3E47E4D240758ADBCB776153C5D9" commented="no">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
                                <header>Data derived from surveys</header>
 <text>To the extent feasible, under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall collect, through surveys, reporting requirements, or other data-collection mechanisms, data representing the amount of incident energy, consistent with the approaches used to evaluate primary energy for thermal energy sources.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="H20DC31A3E59E44FD965A8D5E1E11DAB8" commented="no">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
                                <header>Derived estimates</header>
 <text>With respect to energy sources for which it is not feasible to collect data under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall develop and publish model-based estimates or analytical approximations of the amount of incident energy, updated on an annual basis, based on—</text>
                                <clause id="H9D573870C7F24933A55970B902BAF7D5" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>data collected through new or existing surveys of manufacturers, operators, or users of energy conversion technologies;</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H70B6D39C13FB442383B988E942C9DEBD" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>physical models or statistical analyses developed or adopted by the Energy Information Administration; and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="HE2DC45E6DAE1416BB6E661DCC03634C1" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>information derived from Federal research institutions, National Laboratories, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or other appropriate entities using remote sensing, satellite imagery, or comparable observational techniques, as may be necessary.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA07FA62350474B7CBC86007A3F9BDC79" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Integration and publication</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4FF8EEFF45794164A010573B315BC93C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall include the data on the amount of incident energy included in each report required by paragraph (1) in the existing reports or other products published by the Energy Information Administration that include primary energy and final energy statistics in a manner that enables side-by-side comparison of energy-conversion efficiency and system performance.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14643A7D47674FDAA408DED5B12DADDD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Administrator shall make all data, assumptions, and methods used under this subsection for purposes of developing, collecting, analyzing, and reporting on incident energy publicly available in machine-readable formats and shall describe the degree of uncertainty or approximation associated with the estimates and analytical approximations developed and published under paragraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7CEA62025894F34B11837FE610D865A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relationship to existing statistics</header><text>This subsection shall not be construed to affect how the Energy Information Administration defines or reports primary energy as of the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1B9F1AE93074543B86025D3460F7F5F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAB7BCD08668F441BAEA0B78EC3445DF2" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Energy conversion</header><text>The term <term>energy conversion</term> means any physical, chemical, or mechanical process by which energy is transformed from one form to another for the purpose of producing electricity, heat, mechanical work, chemical energy, or another usable or storable form of energy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE64AC542DAAA44B995DE8EE5FD8D428F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final energy</header><text>The term <term>final energy</term>—</text> 
<clause id="HEAF51FC8B0CC4A3188B670EC22D9F10A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means energy in the form delivered to end users for consumption in buildings, transportation, industrial processes, or other sectors; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5FD06D0326F247BF83C88010E925D014" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes electricity, pipeline gas, gasoline, diesel, hydrogen, and district heat.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBB9E37F443D74219A6A103EBE3A11FBE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Incident energy</header><text>The term <term>incident energy</term>—</text> <clause id="H22E75E2ACBEC47F8948F4914149C79AC" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means the total energy entering an energy conversion technology or system from natural or environmental sources, including both thermal and nonthermal forms, before any transformation or conversion losses occur; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1757E1018CBB4F2587D8489525F68DA1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes energy from combustible fuels, biomass, nuclear materials, solar radiation, wind, geothermal heat, hydroelectric potential, and other renewable or nonrenewable resources.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

