<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H88EABCF3661A47BF800045195C04B66C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9642 IH: Medicare Access to Rural Anesthesiology Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9642</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide payment under part A of the Medicare program on a reasonable cost basis for anesthesia services furnished by an anesthesiologist in certain rural hospitals and critical access hospitals.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H242AACC1B07C40E9A7E91B73B3C076B5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3DEF33263CF94304AB01BDD436AE7CBE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Access to Rural Anesthesiology Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC4790A61A20B4A818505621DBFE6A28D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medicare part A payment for anesthesiologist services in certain rural hospitals and critical access hospitals</header> <subsection id="H2E50DF9CA36F4694B501D268511D462C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Subsection (d) hospitals</header> <paragraph id="H717491B4FF7E4BDD84A40490F2F9B0AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1886(d)(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8576B8A94B7D480B864A0168C461B5A8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HF6A92A1E81084DBE88F6134149FA4EF5" commented="no" indent="up2"><enum>(N)</enum> 
<clause id="HA211DE70766446988B7F8B9CFDB01AB4" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no" indent="up3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For cost reporting periods beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Medicare Access to Rural Anesthesiology Act</short-title>, in the case of a subsection (d) hospital described in <internal-xref idref="H6E91EC95AF2B4F62B310B28258664E55" legis-path="(N)(ii)">clause (ii)</internal-xref>, payment to such hospital for physicians’ services that are anesthesia services furnished by a physician who is an anesthesiologist in such hospital shall be made on a reasonable cost basis.</text></clause> <clause id="H6E91EC95AF2B4F62B310B28258664E55" indent="up1" commented="no"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause id="HC0E18E43CEA241719EC898C2AE3337DF" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to <internal-xref idref="H1D2DE03C52904A9DB8282516FAFE24D0" legis-path="(N)(ii)(II)">subclause (II)</internal-xref>, for purposes of <internal-xref idref="HA211DE70766446988B7F8B9CFDB01AB4" legis-path="(N)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref>, a subsection (d) hospital described in this clause is, with respect to a year (beginning with 2026), a subsection (d) hospital that is located in a rural area (as defined in paragraph (2)(D)) (but not including any hospital that is treated as being located in such an area pursuant to paragraph (8)(E)) that establishes, at any time before the year, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that—</text>
                                    <item id="H3EF6DF69CEEF421780A33499664E9B12" indent="up1" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no">
                                        <enum>(aa)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as of the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Medicare Access to Rural Anesthesiology Act</short-title>, the hospital employed or contracted with a physician who is an anesthesiologist (but not more than one full-time equivalent physician);</text>
                                    </item>
                                    <item id="HC6761152ACE9422FB77B7300A6B9DBA0" indent="up1" commented="no">
                                        <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in 2026, the hospital had a volume of surgical procedures (including inpatient and outpatient procedures) requiring anesthesia services that did not exceed 800 (or such higher number as the Secretary determines to be appropriate); and</text>
                                    </item>
                                    <item id="H3C2CA0DFAB8845B8BA8740FBB0A60B0E" indent="up1" commented="no">
                                        <enum>(cc)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each physician who is an anesthesiologist employed by, or under contract with, the hospital has agreed not to bill under part B for professional services furnished by the anesthesiologist at the hospital.</text>
                                    </item>
                                </subclause>
                                <subclause id="H1D2DE03C52904A9DB8282516FAFE24D0" indent="up1" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a year (after 2027), a hospital is not a subsection (d) hospital described in this clause unless the hospital establishes, before the beginning of the year, that the hospital has had a volume of surgical procedures (including inpatient and outpatient procedures) requiring anesthesia services in the previous year that did not exceed 800 (or such higher number as the Secretary determines to be appropriate).</text>
                                </subclause>
                            </clause> </subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2CB14F051C6406A8426E8CE4F066D33" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treated as part of inpatient hospital services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H997F18AD9CFA46B8B35D3D1FA48361D2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1DC390E4DDB44BD487EDDCAF3C06FA5C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5543E1871A32467DB0A32157FA17E16B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC5429879343B4220BA2219DD446FB571" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HE1AD2935A42047669A397B1C32032DC7" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a physician who is an anesthesiologist where the hospital is a subsection (d) hospital described in section 1886(d)(5)(N)(ii).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EF110C8823940639655FD40EE80850A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Excluded from operating costs of inpatient hospital services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1886(a)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended in the second sentence by inserting <quote>for cost reporting periods beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Medicare Access to Rural Anesthesiology Act</short-title>, costs of physicians’ services that are anesthesia services furnished by a physician who is an anesthesiologist in a subsection (d) hospital described in subsection (d)(5)(N)(ii),</quote> before <quote>or costs with respect to administering blood clotting factors</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE0FE42CCFE2F41BEA3BF0C81E08E6338"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Critical access hospitals</header><text>Section 1861(mm) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(mm)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H95B0168500F147409CD42EC3ECB1C0CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For cost reporting periods beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Medicare Access to Rural Anesthesiology Act</short-title>, such term includes physicians’ services that are anesthesia services furnished by a physician who is an anesthesiologist in a critical access hospital described in paragraph (4).</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H885E2E64D0004A22B7D52D5FDF3915EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0E14648ABD2F48B1BB2B50400B88CBE1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H23B24CD9C15E483C80924EF938007CF8" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum> <subparagraph id="H921D9E2C03E14B419AE878A0BBD192C5" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), for purposes of paragraph (2), a critical access hospital described in this paragraph is, with respect to a year (beginning with 2027), a critical access hospital that establishes, at any time before the year, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that—</text> 
<clause id="HF873C290D6664947B0FD6EE6BE026504" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as of the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Medicare Access to Rural Anesthesiology Act</short-title>, the critical access hospital employed or contracted with a physician who is an anesthesiologist (but not more than one full-time equivalent physician);</text></clause> <clause id="HF31BE9A86E244F46A146AC5013A0AC19" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in 2026, the critical access hospital had a volume of surgical procedures (including inpatient and outpatient procedures) requiring anesthesia services that did not exceed 800 (or such higher number as the Secretary determines to be appropriate); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2C434559AF5D460EA11C264352803085" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>each physician who is an anesthesiologist employed by, or under contract with, the critical access hospital has agreed not to bill under part B for professional services furnished by the anesthesiologist at the critical access hospital.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H81CF8135F00D44EFA2EF005D825B6552" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to a year (after 2027), a critical access hospital is not a critical access hospital described in this paragraph unless the critical access hospital establishes, before the beginning of the year, that the critical access hospital has had a volume of surgical procedures (including inpatient and outpatient procedures) requiring anesthesia services in the previous year that did not exceed 800 (or such higher number as the Secretary determines to be appropriate).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H95CD992FB395415FB3A83721945C1BBD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Excluded from medical and other health services</header><text>Section 1861(s)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(other than physicians’ services that are anesthesia services furnished during a cost reporting period beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Medicare Access to Rural Anesthesiology Act</short-title> by a physician who is an anesthesiologist in a subsection (d) hospital described in section 1886(d)(5)(N)(ii) or a critical access hospital described in section 1861(mm)(4))</quote> before the semicolon.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8BB7E0E5952041EFBB34A7C6F6AD5DF1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall revise the regulations promulgated for purposes of section 1862(a)(14) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)(14)</external-xref>) such that, for cost reporting periods beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, such regulations define the term <quote>physicians’ services</quote> to exclude physicians’ services that are anesthesia services furnished by a physician who is an anesthesiologist in—</text> 
<paragraph id="HABFAF0F7EB8F41A79470B374A27D545F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a subsection (d) hospital described in subparagraph (N)(ii) of section 1886(d)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D095FDA681D4D3B9B53909AE65B6D6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a critical access hospital described in paragraph (4) of section 1861(mm) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(mm)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

