<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP26026-ND7-RY-PVF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3611 IS: Blockchain Regulatory Certainty Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3611</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260112">January 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To clarify the treatment of certain non-controlling developers or providers of distributed ledger services involved in digital assets with respect to money transmission laws, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Blockchain Regulatory Certainty Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide31eceb5e274404484e6658dca959b09"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of certain non-controlling developers with respect to money transmission laws</header><subsection id="ide6d21134808a470fa761d7e3cc2dbbf6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idd90329e8fe594e4b95bd198329f830bf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Developer or provider</header><text>The term <term>developer or provider</term> means any person or business that creates or publishes software to facilitate the creation of, or provide maintenance to, a distributed ledger, or a service associated with a distributed ledger.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5132bab56284f92997069a6fe5fcd75"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Digital asset</header> <text>The term <term>digital asset</term> means any digital representation of value which is recorded on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id614c7badf0474cb4b7e06060877b1bcb"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Distributed ledger</header><text>The term <term>distributed ledger</term> means technology in which data is shared across a network that—</text><subparagraph id="idedd99bc3a37f4f0db8662ce1f150c822"><enum>(A)</enum><text>creates a public digital ledger of verified transactions or information among network participants; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb500f50f1b514bc28704a984a19d2704"><enum>(B)</enum><text>uses cryptography to link the data to maintain the integrity of the public ledger and execute other functions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc06a58884974dfe83a2810fcf153aca"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Distributed ledger service</header><text>The term <term>distributed ledger service</term> means any information, transaction, or computing service or system that provides or enables access to a distributed ledger system by multiple users, including a service or system that enables users to send, receive, exchange, or store digital assets described by distributed ledger systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4272eee6ec9e4ca29cfe9e9401ad2ada"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Non-controlling developer or provider</header><text>The term <term>non-controlling developer or provider</term> means a developer or provider of a distributed ledger service that, in the regular course of operations, does not have the legal right or the unilateral and independent ability to control, initiate upon demand, or effectuate transactions involving digital assets to which users are entitled, without the approval, consent, or direction of any other third party.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfd1ad412e83f4afdb31be5e6a9a5ebc4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a non-controlling developer or provider—</text><paragraph id="id54a18c0e5b1d46ebb03de47bf4c5908d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not be treated as—</text><subparagraph id="id8e023fc866724d7da8942001c5cec6bd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a money transmitting business, as defined in section 5330 of title 31, United States Code, and the regulations promulgated under that section; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf7046ff984e74e549b75fbf6c7b299a5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engaged in money transmitting, as defined in section 1960 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by this Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id72705fd6f3534d799a0881c8875ff1b3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on or after the date of enactment of this Act, shall not be otherwise subject to any registration requirement that is substantially similar to a requirement (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act) that applies to an entity described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1), solely on the basis of—</text><subparagraph id="id0e43c3923cd841c7906a01ada00022f3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>creating or publishing software to facilitate the creation of, or providing maintenance services to, a distributed ledger or a service associated with a distributed ledger;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f072f00d1504a1bbef8f0ba25e540e0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing hardware or software to facilitate a customer’s own custody or safekeeping of the digital assets of the customer; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d929fb013fb477ebc254f4e42e7b120"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing infrastructure support to maintain a distributed ledger service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbd523faceb954ca8843c1c387c14dcb4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed—</text><paragraph id="id729c7963eae94c8cbed801245ad8bde2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to affect whether a developer or provider of a blockchain service is otherwise subject to classification or treatment as a money transmitter, or as engaged in money transmitting, under applicable Federal or State law, including laws relating to anti-money laundering or countering the financing of terrorism, based on conduct outside the scope of subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id616f97d569924777801fa049be25ce3d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to affect whether a developer or provider is otherwise subject to classification or treatment as a financial institution under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, this Act, any amendment made by this Act, or any Act enacted after the date of enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0324dd780dae41d7a73730b655f70334"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to limit or expand any law pertaining to intellectual property;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9be4c13b15384cd0afcefd03aaa2bc3b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to prevent any State from enforcing any State law that is consistent with this section; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfeeed8493c644fadb7a0e55e7079c2f2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to create a cause of action or impose liability under any State or local law that is inconsistent with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

