<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H25E33BEF2E72465D93D2E572F0E71AB6" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1347 IH: Recognizing the roles and contributions of automotive workers in the United States, with particular recognition of their impact in Michigan, and expressing support for the designation of September 2026 as “American Automotive Worker Recognition Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1347</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000307">Mr. James</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the roles and contributions of automotive workers in the United States, with particular recognition of their impact in Michigan, and expressing support for the designation of September 2026 as <quote>American Automotive Worker Recognition Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States automotive industry exemplifies the American worker, is a cornerstone of the Nation’s manufacturing base, and drives economic production for the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the State of Michigan serves as the focal point of American automotive manufacturing, earning the reputation as the heart and soul of the Nation’s auto industry;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Michigan is proud to be home to more than 160,000 direct automotive manufacturing jobs, the largest amount in the United States, producing vehicles and components that are safely relied upon by families, businesses, and first responders across the country, and supports hundreds of thousands more jobs across the supply chain and its related industries;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the broader automotive industry supports more than 10,000,000 American jobs, including direct manufacturing, suppliers, logistics, and dealership employment, which contributes $1,200,000,000,000 to the American economy, which will be approximately 3.7 percent of the Nation’s gross domestic product, with Michigan serving as a leading contributor to that output;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Michigan-based workers, engineers, and manufacturers have been at the forefront of innovation for more than a century, from inventing the assembly line to creating advanced mobility technologies;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the automotive industry remains an essential backbone of blue-collar employment in Michigan and across the United States, providing stable, good-paying jobs that support strong American families and strengthen local communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Michigan’s automotive supply chain includes thousands of manufacturers, from small family-owned shops to large century-old corporations, many located in communities that rely on a strong domestic auto industry for economic stability and growth;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas automotive workers play a vital role in maintaining and advancing industrial capacity within the United States, which is essential for economic resilience, worldwide stability and security, and preparedness in times of crisis resulting in the home of the Arsenal of Democracy;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas continued investment in American manufacturing, with Michigan’s automotive sector being at the forefront, strengthens domestic supply chains and reduces reliance on foreign production, resulting in a stronger, and more United States of America;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas policies that support domestic production and a skilled workforce are essential and great drivers to ensuring that automotive jobs remain and grow in the State of Michigan and the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a strong automotive workforce contributes to American energy independence, mobility, and infrastructure development; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas recognizing the contributions of autoworkers honors a proud tradition of American manufacturing excellence deeply rooted in Michigan: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H42B203F4847149A4933D484E88EA8C07"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H040956D3808D4A63ADD2BA5B1CADF51B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H6B2D973C756C4F1997D7706D3F97149E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>American Automotive Worker Recognition Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EA7C783B34340E8BAE03853B4E945BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the vital role of automotive workers, particularly those in Michigan, in strengthening the United States economy, manufacturing base, and national security;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1215321342274DF2AC98681DFD51CA27"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the skill, dedication, and productivity of American autoworkers across manufacturing plants, supply chains, and dealerships;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FA28FE9CC5F4D6FB3ACE68FA4FF6840"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acknowledges the importance of policies that promote domestic production, workforce development, and supply chain resilience, especially in leading automotive States like Michigan;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BCF85192A6C47E0BF755DE827548341"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages continued investment in the American automotive industry to ensure global competitiveness; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2397A0731D144AC7A5637692CF5ED1DD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>thanks the Nation’s automotive workers, including the generations of workers in Michigan, for their contributions to American industry, innovation, and prosperity.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution> 

