<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELL26174-8Y7-K7-JNH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4151 IS: Unfunded Mandates Accountability and Transparency Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4151</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 to provide for regulatory impact analyses for certain rules, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H1ED06CB51D0C4C1B96B6A5D2D24479AA"><section section-type="section-one" id="H1EC2AEEB395D452083F5466D27DBC965"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unfunded Mandates Accountability and Transparency Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H74971B14188242829599451BAF51FB93"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulatory impact analyses for certain rules</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1501">2 U.S.C. 1501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3AD5C8863E844C248589F70F10A6509F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>tribal</quote> each place that term appears and inserting <quote>Tribal</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6C634A8AA7C4208B7171B0510412DD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 3 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1502">2 U.S.C. 1502</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HE1916921F63D49A497F358CD4588D9FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED57C097FD354869A5515D7197455DA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01596C73B90E40ABB95E82198CD3003F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H474AF677803944B09E453A707EADB4F4"><paragraph id="H96A5EACB5D5A4F4F98A4F3E5B3EAEC5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>major rule</term> means a rule, as defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code, that the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs determines is likely to cause—</text><subparagraph id="H8FD7C3D701C34419BF9AF83DDEE756BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an annual effect on the economy of $100,000,000 or more, adjusted once every 5 years to reflect increases in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers, as published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE517F6E48B2548FEAA37011701D7D683"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, Federal, State, local, or Tribal government agencies, or geographic regions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EE136139CE94A91BFD66DC596CF3938"><enum>(C)</enum><text>significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, public health and safety, or the ability of United States-based enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises in domestic and export markets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H568C4A06560C4D46900B062BA8E10D0C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 202 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1532">2 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H04D160F914E648098CEBDEDE508A868B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking the section heading and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="section">Regulatory impact analyses for certain rules.</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CA39AE4A03D4F8CA15EC41E2AE8C6A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C26B593B45F447489B7304FF70B28EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H778138629A724A21B562A42DAB163E20"><subsection id="HDB290F0AAA3A4E49936A6E96DDB2FE1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of cost</header><text>In this section, the term <term>cost</term> means the cost of compliance and any reasonably foreseeable indirect costs, including revenues lost, as a result of a major rule of an agency that is subject to this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H690C3FA0731E454B8E851EF2C88892D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulatory impact analyses</header><paragraph id="H4293C8159FFB4D24AFF9026DE94D543B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Before promulgating any proposed or final major rule, the agency promulgating the major rule shall prepare and publish in the Federal Register an initial and final regulatory impact analysis with respect to the major rule.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DDCE4019D8F41CA88868C990AAD8F6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial regulatory impact analysis</header><text>An initial regulatory impact analysis required under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H0EDB4D697A7F430D9F44F2FAA9E4C34B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accompany the notice of proposed rulemaking with respect to the major rule that is the subject of the analysis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE429329435147C8852266C20C62C7AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be open to public comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC043F61DABA4E3C9CF8175584590AD4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final regulatory impact analysis</header><text>A final regulatory impact analysis required under paragraph (1) shall accompany the final major rule that is the subject of the analysis.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94AFC64DAC8F45BCAA92F8769B9B258E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Content</header><text>Each initial and final regulatory impact analysis prepared and published under subsection (b) shall include, with respect to the major rule that is the subject of the analysis—</text><paragraph id="H93012BB4A94D42B982E418F46CE98730" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8DC158FD6EBA46D38D09D951D66B887C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of the anticipated benefits and costs of the major rule, which shall be quantified to the extent feasible;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC8A3EB8B9BE44EA9ECFBCA720C10A1E" indent="up1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of the benefits and costs of a reasonable number of regulatory alternatives within the range of the discretion of the agency under the statute authorizing the major rule, including alternatives that—</text><clause id="H33AE0F7ACC6548A6997F69197E8A7A70" changed="not-changed"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use incentives and market-based means to encourage the desired behavior;</text></clause><clause id="HC07F1F74FA244353AE97E63AF57D7D2C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide information based upon which the public can make choices; or</text></clause><clause id="HE4E8864B51F34325A41CACEC3E31CBB6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employ other flexible regulatory options that permit the greatest flexibility in achieving the objectives of the statute authorizing the major rule; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2EB1E8288794A048C0480782845CDA0" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an explanation of how the major rule complies with the requirements of section 205;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79A1BB8B66924A669AA721160AACB604"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of the extent to which—</text><subparagraph id="HFEF3AC49F7DA4EB9A4B8858687CD957B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the costs to State, local, and Tribal governments may be paid with Federal financial assistance (or otherwise paid for by the Federal Government); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66C50EE3D5574AE6BC8AC9CEC932057D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal resources are available to carry out the major rule;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0C9282197134E6A970770AD552B64C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>estimates of—</text><subparagraph id="H6A756F070EC74DBD9518A65B10D45E42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any disproportionate budgetary effects of the major rule upon any particular—</text><clause id="HF617199BF77346EABC1C5CDB9F3C909A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>regions of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H9F0FB03702C0477993833BA310B34844"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>State, local, or Tribal governments;</text></clause><clause id="HCB216E0C010F4B41B54564A353F5ACFD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>types of communities, including urban or rural communities; or</text></clause><clause id="HA69E41673AAF4ABA8B365DCB2597437E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>segments of the private sector; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H196A2EBE1F824DFAB3ABF2C4F4F8B313"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effect of the major rule on job creation or job loss, which shall be quantified to the extent feasible; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E976036742B4E1B83BEF25D24013340"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H919DDF8EC1CD40DC8B9C4A8BD79B9492"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the extent of the prior consultation of the agency under section 204 with elected representatives of each affected State, local, or Tribal government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEEBDEB7BF2442AC8EFE744BA43B7274" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary of the comments and concerns that were presented to the agency orally or in writing by State, local, or Tribal governments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18583FD13B674B7B8B53E57CD93F0409" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a summary of the evaluation by the agency of the comments and concerns described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49DAEC83FCE7437081FEC8EF344C9076"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (d), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>a statement under subsection (a) is required, the agency shall include in the promulgation a summary of the information contained in the statement</quote> and inserting <quote>an analysis under subsection (b) is required, the agency promulgating the major rule shall include in the promulgation a summary of the information contained in the analysis</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA42D3440747E441E8D339DBB8696A99A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subsection (e), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>any statement required under subsection (a) in conjunction with or as a part of any other statement or analysis, if the statement or analysis satisfies the provisions of subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>any analysis required under subsection (b) in conjunction with, or as a part of, any other analysis if the other analysis satisfies the requirements of subsections (b) and (c)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HFE9B5BF462ED4255B22880EC69B9369C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enhanced stakeholder consultation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 204 of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1534">2 U.S.C. 1534</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4C1A99AC02A446D8B176500F717EB192"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and private sector</header-in-text></quote> before <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">input</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H507B706401714769A58761086ACE41FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HE65276F1C2E24B808A5428E26C369278"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and impacted parties within the private sector (including small businesses),</quote> after <quote>on their behalf)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0055D4CB71E8474F9285B09BF4574CF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Federal intergovernmental mandates</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal mandates</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E790AC5E5CB455B9C7F2D11358D65B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE050F39EDEDE4A70B391A0595414F3EE"><subsection id="H2D5A5432021944BEA6D8EB29DD9DC8EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>For appropriate implementation of subsections (a) and (b) consistent with applicable laws and regulations, the following guidelines shall be followed:</text><paragraph id="H49BCE9EDE1384DD084C80054C2AEEE09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Consultations described in those subsections shall take place as early as possible, before issuance of a notice of proposed rulemaking, continue through the final rule stage, and be integrated explicitly into the rulemaking process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H438DC54175D0422F8FA4BB44B811291E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Agencies shall consult with a wide variety of State, local, and Tribal officials and impacted parties within the private sector (including small businesses). Geographic, political, and other factors that may differentiate varying points of view should be considered.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4670613704A541FDA3915EDDB7E0840A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Agencies should estimate benefits and costs to assist with the consultations described in those subsections. The scope of the consultation should reflect the cost and significance of the Federal mandate being considered.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D861FA8F25B4531BEDDF17F135DF41D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Agencies shall, to the extent practicable—</text><subparagraph id="H6AC554E342904C90A4A380413D1BB3E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seek out the views of State, local, and Tribal governments, and impacted parties within the private sector (including small businesses), on costs, benefits, and risks with respect to the applicable regulatory proposal; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E1C922DE9874AD7971BA146106F810E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>solicit ideas about alternative methods of compliance and potential flexibilities, and input on whether the applicable Federal regulation will harmonize with and not duplicate similar laws in other levels of government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H680B80C61FC34D7DA25FBB055C9280BE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Consultations described in those subsections shall address the cumulative impact of regulations on the affected entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8C8EDB7CB0D4C66AE7C9DE107ED1301"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Agencies may accept electronic submissions of comments by relevant parties but may not use those comments as the sole method of satisfying the guidelines in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H9B3CED4EEAD34117A741B3E0F1FA42ED"><enum>4.</enum><header>Maximize net benefits or provide explanation</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2e990db8cd7b4c6894f978f535448331"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title II of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1531">2 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by striking section 205 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1535">2 U.S.C. 1535</external-xref>) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5CBCDA8E3C3A46D09F599DBF824E570C"><section id="H4EDE1BD004B049DFA8AD815574D859D8"><enum>205.</enum><header>Maximize net benefits</header><subsection id="HB91960950A8F41DCB2F157CA32C92768"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of cost</header><text>In this section, the term <term>cost</term> has the meaning given the term in section 202(a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD240451CAFCF4F87AE2863F137794CA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before promulgating any proposed or final major rule for which a regulatory impact analysis is required under section 202, an agency shall, from the alternatives identified and considered under section 202(c)(1)(B), select the alternative that maximizes net benefits, taking into consideration only the costs and benefits that arise within the scope of the statutory provision that authorizes the rulemaking.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA6834F350263418FB81C11C636D3179B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency may adopt an alternative other than as required under subsection (b) only if—</text><paragraph id="HF75589C8DDBF42AE9746BF38469D339F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs approves the adoption by the agency of the alternative; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H747BBC95E22746AFBCBF6B958ED3B2D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alternative is adopted to—</text><subparagraph id="H29F249F59C43403F8A9A719C0FA7979E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>account for costs or benefits that cannot be quantified, including costs or benefits relating to constitutional or civil rights, if the agency identifies all such costs and benefits and explains why those costs and benefits justify the adoption of the alternative; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E056964E1F943A6AACFE4AA628538A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>achieve additional benefits or cost reductions, if the agency—</text><clause id="H5513AF96A0B74CB2A462649B66954E44"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifies—</text><subclause id="H42358F64B48941D69BC9D25B3734A023"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all such additional benefits and the associated costs of those benefits; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAE165942CB824AC9B8FC9BD62389A760"><enum>(II)</enum><text>all such cost reductions and the associated benefits of those cost reductions; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0227B26CDE0A499AAD3578486A5D8E96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>explains why—</text><subclause id="H9533E52A7722489BB3133BAE08503754"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the additional benefits justify the additional costs; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H33E3374F9A3A4427A85B6996C3E4AAD5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the additional cost reductions justify any benefits foregone.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30a3b3687bf7401ca0b85460387e7564"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 206 of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1536">2 U.S.C. 1536</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb8cd365243b495695f3a31ab624a0ec"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>statements</quote> each place the term appears and inserting <quote>analysis</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a5de3ff7b2b44baab7a9ab89eb7c603"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>statement</quote> and inserting <quote>analysis</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H48C38E8095D74B07BEE8AEDD4B2460FE"><enum>5.</enum><header>New authorities and responsibilities for Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 208 of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1538">2 U.S.C. 1538</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H822E9124032A47C196F7BA106D3203F2"><section id="H9114D84B6DE9490FBA33EA5FF0BA24FA"><enum>208.</enum><header>Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs responsibilities</header><subsection id="H0BD1024680134A8BB31B8A3BE46CBDE0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (in this section referred to as the <term>Administrator</term>) shall provide meaningful guidance and oversight so that the major rules of an agency for which a regulatory impact analysis is required under section 202—</text><paragraph id="H0F1AD2245917429C9F1D9CF80FCB3656"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is consistent with the principles and requirements of this title, as well as other applicable laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD24293343D334AF29B11CDA875CF58FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not conflict with the policies or actions of another agency. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1A76E4905944763BCF5143248F3040E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator determines that a major rule of an agency for which a regulatory impact analysis is required under section 202 does not comply with the principles and requirements of this title, is not consistent with other applicable laws, or conflicts with the policies or actions of another agency, the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H297D974B7D6840F8B1D155BE34121A88"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify areas of noncompliance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEB054C972094680BC4FFA3564A9D84E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the agency; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE78B03535D84C26B49F0D2833B09B74"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">request that the agency comply before the agency finalizes the major rule.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEA2A19BEF944F40BD8DEB11B986E737"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual statements to Congress on agency compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall submit to Congress, including the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, an annual written report that, for the 1-year period preceding the submission of the report—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H985C1011AA8D4CD38B817856630CAD82"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">details compliance by each agency with the requirements of this title that relate to major rules for which a regulatory impact analysis is required by section 202, including activities undertaken at the request of the Administrator to improve compliance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D1428F455414AE78B9C03E8FD4DCFE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains an appendix detailing compliance by each agency with section 204.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HB65D25DC1305471F956D400F387EF3CE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Initiation of rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1501">2 U.S.C. 1501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H20B6221E9F1149E8AFC68E4AC2A7F159"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 209 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1531">2 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> note) as section 210; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D97FDE8854B4EAB8DB804756B12E66B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 208 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1538">2 U.S.C. 1538</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD205A32D04444E668F5ADD0A6A58706B"><section id="H5C1598B449A5460A9769E03FB883454F"><enum>209.</enum><header>Initiation of rulemaking for major rules</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">When an agency determines to initiate a rulemaking that may result in a major rule, the agency shall—</text><paragraph id="H85CDDBB79DAC48B3BB93F70CED1E262B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish an electronic docket for that rulemaking, which may have a physical counterpart; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFEA1D29ED434C48AA7D7862FF54A636"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish a notice of initiation of rulemaking in the Federal Register, which shall—</text><subparagraph id="H8391199318884E2681B913A8E60702D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>briefly describe the subject and objectives of, and the problem to be solved by, the major rule;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F6454DEBBF942B09D52562D9994FCF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>refer to the legal authority under which the major rule would be proposed, including the specific statutory provision that authorizes the rulemaking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61DE88D1DFD94930B9A544174CF5D9BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>invite interested persons to propose alternatives and other ideas regarding how best to accomplish the objectives of the agency in the most effective manner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD90156D27AA4D318E9F5799448A7399"><enum>(D)</enum><text>indicate how interested persons may submit written material for the docket; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61385CC8C70243548F5AA5CCA37D4F4E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>appear in the Federal Register not later than 90 days before the date on which the agency publishes a notice of proposed rulemaking for the major rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HE1F7CEB7E7974319A41EFB85D92B2EBF"><enum>7.</enum><header>Inclusion of application to independent regulatory agencies</header><subsection id="H33C0AF3EA9354B2181DC9EDA39D849CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 421(1) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/658">2 U.S.C. 658(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, but does not include independent regulatory agencies</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC48A1EA99F544431B50CCC93123A930F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption for monetary policy</header><text>The Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1501">2 U.S.C. 1501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 5 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1504">2 U.S.C. 1504</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1389B862AB14525974D7108A710B5D7"><section id="H6739A3231BC14EFA969E5F163061656F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Exemption for monetary policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in title II, III, or IV shall apply to rules that concern monetary policy proposed or implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H5EB8569CDA71480F99C608574238E8F2"><enum>8.</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 is amended by striking section 401 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1571">2 U.S.C. 1571</external-xref>) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D842EF1836C45308CC27C196901B3B8"><section id="H88EB382F929F4D388C1F32160FDEF9EB"><enum>401.</enum><header>Judicial review</header><subsection id="HE936CAD268364A95B350266EE7515DFD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person that is aggrieved by final agency action in adopting a major rule that is subject to section 202 is entitled to judicial review of whether the agency complied with section 202(b), 202(c)(1), or 205 with respect to the rule.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0EEB3D0FB185446E9B8D799A4C0F0821"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope of review</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall govern the scope of judicial review under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H0313310F94B840B299A5B7C7DE4A9162"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>Each court that has jurisdiction to review a rule for compliance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, or under any other provision of law, shall have jurisdiction to review a claim brought under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1CF80E51E164D34B46A1D8D1B00432B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relief available</header><text>In granting relief in an action under this section, a court shall order the agency that promulgated the major rule that is under review to take remedial action consistent with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H33C49B85937444C1BEAF616E460EDAA0"><enum>9.</enum><header>Applying substantive point of order to private sector mandates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 425(a)(2) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/658d">2 U.S.C. 658d(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text><paragraph id="HF66E3F88169B45D8A54256E5C8D0F342"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Federal intergovernmental mandates</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal mandates</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H473F7286E9AC4F649D1B3DD6106FA673"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 424(a)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1) of section 424</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HAEC2DB090FCE4E3FA1A8B488FA3608E5"><enum>10.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 2, 3, 4, and 6 of this Act and the amendments made by those sections shall take effect on the date that is 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

