<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WIL26131-HC2-41-NSJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4143 IS: Fair Wages for Incarcerated Workers Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4143</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require coverage of incarcerated workers under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Wages for Incarcerated Workers Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id21A731067C59487292CA345AF65A7EB6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coverage of incarcerated workers under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id8FB39649070F46DFBEA450F57C6CFF86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="idFDD24F6366C34386809264CDCE6110DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="id62599EEF20DD4D628E50EFC7478180B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause><clause id="id23F9BA89EE644E22844711B6F845AA92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii)(V), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id6D78CB797A2B44C59D1141308C361096"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD9BAF4E1230544789A5E25AAE77FE801"><subparagraph id="id6036E8FC4E4A4EB5AA761A73BFCD86C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any individual employed as an incarcerated worker by a public agency that operates the correctional facility in which such individual is incarcerated or detained.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72058BE3A7734213A8F0E6A9519B5F4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id762CF10B19E7421988A841FE462E1501"><paragraph id="id50CA0E5E7A3A4EA68B392BD8D982D17D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>employee</term> includes (in addition to an individual described in paragraph (2)(D)) any individual employed as an incarcerated worker by a private entity that operates, through a contract with a public agency, the correctional facility in which such individual is incarcerated or detained.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5267E78D0A374BE9A1AB3CF11773F2A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (m)(1), by striking <quote>any employee.</quote> and inserting <quote>any employee: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, in the case of an employee who is an incarcerated worker, the cost of board, lodging, or other facilities and any amount taken from amounts paid such incarcerated worker for payment of a court-imposed fee shall not be included in the wage paid to such employee.</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB1F79F314CEB47D8BEA6314243EF8761"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAB66A24BD0CE495999F659C72AF3DE7E"><subsection id="id85782F20C5B348BEB5A1E9492F12B1A9"><enum>(z)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id0864706E8B9543499E72B59183D99711"><enum>(1)</enum><text><term>Incarcerated worker</term> means an individual, incarcerated or detained in a correctional facility operated by a public agency or by a private entity through a contract with a public agency, who performs work offered or required by or through the correctional facility, including work associated with prison work programs, work release programs, the UNICOR program, State prison industries, public works programs, restitution centers, correctional facility operations and maintenance, and private entities. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAB7D1E8EFEA241B6B78ACB420F231256" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An incarcerated worker shall be considered employed by—</text><subparagraph id="idA12B368AEF124A43AD19E2D77697B9FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the public agency operating the correctional facility in which the individual is incarcerated or detained; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4C4B35AFF3F947DFA1383DC0016A70C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a correctional facility operated by a private entity through a contract with a public agency, such private entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7C384B40FA16479B8C843FDC7F68FE6B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text><term>Correctional facility</term> has the meaning given such term in section 901 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id74985E4507244653997450CB5879FDA4"><enum>(bb)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3999FDA6176441CEADBD2811368C1B33"><enum>(1)</enum><text><term>Court-imposed fee</term> means any fee imposed by a court as a result of a criminal conviction, including any surcharge imposed for a felony or misdemeanor conviction, a criminal justice administrative fee, a court-appointed attorney fee, a court clerk fee, a filing clerk fee, a DNA database fee, a jury fee, a crime lab analysis fee, a late fee, an installment fee, or any other court cost.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDCE3B37AA1CB49FEB09E20EFD15FA7C9" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>court-imposed fee</term> does not include any amount required by a court to be paid for child support, to a crime victim compensation fund, for a civil judgment, or for a criminal fine.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

